<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <?xml-stylesheet 
  type="text/xsl" 
  href="../../../xsl/descriptions.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE 
  express SYSTEM "../../../dtd/description.dtd">
<ext_descriptions module_directory="constructive_solid_geometry_3d" schema_file="arm.xml" rcs.date="$Date: 2002/05/10 16:08:54 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.2 $">


  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm"/>


  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: CSG_shape_representation_3d 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.CSG_shape_representation_3d">
        A <b>CSG_shape_representation_3d</b> is a
      <b>CSG_shape_representation</b> whose members are three dimensional.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Block 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Block">
        A <b>block</b> is a solid rectangular parallelepiped defined with a
      location and placement coordinate system. The <b>block</b> is
      specified by the positive lengths x, y, and z along the axes of the
      placement coordinate system, and has one vertex at the origin of the
      placement coordinate system.  
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Ellipsoid 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Ellipsoid">
        An <b>ellipsoid</b> is a type of CSG primitive that is defined by
      its location and 
        orientation and by the lengths of the three semi-axes.  
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Sphere 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Sphere">
        A <b>Sphere</b> is a CSG primitive with a spherical shape de.ned by
      a centre and a radius.  
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Torus 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Torus">
        A <b>Torus</b> is a solid primitive defined by sweeping the area of a circle (the generatrix) about a larger circle (the directrix). The directrix is defined by a location and direction.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Eccentric_cone 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Eccentric_cone">
        An <b>Eccentric_cone</b> is a CSG primitive which is a
generalisation of the right circular cone. The <b>Eccentric_cone</b> may
have an elliptic cross section, and may have a central axis which is not
perpendicular to the base. Depending upon the value of the ratio attribute,
it may be truncated, or may take the form of a generalised cylinder. When
truncated, the top face of the cone is parallel to the plane of the base
and has a similar cross section. 
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Right_circular_cylinder 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Right_circular_cylinder">
        A <b>Right_circular_cylinder</b> is a CSG primitive in the form of a solid cylinder of finite height. It is defined by an axis point at the centre of one planar circular face, an axis, a height, and a radius. The faces are perpendicular to the axis and are circular discs with the specified radius. The height is the distance from the first circular face centre in the positive direction of the axis to the second circular face centre.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Right_angular_wedge 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Right_angular_wedge">
        A <b>Right_angular_wedge</b> can be envisioned as the result of intersecting a block with a plane perpendicular to one of its faces. It is defined with a location and local coordinate system. A triangular/ trapezoidal face lies in the plane defined by the placement X and Y axes. This face is defined by positive lengths x and y along the placement X and Y axes, by the length ltx (if nonzero) parallel to the X axis at a distance y from the placement origin, and by the line connecting the ends of the x and ltx segments. The remainder of the wedge is speci.ed by the positive length z along the placement Z axis which de.nes a distance through which the trapezoid or triangle is extruded. If ltx = 0. the wedge has fivve faces; otherwise, it has six faces.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Rectangular_pyramid 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Rectangular_pyramid">
        A <b>Rectangular pyramid</b> is a solid pyramid with a rectangular base. The apex of the pyramid is directly above the centre point of the base. The rectangular pyramid is specified by its position, which provides a placement coordinate system, its length, depth and height.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Right_circular_cone 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Right_circular_cone">
        A <b>Right_circular_cone</b> is a CSG primitive in the form of a cone which may be truncated. It is defined by an axis, a point on the axis, the semi-angle of the cone, and a distance giving the location in the negative direction along the axis from the point to the base of the cone. In addition, a radius is given, which, if nonzero, gives the size and location of a truncated face of the cone.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Cyclide_segment_solid 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Cyclide_segment_solid">
        A <b>Cyclide_segment_solid</b> is a partial Dupin cyclide solid. This solid has two planar circular faces that in general have different radii and different normal directions. Around the boundary of each of these faces, the curved surface of the solid is tangent to a right circular cone. The semi-vertex angle of the cone is, in each case specified, with respect to the outward normal to its corresponding circular face.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Faceted_primitive 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Faceted_primitive">
        A <b>Faceted primitive</b> is a type of CSG primitive with planar faces. It is defined by a list of four or more points which locate the vertices. These points shall not be coplanar.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Tetrahedron 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Tetrahedron">
        A <b>Tetrahedron</b> is a type of CSG primitive with 4 vertices and 4 triangular faces. It is defined by the four points which locate the vertices. These points shall not be coplanar.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Convex_hexahedron 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Convex_hexahedron">
        A <b>Convex hexahedron</b> is a type of CSG primitive with 8 vertices and 6 four-sided faces. It is defined by the 8 points which locate the vertices.
      </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm  Entity: Half_space_solid 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Constructive_solid_geometry_3d_arm.Half_space_solid">
        A <b>Half_space_solid</b> is defined by the half space which is the regular subset of the domain which lies on one side of an unbounded surface. The domain is limited by an orthogonal box in the <b>Boxed_half_space</b> subtype. The side of the surface which is in the half space is determined by the surface normals and the agreement flag. If the agreement flag is TRUE, then the subset is the one the normals point away from. If the agreement flag is FALSE, then the subset is the one the normals point into.
        <p>
          For a valid <b>Half_space_solid</b>, the surface shall divide the domain into exactly two subsets. Also, within the domain, the surface shall be manifold and all the surface normals shall point into the same subset.
        </p>
      
   </ext_description>
</ext_descriptions>