<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.1 2009/08/20 11:38:09 liutkuviene Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="kinematics"
   part="105"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="3"
   wg.number="492"
   wg.number.express="0000"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="1996"
   published="n"
   previous.revision.year="1996" 
   previous.revision.cancelled="NO"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2009/08/20 11:38:09 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.1 $">

 <keywords>
    resource,  kinematic model, kinematic motion representation, kinematic analysis, 
    Sheth-Uicker Parameter, joint, link, pair
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>
		This part of ISO 10303 specifies an information model for the kinematic aspects of 
		a mechanical product as required for the communication between CAD systems and kinematic
		analysis systems as well as between dissimilar kinematic analysis systems.
	</p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="simon.frechette"/>
   <editor ref="lothar.klein"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
	This part of ISO 10303 specifies an information model for the kinematic aspects of a mechanical
	product as required for the communication between CAD systems and kinematic analysis systems, 
	and among dissimilar kinematic analysis systems.
	Kinematic information in the context of this part of ISO 10303 may be used in:
   </p>
   <ul>
   		<li>
   			early design stages, where detailed component shape is yet undetermined.
   			The purpose of the kinematic description in these stages is to develop 
   			the conceptual model of the mechanical product to understand its motion characteristics;
   		</li>
   		<li>
   			detail design stage where detailed shapes of components are determined.
   			The purpose of the kinematic description in that stage is to verify the 
   			performance of the kinematic characteristics of a mechanical product using 
   			the final shape of its components, e.g., by means of collision checking.
   		</li>
   </ul>
   <p>
   	The kinematic structure in this part of ISO 10303 is composed of rigid components related by
	kinematic pairs along a surface, on a curve, or at a point.
   </p>
   <p>
   	The kinematic structure schema defines the kinematic structure of rigid objects in terms of
	links, pairs, and joints.
	A link is the rigid part of a kinematic object.
	A pair represents the geometric aspects of the kinematic constraints of motion of these objects, 
	and a joint represents the topological aspects of these constraints.
	The kinematic structures are represented by graphs in which the vertices of the graph correspond 
	to the links, and the edges of the graph correspond to the joints.
   </p>
   <p>
   	The kinematic motion representation schema specifies the motion of a mechanical product by
	using a parametric path definition.
   </p>
   <p>
   	The kinematic analysis control and result schema specifies configurations of kinematic structures
	and the interpolation between configurations.
	This schema describes prescribed paths for a kinematic analysis and paths resulting 
	from such a kinematic analysis.
   </p>   
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
	<express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="The relationships between the three schemas of ISO 10303-105: Kinematics (1 of 1)"/>
   </express-g>   
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>definition of kinematic relationships between rigid objects called links;</li>
   <li>representation of the topology for a kinematic structure;</li>
   <li>definition of a kinematic motion as a sequence of discretised positions and orientations;</li>
   <li>representation of the input to and the result of a kinematic analysis.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>description of tolerances and clearances in kinematic structures;</li>
   <li>description of motion parameters in terms of a continuous time variable;</li>
   <li>representation of intermittent joints with variable constraints on motion;</li>
   <li>representation of dynamic mechanical assemblies;</li>
   <li>representation of force, mass, and friction.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1.1994">
 		<!-- application resource -->
 		<term.ref linkend="term41"/>
 		<!-- data -->
 		<term.ref linkend="term5"/>
 		<!-- generic resource -->
 		<term.ref linkend="term42"/>
 		<!-- information -->
 		<term.ref linkend="term6"/>
 		<!-- product -->
 		<term.ref linkend="term8"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.2004"/>
 	<!--  <normref.inc normref="ref10303-21.2002"/>  -->
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-42">
 		<term.ref linkend="geom_coord_system"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="geom_founded"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="graph"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
 </normrefs>	

 <definition>
 	<term id="base">base</term>
 	<def>
 		a link which is fixed to the ground or whose motion is prescribed along a defined path
 	</def>
 </definition>	
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="frame">frame</term>
 	<def>
 		a coordinate system used in kinematic representations
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="ground">ground</term>
 	<def>
 		the immobile part of a mechanical product in the world coordinate system
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="joint">joint</term>
 	<def>
 		the topological aspect of an ordered connection or motion constraint between two
		and only two links
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="kinematics">kinematics</term>
 	<def>
 		the description of movable mechanical structures consisting of joints and
		links including the number, location, and orientation of the joints
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="kinematic_chain">kinematic chain</term>
 	<def>
 		a sequence of kinematic links connected by joints
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="link">link</term>
 	<def>
 		a rigid kinematic object whose motion is constrained by one or more joints
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="link_frame">link frame</term>
 	<def>
 		the local coordinate system of a link, implicitly defined as the geometric
		context of the link, with respect to which all geometric definitions of the link are defined
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="loop">loop</term>
 	<def>
 		a part of a mechanical structure whose joints and links together form a closed kinematic chain
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="mechanism">mechanism</term>
 	<def>
 		a mechanical product whose motion is constrained by joints
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="motion">motion</term>
 	<def>
 		change of position and orientation of a rigid body
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="pair">pair</term>
 	<def>
 		the geometric aspect of either an ordered connection or motion constraint between
		two and only two links
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="pair_actuation">pair actuation</term>
 	<def>
 		the assignment of a pair value to a kinematic pair by an application
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="placement">placement</term>
 	<def>
 		the location and orientation of a frame
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="transform">transform</term>
 	<def>
 		a representation of a placement that is specified with respect to an independent reference frame
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="su_arameters">SU-parameters</term>
 	<def>
 		the parameters that specify the placement between a pair of frames
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="world_oordinate_system">world coordinate system</term>
 	<def>
 		the initial coordinate system from which all other frames are defined
 	</def>
 </definition>

 <abbreviations>
 	<abbreviation id="SU">
 		<acronym>SU</acronym>
 		<term>Sheth-Uicker</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	<abbreviation id="ypr">
 		<acronym>ypr</acronym>
 		<term>rotation angles called yaw, pitch, and roll</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 </abbreviations>



<schema name="kinematic_structure_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<p>
		The subject of the <b>kinematic_structure_schema</b> is the description of the kinematic information 
		of a mechanical product defining its motion capabilities.
	</p>
	<p>
		Motion in this part of ISO 10303 comprises both free, unconstrained motion of objects in a
		Cartesian coordinate system and motion constrained by kinematic joints and pairs.
	</p>
	<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 covers the following types of pairs.
	</p>
	<ol>
		<li>revolute pair;</li>
		<li>prismatic pair;</li>
		<li>screw pair;</li>
		<li>cylindrical pair;</li>
		<li>spherical pair;</li>
		<li>universal pair;</li>
		<li>planar pair;</li>
		<li>gear pair;</li>
		<li>rack and pinion pair;</li>
		<li>unconstrained pair;</li>
		<li>fully constrained pair;</li>
		<li>point on surface pair;</li>
		<li>sliding surface pair;</li>
		<li>rolling surface pair;</li>
		<li>point on planar curve pair;</li>
		<li>sliding curve pair;</li>
		<li>rolling curve pair.</li>
	</ol>
	<p>
		Pair types 1 through 11 are called low order pairs and the remaining pair types are called high
		order pairs.
	</p>
		<note>
			Pair types 1 through 11 do not require explicit geometric information to describe their
			kinematic behaviour.
			Pair types 12 through 17 require a reference to a surface or to a curve in order
			to be defined kinematically.
		</note>
	<p>
		For surface pairs and curve pairs, two specialisations are distinguished: the sliding and rolling subtypes.
		A rolling pair is constrained in the relative motion of the two surfaces or curves such
		that they cannot slide on each other.
	</p>
		<example number="1">
			High levels of friction between two surfaces or curves may be the cause for relative
			motion to be constrained to rolling.
		</example>
	<p>
		For sliding pairs such a constraint does not exist.
	</p>
	<p>
		Low order pairs can be represented as sliding high order pairs.
		If a pair can be represented as a low order pair, it should be so represented and 
		not as a high order pair.
	</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<!-- Kinematic model structure -->
   	<b><i>Kinematic model structure</i></b>
   	<p>
   		Mechanical products with kinematic representations may have arbitrary topological structures.
		The topological structures are not constrained to simple chains (i.e., open kinematic chains
		without branches) or to tree-type structures; they may include loops or a network structure.
   	</p>
   		<note>
   			Every kinematic structure can be described in terms of its joints and links.
   			Joints constrain the motion between two rigid objects called links.
   			Joints and links are sufficient to describe the topology of kinematic structures, 
   			but for computation it is meaningful to introduce additional levels of structure based on graph theory.
   			Information related to the graph representation of a kinematic structure is given in <b>kinematic_substructure</b>.
   		</note>
   		<example number="2">
   			Simple chains are suitable kinematic structures for many industrial robots or cranes.
   			Tree-type structures are used to represent multi-arm manipulators.
   		</example>
   		<example number="3">
   			Network structures occur in industrial products.
   			One example is the mechanism used for windscreen wipers.
   		</example>
   	<p>
   		In this part of ISO 10303, kinematic structures are represented by graphs where the links represent 
   		the vertices of the graph, and the joints represent the edges.
   		The rigid objects with kinematic representations are defined kinematically in terms of links and 
   		geometrically in terms of their associated shape representation.
   		All coordinate systems related to a kinematic link are founded in the link frame, 
   		which is the geometric context of the related link representation.
   		These coordinate systems are called frames in this part of ISO 10303.
   		For the purpose of representing the kinematic aspect of a mechanism, the shape of the link is 
   		represented by the relative location and orientation of all its pair frames with respect to 
   		its link frame.
   	</p>
   	
   	<!-- Positioning and placement -->
   	<b><i>Positioning and placement</i></b>
   	<p>
   		Whenever constraints are imposed on the relative motion of two kinematic links, this fact is 
   		topologically represented by a joint.
   		The geometric aspect of this motion constraint is represented by the corresponding pair.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		A placement describes a relative position and orientation of a frame with respect to another frame.
   		There are different ways of representing a placement.
   		Eight different representations of placement are used in this part of ISO 10303:
   	</p>
   	<ul>
   		<li>rigid homogenous matrix;</li>
   		<li><b>axis2_placement_3d</b>;</li>
   		<li><b>transform</b>;</li>
   		<li><b>su_parameters</b>;</li>
   		<li><b>point_on_curve</b>;</li>
   		<li><b>point_on_surface</b>;</li>
   		<li>a pair type with its <b>initial_state</b>;</li>
   		<li><b>cartesian_transformation_operator_3d</b>.</li>
   	</ul>
   	<p>
   		The rigid homogeneous matrix is used only as a notation in mathematical formulas.
   		It defines the relative position and orientation of one frame with respect to another.
   		The terms of this matrix are as follows:
   	</p>
   	<img src="hom_matrix.gif"/>
   	<p>
   		where the notation used for a frame <b>P</b> shall be <i><sup>k</sup><b>P</b><sub>i</sub></i> with:
   	</p>
   	<p><i>k</i> = identification of the reference frame in which the position of frame <i>i</i> is described;</p>
   	<p><i>i</i> = identification of the frame whose position is described with respect to frame <i>k</i>;</p>
   	<p><i>&#948;x</i>, <i>&#948;y</i>, <i>&#948;z</i> = the components of the translation vector.</p>
   	<p><sup>0</sup><i><b>P</b><sub>i</sub></i> represents the placement relative to the world coordinate system.</p>
   	<p>
   		The transform includes three rotational and three translational components.
   		The transform is the only form of placement representation which is suitable for interpolation 
   		or approximation via weighting functions.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The remaining representations are described in the schema.
   	</p>
   	
   	<!-- Positive sense of rotations -->
   	<b><i>Positive sense of rotations</i></b>
   	<p>
   		For any rotation defined in the <b>kinematic_structure_schema</b>, a positive value of the rotation
		angle indicates a counter-clockwise rotation when looking in the negative direction with respect
		to the axis of that rotation.
   	</p>
   	
   	<!-- Shape representations -->
   	<b><i>Shape representations</i></b>
   	<p>
   		Kinematic structure representations are frequently associated with shape representations for
		single parts of the structure at various levels of detail.
		In this part of ISO 10303, three kinds of shape representations are distinguished:
   	</p>
   	<ul>
   		<li>
   			shape representations of parts that belong to the immobile environment of a kinematic
			structure, referred to as the <i>ground shape</i>;
		</li>
   		<li>
   			shape representations describing the shape of a link of a kinematic structure, referred
			to as the <i>link shape</i>;
   		</li>
   		<li>
   			shape representations describing specific aspects of the shape of a kinematic pair, 
   			referred to as the <i>pair shape</i>.
   		</li>
   	</ul>
   	<p>
   		The <b>geometric_representation_items</b> which contribute to the ground shape representation
		may be in the <b>items</b> set either of the <b>kinematic_ground_representation</b> of the kinematic
		structure which, in this case, should be simultaneously a <b>shape_representation</b>, or of a
		<b>shape_representation</b> which is related to the <b>kinematic_ground_representation</b> of the
		kinematic structure by any means.
		This part of ISO 10303 does not specify any specific constraints on the representation of ground shape.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The <b>geometric_representation_items</b> contributing to a link shape representation shall not
		be in the <b>items</b> set of the corresponding <b>kinematic_link_representation</b>;
		rather they shall be in the <b>items</b> set of a <b>shape_representation</b> which is related to 
		this <b>kinematic_link_representation</b> by means of a <b>kinematic_link_representation_association</b>.
		Any number of <b>shape_representation</b>s may be related in this way to a specific 
		<b>kinematic_link_representation</b>.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		For the purpose of a pair shape representation, only <b>geometric_representation_items</b> of
		type <b>kinematic_frame_background</b>, i.e., <b>point</b>, <b>curve</b>, or <b>surface</b> are allowed.
		They shall be in the <b>items</b> set of a <b>kinematic_frame_background_representation</b> which, 
		in turn, is related to one of the <b>kinematic_link_representation</b>s of the pair by means of a 
		<b>kinematic_frame_background_representation_association</b>.
		The <b>items</b> set of a <b>kinematic_frame_background_representation</b> may contain more than one item, 
		and in general any number of <b>kinematic_frame_background_representation</b>s may be related to a 
		<b>kinematic_link_representation</b> and to any frame in its <b>items</b> set.
		In the case of the higher pair types, however, which need explicit geometric information to describe 
		their kinematic behaviour, at least one <b>kinematic_frame_background_representation</b> is required 
		for each <b>curve</b> or <b>surface</b> that is referenced in its specification.
   	</p>
   	
   	<!-- Consistent use of units -->
   	<b><i>Consistent use of units</i></b>
   	<p>
   		It is required that units are used consistently throughout a kinematic structure, although such
		a kinematic structure will include a variety of <b>representation</b>s and related 
		<b>representation_context</b>s.
		To ensure this consistency, it is further required that all units which are to be used
		in a kinematic structure are assigned globally to the items of the respective <b>representation</b>s
		by means of the <b>global_unit_assigned_context</b> subtype of the <b>representation_context</b> 
		(see ISO 10303-41).
		Units for <b>measure_value</b>s of the same kind shall be identical throughout all
		the <b>representation</b>s in a kinematic structure.
   	</p>
   		<example number="4">
   			The pair placements of a <b>kinematic_pair</b> are founded in two different 
   			<b>kinematic_link_representation</b>s.
   			Consistent use of units requires that these two <b>kinematic_link_representation</b>s 
   			share the same units via their <b>global_unit_assigned_context</b>s.
   		</example>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
    <!-- <imgfile file="kinematic_structure_schemaexpg1.xml"/> -->
   </express-g>
</schema>

<schema name="kinematic_motion_representation_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   <p>
		The subject of the <b>kinematic_motion_representation_schema</b> is the description of motion.
		It specifies different types of paths that comprise the motion for a kinematic model.
   </p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		Motion in this part of ISO 10303 is defined in terms of a parameter t. t is a non-decreasing
		parameter as motion progresses.
		Several motions may be synchronised by the requirement that the actual state of all motion in a 
		kinematic model is controlled by a single parameter t which appears as an attribute in the 
		<b>kinematic_control</b> and in the <b>kinematic_result</b>.
   	</p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
    <!--  <imgfile file="kinematic_motion_representation_schemaexpg1.xml"/>  -->
   </express-g>
</schema>

<schema name="kinematic_analysis_control_and_result_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   <p>
   		The subject of the <b>kinematic_analysis_control_and_result_schema</b> is the identification and
		analysis of configurations of <b>kinematic_structure</b>s and the interpolation between configurations.
		The schema covers the prescribed paths and the paths resulting from analysis.
   </p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   <p>
	   	A kinematic analysis is a specific presentation of the kinematic behaviour of a mechanical product.
	   	There are two possible ways to check the kinematic behaviour of a kinematic structure:
   </p>
		<ul>
			<li>forward analysis;</li>
			<li>backward analysis.</li>
		</ul>
   <p>
	   	The forward analysis specifies the motion of a kinematic structure in terms of a sequence of
		configurations and of the interpolations between them.
		The result of a forward analysis is the path of specified frames on specified links.
   </p>
   <p>
   		The backward analysis specifies the motion of a kinematic structure with a prescribed path defined by frames.
   		The result of a backward analysis is the sequence of configuration definitions in the form of 
   		the pair parameter values for a sufficiently large number of pairs to control the motion.
   </p>
   <p>
   		A configuration of a kinematic structure is defined by the specification of pair values for a set
		of pairs of the kinematic structure.
   </p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
    <!-- <imgfile file="kinematic_analysis_control_and_result_schemaexpg1.xml"/> -->
   </express-g>
</schema>


 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="RTABDR" entity="rotation_about_direction"/>
 	<shortname name="KNPRDF" entity="kinematic_property_definition"/>
 	<shortname name="KPRR" entity="kinematic_property_representation_relation"/>
 	<shortname name="KNGRRP" entity="kinematic_ground_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="MCHNSM" entity="mechanism"/>
 	<shortname name="MCBSPL" entity="mechanism_base_placement"/>
 	<shortname name="INTSTT" entity="initial_state"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMSTR" entity="kinematic_structure"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMJNT" entity="kinematic_joint"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMLNK" entity="kinematic_link"/>
 	<shortname name="KLRR" entity="kinematic_link_representation_relation"/>
 	<shortname name="KNLNRP" entity="kinematic_link_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="KLRA" entity="kinematic_link_representation_association"/>
 	<shortname name="KFBR" entity="kinematic_frame_background_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="KFBT" entity="kinematic_frame_based_transformation"/>
 	<shortname name="KFBRA" entity="kinematic_frame_background_representation_association"/>
 	<shortname name="SPRM" entity="su_parameters"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMPR" entity="kinematic_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="PRACT" entity="pair_actuator"/>
 	<shortname name="PRVL" entity="pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="SMPRRN" entity="simple_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="RVLPR" entity="revolute_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="RVPRVL" entity="revolute_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="RVPRRN" entity="revolute_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="PRSPR" entity="prismatic_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="PRPRVL" entity="prismatic_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="PRPRRN" entity="prismatic_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="SCRPR" entity="screw_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="SCPRVL" entity="screw_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="SCPRRN" entity="screw_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="CYLPR" entity="cylindrical_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="CYPRVL" entity="cylindrical_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="CYPRRN" entity="cylindrical_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="SPHPR" entity="spherical_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="SPPRVL" entity="spherical_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="SPPRRN" entity="spherical_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="UNVPR" entity="universal_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="NPRVL" entity="universal_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="UNPRRN" entity="universal_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="PLNPR" entity="planar_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="PLPRVL" entity="planar_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="PLPRRN" entity="planar_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="UNCPR" entity="unconstrained_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="UNPRV" entity="unconstrained_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="FLCNPR" entity="fully_constrained_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="POSP" entity="point_on_surface_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="POSPV" entity="point_on_surface_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="POSPR" entity="point_on_surface_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="SRFPR" entity="surface_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="SRPRRN" entity="surface_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="SLSRPR" entity="sliding_surface_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="SSPV" entity="sliding_surface_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="RLSRPR" entity="rolling_surface_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="RSPV" entity="rolling_surface_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="POPCP" entity="point_on_planar_curve_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="POPCPV" entity="point_on_planar_curve_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="POPCPR" entity="point_on_planar_curve_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="PLCRPR" entity="planar_curve_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="PCPR" entity="planar_curve_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="SLCRPR" entity="sliding_curve_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="SCPV" entity="sliding_curve_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="RLCRPR" entity="rolling_curve_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="RCPV" entity="rolling_curve_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="GRPR" entity="gear_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="GRPRVL" entity="gear_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="GRPRRN" entity="gear_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="RAPP" entity="rack_and_pinion_pair"/>
 	<shortname name="RAPPV" entity="rack_and_pinion_pair_value"/>
 	<shortname name="RAPPR" entity="rack_and_pinion_pair_range"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMSTR" entity="kinematic_substructure"/>
 	<shortname name="KNNTST" entity="kinematic_network_structure"/>
 	<shortname name="KNTRST" entity="kinematic_tree_structure"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMLP" entity="kinematic_loop"/>
 	<shortname name="JNLGRL" entity="joint_logical_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="ORNJNT" entity="oriented_joint"/>
 	<shortname name="OJIT" entity="oriented_joint_in_tree"/>
 	<shortname name="ADORJN" entity="advent_oriented_joint"/>
 	<shortname name="TRNSLT" entity="translation"/>
 	<shortname name="TRNSFR" entity="transform"/>
 	<shortname name="PTHND" entity="path_node"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMPTH" entity="kinematic_path"/>
 	<shortname name="PTELCN" entity="path_element_connection"/>
 	<shortname name="CMPPTH" entity="composite_path"/>
 	<shortname name="PTHELM" entity="path_element"/>
 	<shortname name="PTPP" entity="point_to_point_path"/>
 	<shortname name="CRCPTH" entity="circular_path"/>
 	<shortname name="LNRPTH" entity="linear_path"/>
 	<shortname name="CRBSPT" entity="curve_based_path"/>
 	<shortname name="CNFINT" entity="configuration_interpolation"/>
 	<shortname name="KNMCNT" entity="kinematic_control"/>
 	<shortname name="FNKNPT" entity="founded_kinematic_path"/>
 	<shortname name="MTLNRL" entity="motion_link_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="CNFDFN" entity="configuration_definition"/>
 	<shortname name="INCNSQ" entity="interpolated_configuration_sequence"/>
 	<shortname name="PRSPTH" entity="prescribed_path"/>
 	<shortname name="KNANRS" entity="kinematic_analysis_result"/>
 	<shortname name="KNANCN" entity="kinematic_analysis_consistency"/>
 	<shortname name="RSLPTH" entity="resulting_path"/>
 </shortnames>

  
 <tech_discussion>
	 <b>Rotation matrix corresponding to ypr_rotation</b>
	 <p>
	 	This annex provides additional information. It is included here in order to ensure a common
		understanding of the semantics of 
		<express_ref linkend="kinematic_structure_schema:ir_express:kinematic_structure_schema.ypr_rotation"/>.
	 </p>
	 <p>
	 	An <b>ypr_rotation</b> defines a sequence of three rotations about the yaw, pitch, and roll axes (in this order).
	 	In this part of ISO 10303, this rotation sequence is applied mainly to frames;
	 	in the case of a 
	 	<express_ref linkend="kinematic_structure_schema:ir_express:kinematic_structure_schema.spherical_pair_value"/>,
	 	e.g., it relates the axis directions of the pair frame on the second link of a
	 	<express_ref linkend="kinematic_structure_schema:ir_express:kinematic_structure_schema.spherical_pair"/>
	 	to the axis directions of the pair frame on the first link of the same pair.
	 	It may be applied, however, to any vector-valued quantity in <b><i>R</i></b><sup>3</sup>.
	 </p>
	 
	 <b><i>E.1 Matrix representation of ypr_rotation</i></b>
	 <p>
	 	Let <img src="v_vector.gif"/> be a 3D vector to which a <b>ypr_rotation</b>
	 	is applied, and let <img src="w_vector.gif"/> be the same vector, but measured with respect to the unrotated,
	 	i.e., inertial coordinate system.
	 	Then the transformation from <img src="v_to_w.gif"/> can be written in matrix notation as follows:
	 	<img src="w_formula.gif"/>
	 	where
	 	<img src="t_formula.gif"/>
	 	(the rightmost transformation is performed first).
	 	Since the yaw, pitch, and roll rotations are rotations about the z-, y-, and x-axis, respectively, 
	 	of temporary coordinate systems, it is easily shown that
	 	<img src="t_yaw_matrix.gif"/>
	 	with <i>&#945;</i> being the yaw angle,
	 	<img src="t_pitch_matrix.gif"/>
	 	with <i>&#946;</i> being the pitch angle, and
	 	<img src="t_roll_matrix.gif"/>
	 	with <i>&#947;</i> being the roll angle.
	 	Hence, the rotation matrix for the entire <b>ypr_rotation</b> becomes
	 	<img src="t_ypr_matrix.gif"/>
	 </p>
	 <b><i>E.2 EXPRESS function compute_rotation_matrix_from_ypr_rotation</i></b>
	 <p>
	 	The function <b>compute_rotation_matrix_from_ypr_rotation</b> computes the rotation matrix
		which corresponds to a <b>ypr_rotation</b>, given by its angles <b>yaw</b>, <b>pitch</b>, and <b>roll</b>, 
		according to the notation specified in E.1. 
		The function returns an ARRAY [1 : 3] OF ARRAY [1 : 3] OF REAL.
	 </p>
	 <note number="1">
	 	This function is provided as an example for applications which need rotations to be given in
		matrix notation rather than in terms of ypr angles.
		It should fit into a schema that USEs or REFERENCEs the <b>kinematic_structure_schema</b>.
	 </note>
	 <note number="2">
	 	The term 'rotation matrix' is not used uniquely within the scientific community.
	 	The result of <b>compute_rotation_matrix_from_ypr_rotation</b> is valid only for a notation as used in E.1.
	 </note>
	 <i>EXPRESS</i> specification:
	 
	 <screen>
FUNCTION compute_rotation_matrix_from_ypr_rotation
		 (yaw		: REAL;
		  pitch		: REAL;
		  roll		: REAL;
		  factor	: REAL)
				: ARRAY [1 : 3] OF ARRAY [1 : 3] OF REAL;
  LOCAL
	y, p, r	: REAL;
	result	: ARRAY [1 : 3] OF ARRAY [1 : 3] OF REAL;
  END_LOCAL;

  y := factor * yaw;
  p := factor * pitch;
  r := factor * roll;
  
  result := [ [	COS(y) * COS(p),
	-	SIN(y) * COS(p),
		SIN(p) ],
	[	SIN(y) * COS(r) + COS(y) * SIN(p) * SIN(r),
		COS(y) * COS(r) - SIN(y) * SIN(p) * SIN(r),
	-	COS(p) * SIN(r) ],
	[	SIN(y) * SIN(r) - COS(y) * SIN(p) * COS(r),
		COS(y) * SIN(r) + SIN(y) * SIN(p) * COS(r),
		COS(p) * COS(r) ] ];
  RETURN (result);
END_FUNCTION;
	 </screen>
	 <p>
	 Argument definitions:
	 </p>
	 <p>
	 	<b>yaw:</b> the yaw angle of the <b>ypr_rotatio</b>n which is being evaluated.
	 </p>
	 <note number="3">
	 	For an attribute <b>ypr</b> of type <b>ypr_rotation</b> in an entity <b>e</b>, the actual parameter for <b>yaw</b>
		could be either <b>e.ypr[ypr index(ypr enumeration.yaw)]</b> or just <b>e.ypr[1]</b>.
	 </note>
	 <p>
	 	<b>pitch:</b> The pitch angle of the <b>ypr_rotation</b> which is being evaluated.
	 </p>
	 <note number="4">
	 	For an attribute <b>ypr</b> of type <b>ypr_rotation</b> in an entity <b>e</b>, the actual parameter for
		<b>pitch</b> could be either <b>e.ypr[ypr index(ypr enumeration.pitch)]</b> or just <b>e.ypr[2]</b>.
	 </note>
	 <p>
	 	<b>roll:</b> The roll angle of the <b>ypr_rotation</b> which is being evaluated.
	 </p>
	 <note number="5">
	 	For an attribute <b>ypr</b> of type <b>ypr_rotation</b> in an entity <b>e</b>, the actual parameter for <b>roll</b>
		could be either <b>e.ypr[ypr index(ypr enumeration.roll)]</b> or just <b>e.ypr[3]</b>.
	 </note>
	 <p>
	 	<b>factor:</b> The conversion factor that is required to convert <b>yaw</b>, <b>pitch</b>, and <b>roll</b> into equivalent
		angle measurements using radian as the plane angle unit.
	 </p>
	 <note number="6">
	 	ISO 10303-11 requires the parameters of the <b>SIN</b> and <b>COS</b> functions to be expressed in radians.
	 </note>
 
 	<p><b>Replacement of DH-Parameters by SU-Parameters</b></p>
 	
 	<p>
 		The principle of the DH-notation is to relate a target frame on a link (denoted <i>k</i>, e.g.) to that
		pair frame on the preceeding link (denoted <i>k</i> - 1) in the kinematic chain which belongs to the
		pair by which link <i>k</i> is connected to link <i>k</i> - 1.
		The target frame may either be a pair frame of another pair on link <i>k</i> or any other frame on link <i>k</i>, 
		e.g., a tool center point frame.
		The four DH-parameters <i>a<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, <i>&#945;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, 
		<i>&#952;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, and <i>s<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i> define the transformation 
		from the relating pair frame on link <i>k</i> - 1 to the target frame on link <i>k</i>, 
		including the motion in the pair shared by both links.
		See [3] for details of the DH-notation.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The use of DH-parameters is commonly restricted to links that are connected to their predecessor
		by either a revolute pair or a prismatic pair.
		One could imagine its application also to cylindrical pairs and to screw pairs.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		When using SU-parameters, the relationship between the pair frames of the shared pair is
		separated from the kinematic link description.
		The pair is characterised by a transformation involving the pair parameters, which is specific to the pair type, 
		whereas the link data relevant to kinematics are constant transformations from an arbitrarily chosen, 
		but fixed link frame to the various pair frames on the same link. See 
		<express_ref linkend="kinematic_structure_schema:ir_express:kinematic_structure_schema.su_parameters"/>.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		A pair and a link whose data are specified using DH-notation can easily be redefined using SU-notation.
 		The resulting frame definition will probably not take full advantage of the exibility given by 
 		the SU-notation, but it will be a valid definition.
 		The following paragraphs provide a guidance to such a redefinition.
 		The 'target frame' of the DH-notation is chosen as the link frame of link <i>k</i>, 
 		as it is usually done implicitly also with the DH-notation.
 		The SU-parameters for the pair frame on link <i>k</i> which mates with the 'relating' pair frame 
 		on the preceeding link <i>k</i> - 1 are derived from the inverse of the transformation matrix 
 		defined by the DH-parameters, with zero pair parameters.
 		Angles are given in radians; occasionally, the given values have to be replaced
		by the equivalent values in the plane angle units that are actually used by an application.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		<b>Revolute pair:</b> For a link <i>k</i> connected to its predecessor <i>k</i> - 1 by a revolute pair, 
 		the pair transformation corresponds essentially to the yaw rotation as given in E.1, replacing there
 		<i>&#945;</i> by the pair parameter <i>&#952;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>.
 		The SU-parameters for the pair frame of the revolute pair on link <i>k</i>, as defined in
 		<express_ref linkend="kinematic_structure_schema:ir_express:kinematic_structure_schema.su_parameters"/>,
 		are found by setting <i>a<sub>k</sub> = a<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, 
 		<i>&#945;<sub>k</sub> = &#945;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>,
 		<i>b<sub>k</sub> = -s<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>,
 		<i>&#946;<sub>k</sub> = &#960;</i>, <i>c<sub>k</sub> = 0</i>, and <i>&#947;<sub>k</sub> = &#960;</i>.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		<b>Prismatic pair:</b> For a link <i>k</i> connected to its predecessor <i>k</i> - 1 by a prismatic pair, 
 		the pair transformation is a pure translational transformation along the z-axes, with
 		<i>s<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i> being the pair parameter.
 		The SU-parameters for the pair frame of the prismatic pair on link <i>k</i> are found by setting
 		<i>a<sub>k</sub> = a<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, 
 		<i>&#945;<sub>k</sub> = &#945;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>,
 		<i>b<sub>k</sub> = 0</i>,
 		<i>&#946;<sub>k</sub> = &#960; - &#952;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>,
 		<i>c<sub>k</sub> = 0</i>, and <i>&#947;<sub>k</sub> = &#960;</i>.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		<b>Cylindrical pair and screw pair:</b> For a link <i>k</i> connected to its predecessor <i>k</i> - 1 by a
		cylindrical pair or by a screw pair, the pair transformation is composed of a translational transformation along the z-axes
		(pair parameter <i>s<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>) and a rotational yaw transformation (pair
		parameter <i>&#952;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>).
		In the case of a cylindrical pair, the pair parameters <i>s<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i> and
		<i>&#952;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i> are independent one from the other, whereas for a screw pair 
		one of them depends functionally on the other (see
		<express_ref linkend="kinematic_structure_schema:ir_express:kinematic_structure_schema.screw_pair_value"/>).
		The SU-parameters for the pair frame of the cylindrical pair or of the screw pair on link <i>k</i> 
		are found by setting
		<i>a<sub>k</sub> = a<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, 
 		<i>&#945;<sub>k</sub> = &#945;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>,
 		<i>b<sub>k</sub> = 0</i>,
 		<i>&#946;<sub>k</sub> = &#960;</i>,
 		<i>c<sub>k</sub> = 0</i>, and <i>&#947;<sub>k</sub> = &#960;</i>.
 		Here it is supposed that both pair frames of the cylindrical or screw pair coincide if both parameters,
 		<i>s<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i> and <i>&#952;<sub>k</sub><sup>DH</sup></i>, are equal to zero.
 	</p>
 </tech_discussion>
 <!-- optional annexes
 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->
 <bibliography>
 	<bibitem id="su_gsnfm">
    	  <stdnumber>SHETH, U.N. and UICKER, J.J.</stdnumber>
    	  <pubdate>Feb. 1971</pubdate>          
           <stdtitle>
          	A generalized symbolic notation for mechanisms
           </stdtitle>
           <subtitle>
           	Journal of Engineering for Industry, Trans. ASME
           </subtitle>          
    </bibitem>
    
    <bibitem id="dh_knflpmbom">
    	  <stdnumber>DENAVIT, J. and HARTENBERG, R.S.</stdnumber>
    	  <pubdate>1955</pubdate>          
           <stdtitle>
          	A kinematic notation for lower pair mechanisms based on matrices
           </stdtitle>
           <subtitle>
           	Journal of Applied Mechanics, Vol. 22, Trans. ASME, Vol. 77, Series E
           </subtitle>          
    </bibitem>
    
    <bibitem id="hr_pgt">
    	  <stdnumber>HARTSFIELD, N. and RINGEL, G.</stdnumber>
    	  <pubdate>1990</pubdate>          
           <stdtitle>
          	Pearls in Graph Theory: a Comprehensive Introduction
           </stdtitle>
           <subtitle>
           	Academic Press, Inc., San Diego
           </subtitle>          
    </bibitem>
 </bibliography>

</resource>

