<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.5 2009/11/13 14:54:01 liutkuviene Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="shape_variation_tolerances"
   name.french="Tol&#233;rances de variation de forme"
   part="47"
   version="2"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="6146"
   wg.number.express="6147"
   checklist.internal_review="6148"
   checklist.project_leader="6149"
   checklist.convener="6150"
   status="DIS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2009"
   published="n"
   previous.revision.year="1997" 
   previous.revision.cancelled="NO"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2009/11/13 14:54:01 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.5 $">

 <keywords>
    resource, tolerance, dimension, datum
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>
    This part of ISO 10303 supports the dimensioning and tolerancing methods defined by the ISO 1101
    family of standards for the dimensions and tolerances on engineering drawings. 
    This part captures the semantic contents of the dimensions and tolerances as specified in 
    those standards and applies them to three-dimensional geometric models.
    </p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="simon.frechette"/>
   <editor ref="lothar.klein"/>
 </contacts>
 
  <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
   	This part of IS0 10303 specifies the integrated resources to support all of the dimensioning and tolerancing methods as defined by existing
	International Standards on technical drawings.
	These methods include explicit dimensioning, associative dimensioning, plus-minus tolerancing, and geometrical tolerancing.
   </p>
   <p>
   	The shape aspect definition schema provides resources for the representations of shapes to which dimensions and
	tolerances are applied.
   </p>
   <p>
   	The shape dimension schema provides resources for the representations of size and relative location to meet the
	dimensioning requirements found in engineering design.
   </p>
   <p>
   	The shape tolerance schema provides resources for the representations of limits within which manufactured
	shapes are permitted to vary.
   </p>
   
   
   <p>
	   	This second edition of this part of ISO 10303 incorporates modifications that are upwardly compatible with the first edition.	
	   	Modifications to EXPRESS specifications are upwardly compatible if:
   </p>
   <ul>
   		<li>
	   		instances encoded according to ISO 10303-21 [1], and that conform to an ISO 10303 application
			protocol based on the previous edition of this part of ISO 10303, also conform to a revision of that 
			application protocol based on this edition of this part of ISO 10303;
		</li>
		<li>
			interfaces that conform to ISO 10303-22 [2] and to an ISO 10303 application protocol based on the
			previous edition of this part of ISO 0303, also conform to a revision of that application protocol 
			based on this edition of this part of ISO 10303;
		</li>
		<li>
			the mapping tables of ISO 10303 application protocols based on the previous edition of this 
			part of ISO 10303 remain valid in a revision of that application protocol based on this edition of this part of ISO 10303.
		</li>
	</ul>
	<p>
		Technical modifications to the first edition of this part of ISO 10303 and its technical corrigenda are categorised as follows: changes to the EXPRESS
		declarations, new EXPRESS declarations, and changes to definitions of EXPRESS entity data types.
	</p>
	<!-- shape_aspect_definition_schema -->
	<p>The following shape_aspect_definition_schema EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been added:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>common_datum.</li>
	</ul>
	<p>The following shape_aspect_definition_schema EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been modified:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>datum;</li>
		<li>datum_feature;</li>
		<li>datum_target.</li>
	</ul>
	<!-- shape_tolerance_schema -->
	<p>The following shape_tolerance_schema EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been modified:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>tolerance_value.</li>
	</ul>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <!-- 
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>
 -->
 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <scope>
		Shape variation tolerances are represented by dimensions and tolerances of the shape of the product.
		The dimensions specify the sizes of a shape and locations of identifiable portions of a shape.
		The tolerances specify the allowable deviation of a product from its defined shape and dimensions.
		The representations of dimensions and tolerances provided by this part of IS0 10303 are appropriate for use with
		both 2D and 3D geometric models of parts.
	
	<p>
		The following are within the scope of this part of IS0 10303:
	</p>
   <ul>
		<li>tolerances as constraints on the shape characteristics of a product;</li>
		<li>the specification of the tolerances on a defined shape;</li>
		<li>the representation of geometrical tolerances and plus-minus tolerances;</li>
		<li>the representation of tolerance values;</li>
		<li>the representation of dimensions;</li>
		<li>the assignment of size characteristics to a shape;</li>
		<li>the assignment of location and orientation characteristics to a shape;</li>
		<li>the specification of datums and datum references;</li>
		<li>the identification of derived shape elements such as centre lines and intersections;</li>
		<li>the structure for limit and fit systems for shapes.</li>
   </ul>
</scope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the definition of the fundamental principles, concepts and terminology of tolerancing and dimensioning;</li>
   <li>the mathematical definition of tolerances and datums;</li>
   <li>the description of dimensioning or tolerancing practices;</li>
   <li>the specification of dimensional inspection methods;</li>
   <li>the synthesis and analysis of tolerances;</li>
   <li>the tolerancing of product characteristics other than shape;</li>
   <li>the presentation of tolerances on engineering drawings;</li>
   <li>the specification of surface finish or surface roughness.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref129-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_dimension"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_dimensioning"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_feature"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref286_1.">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_fit_system"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_hole"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_limit_system"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_shaft"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_standard_tolerance"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_tolerance_class"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref286_2."/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref406"/>
 	
 	<normref.inc normref="ref1101.1983">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_axis"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_geometrical_tolerance"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_median_plane"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_projected_tolerance_zone"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_runout_tolerance"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_symmetry"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_tolerance"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_tolerance_zone"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_total_runout_tolerance"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref2693.1988">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_least_material_condition"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_maximum_material_condition"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref5458.1987"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref5459.1981">
 		<term.ref linkend="datum"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="datum_feature"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="datum_system"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="datum_target"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.2004"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-42"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10578">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_projected_tolerance_zone_10578"/>
 	</normref.inc>
	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1.1994">
 		<term.ref linkend="application_context"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term3"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term8"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term43"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term33"/>
 	</normref.inc> 
 	<normref.inc normref="ref8824-1"/>
 </normrefs>

 <definition>
 	<term id="boundary">boundary</term>
 	<def>
 		the surfaces that surround and enclose the physical mass of the product shape
 	</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 	<term id="form_tolerance">form tolerance</term>
 	<def>
 		geometric tolerance applied to a feature or single feature element that requires no datum reference
 	</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 	<term id="profile_tolerance">profile tolerance</term>
 	<def>
 		geometric tolerance applied to a uniform boundary along the true profile within
		which the elements of the surface must lie
 	</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 	<term id="plus-minus_tolerance">plus-minus tolerance</term>
 	<def>
 		tolerance that is defined by two values that represent the minimum and
		maximum limits of a range within which the toleranced dimension may deviate
 	</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 	<term id="toleranced_feature">toleranced feature</term>
 	<def>
 		identifiable portion of the product shape to which one or more tolerances are applied
 	</def>
 </definition>
<!--
 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="shape_aspect_definition_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
	<p>
	   	The subject of the <b>shape_aspect_definition_schema</b> is to provide definitions of the spatial characteristics of 
	   	a shape that are required for dimensioning and tolerancing.
	   	This schema provides representations for a <b>derived_shape_aspect</b> and a <b>datum</b>.
	   	A <b>derived_shape_aspect</b> is a <b>shape_aspect</b> that is developed from the defined
		shape of the product, but that is not required for defining the product shape.
		A <b>datum</b> is a <b>shape_aspect</b> that provide the origin from where dimensions and tolerances are referenced.
		A <b>derived_shape_aspect</b> and a <b>datum</b> are aspects of the shape that are required for dimensioning and 
		tolerancing the size, the location, the orientation, and the form of a product shape.
	</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	<p>
   		The product shape is the concept of shape as a property that characterizes a product.
   		Geometric models and engineering drawings are formal methods used to represent the product shape.
   		Dimensions and tolerances are elements of the product shape definition which are independent from how the shape is represented.
   		Dimensions may be explicitly identified as part of the shape characteristics, implicitly included in a geometric model that
		represents the shape, or explicitly presented in a two-dimensional drawing.
	</p>
	<p>
		A <b>shape_aspect</b> is an element of a product shape.
		Dimensions may be specified for both the entire product shape and aspects of the shape.
		This schema augments the <b>shape_aspect</b>s and the relationships among them as the definitional mechanism 
		for specifying dimensions and tolerances.
		A <b>shape_aspect</b>, relationships between <b>shape_aspect</b> elements, and their specified dimensions and tolerances are 
		always defined in the context of the product shape property. 
		These dimensions and tolerances can be represented as elements of geometric models or engineering drawings.
	</p>
	<p>
		For the purpose of identifying dimensions and tolerances, this schema specifies the concept of a derived <b>shape_aspect</b>.
		A derived <b>shape_aspect</b> is a <b>shape_aspect</b> that is defined based on the specific way in which it relates
		to another shape aspect.
		The derived <b>shape_aspect</b> is used in conjunction with their related <b>shape_aspect</b> elements to specify 
		dimensions and tolerances.
		The specific geometry that can represent the derived <b>shape_aspect</b> and a <b>shape_aspect</b> that provide 
		the definitional relationship are not in the scope of this schema.
		The geometry, the representation structure, and their association to the dimension and tolerance elements specified
		in this part are defined in IS0 10303-41, IS0 10303-42, and IS0 10303-43.
		Only the generic concept of derived <b>shape_aspect</b> is specified here.
		Application protocols may specify additional derived <b>shape_aspect</b> elements from those provided.
	</p>
	<note>
		Legal values that are computer sensible for attributes of entities in this schema may be specified in application protocols.
	</note>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="shape_aspect_definition_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="shape_aspect_definition_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

<schema name="shape_dimension_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
	<p>
		The <b>shape_dimension_schema</b> provides a representation for the description of location and size dimensions.
		The measure of a dimension may be either assigned to or derived from other <b>shape_aspect</b> elements.
		The supported types of measurement path for applying a dimension are:
	</p>
		<ul>
			<li>a linear path;</li>
			<li>a curved path;</li>
			<li>an angular path.</li>
		</ul>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		Dimensions that are derived from the geometric representations of <b>shape_aspect</b>s are considered to be implicitly defined.
   		Dimensions that are assigned to a <b>shape_aspect</b>, which may or may not have associated geometric representation, 
   		are considered to be explicitly defined.
   		A size or location dimension may be both implicitly and explicitly defined for a given <b>shape_aspect</b>.
   	</p>
   	<note number="1">
   		The lower limit of a limit dimension can be represented by either an explicit or assigned, dimension, while the upper limit value 
   		may be on an implicit or explicit dimension.
   	</note>
   	<note number="2">
   		Legal values that are computer sensible for attributes of entities in this schema may be specified in application protocols.
   	</note>
   	<p>
   		This part of IS0 10303 does not distinguish between intended values (e.g., designed values) and actual values (e.g., measured values) 
   		for either dimensions or tolerances.
   		Geometrical tolerances and plus-minus tolerances may be applied to a dimension.
   		Dimensions need not have a tolerance value.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		This part of IS0 10303 does not distinguish between uses of dimensions.
   		Uses of dimensions are defined in application protocols using this part of IS0 10303.
   	</p>
   	<example>
   		The specification of a dimension to define the desired product shape and the specification of a dimension to describe 
   		as-manufactured product shape are two uses of dimension.
   	</example>
   	<p>
   		This part of IS0 10303 provides for the representation of dimensions in a manner that is independent of any
		requirements for draughting presentation.
   	</p>
   	<note number="3">
   		The application and use of basic dimensions or reference dimensions are specified in an application protocol.
   	</note>
   	<p>
   		A dimensional location is a relationship between two <b>shape_aspect</b> elements that identifies a spatial constraint
   		that shall be maintained during any physical transformation, translation, or rotation of the <b>shape_aspect</b> elements together.
   		This relationship is either directed from the origin <b>shape_aspect</b> or <b>datum</b> to the target <b>shape_aspect</b>, or it is non-directed.
   		Only non-directed dimensional location is addressed in this part of IS0 10303.
   	</p>
   	<note number="4">
   		The decision as to whether the dimensional location is directed or non-directed is specified in an application protocol.
   	</note>
   	<p>
   		A dimensional size of a <b>shape_aspect</b> identifies a constraint between the relative position of the boundary of the
		<b>shape_aspect</b> with either its axis of symmetry or another boundary of the same <b>shape_aspect</b>.
		The dimensional size is unaffected by any translation or rotation of the <b>shape_aspect</b>.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		A dimension is applied along a specific measuring path. 
   		When the measuring path is not explicitly identified, the dimension will apply along an implicit path.
   		The definition of an implicit measuring path is dependent on the context of use and is specified in an application protocol.
   	</p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="shape_dimension_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="shape_dimension_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

<schema name="shape_tolerance_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
	<introduction>
		<p>
			The <b>shape_tolerance_schema</b> provides the constructs for describing tolerances that apply to dimensions 
			and to elements of <b>shape_aspect</b>.
			This schema includes two types of tolerance: plus-minus tolerance and geometrical tolerance.
			The plus-minus tolerance provides the constructs for specifying tolerances in one of two ways:
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>the specification of upper and lower limits within which a dimension may vary;</li>
			<li>the specification of limits and fits as specified in IS0 286-l and IS0 286-2.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
			The representation of statistical tolerance may be associated with the direct specification of the upper and the lower limits 
			of the plus-minus tolerance or with a geometric tolerance.
		</p>
		<p>
			The geometrical tolerance provides the constructs for applying tolerance zones to elements of <b>shape_aspects</b>.
			A tolerance zone defines a region or an area within which a <b>shape_aspect</b> may vary and is bounded by a set of
			tolerance zone elements.
			These constructs support tolerances for the form, orientation, location, profile, and runout of a <b>shape_aspect</b>.
			A tolerance zone may be represented by specific geometry and is used for various tolerancing methods.
		</p>
	</introduction>
	<fund_cons>
		<p>
			A toleranced dimension is an exact dimension with a plus-minus tolerance.
			A plus-minus tolerance limits the dimensional variation of a dimension of a product.
			The plus-minus tolerance range is limited by either assigned values, which define the upper bound and lower bound of a dimension, 
			or a standard tolerance as specified in IS0 286-l and IS0 286-2.
			The tolerance with a statistical distribution provides an additional specification of the variation of a dimension and 
			may be used with either a plus-minus tolerance or a geometric tolerance.
		</p>
		<p>
			Geometrical tolerances constrain the variations in the geometric properties of a product shape.
			These properties are form, location, orientation, profile, and runout.
			IS0 1101 specifies geometrical tolerances for form, location, orientation, profile, and runout.
			IS0 5458 specifies the geometrical tolerance for position.
			A limit condition modifies a geometrical tolerance such that the size variation of a <b>shape_aspect</b> may increase or decrease, 
			as specified in IS0 2692.
			A geometrical tolerance has a tolerance zone that defines the limits of the variation of a <b>shape_aspect</b>.
			Tolerance zone elements define the boundaries of a geometrical tolerance zone.
			The tolerance zone for a single <b>shape_aspect</b> may be defined as a single zone or in increments that are contiguous 
			with a defined unit or by length or area.
			The size of the tolerance zone is defined by the measure of the tolerance.
			Tolerance zones for geometrical tolerances are specified in IS0 1101 and 5458.
		</p>
		<p>
			A geometrical tolerance may reference a <b>datum</b> system which is composed of one or more <b>datum</b>s.
			The <b>datum</b> system defines an origin for the geometrical properties.
		</p>
		<note number="1">
			When the tolerance zone is not fully bounded, it is appropriate to assume that the tolerance zone extends to infinity
			at the unbounded areas
		</note>
		<note number="2">
			Legal values that are computer sensible for attributes of entities in this schema may be specified in application protocols.
		</note>
		<example>
			A flatness tolerance zone of a planar surface is bounded by two parallel, infinite planes separated 
			by a distance of the tolerance magnitude.
		</example>
	</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="shape_tolerance_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="shape_tolerance_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="shape_tolerance_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="APEX" entity="apex"/>
 	<shortname name="CNOFSY" entity="centre_of_symmetry"/>
 	<shortname name="CMMDTM" entity="common_datum"/>
 	<shortname name="CMSHAS" entity="composite_shape_aspect"/>
 	<shortname name="DATUM" entity="datum"/>
 	<shortname name="DTMFTR" entity="datum_feature"/>
 	<shortname name="DTMRFR" entity="datum_reference"/>
 	<shortname name="DTMTRG" entity="datum_target"/>
 	<shortname name="DRSHAS" entity="derived_shape_aspect"/>
 	<shortname name="EXTNSN" entity="extension"/>
 	<shortname name="GMTALG" entity="geometric_alignment"/>
 	<shortname name="GMTINT" entity="geometric_intersection"/>
 	<shortname name="PRLOFF" entity="parallel_offset"/>
 	<shortname name="PRPT" entity="perpendicular_to"/>
 	<shortname name="RFMDDT" entity="referenced_modified_datum"/>
 	<shortname name="SADR" entity="shape_aspect_deriving_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="SYSHAS" entity="symmetric_shape_aspect"/>
 	<shortname name="TNGNT" entity="tangent"/>
 	<shortname name="ANGLCT" entity="angular_location"/>
 	<shortname name="ANGSZ" entity="angular_size"/>
 	<shortname name="DMCHRP" entity="dimensional_characteristic_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="DMNLCT" entity="dimensional_location"/>
 	<shortname name="DLWP" entity="dimensional_location_with_path"/>
 	<shortname name="DMNSZ" entity="dimensional_size"/>
 	<shortname name="DSWP" entity="dimensional_size_with_path"/>
 	<shortname name="SHDMRP" entity="shape_dimension_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="DRTZE" entity="dimension_related_tolerance_zone_element"/>
 	<shortname name="GMTTLR" entity="geometric_tolerance"/>
 	<shortname name="GMTLRL" entity="geometric_tolerance_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="GTWDR" entity="geometric_tolerance_with_datum_reference"/>
 	<shortname name="GTWDU" entity="geometric_tolerance_with_defined_unit"/>
 	<shortname name="MDGMTL" entity="modified_geometric_tolerance"/>
 	<shortname name="PRZNDF" entity="projected_zone_definition"/>
 	<shortname name="RNZNDF" entity="runout_zone_definition"/>
 	<shortname name="RNZNOR" entity="runout_zone_orientation"/>
 	<shortname name="RZORD" entity="runout_zone_orientation_reference_direction"/>
 	<shortname name="SDFT" entity="statistical_distribution_for_tolerance"/>
 	<shortname name="TWSD" entity="tolerance_with_statistical_distribution"/>
 	<shortname name="TLRZN" entity="tolerance_zone"/>
 	<shortname name="TLZNDF" entity="tolerance_zone_form"/>
 	<shortname name="TLZNFR" entity="tolerance_zone_definition"/>
 	<shortname name="LMANFT" entity="limits_and_fits"/>
 	<shortname name="PLMNTL" entity="plus_minus_tolerance"/>
 	<shortname name="TLRVL" entity="tolerance_value"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->
<bibliography>
	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-21-1994"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-22-1998"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_1660_1987"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_5458_1987"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_8015_1985"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_TR_5460_1985"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="dimensioning_and_tolerancing"/>
</bibliography>

</resource>

