<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: mkmodule.js,v 1.11 2002/03/04 07:48:48 robbod Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<module
   name="activity_as_realized"
   part="undefined"
   version="1"
   wg.number="00000"
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2002"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: $">

<express language_version="2"
   rcs.date="$Date:2002/05/14 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.12$"
   description.file="arm_descriptions.xml"
 
/>

 <keywords>
    module
 </keywords>

 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="seanbarker"/>
 </contacts>

 <purpose>
<p>
An activity is recorded when someone does something to the design of a product, or to an actual product. In PLCS, activities done to an actual product include repair, preventive maintenance, replenishment (e.g. refuelling) amd simple observations about the condition of the product. The function of activity_as_realized is to record who did what to which product, together with when and why.
</p>
<p>
The information model for an activity is the same whether or not the activity has occurred. The concept activity_as_realized is introduced to distinguish between the activity (the data that is created in order to describe the activity) and activity_as_realized (the data that records what was actually occurred). In general, the data recorded against the two will be different. However, even if the intention is carried out exactly, activity_as_realized records that the activity occurred at a particular date, while activity records what ought to have happened, whether or not it did.
</p>
 </purpose>

 <inscope>
 <li>Recording the historical occurance of an activity</li>
 <li>Recording the relation of an occurance to the activity it is an occurance of</li>
 <li>Reference data that is used to determine the meaning of an in-scope relationship</li>
 </inscope>

 <outscope>
 <li>Attibutes defined in the Activity module</li>
 <li>Reference data for relationships between activities</li>
 <li>Method by which the activity was realised</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
   <normref.inc normref="ref10303-41.2000"/>
 </normrefs>

 <!--
 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <arm>
   <uof name="Activity_As_Realized">
      <description> 
      The activity_as_realized UoF specifies the information needed to
      record the historical occurrence of an activity. 
    </description>
      <uof.ae entity= "Activity_actual"/>
      <uof.ae entity= "Activity_happening"/>
   </uof>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
    </express-g>
 </arm>

 <mapping_table>

   <ae entity="Activity_actual">
       <aimelt>action_actual</aimelt>
       <source>{this part}</source>
   </ae>

   <ae entity="Activity_happening">
       <aimelt>action_relationship</aimelt>
       <source>{this part}</source>

	  <aa attribute="predicted">
	     <aimelt>action.related</aimelt>
	  <source>41</source>
	  <rule>1</rule>
	  </aa>

	  <aa attribute="actual">
	     <aimelt>action.relating</aimelt>
	  <source>41</source>
	  </aa>
   </ae>
 </mapping_table>


 <mim>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
