<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 <!--
     Autogenerated by AAM Conversion script
 -->
<!DOCTYPE idef0 SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/aam.dtd">
<idef0 application_protocol="product_life_cycle_support">
	<viewpoint> the support of a product through its life cycle</viewpoint>
<page number="0" node="A0" title="provide_through_life_support_for_product">
<activity identifier="provide_through_life_support_for_product" inscope="yes">
  <name>Provide through life support for product</name>
  <description>action to achieve and sustain efficient support of a product in focus throughout its life cycle
</description>
<note>This activity covers the support and disposal of products, the definition, commissioning, use and upkeep of the support system, and the management of support information.  The product is designed, tested, manufacture and operated outside the scope of this model. </note>
</activity>






















</page>
<page number="1" node="A0" title="provide_through_life_support_for_product">
<activity identifier="commission_support_system" inscope="yes">
  <name>Commission support system</name>
  <description>action to establish, test, certify and release all elements of the support system required to provide
the support defined by a support solution
</description>
<note>To avoid duplication of activities, the activity A3 is limited to planning and assessing commissioning activities. The specification and execution of commissioning tasks is performed in activities A2 and A4 respectively, as part of the activities that also provide support. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="generate_support_solutions" inscope="yes">
  <name>Generate support solutions</name>
  <description>identify, develop, validate, and enhance one or more optimized support solution definitions for the product
in focus, exercising appropriate influence on the product design
</description>
<note>This activity is assumed to be performed in an environment of concurrent engineering and integrated teams as defined by the life cycle owner.  It may applied when designing the product and its support concurrently, when developing a support solution for a pre-existing product that is not yet in use or when updating an existing support system. The PIF maybe supported by several support solution definitions, each tailored to a specific group of products, users, roles and support capabilities, collectively known as a deployment environment.  The activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>identification and analysis of support requirements; </li>
  <li>definition of the support activities; </li>
  <li>definition of the resources required for support, including skilled personnel; </li>
  <li>specification of design requirements for support elements and for embedded support features;  </li>
  <li>the identification, definition, generation and management of support engineering analysis data; </li>
  <li>the identification, definition and analysis of support cost and readiness drivers; </li>
  <li>identification and analysis of product availability and support system performance metrics during life cycle of the product.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_information_to_support_a_product" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage information to support a product</name>
  <description>action to capture, and manage through life, the information needed to support the PIF
</description>
<note>This activity includes configuration identification of the PIF and its support system plus configuration change management of the integrated set of APSI used to develop the support solution and provide support.  It also includes development of information management rules that govern the recording, storage and publication of APSI and of all other related information generated or used by support activities such as maintenance history.  APSI includes:   <ul>
  <li>product structure, including identification of permitted, actual and desired configuration; </li>
  <li>product performance, with tolerances and representations; </li>
  <li>support requirements and description of the support environment; </li>
  <li>product failure modes and diagnostic data; </li>
  <li>maintenance concepts, plans and task instructions including definition of the feedback required when tasks are executed;</li>
  <li>resources needed to conduct maintenance. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="provide_support" inscope="yes">
  <name>Provide support</name>
  <description>action to apply the support solution to one or more products needing support
</description>
<note>This activity includes planning of support delivery, provision and disposal of necessary resources, implementation of authorized tasks, and collection and reporting of operational and support feedback. </note>
</activity>














</page>
<page number="2" node="A1" title="manage_information_to_support_a_product">
<activity identifier="manage_configuration_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage configuration change</name>
  <description>action to achieve the systematic proposal, justification, evaluation, coordination and disposition of
proposed changes, and the implementation of all approved changes into applicable configurations of a product,
associated product information and supporting and interfacing products, and the associated information
of those products
</description>
<note>Changes may result from various sources including the discovery of a problem, a suggestion for product improvement or enhancement, a customer request, or a condition dictated by the market place or by public law. Regardless of the type of product or phase of the life cycle, a change to a product should be accomplished using a systematic, measurable change process.  The purpose and benefits of the configuration change management activity are:   <ul>
  <li>enable change decisions to be based on total knowledge of all change impacts; </li>
  <li>limit changes to those that are necessary or offer significant benefit; </li>
  <li>facilitate evaluation of cost, savings and trade-offs; </li>
  <li>ensure customer interests are considered; </li>
  <li>provide orderly communication of change information; </li>
  <li>document and limit variances; </li>
  <li>facilitate continued supportability of the product after change. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_identification" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage identification</name>
  <description>action to provide unambiguous identification of all elements, and versions, of the product or support
system to which reference needs to be made, identification of interfaces between elements, the necessary
assembly, and other breakdowns structures, required to manage the product through life and definition
of the information to be held for each type of product and support system element
</description>
<note>This activity occurs throughout the product life cycle and is the basis of management of configuration change and configuration status accounting of a product and all constituent configuration items.  The purposes and benefits of this activity include:   <ul>
  <li>determining the structure (hierarchy) of a product and the organization and relationships of configuration documentation and other product information;</li>
  <li>documentation of the performance, interface and other attributes of a product; </li>
  <li>determination of the appropriate level of identification marking of product and documentation; </li>
  <li>unique identification of a product or component part of a product; </li>
  <li>unique identification of the technical documents describing the product; </li>
  <li>modification of identification of product and documents to reflect incorporation of change; </li>
  <li>distinction between product versions; </li>
  <li>correlation of document revision level to product version; </li>
  <li>correlation of a PIF to related user or maintenance instructions at the configuration item level. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage information</name>
  <description>action to manage the information related to a PIF
</description>
<note>This activity corresponds to configuration and data management and the major output is APSI, which encompasses the entire configuration and support data.  A subset of the APSI is the configuration status record.  The dynamic nature of the configuration and data management activity, and its importance within the operation of a consistent configuration management process throughout the product life cycle requires a formal approval process to attain APSI status.  All configuration documentation (requirements and design documentation) and associated operational information (operating procedures, parts catalogues, and so on) that comprise the configuration status record must be formally managed and approved.  In essence, approve, release and record is a process that makes configuration and support documentation available for use, subjects it to configuration change management and maintains the assured status of the APSI. </note>
</activity>

</page>
<page number="3" node="A11" title="manage_configuration_change">
<activity identifier="assess_audit_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess audit feedback</name>
  <description>action to monitor approved changes through a planned and scheduled implementation in all documents, facilities,
hardware, and software affected
</description>
<note>The implementation is carried out in accordance with the activity A1.1.3.2.  Change accomplishment in all impacted areas is monitored and verified to track progress and to maintain consistency between each member of the PIF and its applicable configuration and support information, in the form of APSI. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_requirement_for_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish requirement for change</name>
  <description>action to document and assess the problem or change opportunity
</description>
<note>This activity covers documentation of the change opportunity or problem and the creation of a suitable description, analysis of the opportunity or problem, and the reason for a possible change along with a statement of expected impact sufficient for evaluation, determination of the appropriate level of priority, and the raising and the approval of a valid need for change as an input to evaluating and co-ordinating a solution or variance. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="evaluate_and_coordinate_solution_or_variance" inscope="yes">
  <name>Evaluate &amp; coordinate solution or variance</name>
  <description>action to initiate development and assessment of potential solutions to a valid need for change through
identifying potential solutions requiring assessment, planning and initiating the solution development,
assessment, implementation and verification, selecting a recommended solution, and developing a business
case for its authorization, deferral or rejection
</description>
<note>This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>reviewing the impact assessments, determining in detail the impact of a change in respect to operation, support, schedule, effectivity and cost in order to approve or reject the proposal;</li>
  <li>the process of grouping changes to achieve economy of scale and convenience or opportunistic packages.  Variances will be subject to this activity to establish effects on other configuration items;</li>
  <li>considering the technical, support, schedule and cost impacts of a requested change before making a judgment as to whether the change should be approved for implementation and incorporation in the PIF andassociated documentation.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage issue</name>
  <description>action to record and assess issues according to type and priority
</description>
<note>Issues that require change action are passed to the other configuration change management activities.  A unique identifier is issued as part of activity A1.2 (manage identification).  Issues include any issue, problem or proposal related to configuration management.  Such issues can be variances, documentation error reports from any source but principally from support engineering, resource management, maintenance and feedback or configuration discrepancy reports, perhaps arising from change monitoring or audit activity. </note>
</activity>













</page>
<page number="4" node="A111" title="manage_issue">
<activity identifier="assess_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess issue</name>
  <description>action to assess each issue for relevance, requesting and responding to required impact assessments and
classifying the issue according to the intended response.
</description>
<note>Possible classifications include:   <ul>
  <li>requiring change action; </li>
  <li>rejected; </li>
  <li>variance that needs to be recorded in the APSI; </li>
  <li>update to the information set and requires no further action. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="register_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>Register issue</name>
  <description>action to document, identify and monitor issues that may require a change management activity and impact
assessment
</description>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="5" node="A112" title="establish_requirement_for_change">
<activity identifier="analyze_change_problem_or_opportunity" inscope="yes">
  <name>Analyze change problem or opportunity</name>
  <description>analysis of a documented configuration management issue to determine whether there is a need for change
action; a request for clarification or resolution by other means
</description>
<note>While this activity can be very simple and intuitive, often there is a requirement for careful weighing of alternatives and cost benefit trade-offs. The preliminary judgments concern:   <ul>
  <li>the reason for the requested change; </li>
  <li>the basic scope and description of the requested change; </li>
  <li>definition of the impact of the requested change; </li>
  <li>the desired effectivity; </li>
  <li>the urgency and importance of the requested change. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="document_change_opportunity_or_problem" inscope="yes">
  <name>Document change opportunity or problem</name>
  <description>action to document a problem requiring configuration change action, or to resolve the problem by an information
update
</description>
<note>This activity results in a valid need for change, enabling the change to be effectively processed and helping to ensure that the associated configuration documentation provides a comprehensive historical record of the full life cycle of the change.  To adequately evaluate a request for change, the request must be clearly documented.  It is important to accurately describe even minor changes so that an audit trail can be constructed in the event that there are unanticipated consequences or unexpected product failures.  Saving the cost of research involved in one such incident by having accurate accessible records may be sufficient to fully offset diligent, disciplined change processing.  Changes can be required as a result of problems reported during design, build, test, operations and service activities.  Changes can be initiated for a variety of reasons including:   <ul>
  <li>to provide new capabilities desired by a customer; </li>
  <li>to enhance product support; </li>
  <li>to insert new technology; </li>
  <li>to effect product improvement; </li>
  <li>to cater for obsolescence; </li>
  <li>to correct product faults or deficiencies; </li>
  <li>to correct problems and prevent recurrence; </li>
  <li>to eliminate safety hazard conditions; </li>
  <li>to implement pre-planned product improvement; </li>
  <li>to reduce production cost or improve production efficiency; </li>
  <li>to prevent schedule slippage; </li>
  <li>to cover obsolescence. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_and_prioritize_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify &amp; prioritize change</name>
  <description>action to identify and classify a change opportunity or variance based on necessity, urgency or impact
of the potential change
</description>
<note>Classes for prioritizing change include:   <ul>
  <li>class 1; </li>
  <li>class 2; </li>
  <li>major; </li>
  <li>minor. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>





</page>
<page number="6" node="A113" title="evaluate_and_coordinate_solution_or_variance">
<activity identifier="develop_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop change</name>
  <description>action to refine the preliminary assessment to determine all potential consequences of a possible change
including necessary coordination between the impacted items to enable effectivity to be determined
</description>
<note>The preliminary assessment occurs in activity A1.1.2.  The level of analysis required will depend on the nature of the change taking into account effects on support engineering and resource management and impacts on other approved changes. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_business_solution_and_authorize_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish business solution &amp; authorize change</name>
  <description>action to establish the business case for change, select a preferred solution and authorize the change
by approval of appropriate change orders to enable the change to be implemented and verified
</description>
<note>Change approval should be conducted in accordance with the configuration management plan.  Approval authority for a change can be delegated to different levels in the organization, depending upon the classification of the change.  As the life cycle progresses, the change authority often transitions to individuals with greater management and fiscal responsibility because the effect of a change can be more widespread and, as a result, the cost impact of change decisions are normally greater.  Each contract should establish a specific change authority structure taking some of the following factors into consideration:   <ul>
  <li>the organizational structure and relationships within the enterprise; </li>
  <li>the various levels at which change authority is vested; </li>
  <li>the phase of the product life cycle; </li>
  <li>the extent of technical, support, schedule and cost impacts; </li>
  <li>the customer involvement; </li>
  <li>the product attributes subject to formal control; </li>
  <li>the period of performance during which that level of control applies. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan change</name>
  <description>action to establish which members of the PIF are to be changed, including new production and existing
products
</description>
<note>There are many influencing factors on this activity including an assessment of the urgency and priority of the change and the availability of parts and materials, software and replacement parts.  Determining an effectivity requires knowledge not only of the lead times associated with changing the product (whether in production or by retrofit, recall or other means) but of the actions and lead times necessary to effect the associated change in all impacted support areas (such as the update of support software, availability of spare and repair parts, or revision to operating and maintenance instructions).  Once the change is approved detailed implementation planning, which expands but remains consistent with the basic planning is normally required.  Implementation of a change involves the release of new or revised configuration documentation including requirements and design information.  This implementation may involve changes to information on operation and maintenance, build and test, and commercial documentation.  The new or revised information is identified and released within activity A1.3 (manage information).  The release process ties the document revisions to a change.  It is not always necessary to have a plan before a change task can be authorized.  However, a change implementation plan is usually needed. </note>
</activity>












</page>
<page number="7" node="A1131" title="develop_change">
<activity identifier="assess_impact_on_related_changes" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess impact on related changes</name>
  <description>action to identify and define the impact of a change on other related changes and to define constraints
on the order of change implementation
</description>
<note>This activity may initiate further assessment of this and related changes to establish the full impact of a particular solution </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_affected_item" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify affected item</name>
  <description>action to determine those configuration items that will be affected by the possible solutions
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_solution_options" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify solution options</name>
  <description>action to identify potential solutions that may meet the change requirement
</description>
<note>The development stage of the change will identify a choice of solutions that may meet the change requirement.  Viable solutions are developed so that the impact of each can be assessed. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="initiate_solution_development_and_impact_assessment" inscope="yes">
  <name>Initiate solution development &amp; impact assessment</name>
  <description>action to raise work requests for the definition of a potential solution and assessment of its impact
</description>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="8" node="A1132" title="plan_change">
<activity identifier="plan_change_implementation" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan change implementation</name>
  <description>action to define the effectivity of the classified solution and to plan the work required to implement
a solution to a valid need for change, to the level of individual products


</description>
<note>This includes identification of the point in production at which the change will take effect and identification of the realized products, in manufacture or in use, to which the change applies.  This activity extends the development plan to include assessment of the impact of the proposed implementation and any additional work required to quantity the change.  Related change tasks will be identified in this plan. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_validation_verification_or_audit_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan validation, verification or audit change</name>
  <description>action to develop a plan for the tasks required to validate, verify or audit a change
</description>
<note>Such plans should be based on the decision taken concerning the introduction point and effectivity of the change.  It will cover both production embodiment and retrospective embodiment, before or after the delivery of the product as appropriate.  An approved change is planned and scheduled for implementation in all documents, facilities, hardware and software impacted change.  The implementation is carried out in accordance with the plan.  Implementation of a change involves the release of new or revised configuration documentation (APSI) including requirements and design information.  The implementation may involve changes to operation and maintenance information, build and test information, and sales information (such as catalogues, marketing literature).  The new or revised information is identified and released as APSI.  The release process should correlate the document revisions to the change or changes incorporated.  A common method of disseminating document change is by means of document change notices, which establish a permanent record of specific changes and facilitates distribution. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_work_to_develop_change_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan work to develop change solution</name>
  <description>action to plan and monitor the work required to develop an adequate solution to a proposed change
</description>
<note>The basic planning for implementation of the change is accomplished during the change evaluation before the change is approved.  The level of detail required in the plans and schedules will be dependent upon the change complexities in respect to the interrelated change activities across the whole business scenario. </note>
</activity>








</page>
<page number="9" node="A1133" title="establish_business_solution_and_authorize_change">
<activity identifier="assess_solution_risk" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess solution risk</name>
  <description>action to assess the risks associated with a quantified solution to a valid need for change
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="authorize_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>Authorize change</name>
  <description>authorisation, rejection or deferment of a recommended change based on the associated justification
</description>
<note>If the change is authorized a change order will be issued for implementation.  If the change is rejected a further review can be initiated. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="classify_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Classify solution</name>
  <description>action to classify the chosen solution with respect to appropriate parameters
</description>
<note>Change solutions can be classified in many ways, including:   <ul>
  <li>nature of change, such as safety critical; </li>
  <li>scale of change, such as major or minor; </li>
  <li>implementation impact, such as an in-service change; </li>
  <li>regulatory interest, such as FAA approval required. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="compare_solution_options" inscope="yes">
  <name>Compare solution options</name>
  <description>action to select the solution that best meets the valid need for change
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="compile_justification_for_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Compile justification for solution</name>
  <description>action to review the total change package and complete a justification for the implementation requirements
with a recommended classification and priority
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_cost_of_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish cost of solution</name>
  <description>action to evaluate the cost of a change by subjecting the most beneficial solution to a commercial pricing
exercise, creating a price that meets the implementation and effectivity requirements
</description>
</activity>






</page>
<page number="10" node="A12" title="manage_identification">
<activity identifier="define_product_structure" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define product structure</name>
  <description>action to develop the required views of each relevant product, in the form of assembly structures or
breakdowns built from classified elements and to establish necessary relationships between the different
views to provide navigation between views

</description>
<note>This managed set of product views (the PIF Structure) provides unambiguous identification of the PIF for support management purposes and a key mechanism for navigating, and managing the effectivity of all related information, including that specified by the &quot;information&quot; need which provides the product definition and support solution.    </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_product_and_support_system_elements" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify product &amp; support system elements</name>
  <description>action to provide both unambiguous identification and classification of all elements forming part of
the PIF and its support system to which reference needs to be made, including interfaces and other relationships
between such elements to which configuration management shall apply
</description>
<note>Classification of elements and interfaces can be used to assist in defining information needs. </note>
</activity>







</page>
<page number="11" node="A121" title="identify_product_and_support_system_elements">
<activity identifier="classify_element_or_interface" inscope="yes">
  <name>Classify element or interface</name>
  <description>action to classify elements to provide a convenient reference in the business context
</description>
<note>The classification method will also assist in defining information needs.  Classification of elements can include:   <ul>
  <li>the selection of configuration items and configuration item interfaces; </li>
  <li>differentiation by size or complexity, using distinctions such as, major unit, minor unit, assembly, and raw material;</li>
  <li>differentiation in respect of types of information to be held, including those items that require load testing.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_information_required_for_element_or_interface" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define information required for element or interface</name>
  <description>action to define what APSI shall be developed and maintained  for each item in question, to enable the
support solution definition to be implemented and maintained throughout the life of the PIF
</description>
<note>A configuration item can have a large quantity of associated information.  Such information can include:   <ul>
  <li>design data; </li>
  <li>configuration item interfaces; </li>
  <li>specifications; </li>
  <li>interface control documentation; </li>
  <li>records of support analyses such as reliability centred maintenance analysis, or level of repair analysis; </li>
  <li>the support solution definition; </li>
  <li>technical publications; </li>
  <li>test results and certification; </li>
  <li>quality assurance documentation. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_interface_between_elements" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define interface between elements</name>
  <description>action to identify any interfaces between elements that will be subject to configuration management
</description>
<note>The nature of interfaces depends on the nature of the elements themselves.  The interface description may include the physical and functional attributes of the connection, spatial relationships, parent-child relationships and other forms of reference, such as the links to product, support and configuration data.  This activity provides the foundation on which to generate the checklist, which is used when changes to elements are proposed and ensures that all consequences of a proposed change are considered.  The descriptions of interface elements also provide a starting point for the development of product structures. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_pif_boundary" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define PIF boundary</name>
  <description>action to provide a boundary definition of the set of products for which support is required, including
an indication of the level product decomposition at which support is expected
</description>
<note>The PIF is the set of operational products, usually sharing a common product design, for which support is required. This set of products may be further subdivided across several deployment environments, each requiring a tailored support solution based on a common set of task specifications. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_element" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify element</name>
  <description>action to provide unambiguous names and identifiers for all elements of the Product in Focus and the
support system
</description>
<note>An element may have many identifiers, each assigned by a different organization.  This model assumes that the pair of values for &quot;identifier&quot; and &quot;assigning organization&quot; are unique across the PIF scope.  This should be reflected in the Information Management Rules. </note>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="12" node="A122" title="define_product_structure">
<activity identifier="define_link_between_product_structures" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define link between product structures</name>
  <description>action to establish necessary links between different product breakdown views, reflecting relationships
of interest
</description>
<note>Potential relationships include:   <ul>
  <li>connectivity relationships between parts that can be supported by interfaces; </li>
  <li>parts used to realize a function; </li>
  <li>parts located in a zone. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_structure_views" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop structure views</name>
  <description>action to establish the necessary breakdown or assembly views of the PIF by defining next higher assembly
usage relationships between related elements
</description>
<note>This part of ISO 10303 provides a generic mechanism for representing product assemblies or product breakdowns from any required perspective.  A product assembly breakdown is usually developed by the engineering design process. This is used to define the parts and versions that make up the product and to develop a bill of material for product manufacture.  Life cycle support activities will usually require the establishment of other product breakdowns views.  These views can include a decomposition of product functions from the operator or maintainer perspective and, in some cases, a zonal description of the product to assist maintenance planning.  Each breakdown will contain similar classified elements, linked together in a hierarchical fashion.   </note>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="13" node="A1221" title="develop_structure_views">
<activity identifier="develop_breakdown_of_logistically_significant_items" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop breakdown of logistically significant items</name>
  <description>action to develop a breakdown of the logistically significant items for each product within the PIF to
which support activities may be assigned
</description>
<note>This breakdown can be developed as either a physical breakdown or a hybrid breakdown.  The product assembly structure can be used as a start point for this breakdown, noting the requirement to trim the assembly structure by selecting those items that are logistically significant, to develop adequate representation of product usage occurrences, such as a starboard inner engine, and to identify required attachment slots. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_functional_breakdown" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop functional breakdown</name>
  <description>action to identify all functions to be maintained by creating or importing a functional decomposition
of each product design within the PIF scope
</description>
<note>Every element within a functional breakdown is a function. The functional breakdown is used to identify the functions which support activity shall sustain. Elements within a functional breakdown may be related to functional requirements or to potential fault states and related symptoms.  </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_other_required_breakdowns" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop other required breakdowns</name>
  <description>action to develop any additional breakdown views of the product required for support purposes
</description>
<note>This may include zonal views or any other additional breakdowns deemed to be necessary.   </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_system_breakdown" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop system breakdown</name>
  <description>action to develop a system breakdown for the PIF scope which can act as a collector for product and support
requirements

</description>
<note>Requirements may be allocated to any assembly or breakdown type. Elements in a system breakdown can be:   <ul>
  <li>physical or functional in nature, or have aspects of both; </li>
  <li>satisfied by different a number of different products. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="load_product_assembly_structure" inscope="yes">
  <name>Load product assembly structure</name>
  <description>action to import the design assembly structure for each product variant and version for each product
within the PIF scope
</description>
<note>The assembly structure is assumed to be available from the product designer where it is used to generate parts lists and manufacturing bills of materials. </note>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="14" node="A13" title="manage_information">
<activity identifier="define_information_architecture_or_rule" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define information architecture or rule</name>
  <description>action to establish necessary information management rules to achieve unambiguous information sharing
and exchange capability in a digital environment including definition of the meaning, structure and organization
of data required by the extended enterprise engaged in product support
</description>
<note>This activity covers the production of an information model that defines how the product data will be held.  The architecture may prescribe a set of tools or specify an open data architecture.  The activity generates the associations and relationships between data and documents and a definition of how that information is represented in different views.  This may involve the specification of relevant parts of ISO 10303 or other standards, such as EIA 836. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_information_management_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop information management plan</name>
  <description>action to generate a plan for the information management activities required to achieve and sustain a
coherent information environment, reflecting the information management strategy and requirements
</description>
<note>Activities within the plan include specification of required information deliverables, development of the information management rules, development of information exchange agreements between participating organizations, development and testing of information exchange capability, tasks to reformat information to comply with the rules.  The information strategy requirements usually originate in customer or contractor policies and standards (covering information technology, business-to-business trading, configuration management, quality assurance).  The contractual requirements usually originate in the change management plan or a change order. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="populate_information_structure" inscope="yes">
  <name>Populate information structure</name>
  <description>action to populate the PIF structure with the information specified by information needs
</description>
<note>This activity captures all necessary information on product and support elements, including relevant interfaces and inter-changeability information, and establishes appropriate relationships with the PIF structure to establish a sufficient set of product and support information for the PIF to meet life cycle support needs. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="release_assured_product_and_support_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>Release assured product &amp; support information</name>
  <description>action to authorise and release the assured information needed to achieve product life cycle support
</description>
<note>This action involves checking the PSI for:   <ul>
  <li>completeness against the information need; </li>
  <li>compliance with the change order and the information management rules; </li>
  <li>timely release as required by the change implementation plan.  </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>









</page>
<page number="15" node="A132" title="define_information_architecture_or_rule">
<activity identifier="define_information_management_procedure" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define information management procedure</name>
  <description>action to produce guidelines and constraints pertaining to the creation, use, maintenance and disposal
of information by life cycle users
</description>
<note>This activity defines applicable methods and creates a structured set of information management rules. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_information_model" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop information model</name>
  <description>action to produce or select a conceptual information model to define the entities, attributes and relationships
of interest to product life cycle support, and define the format in which required information shall be
captured so that relevant information can managed over time
</description>
<note>This part of ISO 10303 can be used for this purpose. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_product_structure_view" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify product structure view</name>
  <description>action to define which product breakdown views are required by relevant stakeholders and support participants,
to store, search and retrieve product and support information
</description>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="16" node="A134" title="release_assured_product_and_support_information">
<activity identifier="create_information_release_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>Create information release plan</name>
  <description>action to develop a schedule for the release of APSI in response to change orders and implementation
plans
</description>
<note>This activity ensures that assured product and support information is provided to approved recipients in a timely manner consistent with the approval and implementation of a change. Consideration should be given to:   <ul>
  <li>the scope and timing of the change; </li>
  <li>dependencies on other products; </li>
  <li>restrictions on the usage of the information; </li>
  <li>the user requirement for access. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="implement_information_release_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>Implement information release plan</name>
  <description>action to execute and monitor the release process in accordance with a change order
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="verify_suitability_for_release" inscope="yes">
  <name>Verify suitability for release</name>
  <description>action to check that all required approvals are present and segregate private and public view information
from common configurations but for different customers
</description>
<note>The private and public view information will be placed on different release plans. </note>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="17" node="A2" title="generate_support_solutions">
<activity identifier="assess_support_performance" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess support performance</name>
  <description>action to assess the performance of the support solution definition in relation to the metrics specified
by the support solution requirement
</description>
<note>This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>identification of the information to be collected; </li>
  <li>specification of the means of collection; </li>
  <li>definition of the assessment strategy; </li>
  <li>analysis of the feedback obtained from support activity; </li>
  <li>identification of the need for corrective action. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_support_context" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support context</name>
  <description>action to define a context, or deployment environment, for each required support solution per sub-group
of product within the PIF that need tailored support
</description>
<note>The context definition consists of the product group, its intended life and usage profile, potential support opportunities, support providers, and available resource items.  This definition will evolve through time, from an initial listing of assumptions into a complete description of the support providers and available resources. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="design_support_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Design support solution</name>
  <description>action to develop a support solution definition to meet requirements for each recognized deployment environment
</description>
<note>This activity can include:   <ul>
  <li>identification of reasons why support tasks may be needed; </li>
  <li>the development of a common set of task procedures applicable to the PIF; </li>
  <li>the optimization of a support solution for each recognized deployment environment; </li>
  <li>exploration of alternative support concepts and solution options within a support solution; </li>
  <li>specification of the conditions under which any task falls due (task triggers); </li>
  <li>optimisation of the tasks, task triggers and task groupings within each support solution. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_requirements_for_support_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish requirements for support solution</name>
  <description>action to collect and consolidate all potential requirements and valid stakeholder needs, to establish
an approved set of requirements for each support solution definition and to define the scope and characteristics
of the deployment environment to which the solution applies
</description>
<note>This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>definition of the characteristics to be used set goals and metrics for support delivery and assess support performance;</li>
  <li>identification of explicit and implicit needs for performance of through life support; </li>
  <li>local and international legislation and standardization requirements; </li>
  <li>definition of the operational and support environments; </li>
  <li>lessons learned from other programmes such as experience from operation and support of comparable products and usage; </li>
  <li>feasible and needed repair and supply policy and concepts; </li>
  <li>available skills and resources in existing support organizations; </li>
  <li>supportability, cost and readiness characteristics, goals and thresholds, and related risks; </li>
  <li>available new technologies that may increase supportability or reduce support resource requirements. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_support_engineering_programme" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage support engineering programme</name>
  <description>action to manage the development of a support solution definition for each deployment environment, over
the life cycle of the PIF, by defining objectives and acceptance criteria, establishing a support strategy,
developing a support engineering plan and monitoring resultant activities
</description>
</activity>

















</page>
<page number="18" node="A21" title="manage_support_engineering_programme">
<activity identifier="define_objectives_of_support_engineering_programme" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define objectives of support engineering programme</name>
  <description>action to define the objectives to be applied to the support engineering programme including identification
of desired characteristics of interest with metrics and targets
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_support_risks_and_improvement_opportunities" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify support risks &amp; improvement opportunities</name>
  <description>action to identify opportunities for improving the support solution in the form of proposed tasks for
inclusion in the support engineering plan, or for release as work requests to the life cycle owner
</description>
<note>This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>identification of opportunities for improving availability or reducing life cycle cost arising from advances in technical capability or from experience with similar product or support systems;</li>
  <li>analysis of factors in the external environment that could influence, or pose risks to the support solution, including political, legal, international, economic, social, and cultural aspects.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_support_engineering_activity" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan support engineering activity</name>
  <description>action to develop a programme of work for generating a support solution to meet the support engineering
objectives
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="review_support_engineering_programme" inscope="yes">
  <name>Review support engineering programme</name>
  <description>action to review the performance of the support engineering activities by comparing progress against
the support engineering plan and support system performance against support engineering objectives and
raising proposals for change as required
</description>
</activity>





</page>
<page number="19" node="A212" title="identify_support_risks_and_improvement_opportunities">
<activity identifier="analyze_external_environmental_factor" inscope="yes">
  <name>Analyze external environmental factor</name>
  <description>analysis of the political, legal, international, economic, social, cultural, and technological factors
in the external environment that offer opportunities and pose risks to the successful provision of support
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="evaluate_support_improvement_opportunity" inscope="yes">
  <name>Evaluate support improvement opportunity</name>
  <description>action to analyze support improvement opportunities for their ability to contribute to realizing the
support objectives
</description>
<note>This activity includes the definition of actions needed to realize each potential improvement opportunity, and to rank opportunities by their potential contribution to optimum support by assessing potential costs, benefits and risks. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_support_improvement_opportunity" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify support improvement opportunity</name>
  <description>action to identify and review potential opportunities for improving a support solution and identify those
that shall be addressed as part of the support engineering programme
</description>
<note>This activity can include:   <ul>
  <li>screening opportunities for applicability to the support solution requirements; </li>
  <li>establishing requirement to address alternative solutions in trade-off analyses; </li>
  <li>proposals for work to be done to improve support. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="20" node="A22" title="define_support_context">
<activity identifier="define_available_support_resources" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define available support resources</name>
  <description>action to identify and describe, for each product group and usage profile, the intended resource items
expected, or required to be available at each location where support could be provided
 
</description>
<note>Resources items may include organizations, people, facilities, parts, tools or test equipment. Resource items may be types or individuals. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_deployment_environment" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define deployment environment</name>
  <description>dummy activity to collect the various inputs into a single output arrow, named deployment environment,
to simplify arrow flows at higher levels of this model
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_life_and_usage_profile" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define life &amp; usage profile</name>
  <description>action to define the intended life and usage pattern for a product group including: overall product life;
operating environments and usage scenarios of relevance to support; applicable usage parameters and expected
types and durations of support opportunities
</description>
<note>This activity can identify:   <ul>
  <li>ranges of frequency and duration for the intended operational scenarios or missions; </li>
  <li>critical frequencies (how often), duration (time and distance) and permitted time for preparation for and conduct of the different states of the scenarios;</li>
  <li>how many times (ranges, minimum and maximum weighted) a state occurs in a scenario; </li>
  <li>relative importance (criticality) that product functions are available at the start of and throughout the individual scenarios and states;</li>
  <li>required functional uptime during a state or scenario, and permitted functional downtime. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_product_groups" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define product groups</name>
  <description>action to define any sub-groups of products, within a PIF, that may need a separate support solution

</description>
<note>Separate support solutions may be needed for different variants of a product, operated by a single customer or for sets of identical products operated by different customers. </note>
</activity>








</page>
<page number="21" node="A222" title="define_life_and_usage_profile">
<activity identifier="define_life_and_usage_parameters" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define life &amp; usage parameters</name>
  <description>action to define the properties or characteristics to be used to quantify product life and usage
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_operating_environments" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define operating environments</name>
  <description>action to identify and describe any operating environments likely to impact the requirement for support
or the options for support delivery
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_potential_faults" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define potential faults</name>
  <description>action to determine the potential faults, or other degraded states which the support solution shall address,
including cause, effect and other relationships between them, as applicable to each product function requiring
support, part, and attachment slot
</description>
<note>The ARM of this part of ISO 10303 defines the concept of predicted states of a product and this concept is appropriate for representation of faults.  A product can be either a part of a function. The sequences of individual faults involved in a failure can be represented by the relationship between predicted states. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_expected_scenarios_and_usage_pattern" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop expected scenarios &amp; usage pattern</name>
  <description>action to identify and describe any operating scenarios or patterns of use that shall be taken into account
when generating a support solution definition
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_support_opportunities" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify support opportunities</name>
  <description>action to identify the type of opportunities that may be available when work can be done on a product
needing support
</description>
<note>This activity can include opportunities such as when operating, daily checks, pre-flight inspection or annual overhaul. </note>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="22" node="A223" title="define_available_support_resources">
<activity identifier="define_environment_at_each_location" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define environment at each location</name>
  <description>action to define the environment at each potential support location in so far as this may impact the
support solution design
</description>
<note>The environment can be defined by terms including:   <ul>
  <li>covered dock facility; </li>
  <li>arctic conditions; </li>
  <li>a clean room to a given specification. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_support_capability_at_each_location" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support capability at each location</name>
  <description>action to define and describe the resources and capabilities available to support the product group at
each identified location where support activity may occur

</description>
<note>This activity can including defining the organization of potential support providers and their capability in terms on the type of tasks they can undertake, the quantity and description of resources types available, and the planned or actual availability of individual resources.  This activity is used initially to record the assumptions made to facilitate support analysis.  As the analysis proceeds the assumptions are updated to reflect intentions to record the planned and actual capabilities and resources available at each location. Resources include infrastructure, facilities, personnel, spares, tools, test equipment, ground support equipment and any other category of resource required for product support. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_support_locations" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify support locations</name>
  <description>action to identify locations at which support could be provided
</description>
<note>This activity can include the provision of support whilst a product is operating. </note>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="23" node="A23" title="establish_requirements_for_support_solution">
<activity identifier="define_support_solution_requirements" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support solution requirements</name>
  <description>action to establish an unambiguous statement of the requirements to be addressed by a specific support
solution by de-conflicting any contradictory, ambiguous, inconsistent, incongruous or unverifiable requirements
from the complete set of elicited needs and to define the metrics by which support performance will be
judged
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="elicit_support_stakeholder_need" inscope="yes">
  <name>Elicit support stakeholder need</name>
  <description>action to capture the needs, wants, desires, expectations and constraints that each recognized stakeholder
wishes to apply to the support solution definition, including action to seek clarification and justification
as needed; review experience with similar product or support systems for potential additional requirements
and identify requirements for standardization of the product or support elements
</description>
<note>Wherever possible stakeholder needs shall be expressed in a form that permits the operational performance to be measured and assessed for conformance . Stakeholder needs may include the needs and constraints imposed by society, the constraints imposed by acquiring organization and the capabilities and limiting characteristics of operating staff. Expressions of need should be analyzed to identify and remove inappropriate constraints on support system solution options. </note>
</activity>






</page>
<page number="24" node="A231" title="elicit_support_stakeholder_need">
<activity identifier="analyze_previous_experience" inscope="yes">
  <name>Analyze previous experience</name>
  <description>collection and analysis of information from other products, or from past experience with the current
support solution, to identify support related needs that should be addressed during the design and support
of the product
</description>
<note>This activity considers:   <ul>
  <li>support issues needing attention, and why; </li>
  <li>cost drivers and information relating to development, production, deployment, use, support, and disposal of the product;</li>
  <li>factors affecting the ability of the product to perform its intended mission in the intended use and support scenarios;</li>
  <li>risks and assumptions associated with the information from other products, or from previous use, such as relevance and accuracy for comparison with the product;</li>
  <li>information on what has worked well and what not during previous use or during support of similar products in similar environments and scenarios;</li>
  <li>requests for clarification of conflicting or ill-defined stakeholder requirements; </li>
  <li>additional requirements identified by the support engineer stakeholder which may not have been formally specified by any other stakeholder, including legal and social obligations which are not otherwise defined;</li>
  <li>guidance on how to explore technological opportunities, identify the metrics for support, identify trade-off criteria, and provide information for trade-off analyses.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_standardization_requirement" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify standardization requirement</name>
  <description>action to identify standardization requirements related to support that could affect the definition of
the support solution, the product design or the requirements for the support system
</description>
<note>This activity can include consideration of the following:   <ul>
  <li>support concepts; </li>
  <li>interfaces with other products and systems; </li>
  <li>partnerships for support; </li>
  <li>component and spares selection; </li>
  <li>test and training equipment; </li>
  <li>physical product characteristics; </li>
  <li>the need to share support resources with other products consuming similar resources inside the existing organization or support environment;</li>
  <li>the need to share with other organizations using the same support resources. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_support_stakeholder" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify support stakeholder</name>
  <description>action to identify the individual stakeholders or stakeholder classes that have a legitimate interest
in the product throughout its life cycle
</description>
<note>Stakeholders may include users, support engineers, developers, manufacturers, trainers, maintainers, inventory managers, supplier organizations, regulatory bodies and members of society.  Where direct contact is not practicable - as with consumer products and services - representatives or designated proxy stakeholders may be identified in their stead. </note>
</activity>

</page>
<page number="25" node="A232" title="define_support_solution_requirements">
<activity identifier="define_support_characteristics" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support characteristics</name>
  <description>action to define the characteristics that will be used to quantify support objectives and agreed support
needs, and the metrics to be used for assessing the support solution performance
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_support_metric" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support metric</name>
  <description>action to identify potential support solution performance metrics that could be used to assess achievement
of support objectives including, for each metric, the target and threshold values that shall apply
</description>
<note>The metrics may be used as criteria for trade-off analyses, to predict support solution performance or to measure actual performance of a support solution in use. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_support_solution_requirement" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support solution requirement</name>
  <description>action to consolidate the agreed support needs to establish unambiguous and quantified requirements that
shall be applied to the design of a support solution


</description>
<note>The requirement may include a statement of the required support performance, expressed in terms of defined support characteristics with metrics to be used when assessing compliance. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_and_resolve_conflict_between_support_needs" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify &amp; resolve conflict between support needs</name>
  <description>action to define and quantity support needs into an unambiguous and verifiable form, resolving any contradictory,
ambiguous, inconsistent, or unverifiable inputs, and providing notification to stakeholders whose needs
cannot be met by an agreed support need

</description>
</activity>







</page>
<page number="26" node="A24" title="design_support_solution">
<activity identifier="define_support_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support solution</name>
  <description>action to develop a support solution definition for each deployment environment, by defining the tasks
that may be performed and specifying the conditions under which each task falls due
</description>
<note>This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>selection of required tasks; </li>
  <li>consolidation of tasks into logical packages of work; </li>
  <li>harmonization of tasks and task conditions to optimize the solution; </li>
  <li>identification of the precise relationship of tasks and task triggers to the state of the individual product needing support;</li>
  <li>identification of optional tasks to suit differing usage scenarios or support environments within a deployment environment.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_support_drivers" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish support drivers</name>
  <description>action to identify the reason why support activities may be required for a any set of products needing
support in the context of one or more deployment environments and to raise issue reports for any safety
of support critical features that may require action by the life cycle owner
</description>
<note>Support drivers can include:   <ul>
  <li>product fault states; </li>
  <li>failure effect indications and diagnostic opportunities; </li>
  <li>externally imposed damage or user abuse; </li>
  <li>requirements for work in the physical supply chain such as moving, holding, issuing, lifting or packing resources;</li>
  <li>safety drivers (legal and others); </li>
  <li>environmental drivers; </li>
  <li>required operation or servicing tasks to be undertaken as part of the support solution. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="perform_task_analysis" inscope="yes">
  <name>Perform task analysis</name>
  <description>action to identify and define one or more economically viable and feasible support tasks to respond a
support driver

</description>
<note>Activity A2.3.2 addresses individual tasks and their resources. Integration of tasks to form a support solution is performed by activity A2.3.3. Task analysis includes:   <ul>
  <li>generation of work requests for action to identify, modify, design or acquire the resources required by task, providing sufficient information on the resource requirement to permit such activity to proceed;</li>
  <li>generation of requirements for changes in product functionality for support reasons, including support related design features, such as lifting lugs, and requests to embed support functionality, such as built-in-testcapability, within the product design.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>






</page>
<page number="27" node="A242" title="perform_task_analysis">
<activity identifier="assemble_pif_task_set" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assemble PIF task set</name>
  <description>action to assemble the set of identified, valid tasks that are applicable to the PIF

</description>
<note>Each task may be supported by a task description and a resource model.  Each task may have a defined applicability in the context of the overall PIF. Specification of task triggers occurs in activity A2.3, in the context of a specific support solution. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_potential_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define potential task</name>
  <description>action to define the method by which a potential task shall be performed, including sequencing of steps
within the task, requirements for additional or consequential tasks, warnings and cautions applicable
to the task, the identification of task predecessors and successors, the task pre- and post-conditions
and the support resources required to achieve the task, including necessary skills and experience
</description>
<note>This activity can include estimating duration and level of effort of task, assessing alternative methods for performing a task, including the task risks and consequences, and an assessment of the task viability in relation to available technology, past experience, and predicted costs. Non-viable tasks can be re-worked with a different task method, or can give rise to recommendations to the product designer for a design change to remove the support driver, or for incorporation of the task into the product functionality (embedded support capability). </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_potential_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify potential task</name>
  <description>action to identify each possible task that may need to be performed on the PIF by support participants
in one or more of the predicted support and operational environments
</description>
<note>This activity includes:  <ul>
  <li>tasks to respond to identified support drivers; </li>
  <li>configuration change management tasks to be undertaken by support participants such as fitting a local modification or conducting an audit of product configuration;</li>
  <li>tasks related to commissioning or other activities within this model. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>





</page>
<page number="28" node="A2422" title="define_potential_task">
<activity identifier="assess_task_viability_and_applicability" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess task viability &amp; applicability</name>
  <description>action to assess the viability, risks and benefits of performing each task on different product groups
or product versions, and in different locations, during different types of support opportunity
</description>
<note>An applicability of classification can be defined for viable tasks in relation to the options above.  Non-viable tasks can be referred for task evolution, or identified as candidates for resolution by embedded support features within the product. Embedded support features include:   <ul>
  <li>static design features of the product provided for support reasons such as lifting points or access panels;</li>
  <li>human factors improvements such as labelling or re-positioning of gauges and support related functionality within the product such as condition monitoring or built-in-test equipment (BITE).</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_resource_model_for_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop resource model for task</name>
  <description>action to develop a resource consumption model for a potential task, including expected task duration
and typical resource usage
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_task_description" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop task description</name>
  <description>action to define a task to the level needed to establish the task method and enable quantification of
related resource requirements
</description>
<note>If the task requirement can be met by more than one method, each method should be defined as a separate task. This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>identification of the support driver that justifies the task; </li>
  <li>definition of the conditions under which the task may be safely performed, including any pre-task and post-task conditions;</li>
  <li>development and description of the method by which the task shall be performed including the sequence of steps within the task;</li>
  <li>the development of additional tasks if the same objective is to be realized using different methods; </li>
  <li>identification of related tasks which need to precede and succeed this task. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_task_resource" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify task resource</name>
  <description>action to identify all the support resources that are needed to perform a required task and to compare
required resources with resource items available, including the development of requirements for new or
specialized resources which are not currently available to potential support providers
</description>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="29" node="A243" title="define_support_solution">
<activity identifier="assemble_support_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assemble support solution</name>
  <description>action to collect and assemble the information needed to define the  support to be provided to a group
of products within a deployment environment
</description>
<note>The support solution includes:   <ul>
  <li>task procedure for all necessary tasks; </li>
  <li>the support plan; </li>
  <li>task triggers for all necessary tasks; </li>
  <li>predictions of the support system performance, under one or more operating schedules, including predictions of resource usage.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="complete_task_procedures" inscope="yes">
  <name>Complete task procedures</name>
  <description>action to develop the applicable task specifications into the form in which they will be presented to
support providers


</description>
<note>This may include specification of the presentation format such as fonts, layout, and graphical user interface design or the adoption of specific language and editorial rules, such as simplified English, to remove ambiguity from potential end-users. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_support_policy" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define support policy</name>
  <description>action to define the approach to be taken when designing the support solution for a set of products within
a support context, including any requirement to develop and compare alternative support solution options
</description>
<note>The support policy includes:   <ul>
  <li>contractual arrangements for support such as organic support, contractor logistic support, contract for availability;</li>
  <li>the maintenance philosophy to be applied such as reliability centred maintenance or calendar based maintenance;</li>
  <li>the stock holding policy to be applied such as just in time supply or managed inventory; </li>
  <li>training philosophy to be used such as on-the-job training. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_support_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop support plan</name>
  <description>action to develop a support plan option for each support concept to permit optimization of the support
solution definition and raise work requests for the evolution of tasks where this is needed to optimize
support
</description>
<note>Each support plan should identify all tasks which may be required to satisfy the support solution requirements in the specified deployment environment, the logic through which tasks are combined or otherwise related, and the conditions under which each task would fall due.   </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="predict_support_performance_and_resource_use" inscope="yes">
  <name>Predict support performance &amp; resource use</name>
  <description>action to predict the performance of the support solution when applied under specified conditions
</description>
<note>Performance may include predictions of the impact of the support regime on the product downtime and availability, and predictions of the expected resource requirements or consumption. Prediction of some metrics may require assumptions to be made about the availability of required resources. </note>
</activity>








</page>
<page number="30" node="A2432" title="develop_support_plan">
<activity identifier="develop_support_plan_logic" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop support plan logic</name>
  <description>action to develop and optimize the logic of a support plan by assigning tasks to product elements, setting
task trigger conditions and rationalizing the grouping and sequencing of task in time and in space
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="select_necessary_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Select necessary tasks</name>
  <description>action to select the tasks needed to address relevant support drivers within a deployment environment
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="select_relevant_support_drivers" inscope="yes">
  <name>Select relevant support drivers</name>
  <description>action to select the support drivers of relevance to a specific support context
</description>
</activity>

</page>
<page number="31" node="A24323" title="develop_support_plan_logic">
<activity identifier="assign_task_to_product_elements" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assign task to product elements</name>
  <description>action to define the specific product elements to which each task applies
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_task_trigger" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define task trigger</name>
  <description>action to define the logical conditions that require a task to be done within a specific support solution
definition and deployment environment, including a justification for the selection of the trigger, with
appropriate  reference to any analysis process that established the trigger condition
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="rationalize_tasks_and_task_relationships" inscope="yes">
  <name>Rationalize tasks &amp; task relationships</name>
  <description>action to rationalize the set of necessary tasks and task triggers to develop a viable support plan for
each product group, and support concept within a deployment environment
</description>
<note>A further level of rationalization may be required across support plans and resource holdings across many product groups for the PIF as a whole.  This activity is not made explicit in this AAM. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="select_support_plan_option" inscope="yes">
  <name>Select support plan option</name>
  <description>action to select the support plan option which best meets the support solution requirements based on
predicted or measured performance
</description>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="32" node="A2435" title="predict_support_performance_and_resource_use">
<activity identifier="predict_required_tasks_and_downtime" inscope="yes">
  <name>Predict required  tasks &amp;  downtime</name>
  <description>action to predict, for each product, the tasks that will fall due during the operating period of interest
and their impact on product downtime
</description>
<note>Given sufficient information on the product state the required task can be derived from the support solution by evaluating task trigger conditions. The expected downtime can be estimated from the time needed to perform required tasks, plus logistic delay time. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="predict_resource_consumption" inscope="yes">
  <name>Predict resource consumption</name>
  <description>action to predict the resources needed to support a product during a specified period of operation
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="predict_state_of_product_over_time" inscope="yes">
  <name>Predict state of product over time</name>
  <description>action to predict the likely future state of each product needing support throughout the period of intended
use
</description>
<note>Predictions are required  in terms of the parameters that define task trigger conditions such as the likelihood of occurrence of fault states, product wear or other relevant condition and usage parameters used by tasks triggers. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="predict_support_performance" inscope="yes">
  <name>Predict support performance</name>
  <description>action to predict the performance of the support system over the operating period of interest in terms
of the support characteristics applicable to the support solution definition
</description>
</activity>





</page>
<page number="33" node="A25" title="assess_support_performance">
<activity identifier="analyze_assessment_data" inscope="yes">
  <name>Analyze assessment data</name>
  <description>analysis of operator and support feedback to validate and verify the support solution against its requirements,
to report support solution performance against agreed metrics, and to raise issues or suggest improvements
to the assessment strategy, the support solution, or the product
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_needed_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define needed information</name>
  <description>action to define the information that must be collected to support the assessment process

</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_assessment_strategy" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop assessment strategy</name>
  <description>action to define the approach to be taken, and activities required, to validate the support solution
against its requirements over the product life cycle, using the specified performance metrics
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_information_collection_mechanisms" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish information collection mechanisms</name>
  <description>action to identify the means by which information needed to assess performance will be collected including
the definition of additional tasks, or embedded support capabilities, required to generate or collect
assessment data that will not otherwise be generated by operation of a support solution definition
</description>
<note>Additional assessment tasks may be needed during product and support solution development such as conducting a maintenance assessment of a new equipment, or during normal operations such as a requirement to measure hours run, or to conduct an annual review of some aspect of performance. </note>
</activity>





</page>
<page number="34" node="A3" title="commission_support_system">
<activity identifier="analyze_commissioning_data" inscope="yes">
  <name>Analyze commissioning data</name>
  <description>analysis of data collected from the implementation of commissioning tasks to report progress against
the commissioning schedule and objectives or a need for proposal for change to the product, the support
solution, or the commissioning schedule
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="certify_support_system" inscope="yes">
  <name>Certify support system</name>
  <description>action to review commissioning feedback to confirm completion of all necessary tasks and resolution of
significant issues and to certify the support system as ready for use
</description>
<note>This process should provide assurance that appropriate capability is in place to provide required support.    </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="develop_commissioning_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop commissioning schedule</name>
  <description>action to identify and schedule the tasks needed to commission a support system that can deliver a support
solution
</description>
<note>Commissioning tasks are performed in activity A4.  These task include:   <ul>
  <li>planning and controlling the execution of commissioning tasks; </li>
  <li>arranging provision of all necessary resources (materials, labour, support equipment, facilities, documentation) at required locations;</li>
  <li>certifying the support solution as ready for use. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="35" node="A31" title="develop_commissioning_schedule">
<activity identifier="define_commissioning_objectives" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define commissioning objectives</name>
  <description>action to define the objectives of the commissioning activity including any metrics for commissioning
tasks
</description>
<note>May include action to raise requests to the life cycle owner for action required beyond the scope of activity A3 to resolve commissioning problems or issues. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_commissioning_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Define commissioning tasks</name>
  <description>action to identify the tasks required to commission the required support system
</description>
<note> These may include tasks previously defined by the support solution, and additional tasks required only for commissioning purposes.  The development of task description for a commissioning task may be initiated by a commissioning task request.  </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_commissioning_programme_logic" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish commissioning programme logic</name>
  <description>action to establish an optimal sequence for commissioning activities to take account of constraints,
relationships and interfaces of and between tasks such as those due to temporal, spatial, or sequential
dependencies, or imposed by safety or other policies
</description>
<note>This establishes constraints and relationships on and between tasks. These may be due temporal, spatial, or sequential dependencies, or imposed by safety or other policies. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_commissioning_resource_requirement" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify commissioning resource requirement</name>
  <description>action to identify the resources required to perform commissioning tasks, including the resources needed
to establish the support system and to issue transaction requests for provision of resources at the required
locations and dates

</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="schedule_commissioning_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>Schedule commissioning task</name>
  <description>action to develop the commissioning programme logic and identify when commissioning tasks must start
and finish to make support capability available by the expected first use dates, derived from the operational
schedule
</description>
<note>Scheduling may involve multiple time planning horizons as long range plans are progressively refined. </note>
</activity>




</page>
<page number="36" node="A4" title="provide_support">
<activity identifier="arrange_support_element_provision" inscope="yes">
  <name>Arrange support element provision</name>
  <description>action to arrange provision of required resources, in the required quantity and state, at the specified
location, on the specified date as required by a resource schedule
</description>
<note>This activity assumes the availability of a standard transaction set that can be used to achieve provision of the necessary human and material resources required by scheduled tasks.  The transaction set is assumed to include sufficient requests and responses to complete the planning (activity A4.1) and execution (activity A4.3) of support activities. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="collect_data_and_provide_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>Collect data &amp; provide feedback</name>
  <description>action to collect and capture into the information technology infrastructure the data generated by support
activities or by use of the product
</description>
<note>Feedback includes:   <ul>
  <li>support task records, including product data collected by the task; </li>
  <li>product state and usage records; </li>
  <li>resource element state and usage records; </li>
  <li>product configuration information; </li>
  <li>any issues arising from work. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="execute_authorized_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>Execute authorized task</name>
  <description>action to execute each released task by performing the steps specified by the task procedure, including
any associated data reporting
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_and_control_support_delivery" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan &amp; control support delivery</name>
  <description>action to plan and control the execution of maintenance and support tasks
</description>
</activity>








</page>
<page number="37" node="A41" title="plan_and_control_support_delivery">
<activity identifier="control_support_activity" inscope="yes">
  <name>Control support activity</name>
  <description>activity to control work in progress to achieve efficient attainment of support opportunity objectives
in accordance with a support schedule including: releasing tasks on which work may begin; monitoring task
progress; certification of successfully completed tasks and release of the product for use when all actions
are complete
</description>
<note>This activity implements and manages achievement of a support schedule. The activity controls the physical performance of the actions required to service, repair, test, overhaul, modify, calibrate or inspect a product needing support as specified by the task specification within the support solution definition or commissioning schedule.  This activity includes:   <ul>
  <li>releasing the support tasks for performance of work; </li>
  <li>monitoring progress; </li>
  <li>accepting support task completion; </li>
  <li>providing appropriate feedback data for record and planning purposes. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_support_activity" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plan support activity</name>
  <description>action to create a schedule for a support opportunity including the identification of objectives; the
identification, sequencing and scheduling necessary tasks, and arranging the provision and disposal of
all necessary resources such as materials, labour, support equipment, facilities and, documentation to
be available at appropriate times and locations
</description>
<note>Support schedules may have different planning horizons such as annual, quarterly, monthly, weekly, and daily.  One schedule may be a decomposition of another.  Support tasks should be scheduled against a specific products or support element.  Each schedule may be progressively refined and expanded until it defines the timing and location for all tasks applicable to the support opportunity in question. </note>
</activity>


</page>
<page number="38" node="A411" title="plan_support_activity">
<activity identifier="develop_support_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>Develop support schedule</name>
  <description>action to develop a schedule for the work to be accomplished to meet the objectives of the support opportunity
by identifying required activities, developing an activity logic and defining the required timing of activities
to reflect the task resource models, the available of required resources and the support opportunity objectives

</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="select_support_opportunities_to_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>Select support opportunities to schedule</name>
  <description>action to select, from the operating or resource use schedule, the support opportunity in which work
shall be scheduled and to establish the objectives and definition of each support opportunity to the level
needed for developing the support schedule

</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="select_support_provider" inscope="yes">
  <name>Select support provider</name>
  <description>action to select the support provider, or providers, to perform the scheduled activities

</description>
<note>Selection of the provider may alter the support schedule, owing to different locations, skills or available resources. </note>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="39" node="A4112" title="develop_support_schedule">
<activity identifier="establish_task_logic" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish task logic</name>
  <description>action to establish the optimal sequence of activities applicable to a given support opportunity that
will best achieve the support opportunity objectives, within the known task and resource constraints
</description>
<note>This activity establishes constraints and relationships on and between maintenance support tasks. These constraints can be due temporal, spatial, or sequential dependencies, or imposed by safety or other policies. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_intended_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify intended tasks</name>
  <description>action to identify the tasks that need to be undertaken during a given support opportunity to achieve
the support objectives
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_required_resources" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify required resources</name>
  <description>action to identify the resources required to perform the selected activities, including when and where
the resources are needed
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="schedule_activities" inscope="yes">
  <name>Schedule activities</name>
  <description>action to develop an activity schedule and resource schedule for the work to be undertaken during a support
opportunity
</description>
</activity>



</page>
<page number="40" node="A41121" title="identify_intended_tasks">
<activity identifier="establish_state_of_products_needing_support" inscope="yes">
  <name>Establish state of products needing support</name>
  <description>action to predict or otherwise determine the configuration and condition of each individual product needing
support, as it is expected to arrive at the support opportunity including the raising of work orders for
any inspection tasks required to resolve ambiguities in the product state
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_consequential_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify consequential tasks</name>
  <description>action to identify additional activities that need scheduling to support the activity logic  or preparation
of required resources
</description>
<note>This may include actions to fit temporary protection; calibrate a required test equipment or flush a pipework system after an inspection task. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_other_required_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify other required tasks</name>
  <description>action to identify any other activities that shall be included in a schedule, beyond those arising from
the support solution or commissioning schedule
</description>
<note>This activity may include tasks to implement a change, tasks deferred or brought forward from another support opportunity, or exceptional tasks required to achieve the support opportunity objective. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_triggered_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify triggered tasks</name>
  <description>action to identify due tasks specified by the support solution by evaluating the task trigger conditions
using the individual product state, usage or other relevant parameter
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="select_commissioning_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>Select commissioning tasks</name>
  <description>action to select tasks from the commissioning schedule due to be undertaken in a given support opportunity

</description>
</activity>







</page>
<page number="41" node="A412" title="control_support_activity">
<activity identifier="confirm_task_completion" inscope="yes">
  <name>Confirm task completion</name>
  <description>action to check and confirm that a released support task has been completed in accordance with the task
specification and the approved support schedule
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_progress" inscope="yes">
  <name>Manage progress</name>
  <description>action to monitor the support feedback to confirm task completion and product status, to identify new
tasks for release or the need for a scheduling revision
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="release_product_for_use" inscope="yes">
  <name>Release product for use</name>
  <description>action to monitor the progress of work and the state of the product to enable release of the product
back to operational use

</description>
<note>This process must take account of any limitations or restrictions which have been recognized or documented during the support cycle.  It may not be possible to release the product unless the condition and configuration are within the conditions specified by the support solution. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="release_support_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>Release support task</name>
  <description>action to authorize work to begin on a task in accordance with the support schedule, the product status
and the progress of work
</description>
</activity>







</page>
<page number="42" node="A44" title="collect_data_and_provide_feedback">
<activity identifier="analyze_support_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>Analyze support feedback</name>
  <description>analysis of support feedback from individual tasks to determine exceptions from the support solution,
exceptional maintenance needs, the impact on operations, and suggestions for improvement
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="extract_and_collate_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>Extract &amp; collate information</name>
  <description>action to extract and collate information from operation and support activities into a form that complies
with the information management rules
</description>
</activity>








</page>
<page number="43" node="A442" title="analyze_support_feedback">
<activity identifier="assess_impact_on_operation" inscope="yes">
  <name>Assess impact on operation</name>
  <description>action to assess the potential impact on operations of the state of a product after completion of a task
including provision of advice or instructions to operators concerning any limitations of use which apply

</description>
<note>This activity can include:   <ul>
  <li>information on additional maintenance requirements and the timing of future support tasks; </li>
  <li>limitations on product performance, such as speed and altitude, or cautions on environmental conditions to be avoided;</li>
  <li>information of relevance to system operators on the readiness of the support system and availability of support elements and services;</li>
  <li>information on limitations on availability including possible impact on operational plans arising from the product condition.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="create_suggestion_for_improvement" inscope="yes">
  <name>Create suggestion for improvement</name>
  <description>action to collate ideas and comments generated by support personnel into clear proposals for improving
the support solution
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="determine_exception" inscope="yes">
  <name>Determine exception</name>
  <description>action to compare results obtained from actual tasks with those expected from the task procedure to identify
discrepancies and anomalies for feedback and to compare results from observations of the product condition
with expected values to identify any product integrity exceptions
</description>
<note>The absence of an adequate response to the task or product discrepancies may prevent release of the product to service. </note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="determine_maintenance_need" inscope="yes">
  <name>Determine maintenance need</name>
  <description>action to identify any additional maintenance needs, not addressed by the current support schedule, for
consideration during this, or future support opportunities
</description>
<note>Maintenance needs may arise from work deferred or delayed by local circumstances or from observations on the product condition. </note>
</activity>




</page>
<icoms>
<icom identifier="affected_item" inscope="yes">
  <name>affected item</name>
  <description>item affected by relevant solution
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="apsi_and_related_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>APSI and related information</name>
  <description>set of assured and related information used to develop and deliver support for a product in focus, including
feedback from using and supporting the product over its life cycle
</description>
<note>Related information includes records of the history of the usage or support of realized products, design and support analysis results and reasons why decisions were taken.  Such information includes design and failure analysis records, logistic support analyses, running hours, environment descriptions, operating profiles; test results, records of maintenance activities, resources used, and faults found plus any other content deemed relevant to life cycle support. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="development_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>development plan</name>
  <description>plan of the activities required to develop and evaluate a possible change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="identified_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>identified solution</name>
  <description>identification of a potential solution that may satisfy a valid need for change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="impact_on_related_changes" inscope="yes">
  <name>impact on related changes</name>
  <description>consequences that a potential solution has on other changes that are proceeding in parallel
</description>
<note>Such impacts can include the situation where one change is necessary before another change can be implemented. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="need_for_revised_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>need for revised solution</name>
  <description>request for action to respond to issues revealed by an impact report relating to a proposed solution
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="potential_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>potential solution</name>
  <description>identification of the items forming a potential solution to a valid need for change, including conditions
for supersession of existing items within a product design
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="rejected_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>rejected solution</name>
  <description>potential solution which has been rejected because it not an optimal response to a valid need for change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_solution_development_and_impact_assessment" inscope="yes">
  <name>request solution development &amp; impact assessment</name>
  <description>request for impact assessment of potential design solutions that could satisfy a valid need for change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="solution_definition_report" inscope="yes">
  <name>solution definition report</name>
  <description>definition of a potential solution plus recommendations for further work required to complete assessment
of a potential solution
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="valid_need_for_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>valid need for change</name>
  <description>confirmed requirement for configuration change action
</description>
<note>This may include an identifier, a name, a classification, the reason for change and a sufficient description to permit impact assessment and may lead to one or more proposed solutions. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="audit_or_verification_report" inscope="yes">
  <name>audit or verification report</name>
  <description>feedback from audit or verification tasks reporting the progress of work and audit or verification findings
</description>
<note>This may include configuration records or reports of variance for realized products. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_development_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>change development plan</name>
  <description>plan that identifies and schedules the tasks required to develop a change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_development_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>change development task</name>
  <description>task required to progress the development of a change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_directive" inscope="yes">
  <name>change directive</name>
  <description>work orders and work requests that result from the configuration change management process
</description>
<note>Change directives serve as controls on the implementation or investigation of an identified change.  Change directives include change orders, change tasks, change plans and change requests. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="checklist" inscope="yes">
  <name>checklist</name>
  <description>detailed list of possible features of the product and its support solution that may be affected by the
change, each of which requires assessment before a change decision can be made
</description>
<note>The checklist may form part of the life cycle directives </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="customer_disposition" inscope="yes">
  <name>customer disposition</name>
  <description>lifecycle directive confirming the approval, deferment or rejection of a change by a customer or other
external authority
</description>
<note>The directive may specify a particular disposition such as in-work; complete; rejected; approved; deferred or pending. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="effectivity_impact_report" inscope="yes">
  <name>effectivity impact report</name>
  <description>definition of which realized products shall be affected by a change 
</description>
<note>This report may define the 'production break in' point or the applicability of modifications to realized product already built. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>feedback</name>
  <description>information of relevance to support that is derived from experience or observation
</description>
<note>In combination with other inputs to the configuration management activities feedback may prompt the need for a change and assist the development of a change.  Feedback may include:   <ul>
  <li>work requests or issues that may lead to change; </li>
  <li>requests for identifiers for product or support elements; </li>
  <li>impact reports in response to change tasks; </li>
  <li>status reports on progress with change tasks; </li>
  <li>support and commissioning feedback. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="implementation_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>implementation plan</name>
  <description>plan defining the activities needed to realize a solution to a valid need for change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plan_for_validation_verification_and_audit" inscope="yes">
  <name>plan for validation, verification &amp; audit</name>
  <description>schedule identifying the tasks required to validate, verify and audit a classified solution
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="quantified_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>quantified solution</name>
  <description>definition of a potential solution to a valid need for change, supported by plans for its implementation,
validation and audit
</description>
<note>A quantified solution should include:   <ul>
  <li>identification of the products or support elements that require change; </li>
  <li>definition of the new items generated by the change; </li>
  <li>definition of the work to be done, by whom and when, to complete the change; </li>
  <li>information on why the change is required, and how it was justified; </li>
  <li>impact on related changes; </li>
  <li>requirements for reporting progress and completion of change implementation. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_assessment_of_financial_impact" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for assessment of financial impact</name>
  <description>request to provide a price or cost impact statement against a statement of work
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_effectivity_impact_assessment" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for effectivity impact assessment</name>
  <description>request for an assessment of the impact of a proposal to apply a change to specified products
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_update" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for update</name>
  <description>request for an update to an implementation plan, following authorization of a change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="status_of_change_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>status of change task</name>
  <description>information on the progress of a task in the change development plan
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="business_impact_of_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>business impact of solution</name>
  <description>information required to evaluate the potential cost, risks and benefits of any element of a proposed
change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_justification" inscope="yes">
  <name>change justification</name>
  <description>business case for making a change, including assessment of cost, benefits and risks
</description>
<note>The change justification acts as a control when authorizing change. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_order" inscope="yes">
  <name>change order</name>
  <description>authority to implement a change to a product
</description>
<note>The change order defines the change and authorizes release of updated APSI </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>change plan</name>
  <description>information defining the tasks required to implement a potential solution including the required time,
resources and budget
</description>
<note>Such plans include change development plans, change implementation plans and change validation, verification and audit plans. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_risk" inscope="yes">
  <name>change risk</name>
  <description>risk relating to a potential change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="classified_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>classified solution</name>
  <description>potential solution to a valid need for change to which a class has been assigned
</description>
<note>The solution should include specification of the intended design change and related impact assessments  to be evaluated for effectivity and cost implications and work to plan change tasks can be initiated </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="costed_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>costed change</name>
  <description>quantified change with life cycle costs incorporated
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="recommended_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>recommended change</name>
  <description>recommended solution to a valid need for change, after comparison of potential solution options
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="rejected_issue_or_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>rejected issue or change</name>
  <description>message advising that no further action is intended in respect to an issue or change
</description>
<note>A rejected issue or change should be supported by a reason for rejection and may include:   <ul>
  <li>issues that will not be taken forward as change orders and for which exists no further planned configuration change management action;</li>
  <li>a valid need for change that was rejected following evaluation on cost, effectiveness or other grounds; </li>
  <li>a variance that has been rejected as a method of correcting a non-conformance. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="classified_element_or_relationship" inscope="yes">
  <name>classified element or relationship</name>
  <description>element of the PIF or its support system which has been identified and assigned to one or more classes
of element, plus any relationships between elements which need to be tracked for support purposes
</description>
<note>Unambiguous identification includes the assignment of a name (for use by humans) and an alphanumeric identifier (for use within computers) that are unique within a context.  The context for a name or identifier is the organization that provides the name and identification.  Elements can have more than one name and identifier assigned by different organizations.  The classification of an element can include a class that helps identify the APSI that is required for this element type.  Relationships can include any of those specified by the information model of this part of ISO 10303. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_management_rules_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>information management rules *</name>
  <description>set of rules and interpretation guidance provided to achieve effective information sharing and exchange
across the PIF scope
</description>
<note>Such rules can include:   <ul>
  <li>policies and instructions on the management of APSI and related information specifying what information shall be recorded, utilized and archived when performing support activities;</li>
  <li>information models, standards, formats, business rules, naming conventions and reference data required to achieve effective communication;</li>
  <li>specifications of the information to be acquired or disposed of with the product or support elements as they enter or leave the information management domain defined by the PIF scope;</li>
  <li>references to this or other parts of ISO 10303 that shall apply to information of relevance to the PIF.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_need_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>information need *</name>
  <description>specification of the information that shall be developed and maintained within the APSI for any PIF or
support system element or class of elements
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="pif_scope" inscope="yes">
  <name>PIF scope</name>
  <description>identification of the group of actual or potential operational products and related items which require
support during their life cycle

</description>
<note>The PIF scope  can include:   <ul>
  <li>many versions of a product design; </li>
  <li>many operational products, used by different users in different ways; </li>
  <li>any part of the operational product needing support;  </li>
  <li>any related item that requires support. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="pif_structure" inscope="yes">
  <name>PIF structure</name>
  <description>integrated set of classified elements and interfaces, product structure views and relationships between
product structure views required to provide life cycle support
</description>
<note>The PIF structure comprises:   <ul>
  <li>the set of breakdown and assembly views being maintained for the product in focus including effectivity statements on the current, required and permitted configurations of each individual planned or realizedproduct;</li>
  <li>relationships between breakdown and assembly views such as functional to physical links for both design and individual structures;</li>
  <li>identification of interfaces between elements. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_and_support_element_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>product &amp; support element information</name>
  <description>any information about the product in focus and related support elements that is required by participants
in life cycle support
</description>
<note>This information may include:  <ul>
  <li>product definition information; </li>
  <li>product performance information; </li>
  <li>predicted failures; </li>
  <li>diagnostic data; </li>
  <li>descriptions of the product or support element; </li>
  <li>manufacturing records; </li>
  <li>product characteristics of relevance to support; </li>
  <li>descriptions of people and organizations;  </li>
  <li>the operating and maintenance history of individual acquired items if relevant to future support. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_identifier" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for identifier</name>
  <description>request to provide identification for new elements of the product or support system element
</description>
<note>Requests may arise from new product concepts, developing breakdowns of existing products, or from changes. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="identified_element" inscope="yes">
  <name>identified element</name>
  <description>any subdivision of the PIF, the support system or related information to which consistent reference needs
to be made as part of product life cycle support
</description>
<note> Certain identified elements may be selected as Configuration Items. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="interface" inscope="yes">
  <name>interface</name>
  <description>product attributes that exist at a common boundary of two or more products to which reference needs to
be made
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="naming_convention_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>naming convention *</name>
  <description>standards and conventions that are to be applied when identifying elements of the PIF or support system
</description>
<note>Naming conventions are part of the information management rules. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="developed_structure_views" inscope="yes">
  <name>developed structure views</name>
  <description>set of product structure views and breakdowns that the life cycle owner has chosen to establish and maintain
for the life of the PIF
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="required_structures" inscope="yes">
  <name>required structures</name>
  <description>set of product assembly or breakdown views that the life cycle owner requires to establish and maintain
the PIF
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="functional_breakdown" inscope="yes">
  <name>functional breakdown</name>
  <description>hierarchical decomposition of the functions of a product showing the product functions that may require
support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="logistic_item_breakdown" inscope="yes">
  <name>logistic item breakdown</name>
  <description>hierarchical decomposition of the physical elements within a product that are significant from a support
viewpoint
</description>
<note>The logistic item breakdown can be derived from, and related to, the product assembly structure. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_assembly" inscope="yes">
  <name>product assembly</name>
  <description>hierarchical view of a product based on the assembly of its constituent parts
</description>
<note>The product assembly may be used to derive a parts list or bill of materials. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="apsi" inscope="yes">
  <name>APSI</name>
  <description>set of information, subject to configuration change management, that is established to develop and deliver
support for a product in focus
</description>
<note>This term corresponds to the EIA 649 term &quot;product configuration information&quot; which includes:   <ul>
  <li>product definition information that defines the product requirements, documents the product attributes and is the authoritative source for configuration definition;</li>
  <li>product operational information, used to test operate maintain and dispose of the product. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="deployment_environment" inscope="yes">
  <name>deployment environment</name>
  <description>context for which a support solution definition is created
</description>
<note>A deployment environment identifies the set of products and defines the operating and support environment to which a support solution definition applies.  A deployment environment may relate to the entire product in focus, or to a subset of it.  A product in focus may thus give rise to several support solution definitions, each tailored to a different deployment environment. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_management_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>information management plan</name>
  <description>specification and scheduling of the activities required to develop, collect, analyze and publish the
information needed for product support
</description>
<note>This includes a control to ensure that the APSI is released in a timely and appropriate manner. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_management_strategy_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>information management strategy *</name>
  <description>intended approach to managing information for a given product in focus
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_update" inscope="yes">
  <name>information update</name>
  <description>minor corrections to the APSI that do not require formal change action, arising from assessment of issues,
or from configuration audits
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="pif_task_set" inscope="yes">
  <name>PIF task set</name>
  <description>collection of valid tasks that are applicable to a product in focus
</description>
<note>Each task may be supported by a task description or task procedure, and by a task resource model. Task may be related to relevant support drivers and assigned to relevant product groups, versions, support locations, support opportunity type or class of task.  The PIF task set may include tasks that are not used by any support solution definition such as commissioning tasks and tasks that are defined, but are not selected for use when the support solution definition is approved. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_and_support_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>product &amp; support information</name>
  <description>potential APSI prior to authorization and release
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="rejected_psi" inscope="yes">
  <name>rejected PSI</name>
  <description>notification of decision not to release product and support information as APSI
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="related_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>related information</name>
  <description>information that is related to the APSI but is not subject to configuration change management
</description>
<note>Such information includes feedback from operations and maintenance. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_solution_definition" inscope="yes">
  <name>support solution definition</name>
  <description>work required to support a group of products within a deployment environment 


 
</description>
<note>The support solution may include:   <ul>
  <li>identification of the deployment environment and support solution requirements for which the support solution was designed;</li>
  <li>a listing of relevant support drivers; </li>
  <li>a support plan, that identifies necessary tasks to respond to these support drivers, and specifies the conditions under which each task falls due;</li>
  <li>justification for the above; </li>
  <li>task procedures for necessary tasks; </li>
  <li>identification and quantification of resources needed to achieve necessary tasks, including types of person with skill level;</li>
  <li>resource models for necessary tasks; </li>
  <li>product definition data for required resource items. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_model_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>information model *</name>
  <description>model in EXPRESS or other modelling language provided to define how product and support information shall
be structured
</description>
<note>The information model is one component of the information management rules. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="requirement_for_product_structure_view_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>requirement for product structure view *</name>
  <description>need for a breakdown view that is necessary for life cycle support of the PIF
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_information_rules_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>support information rules *</name>
  <description>information models, reference data and rules that specify for the PIF how support information shall be
collected and stored to achieve efficient management of support delivery 


</description>
<note>Requirements to capture specific information may be included in task procedures.  This activity model assumes that:   <ul>
  <li>the support information management rules include the use of this part of ISO 10303 to structure the APSI and the collection of feedback as related information;</li>
  <li>the support information management rules apply to all elements of the PIF and its support system; </li>
  <li>appropriate interfaces and translators are provided to interpret non-compliant information, such as that held in existing information technology systems, into a form that complies with these rules.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_release_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>information release plan</name>
  <description>schedule defining the timing for the release of assured information
</description>
<note>The information release plan may specify who needs what information, when, where, in what formats and what media. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="releasable_product_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>releasable product information</name>
  <description>information relating to the product that can be released as APSI, under the conditions specified by the
information release plan
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="allocated_support_requirements" inscope="yes">
  <name>allocated support requirements</name>
  <description>requirements that have been allocated for consideration during the design of a support solution
</description>
<note>Allocated requirements are typically a subset of the product requirement but may not capture the needs of all recognized stakeholders </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="assessment_results" inscope="yes">
  <name>assessment results</name>
  <description>information arising from assessment activities
</description>
<note>Such information includes reports on the support system performance in relation to support objectives or metrics; recognized deficiencies or proposed improvements to the product or support solution, issues with the support solution requirement. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_task_request" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning task request</name>
  <description>request for the development of a task specification for a commissioning activity not included in the
current PIF task set
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="impact_assessment" inscope="yes">
  <name>impact assessment</name>
  <description>predicted consequences of adopting a potential solution to a valid need for change
</description>
<note>This arrow communicates a solution definition report and an assessment of business impact on support engineering.  It will be combined with similar information from beyond the model boundary assessing the impact on other technical domains. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_collection_requirement" inscope="yes">
  <name>information collection requirement</name>
  <description>expression of need for an activity to collect assessment information
</description>
<note>Requirement may be met by:   <ul>
  <li>adding a task step to an existing task required for other reasons; </li>
  <li>adding information collection tasks to the support engineering programme, or the support solution definition; </li>
  <li>adding embedded support capability in the product such as product health monitoring. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_from_other_systems" inscope="yes">
  <name>information from other systems</name>
  <description>information on the identity, description or in-service performance of other products or support systems
of relevance to the product in focus
</description>
<note>This information could be supplied in a format that conforms to this part of ISO 10303, but is perhaps only be available on paper or in other data formats that do not conform to ISO 10303. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="life_cycle_directive_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>life cycle directive *</name>
  <description>instructions or policies from beyond the model boundary that initiate or constrain support activities
from concept through disposal
</description>
<note>These directives may include:   <ul>
  <li>law and political dictates; </li>
  <li>environmental and safety directives; </li>
  <li>business, organizational and program strategies and policies; </li>
  <li>standardization policy and directives; </li>
  <li>programme plans and schedules defining what action is needed, when, where and by whom; </li>
  <li>programme business goals, objectives, targets and constraints such as annual budgets and performance targets;</li>
  <li>priorities from the life cycle owner that affect the feasibility of providing needed support elements; </li>
  <li>decisions arising from consideration of requests to the life cycle operator; </li>
  <li>exceptional maintenance demands not reflected in the support solution definition; </li>
  <li>information from the operational plan, sufficient to define each support opportunity, and to define the constraint on support delivery.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="needed_information" inscope="yes">
  <name>needed information</name>
  <description>identification of the information that needs to be collected to support assessment of support performance
against the metrics specified by the support solution requirements
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="operating_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>operating schedule</name>
  <description>anticipated support opportunities and expected usage of one or more products needing support during a
period of interest
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="performance_report" inscope="yes">
  <name>performance report</name>
  <description>information on the performance achieved in generating a support solution or in providing support

</description>
<note>A performance report may include:    <ul>
  <li>information on progress achieved against the support engineering program; </li>
  <li>comparison of achievements, predictions and requirements in terms of the support metrics applicable to a given support solution;</li>
  <li>observations on the performance achieved against identified support objectives; </li>
  <li>observations on the ability of the PIF and its support solution to meet expectations of operators and support personnel.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_investigation" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for investigation</name>
  <description>request for action resulting from assessment activities
</description>
<note>May include:   <ul>
  <li>proposal to change the resource provision related to a given task;  </li>
  <li>proposal to change the support solution; </li>
  <li>requests to relax support solution requirements;  </li>
  <li>proposal to change the product; </li>
  <li>requests for additional data from existing source or for new data sources. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_requirement_clarification" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for requirement clarification</name>
  <description>invitation to stakeholders to re-assess allocated requirement, support objectives or elicited needs that
generate requirement conflicts which cannot be resolved adequately by the support engineering programme
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_task_procedure" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for task procedure</name>
  <description>request for the development of a task procedure for an intended task not addressed by the support solution
definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_to_life_cycle_owner" inscope="yes">
  <name>request to life cycle owner</name>
  <description>request for action by the life cycle owner relating to activities beyond the scope of this model
</description>
<note>These requests can result from supportability analyses, assessments or experience.  They can lead to a further iteration of the in-scope activities, triggered by work requests entering the scope of this activity model as feedback.  They can include:   <ul>
  <li>requests for action to develop or acquire required resources not currently available in the deployment environment;</li>
  <li>requests for information; </li>
  <li>proposals for changes to the product requirement, allocated support requirements, product design or life cycle directives to reflect support needs.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="requirement_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>requirement feedback</name>
  <description>proposal for changes to the support solution requirements arising from monitoring support system performance
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="requirement_to_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>requirement to design</name>
  <description>requests to the life cycle owner to address issues identified by the task analysis activity
</description>
<note>This may include:   <ul>
  <li>requests to designers to assess the feasibility of changing the product to improve supportability; </li>
  <li>requests to investigate the feasibility of changing the product design to meet support solution requirements by improving reliability or preventing a failure mode;</li>
  <li>notification of potential health, safety and environmental risks identified by the task analysis that may require design activity;</li>
  <li>notification of constraints imposed by support activity on the intended use of the product; </li>
  <li>requests for action to identify or modify existing resources required by tasks; </li>
  <li>requests for the provision of new resource capability, which may lead to updates of resource item descriptions within a deployment environment.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="resource_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>resource feedback</name>
  <description>information on the adequacy and quality of resources provided to support a specific task, a specific
deployment, a realized product or the overall support solution definition
</description>
<note>This may identify a task or resource imbalance or deficiency that may justify a reassessment of the resource aspects within a task analysis. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="resource_recommendations" inscope="yes">
  <name>resource recommendations</name>
  <description>recommended holdings of resource items required to support a given support solution definition, or the
set of support solutions definitions
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_engineering_objectives" inscope="yes">
  <name>support engineering objectives</name>
  <description>target of goal to be met by the support engineering programme
</description>
<note>Objectives may be communicated as a structured requirement statement. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_engineering_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>support engineering schedule</name>
  <description>identification, timing and sequencing of the activities and resources required to develop a support solution
definition which meets the support engineering objectives and the support solution requirement, within
the constraints specified by life cycle and change directives
</description>
<note>It includes:   <ul>
  <li>a plan of activities and resource schedule for the work required to develop and monitor the performance of one or more support solutions;</li>
  <li>task specifications and other documents related to the schedule specifying the policies and processes to be used in conducting such activities.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>support feedback</name>
  <description>observation on the condition or usage of a product receiving support and on the execution of support
activities
</description>
<note>Support feedback is generated when tasks are performed on a product needing support.  It includes information on:   <ul>
  <li>the operation, usage and location of the product or support element receiving support; </li>
  <li>the current configuration of the product or support element; </li>
  <li>the condition of the product or support element receiving support, before, during or after the support activity, recorded as properties, states or observations;</li>
  <li>the progress and status of work;  </li>
  <li>the resources used to perform work; </li>
  <li>issues arising from work done, including proposals for change to the product or support solution. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_objective_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>support objective issue</name>
  <description>report to the life cycle owner advising that it is either not possible or perhaps not feasible to satisfy
one or more support objectives within a support solution definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_prediction" inscope="yes">
  <name>support prediction</name>
  <description>forecast of the support system performance to be expected when applying a support solution definition
in the context of a predicted operating or usage schedule and support provider performance
</description>
<note>This may include predictions on resource consumption, and hence on provisioning requirements.  The prediction of some metrics may require assumptions to be made about resource availability and delay times. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_solution_requirement" inscope="yes">
  <name>support solution requirement</name>
  <description>set of requirements that shall be addressed during the development of a support solution definition in
the context of a deployment environment

</description>
<note>The requirement may include specified performance metrics for the support solution, with threshold or other tolerance values, defined in terms of agreed support characteristics. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="evaluated_support_improvement_opportunity" inscope="yes">
  <name>evaluated support improvement opportunity</name>
  <description>opportunity to improve the performance of a support solution which shall be addressed as part of the
support engineering programme
</description>
<note>Support improvement opportunities may be expressed as specified tasks or as work requests. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="objective_change_request" inscope="yes">
  <name>objective change request</name>
  <description>request for changes to a support objective which cannot be met
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="programme_change_requirement" inscope="yes">
  <name>programme change requirement</name>
  <description>expression of need for a change of the support engineering programme
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_review_result" inscope="yes">
  <name>support review result</name>
  <description>identified needs to change programme objectives, strategies or plans
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="external_factor_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>external factor *</name>
  <description>aspects of the external environment that provide opportunities or pose risks to the successful provision
of support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_improvement_opportunity" inscope="yes">
  <name>support improvement opportunity</name>
  <description>possible means to improve the performance of a support solution which may warrant investigation as part
of the support engineering programme
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="intended_resource_holdings" inscope="yes">
  <name>intended resource holdings</name>
  <description>quantification and predicted availability of support resources at each support location of relevance
to a product group
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="potential_faults_and_relationships" inscope="yes">
  <name>potential faults &amp; relationships</name>
  <description>identification and description of each potential fault, or other degraded state, which may affect each
part, function or usage occurrence in each operating environment, including cause, effect or other relationships
between relevant states
</description>
<note>The product functions may be represented by a functional breakdown.  Faults may be defined as product states. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="potential_support_provider" inscope="yes">
  <name>potential support provider</name>
  <description>identity, description, organisation, location, environment and capability of each potential support provider
of relevance to a product group
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_group" inscope="yes">
  <name>product group</name>
  <description>set of products, operated by one or more customers, that are to be addressed by a specific support solution
definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_group_usage_profile" inscope="yes">
  <name>product group usage profile</name>
  <description>expected pattern of usage and life constraints applicable to a product group requiring support
</description>
<note>A product group may have several usage profiles, including a prediction of the percentage of time for which each may apply. Each profile may include:    <ul>
  <li>the duration and nature of deployments; </li>
  <li>the intended frequencies, duration, distance, pattern, and nature of operating and support periods; </li>
  <li>the anticipated physical and climatic environments in which usage is expected to occur; </li>
  <li>usage parameters and limits on product use. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="resource_item_description" inscope="yes">
  <name>resource item description</name>
  <description>identification and description of the resource items expected to be available at each location to support
a product group
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_opportunity" inscope="yes">
  <name>support opportunity</name>
  <description>identification and description of an actual opportunity, or a type of opportunity, when work could be
performed on a product needing support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="life_or_usage_parameter" inscope="yes">
  <name>life or usage parameter</name>
  <description>name, definition and representation options of a parameter used to define product usage or set limits
on product life
</description>
<note>Typical parameters include:   <ul>
  <li>elapsed time since vessel launch; </li>
  <li>numbers of landings; </li>
  <li>hours above 30% power; </li>
  <li>fatigue cycles of an identified component, measured in a defined way. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="operating_environment" inscope="yes">
  <name>operating environment</name>
  <description>description of an environment in which a product may be required to operate, from the viewpoint of its
likely impact on the requirement for support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="identified_support_location" inscope="yes">
  <name>identified support location</name>
  <description>identification and description of an intended location or geographical area where support may be required
or provided
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="local_support_environment" inscope="yes">
  <name>local support environment</name>
  <description>definition of relevant environmental conditions at an identified location which could affect the provision
of support and hence the support solution
</description>
<note>Such environments can include artic or desert conditions, or the use of a covered dock. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_location_capability" inscope="yes">
  <name>support location capability</name>
  <description>ability of one or more support organizations at a given location, to undertake classes of tasks within
a support solution definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="elicited_support_need" inscope="yes">
  <name>elicited support need</name>
  <description>potential requirement on the design of the support solution, reflecting the desires and expectations
of a recognized stakeholder
</description>
<note>Elicited needs are derived from analyses of customer and stakeholder needs and priorities with associated rationale, including source documents or agreements.  Elicited needs may include:   <ul>
  <li>expectations for the lifetime of the product and its support; </li>
  <li>intended duration of deployments; </li>
  <li>numbers of products needing support; </li>
  <li>needs for standardization with other organizations, users or partners; </li>
  <li>needs derived from experience with the development, production, use, support or disposal of similar products;</li>
  <li>needs derived from experience of similar organizations, environments and scenarios; </li>
  <li>needs derived from experience with the use and support of the product since its introduction into service. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="feedback_on_support_needs" inscope="yes">
  <name>feedback on support needs</name>
  <description>requests for further information to assist conflict resolution between requirements
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="list_of_stakeholders" inscope="yes">
  <name>list of stakeholders</name>
  <description>set of stakeholders identified by life cycle directives
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="recognized_stakeholder" inscope="yes">
  <name>recognized stakeholder</name>
  <description>person or organisation with a legitimate role in the specification, design, commissioning or use of a
support solution definition
</description>
<note>Recognized stakeholders can include:   <ul>
  <li>users; </li>
  <li>supporters; </li>
  <li>developers; </li>
  <li>producers; </li>
  <li>trainers; </li>
  <li>maintainers; </li>
  <li>disposers; </li>
  <li>acquirers; </li>
  <li>supplier organizations; </li>
  <li>regulatory bodies; </li>
  <li>members or groups in society, including representatives or designated proxy stakeholders. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="requirement_directive" inscope="yes">
  <name>requirement directive</name>
  <description>information derived from the life cycle directives, expressed as a potential requirement for a support
solution definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="agreed_support_need" inscope="yes">
  <name>agreed support need</name>
  <description>support need accepted as suitable for inclusion in a support solution requirement
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="quantified_support_metric" inscope="yes">
  <name>quantified support metric</name>
  <description>performance measure, with target value, to be used for assessing the performance of the support solution
definition
</description>
<note>This includes specification of the performance measure in terms of agreed characteristics, and the quantification of target or threshold values for use when assessing support achievement.  Quantification may be expressed in terms of any agreed characteristic including cost, availability, time or rate of resource use. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_characteristic" inscope="yes">
  <name>support characteristic</name>
  <description>quantifiable parameter used to define an aspect of support system performance
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_characteristic_clarification_request" inscope="yes">
  <name>support characteristic clarification request</name>
  <description>requests to stakeholder seeking clarification of required support characteristics
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_metric_clarification_request" inscope="yes">
  <name>support metric clarification request</name>
  <description>request for clarification of a support metric proposed by a stakeholder
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="unresolved_support_conflict" inscope="yes">
  <name>unresolved support conflict</name>
  <description>notification of a problem identified during support solution development or use, which cannot be resolved
without breaching support solution requirements or constraints
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_behaviour" inscope="yes">
  <name>product behaviour</name>
  <description>expected behaviour of a product for support purposes defined in terms of operating and fault states,
expected values of  measurable parameters, and relationship of symptoms to possible and probable causes

</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_task_evolution" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for task evolution</name>
  <description>invitation to further develop a task specification
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="safety_or_support_critical_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>safety or support critical issue</name>
  <description>request for action by the life cycle owner, or an expression of concern, arising from identification
of support drivers that affect safety or other topics of critical significance to the delivery of viable
support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_driver" inscope="yes">
  <name>support driver</name>
  <description>requirements for support activity, linked to the source from which they arose
</description>
<note>Such drivers include requirements for the development of task specifications to address:   <ul>
  <li>predicted product failure or degradation; </li>
  <li>safety, legal or environmental concerns; </li>
  <li>operational or readiness related tasks to be addressed by the support solution definition; </li>
  <li>tasks to collect the information needed to assess support performance. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="unresolved_support_driver" inscope="yes">
  <name>unresolved support driver</name>
  <description>support driver for which no effective response can be found
</description>
<note>Unresolved support drivers can arise because support task opportunities are not technically feasible or economically viable within the support engineering programme constraints and the support solution requirement. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="potential_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>potential task</name>
  <description>name, identifier and description of a possible support task
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_applicability" inscope="yes">
  <name>task applicability</name>
  <description>classification of a task based on its relevance to a PIF, a product group, a product version, a location
or support opportunity type
</description>
<note>Task applicability criteria may be extended or changed when the task is selected for use within a specific support solution definition. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_description" inscope="yes">
  <name>task description</name>
  <description>definition of a method for performing a potential support task
</description>
<note>The task description may include definition and quantification of the resources required to perform the task. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_resource_model" inscope="yes">
  <name>task resource model</name>
  <description>algorithm or formula for calculating the likely task duration and resource use when the task is executed
</description>
<note>Human resources are included so that a task resource model could predict the time required to perform a task by staff with specified skill levels. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_support_item" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for support item</name>
  <description>request for the design or supply of a new or additional resource item required by a task, or for information
on the feasibility and cost of obtaining these
</description>
<note>This request may also communicate formal requirements and specifications for the design, modification or acquisition of new or critical support items, and could also be used to request information on support cost and lead time for products beyond the PIF scope which have relevance to the support of the PIF. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_to_embed" inscope="yes">
  <name>request to embed</name>
  <description>request for action to assess the feasibility of changing the product to improve supportability, or to
embed support capabilities within the design
</description>
<note>Such a request can result from requirements to improve reliability, maintainability, redundancy, durability, sustainability or product life. Requests to embed can seek to incorporate capability within the product for prognostics, diagnostics, condition monitoring, built in test, safety or environmental protection that is needed for support reasons. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_resources" inscope="yes">
  <name>task resources</name>
  <description>identification and quantification of the resources that are needed to perform an individual task
</description>
<note>This may include definition of required skills and experience of required support personnel. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="necessary_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>necessary task</name>
  <description>name and identifier of a task that is applicable to a given support solution definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="relevant_support_driver" inscope="yes">
  <name>relevant support driver</name>
  <description>support driver of relevance to a specific deployment environment and support concept
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_support_concept_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for support concept change</name>
  <description>request for a change to the support concept
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_plan" inscope="yes">
  <name>support plan</name>
  <description>identification of the tasks required to support a product within a specified deployment environment,
including the logic through which tasks are combined or otherwise related
</description>
<note>A support plan can include a presentation of a typical maintenance programme for a product needing support.  It can also specify non-maintenance tasks, such as activities required to provide and prepare required resources.  Some necessary tasks can never be implemented if the conditions under which they would fall due fail to arise. This can include a task to correct a rare fault state. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_plan_option" inscope="yes">
  <name>support plan option</name>
  <description>possible support plan, corresponding to a specific support policy
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_policy_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>support policy *</name>
  <description>statement defining the approach to be taken when developing a support solution definition for a specific
context
</description>
<note>This could include a requirement to apply a reliability centred maintenance approach. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_procedure" inscope="yes">
  <name>task procedure</name>
  <description>step-by-step instructions for undertaking a necessary activity in a form suitable for use by the support
provider
</description>
<note>The same task may be supported by several task procedures, each tailored to the needs of a class of users, with different skill levels or to alternative task methods. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="rationalization_proposal" inscope="yes">
  <name>rationalization proposal</name>
  <description>proposal to change the assignment of tasks to products, or the task trigger conditions, to achieve rationalization
of work packages within the support plan
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_to_product_relationship" inscope="yes">
  <name>task to product relationship</name>
  <description>relationship between a necessary task and the product element, or elements to which it applies
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_trigger" inscope="yes">
  <name>task trigger</name>
  <description>conditions that require a task to be done, in the context of its assignment to a specific product element
within a support solution definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="predicted_downtime" inscope="yes">
  <name>predicted downtime</name>
  <description>forecast loss of operational time due to support activities during the operating period in question
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="predicted_product_state_and_usage" inscope="yes">
  <name>predicted product state &amp; usage</name>
  <description>forecast state and usage of the product after a period of operation, defined in terms that are meaningful
to the task triggers, including predictions of anticipated faults
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="predicted_resource_consumption" inscope="yes">
  <name>predicted resource consumption</name>
  <description>forecast of the resources needed to support a product during a specified period of operation
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="required_tasks" inscope="yes">
  <name>required tasks</name>
  <description>tasks expected to be performed during the operating period of interest
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="assessment_deficiency" inscope="yes">
  <name>assessment deficiency</name>
  <description>issue from analysis of assessment results which may require change to the assessment strategy
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="assessment_strategy" inscope="yes">
  <name>assessment strategy</name>
  <description>strategy for assessing and validating the support solution definition, and the support engineering programme,
against agreed objectives and metrics
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="assessment_strategy_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>assessment strategy issue</name>
  <description>issue that may require a change to the assessment strategy
</description>
<note>Such issues include:    <ul>
  <li>observations that the strategy for assessment of the support solution is inadequate or unrealistic; </li>
  <li>the identification of information sources that do not provide the required information; </li>
  <li>reports on inconclusive assessment results due to inadequacies in the assessment  method or inadequate information.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inadequate_source" inscope="yes">
  <name>inadequate source</name>
  <description>request for a change to the assessment strategy, arising because available information collection mechanisms
cannot provide the required feedback
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning feedback</name>
  <description>information on the progress of commissioning activities against the plan or recommendations for change
to the support solution, the product, or the commissioning schedule, arising from commissioning experience
</description>
<note>This feedback includes:   <ul>
  <li>aggregated status of commissioning tasks; </li>
  <li>commissioning task discrepancies and proposals for improvement in the commissioning solution; </li>
  <li>proposals for improvements to the support solution or product arising from commissioning experience. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_objective" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning objective</name>
  <description>objective to be achieved by the commissioning activity
</description>
<note>The objective may address any phase of the commissioning process  including acquisition, construction, testing or certification of support system elements  </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning schedule</name>
  <description>schedule showing the intended timing and sequencing of intended commissioning tasks
</description>
<note>Commissioning tasks are those required to create the support system. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_task_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning task feedback</name>
  <description>information on the progress, resource consumption and issues arising from performing commissioning tasks
</description>
<note>Information provided to identify trends or potential problems from applying a commissioning solution. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_task_metrics" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning task metrics</name>
  <description>measures of performance applicable to the performance of commissioning tasks
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="first_use_date" inscope="yes">
  <name>first use date</name>
  <description>date when a support element is required for first operational use
</description>
<note>The first use date is used to establish the schedule of commissioning activities. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_system_release" inscope="yes">
  <name>support system release</name>
  <description>confirmation that the support system is in place and ready to accept products needing support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="transaction_replies" inscope="yes">
  <name>transaction replies</name>
  <description>responses to transaction requests, providing details of price, availability, delivery or forecast availability
of requested resources
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="transaction_request" inscope="yes">
  <name>transaction request</name>
  <description>request for the provision of one or more required resources at a specified location and date, or hastening
a previous transaction request

</description>
<note>Transaction requests arise from the need to supply resources to support work at a specific support opportunity, or to position resources with a support system.   </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_programme_logic" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning programme logic</name>
  <description>logical constraints and relationships applicable to intended commissioning activities
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="scheduling_problem_report" inscope="yes">
  <name>scheduling problem report</name>
  <description>information on issues that prevent successful completion of the commissioning schedule
</description>
<note>Such information can identify tasks that cannot be scheduled due to constraints from resource availability, operational schedule, or other reasons. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="selected_commissioning_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>selected commissioning task</name>
  <description>activity required in the commissioning schedule to establish a viable support system, capable of applying
a support solution definition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="assured_support_solution" inscope="yes">
  <name>assured support solution</name>
  <description>support solution definition that is authorized for use in providing support or disposal to one or more
product or support element
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="authorised_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>authorised task</name>
  <description>task on which work may begin
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="disposed_element" inscope="yes">
  <name>disposed element</name>
  <description>element of the product, or its support system leaving the control of the life cycle owner
</description>
<note>Disposed elements may include:   <ul>
  <li>waste products arising from support tasks; </li>
  <li>resources no longer required for planned tasks; </li>
  <li>elements removed from the product; </li>
  <li>a product retiring from use. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_to_system_operator_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>information to system operator *</name>
  <description>information provided to the user or operator of a product needing support regarding the condition of
the supported product

</description>
<note>Such information can include:   <ul>
  <li>information arising from the maintenance of a realized product and affecting subsequent operation, such as a power limitation pending further maintenance work;</li>
  <li>achieved availability or other aspects of support performance of relevance to operators; </li>
  <li>readiness of the support system and availability of support elements and services; </li>
  <li>limitations on product or support system availability; </li>
  <li>any anticipated impact on operational plans from PIF condition, such as a requirement to perform further maintenance within a specific time period;</li>
  <li>responses to operator requests on operational or support problems. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="maintenance_need" inscope="yes">
  <name>maintenance need</name>
  <description>work request identifying additional support tasks which may be needed to restore products to serviceable
conditions
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="operator_feedback_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>operator feedback *</name>
  <description>information provided to support authorities by operators including information on product health and
usage, and equipment problems discovered by operators
</description>
<note>Such feedback can include trouble reports, log books and other data from on-board recording systems, passed to support authorities for analysis.  The operator feedback is structured to conform to the information management rules by activity A4.4 and is communicated within this model by the support feedback arrow. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_needing_support" inscope="yes">
  <name>product needing support</name>
  <description>one or more realized products that require support
</description>
<note>Such products include any realized element of the PIF.  These elements The include embedded information of relevance to support activities.  This information can take the form of stamped on serial numbers, bar codes, embedded chips, log books or other media carried with the product itself. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_status" inscope="yes">
  <name>product status</name>
  <description>notification of the current state of a product receiving support, as confirmed by the authority controlling
the work
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="required_resources" inscope="yes">
  <name>required resources</name>
  <description>identification of the resources needed to support scheduled work at one or more support opportunities
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="standard_commercial_transaction_set" inscope="yes">
  <name>standard commercial transaction set</name>
  <description>set of standardized business transactions that execute requests for the provision of resources, and provide
responses on their expected delivery
</description>
<note>These transactions can include:   <ul>
  <li>order an item, which may include requirements for delivery to a specified location by or on a due date at an agreed price;</li>
  <li>order a service; </li>
  <li>request a move of item from one location to another, under specified conditions such as use of a packaging standard or need to provide tracking reports;</li>
  <li>query a forecast delivery; </li>
  <li>request review and comments; </li>
  <li>request approval; </li>
  <li>request for a specified repair or overhaul. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_element" inscope="yes">
  <name>support element</name>
  <description>physical item required to sustain product capability
</description>
<note>In this activity model fixed support infrastructure is treated as a mechanism that is separate from the concept of support element.  Within the ARM of this part of ISO 10303, support elements and infrastructure are both represented as resource items. Support elements include:   <ul>
  <li>repair parts, which become part of the equipment when used, and may be expendable or repairable when replaced;</li>
  <li>consumable items, such as oil, which are consumed by the equipment in the course of delivering its designed capability;</li>
  <li>tools, diagnostic and test equipment used to undertake support tasks; </li>
  <li>trained people. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>support schedule</name>
  <description>systematic plan or arrangement for performing one or more support tasks
</description>
<note>The status of the schedule may change as it develops.   The support schedule may include a maintenance schedule defining work to be performed on the product needing support.  A support schedule may also define tasks applicable to support elements or required resources such as the calibration of a test instrument. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="supported_product" inscope="yes">
  <name>supported product</name>
  <description>realized product that is available to the life cycle owner for operational use
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_feedback_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>task feedback *</name>
  <description>information, in any form, derived from observation of a realized activity including progress, findings
or resource use, prior to the capture of this information in the format required by the information management
rules
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="work_status" inscope="yes">
  <name>work status</name>
  <description>information on the progress of activities in relation to a support schedule
</description>
<note>This information on status is transient and will change as the work progresses. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_schedule_revision" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for schedule revision</name>
  <description>request for revisions to the support schedule as a result of feedback from task execution

</description>
<note>This may include reports of deferred tasks or requests for additional activities that should be considered for inclusion in a subsequent revision of a support schedule. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="selected_support_provider" inscope="yes">
  <name>selected support provider</name>
  <description>organization, or organizations, selected to perform  scheduled tasks
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_opportunity_objectives" inscope="yes">
  <name>support opportunity objectives</name>
  <description>objectives applicable to a specific support opportunity
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_logic" inscope="yes">
  <name>task logic</name>
  <description>logical sequence of the intended activities, reflecting the constraints which apply
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_to_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>task to schedule</name>
  <description>activity to be included in the work schedule for a given support opportunity
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>commissioning task</name>
  <description>activity to create, test or validate an element of the support system
</description>
<note>This includes activities to establish resource items in appropriate locations and work to bring support infrastructure to a state fit to receive a product needing support. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="consequential_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>consequential task</name>
  <description>activity that needs to be included in a schedule as a consequence of another task
</description>
<note>May include additional tasks required by the proposed activity logic or by resource preparation requirements such as the work needed to set up and calibrate a test rig. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="individual_product_state" inscope="yes">
  <name>individual product state</name>
  <description>expected configuration and condition of an individual product at the start of the support opportunity
</description>
<note>This information may be available from the APSI and related information. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="other_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>other task</name>
  <description>identification of a task to be scheduled that has not arisen directly from the application support solution
or commissioning schedule
</description>
<note>Such tasks can include change tasks, outstanding tasks from previous work, exceptional tasks required by the life cycle owner, or tasks required to meet support opportunity objectives. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_to_determine_product_state" inscope="yes">
  <name>task to determine product state</name>
  <description>activity required to establish the configuration or condition of a product prior to receiving support
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="triggered_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>triggered task</name>
  <description>activity which the assured support solution definition declares to be necessary based on evaluation of
the task trigger condition
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="completed_task" inscope="yes">
  <name>completed task</name>
  <description>record of successful completion of a task required by a support schedule
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_history" inscope="yes">
  <name>product history</name>
  <description>information of the product usage and condition over a period in the past, derived from support feedback
records
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_related_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>product related feedback</name>
  <description>information on the state of the product or support element on which a work is underway collected by observation
</description>
<note>This may include information about the product configuration, product status and product condition such as test results, wear measurements and information derived from embedded support capabilities. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_release_report" inscope="yes">
  <name>product release report</name>
  <description>information confirming that a realized product, having received support, is now ready for use
</description>
<note>This report can contain or make reference to:   <ul>
  <li>the identity and configuration of the realized product;  </li>
  <li>confirmation of ready for use status; </li>
  <li>a date and time stamp; </li>
  <li>the organization, location or person authorizing release; </li>
  <li>any restrictions or limitations applicable to product use; </li>
  <li>information on tasks scheduled and completed. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_history" inscope="yes">
  <name>task history</name>
  <description>information of previous work done on a product needing, or receiving, support derived from support feedback
records
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="task_related_feedback" inscope="yes">
  <name>task related feedback</name>
  <description>information on the progress and status of a realized activity, including resource use
</description>
<note>This may include information on the person performing the task, task steps completed, man hours used, start time, elapsed time, spares, tools or consumables used. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="configuration_record" inscope="yes">
  <name>configuration record</name>
  <description>record of the configuration of a realized product
</description>
<note>Records of configuration status may be required following incorporation of a configuration change, the removal of a serialized item, the replacement of a serialized item or the performance of a configuration audit task. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_status_record" inscope="yes">
  <name>product status record</name>
  <description>observations, measured characteristics or a record of the state of a product needing support

</description>
<note>The state of a product can include the existence of fault, an operational state or a status in relation to recognized steps or stages of a support process such as awaiting test or ready for dispatch. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_usage_record" inscope="yes">
  <name>product usage record</name>
  <description>information of the past use of an operational product
</description>
<note>Product use can be quantified against any usage parameter in any pre-defined operational or usage state such as product life, number of landings or hours spent above 50% power.  Product use records can be contained in, or extracted from, log-books or electronic records, such as tapes or discs, as provided by product operators or other personnel. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="resource_usage_record" inscope="yes">
  <name>resource usage record</name>
  <description>information on the past use of a resource in the course of performing one or more support tasks 
</description>
<note>Resource usage includes the consumption of spares or consumables, time spent by human resources in performing support tasks and the usage of support locations or facilities.  Usage may also be measured by other parameters such as elapsed time, number of starts or cycles of operation. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_element_status_record" inscope="yes">
  <name>support element status record</name>
  <description>observations on the condition, measured property or status of a support element which has been, or is
being used, as a resource for a task

</description>
<note>Possible states of a support element include:   <ul>
  <li>consumed; </li>
  <li>in-use; </li>
  <li>available to re-locate. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>support issue</name>
  <description>request for action to resolve, or an expression of concern about, a problem arising from working on a
product needing support
</description>
<note>This may include requests to modify the product or support solution definition. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_task_record" inscope="yes">
  <name>support task record</name>
  <description>information on the state of a current or completed activity, including reports of completion of individual
task steps
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="product_integrity_exception" inscope="yes">
  <name>product integrity exception</name>
  <description>identification of product conditions not recognized or addressed by the support solution that require
analysis and direction
</description>
<note>The absence of a response to such exceptions may prevent release of the product to service.  The existence of product integrity exceptions may lead to an extension of planned work or of the support solution definition. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="suggestion_for_improvement" inscope="yes">
  <name>suggestion for improvement</name>
  <description>proposed improvements the support solution definition or the PIF
</description>
<note>Such suggestions can include a change request or proposed alteration to the information management rules. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_task_exception" inscope="yes">
  <name>support task exception</name>
  <description>anomaly between a realized activity and its related task specification
</description>
<note>Anomalies may occur in the task instructions or the resources used and may lead to issues or changes affecting the product or support solution definition. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_technology_service_or_infrastructure" inscope="yes">
  <name>information technology service or infrastructure</name>
  <description>information technology capability able to provide timely, convenient and effective access to all participants
in support activities for entering and reading information
</description>
<note>The activities defined in the model could be performed without this resource but the model was designed to reflect the use of a shared, and integrated, data environment by all participants. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="support_infrastructure" inscope="yes">
  <name>support infrastructure</name>
  <description>fixed physical assets required to provide support
</description>
<note>Fixed infrastructure within a support system, such as docks, workshops, runways, or test beds, is treated in this activity model as a tunnelled mechanism to relevant activities.  Mobile support elements, such as people, parts, tools, and mobile support equipment, are treated as an input or resource to the relevant activity.  The ARM in this part of ISO 10303 treats both of the above as resource items.  Support schedules are assumed to address all required resources. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="apsi_update" inscope="yes">
  <name>APSI update</name>
  <description>proposal for correcting the APSI to reflect findings from verification or audit activities

</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="audit_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>audit issue</name>
  <description>issue arising from configuration audit and verification feedback
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="configuration_management_plan_*" inscope="yes">
  <name>configuration management plan *</name>
  <description>document that specifies how configuration management is to be accomplished for the product in focus
</description>
<note>The CMP provides details of the processes, schedules and associated toolset for performing Configuration Management including resources and skills.  Activities required to develop the CMP are beyond the scope of this activity model. Further information on configuration management can be found in ISO 10007. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="issue_requiring_change_action" inscope="yes">
  <name>issue requiring change action</name>
  <description>issue that, following assessment, is deemed to be worthy of subsequent change action
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="rejected_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>rejected issue</name>
  <description>recorded issue that has been rejected following assessment, possibly including the reasons for rejection
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="rejected_request_for_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>rejected request for change</name>
  <description>request for change that has not been accepted
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_impact_report_relating_to_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for impact report relating to issue</name>
  <description>request for assessment of the potential impact of an issue which may lead to a valid need for change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_other_action" inscope="yes">
  <name>request for other action</name>
  <description>request for action that is not part of a change, arising from a documented problem

</description>
<note>May include request for additional information to support change action, or the deferral of change action to a later date </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="variance" inscope="yes">
  <name>variance</name>
  <description>departure from the design intent as specified by the APSI
</description>
<note>Design intent may apply to the support system and to the manufacturing system as well as to the product itself.  Acceptance of a variance does not change the product version.  Different organizations use different words to describe departures from the design intent. A variant may include departures described by terms such as:   <ul>
  <li>waiver; </li>
  <li>concession; </li>
  <li>non-conformance; </li>
  <li>production permit; </li>
  <li>acceptable fault; </li>
  <li>acceptable limitation. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="impact_report_on_an_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>impact report on an issue</name>
  <description>report on the potential impact of an issue providing an input to a decision on whether to proceed with
a change
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>issue</name>
  <description>question, concern or proposal related to Configuration Management
</description>
<note>Issues may include:   <ul>
  <li>variances such as waivers, deviations or production permits; </li>
  <li>documentation error reports; </li>
  <li>configuration discrepancy reports. </li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="recorded_issue" inscope="yes">
  <name>recorded issue</name>
  <description>work request or expression of concern that has been documented and identified
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_priority" inscope="yes">
  <name>change priority</name>
  <description>priority which has been assigned in accordance with information management rules or local business rules
to enable adequate subsequent processing
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="documented_problem" inscope="yes">
  <name>documented problem</name>
  <description>change opportunity or identified problem to which a change priority has been assigned
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_to_identify_and_prioritize_change" inscope="yes">
  <name>request to identify &amp; prioritize change</name>
  <description>invitation to allocate a change identity and priority following assessment of a documented problem
</description>
<note>This request may lead a valid need for change, after appropriate analysis. </note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_to_redefine_problem" inscope="yes">
  <name>request to redefine problem</name>
  <description>invitation for action to better define a document problem
</description>
</icom>


</icoms>

</idef0>
