<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: aam.xml,v 1.9 2004/12/04 12:16:02 robbod Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE idef0 SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/aam.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkapdoc_main.js, Eurostep limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!-- 
     IDEF0 activity model for functional_data_and_their_schematic_representation_for_process_plant
      -->
<idef0 application_protocol="functional_data_and_their_schematic_representation_for_process_plant">
  <!-- view point of the IDEF0 model -->
  <viewpoint>
  the management of process plant information throughout the
  life of a process plant.
 </viewpoint>

  <!-- IDEF0 page -->

<page number="0" node="A-0" title="Perform process plant life cycle activities - aggregate">
<activity identifier="perform_process_plant_life_cycle_activities" inscope="yes">
<name>Perform process plant life cycle activities</name>
<description>The completion of all tasks involved in the life cycle of a process plant
from conception through final disposal.</description>
<note number="1"><p>These tasks include:</p>
<ul>
<li>conception;</li>
<li>research;</li>
<li>design;</li>
<li>construction;</li>
<li>operation;</li>
<li>maintenance;</li>
<li>retrofit;</li>
<li>disposal.</li>
</ul>
</note>
<note number="2">Major outputs from the life-cycle activities are
contractual documents, regulatory compliance information, data retained beyond
the life time of the plant, useful products generated by the operation of the
plant, and residual materials remaining in the environment upon completion of
the plant life cycle. These residual materials include waste products generated
while producing the product or products and the disassembled plant.</note>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="1" node="A0" title="Perform process plant life cycle activities - breakdown">

<activity identifier="manage_and_plan_project" inscope="no">
  <name>Manage and plan project</name>
  <description>Managing the project
requires that sufficient resources be provided to execute the project and check
that the execution is done in accordance with the plans and regulations.
Planning the project is the activity that establishes a detailed technical plan
and a financial plan that are consistent with the engineering, construction,
and commissioning activities required to fulfill the project objectives. 
  </description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="design_and_engineer_plant" inscope="yes">
  <name>Design and engineer plant</name>
  <description>The activities required to
develop an appropriations request and generate a construction design
specification for some modification to an existing process plant or the
construction of a new process plant.</description>
<note>The appropriation request is submitted to company management
for approval. Upon approval, the construction design specification is
generated.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="procure_goods_and_services" inscope="no">
  <name>Procure goods and services</name>
  <description>The process whereby
needed plant items, equipment, or services are purchased or 
acquired.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="construct_and_commission_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Construct and commission plant</name>
  <description>The process of
building or retrofitting a physical plant, using plans and building materials.
The layout drawings and material requirements are used to establish the
physical arrangement and to procure the materials required. A plan for erecting
the plant is determined from material schedules, heavy equipment schedules,
labor schedules, and environmental conditions (such as weather). Temporary
erection material (such as scaffolding) is procured as needed. Regulatory
requirements and client requirements are used to plan and erect the plant, and
for the final testing and certification for operation. The result is a
completed plant that meets the testing procedures defined in the project
control and approval documentation.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="manage_operate_and_maintain_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Manage, operate, and maintain plant</name>
  <description>The activities
required to manage, operate, and maintain the plant safely, efficiently, and
according to operating procedures and regulations.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="decommission_and_dispose_of_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Decommission and dispose of plant</name>
  <description>The activities
during which the plant is decommissioned, disassembled, and the site either
prepared for a new plant or returned to a state specified by the regulatory
agencies. Records of the disposal of toxic and hazardous waste together with
the location of any holes and the methodology used to plug them are produced
and stored in accordance with approved procedures and guidelines.</description>
</activity>

</page>

<page number="2" node="A1" title="Manage and plan project">

<activity identifier="control_and_approve_activities" inscope="no">
  <name>Control and approve activities</name>
  <description>Prepare plans,
check conformance to plans, and arrange for any corrective actions.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="provide_resources" inscope="no">
  <name>Provide resources</name>
  <description>Acquire and deploy personnel,
tools, and funding to perform the project activities.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="define_procedures_standards_guidelines_specifications_and_codes" inscope="no">
  <name>Define procedures, standards, guidelines, specifications, and codes</name>
  <description>Specify the engineering policies to be used and determine
appropriate procedures, codes, standards, guidelines, and specifications that
may apply.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="plan_and_analyze_project_finances" inscope="no">
  <name>Plan and analyze project finances</name>
  <description>The activity of
anticipating and estimating the financial resource requirements for a project.
This activity establishes the expected financial performance for the project
and the project financial plan.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="obtain_agreements_with_regulatory_bodies" inscope="no">
  <name>Obtain agreements with regulatory bodies</name>
  <description>The
activity of confirming that the intended design, construction, commissioning,
operation, and decommissioning of the proposed project will comply with
requirements of the regulatory body. This confirmation is recorded by formal
documentation such as written agreements and safety compliance reports.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_plant_design_basis" inscope="no">
  <name>Establish plant design basis</name>
  <description>The activity of
collecting a complete and consistent set of constraints, requirements, and
guidelines for subsequent engineering activities.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="3" node="A2" title="Design and engineer plant">

<activity identifier="produce_conceptual_process_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>Produce conceptual process design</name>
  <description>The activity of
defining the basic parameters of a plant flow scheme.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_conceptual_plant_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>Produce conceptual plant design</name>
  <description>The activity of
extending the conceptual process design into a preliminary plant spatial
configuration.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_final_process_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>Produce final process design</name>
  <description>integration of
conceptual process and plant designs to fully define parameters of a plant flow
scheme.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_final_plant_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>Produce final plant design</name>
  <description>The activities required
to generate a construction design specification from the process plant
requirements.</description>
<note>The activities include designing the mechanical, electrical,
and civil engineering systems of the process, designing the detailed
instrumentation systems, producing piping and instrumentation diagrams and
detailed equipment layout through isometric drawings or three-dimensional
computer-aided design (CAD) models.</note>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="4" node="A3" title="Procure goods and services">

<activity identifier="maintain_suppliers_list" inscope="no">
  <name>Maintain suppliers list</name>
  <description>The process whereby a
list of accepted or approved suppliers is kept up to date.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="prepare_bid_packages_and_solicit_bids" inscope="no">
  <name>Prepare bid packages and solicit bids</name>
  <description>The process
whereby the technical and commercial requirements for a plant item are compiled
and sent out for pricing by multiple suppliers.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="evaluate_bids_and_negotiate_purchase" inscope="no">
  <name>Evaluate bids and negotiate purchase</name>
  <description>The process
whereby bid packages are evaluated, a supplier is selected, and an agreement is
entered into for the acquisition of the plant item or items.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="receive_inspect_and_disposition_components" inscope="no">
  <name>Receive, inspect, and disposition components</name>
  <description>The
process of receiving equipment and materials from various suppliers at the
process plant, inspecting the equipment and material for compliance to the
purchase specification, and either placing the equipment or material in stock,
delivering it to construction or maintenance, or returning it to the supplier.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="deploy_component_or_service" inscope="no">
  <name>Deploy component or service</name>
  <description>The process whereby
the part or service is delivered and the
acquisition agreement is fulfilled.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="5" node="A4" title="Construct and commission plant">

<activity identifier="produce_construction_plans" inscope="no">
  <name>Produce construction plans</name>
  <description>Using site drawings,
layout drawings, and other documents, determine the desired sequence for
building the plant that will meet contract budget and schedule. Determine those
services that will be needed from sub-contractors for the site preparation,
erection, and testing of the plant. Develop detailed erection drawings and
schedules for each section of the plant and for temporary structures.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="obtain_construction_services" inscope="no">
  <name>Obtain construction services</name>
  <description>Use the construction
plan as a requirements list for outside services needed and their schedule.
Negotiate contracts and agreements with sub-contractors, equipment suppliers,
and labour unions as needed for the erection of the plant. Adjust the schedule
of the construction plan to allow for the availability of sub-contractors,
equipment and labour.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="erect_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Erect plant</name>
  <description>Utilizing plans, materials, services
and labor, build a physical plant that conforms 
to the detailed design.</description>
<note>This process begins with the site preparation; grading and
primary foundations poured, and temporary roads and rails created. Utility
services are provided and temporary warehouses are built. Major equipment is
moved, often in pieces, and installed on foundations with supporting steel.
Site permanent buildings are built, as are pipe racks and other permanent
steel. Pipe runs and pipe spools are put in place with valves and miscellaneous
equipment and welded or joined. Other items such as ducting, electrical,
instrumentation are installed.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_as-built_surveys" inscope="no">
  <name>Produce as-built surveys</name>
  <description>The completed plant is
given a physical inspection to determine whether the plant conforms to the
detailed design. The detail design drawings and other documents are updated to
reflect the changes to the plant discovered during
the inspection.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="pre-commission_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Pre-commission plant</name>
  <description>Resolve any differences
between the detailed design and the as-built plant, perform all testing
required by regulatory agencies and the client, resolve any problems that were
discovered during testing, and obtain regulatory permission to start-up the
plant for functional testing.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="commission_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Commission plant</name>
  <description>Test the functionality of the
completed plant prior to operation, develop final operating and maintenance
procedures, and obtain final regulatory approval
to operate the plant.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="6" node="A5" title="Manage, operate, and maintain plant">

<activity identifier="manage_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Manage plant</name>
  <description>Direct and administrate the
operations, maintenance, and disposal of the plant.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="operate_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Operate plant</name>
  <description>Conduct and monitor the activities
required to operate the plant.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="maintain_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Maintain plant</name>
  <description>Conduct and monitor the activities
required to maintain the plant.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="7" node="A6" title="Decommission and dispose of plant">

<activity identifier="decommission_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Decommission plant</name>
  <description>Plan and complete the
activities required to decommission the plant.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="dispose_of_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Dispose of plant</name>
  <description>Plan and complete the activities
required to dispose of the plant.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="8" node="A21" title="Produce conceptual process design">

<activity identifier="identify_and_define_unit_operations" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify and define unit operations</name>
  <description>Incorporate
the design basis and owner requirements to define and document the basis for
conceptual process design and estimated time and cost expenditures. If the
design activity is related to an existing plant, then existing operations are
incorporated into the conceptual process design</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="calculate_heat_and_mass_balances" inscope="no">
  <name>Calculate heat and mass balance</name>
  <description>Calculations
performed based on design basis, unit operations, fuel or materials in the
process, along with associated chemical properties to optimize plant and
operational cost.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_and_size_equipment" inscope="yes">
  <name>Identify and size equipment</name>
  <description>Identify equipment
requirements based on the design basis and unit operations. Sizing of the
equipment is based on the heat and mass balance calculations and unit
operations.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="establish_initial_process_control_logic" inscope="no">
  <name>Establish initial process control logic</name>
  <description>Document
philosophical and operational requirements between instrumentation, equipment
and process.</description>
<note>This activity results in the development of the design basis
documents (see 
<clause_ref linkend="aam:activity:design_basis">Design basis</clause_ref>).
</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="identify_and_analyze_safety_requirements_and_hazards" inscope="no">
  <name>Identify and analyze safety requirements and hazards</name>
  <description>Review design basis, unit operations, heat and mass balances,
materials, identified equipment, control logic and process flow diagrams
against federal, state and local regulations, codes and standards to determine
compliance and produce an analysis of results.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_process_flow_diagrams" inscope="yes">
  <name>Produce process flow diagrams</name>
  <description>Production of a
schematic showing basic process flow developed from the cumulative results of
unit operations, equipment sizing, initial logic and safety requirements along
with related chemical properties.</description>
<note>If a design activity is related to a modification or
addition to an existing plant, then the existing plant information is reflected
in the developed process flow diagram.</note>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="9" node="A22" title="Produce conceptual plant design">

<activity identifier="identify_plant_performance_requirements_and_establish_design_strategy" inscope="no">
  <name>Identify plant performance requirements and establish design strategy</name>
  <description>Define a quantitative description of the quantity and
quality of a product to be produced by the plant in a yearly time period and
describe the major steps required to complete enough design to obtain a budget
estimate for business calculations as well as to begin the identification of
process unknowns.</description>
<note number="1">Performance requirements are usually stated as units of
product per unit time.</note>
<note number="2">Additional qualifications are typically made regarding
the quality of the plant. Examples include time between major shutdowns for
continuous processes, percent uptime required, and expected yield.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="engineer_and_design_plant_systems" inscope="yes">
  <name>Engineer and design plant systems</name>
  <description>At the
conceptual level, this is a preliminary scoping of all major modifications or
additions to major plant distribution systems such as steam, compressed air,
electrical power, refrigeration, water, firewater, and sewers (storm, process,
sanitary). Impact on distribution pipe lines and feeder systems quantity and
size are also included. A consideration of system operation in terms of
reliability, uptime, planned maintenance, and winter and summer operations are
vital to proper planning.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="engineer_and_design_equipment" inscope="yes">
  <name>Engineer and design equipment</name>
  <description>Preliminary sizing
of all major pieces of required equipment is made at this time with enough
detail to obtain budget quotes.</description>
<note>This includes equipment such as refrigeration machines,
purchase power substations, secondary substations, switch gear, compressors,
and boilers, as well as the major process equipment specific to the plant.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="layout_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Layout plant</name>
  <description>A general arrangement of the plant
in plan view, showing all the major components of the distribution systems
affected by the plant and the location of the plant. A general arrangement of
all major equipment within the battery limits of the plant is also included.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_conceptual_safety_engineering_designs" inscope="yes">
  <name>Produce conceptual safety engineering designs</name>
  <description>Create designs that specifically address how the major hazards associated with
the new plant are to be dealt with to ensure the safety of all personnel
working in the plant as well as the general site and surrounding neighbourhood
population.</description>
<note>These hazards will have been identified during the
preliminary screening reviews to identify chemical, fire and health hazards
associated with the specific chemical or mechanical characteristics of the
process.</note>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="10" node="A23" title="Produce final process design">

<activity identifier="define_plant_operating_philosophy" inscope="no">
  <name>Define plant operating philosophy</name>
  <description>Ascertain and
confirm those plant operating characteristics and activities necessary to
achieve the plant owner's operational goals such as methods of production,
technology, plant safety, or plant availability. This activity includes
selecting types and sequences of unit operations and processing steps so that
the plant production objectives can be achieved and specifying alternate or
abnormal operating conditions, and procedures such as 
startup and shutdown.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="specify_piping_and_instrumentation" inscope="yes">
  <name>Specify piping and instrumentation</name>
  <description>Define piping
and instrumentation required by the process plant based on the functional
requirements for the plant.</description>
<note>Piping and instrumentation functional requirements are
developed based on plant production capacities, process type or technology,
control methodology, chemical content of process streams, and equipment layout.
Also considered are alternative operating conditions, maintenance requirements,
and plant operating and personal safety are issues. The results of this
activity are detailed on P&amp;IDs, line lists, equipment lists, and instrument
lists.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="specify_equipment_functional_characteristics" inscope="yes">
  <name>Specify equipment functional characteristics</name>
  <description>Define the functional characteristics of each major item of equipment based on
confirmed plant operating requirements, process technologies, and process
optimization.</description>
<example>Functional characteristics include equipment type,
process stream inputs, outputs, capacities, and conditions, equipment
metallurgy, piping and instrumentation, power requirements, and auxiliary
systems.</example>
</activity>

<activity identifier="specify_control_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Specify control requirements</name>
  <description>Define
instrumentation and control system characteristics required to fulfill
requirements for plant operation using the operating procedures and safety
requirements.</description>
<note>Control systems are used to help maintain plant safety,
ensure product quality, and to safeguard equipment. These systems are used to
control areas such as process reactions, flows, temperatures, pressures, and
levels. They operate automatically, or provide indications to plant personnel.
Control requirements are generally defined in the operating procedures and
specified on the P&amp;ID and in the instrument list.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="specify_safety_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Specify safety requirements</name>
  <description>Perform a formal
plant process design, operation, and control review to assess the whether all
safety requirements are met.</description>
<note>Plant safety requirements involve issues such as source
terms for spill scenarios, vapour dispersion for combustible and toxic
releases, reliability of metallurgy and other materials, component failure
rates, operator response and error, fail-safe instrumentation, equipment
spacing, number and size of equipment trains, radiation from fires, relief
system design philosophies, deflagration test results, thermal runaways and
associated vent sizing, detonations and resulting shock waves.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="optimize_for_environment" inscope="no">
  <name>Optimize for environment</name>
  <description>Evaluate the plant
design against the applicable environmental regulations (Federal, State, and
local) and modify the design where required.</description>
<note>These regulations influence many of the activities in plant
and process design such as operating procedures, plant and process control
strategies, specification and design of piping, instrumentation, and equipment,
as well as site selection. Broad regulatory interpretations often mean that
conservative measures are incorporated in plant design.</note>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="11" node="A24" title="Produce final plant design">

<activity identifier="finalize_system_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>Finalize system design</name>
  <description>Develop the system design,
expressed by flow and control information and equipment performance data, to
its final state.</description>
<note>The resulting design serves as a basis for detailed plant
design.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_layout_arrangement_and_spatial_design" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize layout, arrangement, and spatial design</name>
  <description>Develop the spatial design of the plant to its final approved-for-construction
state utilizing the finalized system design as the primary input.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="specify_building_and_plant_services" inscope="yes">
  <name>Specify building and plant services</name>
  <description>Establish
utility and other service needs for the building(s) and plant(s) based on owner
requirements, final system design, and final spatial design.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="confirm_safety_and_regulatory_compliance" inscope="no">
  <name>Confirm safety and regulatory compliance</name>
  <description>Establish
that the final design of the plant meets specified safety and regulatory
criteria.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="analyze_final_plant_design" inscope="no">
  <name>Analyze final plant design</name>
  <description>Examine all aspects of
final design for compliance to performance criteria and generate any necessary
changes required to meet these criteria.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="12" node="A242" title="Finalize spatial layout design">

<activity identifier="finalize_plot_plan" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize plot plan</name>
  <description>Develop the arrangement design of
main equipment, buildings and structures of the 
plant, to its final state.</description>
<note>The plot plan is usually expressed by plan view only.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_layout" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize layout</name>
  <description>Develop the detail arrangement design
of equipment, buildings and structures of the plant, 
to its final state.</description>
<note>The layout is usually expressed by both plan view and
elevation view.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_structure" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize structure</name>
  <description>Develop the structure design of
the plant to its final state.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_hvac" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize HVAC</name>
  <description>Develop the HVAC design of the plant to
its final state.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_electrical_instrumentation_and_control" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize electrical, instrumentation and control</name>
  <description>Develop the design of electrical, instrumentation and control of the plant, to
its final state.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_piping_details" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize piping details</name>
  <description>Develop the special and
prefabrication design of piping of the plant, to its final state.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="13" node="A2426" title="Finalize piping details">

<activity identifier="finalize_piping_routes" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize piping routes</name>
  <description>Develop the piping route design
of the plant to its final state.</description>
<note>The piping route is usually expressed by plan view only.</note>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_3d_piping_details" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize 3D piping details</name>
  <description>Develop the 3D piping
detail design of the plant to its final state.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="finalize_piping_prefabrication" inscope="no">
  <name>Finalize piping prefabrication</name>
  <description>Develop piping
prefabrication design of the plant to its final state.</description>
<note>The resulting design serves as the essential data for
procurement and fabrication of piping prefabrication.</note>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="14" node="A24262" title="Finalize 3D piping details">
</page>

<page number="15" node="A42" title="Obtain construction services">
</page>

<page number="16" node="A423" title="Obtain piping systems">

<activity identifier="fabricate_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Fabricate prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Receive order and input
raw materials and produce inspected spool pieces for installation
in a plant.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="17" node="A4233" title="Shop fabricate piping">

<activity identifier="prepare_prefabrication_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Prepare prefabrication piping</name>
  <description>Prepare all piping
materials and documents that are necessary for piping prefabrication.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="prefabricate_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Prefabricate piping</name>
  <description>Utilizing piping materials and
documents, manufacture spool pieces.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="inspect_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspect prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Examine and analyze
prefabricated piping for manufacturing defects in accordance with inspection
procedure.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="ship_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Ship prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Finish, pack and load spool
pieces, to ship to a plant site. Usually shipping units are specified by
purchaser day by day, or week by week, so as to correspond to site installation
work schedule.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="18" node="A42331" title="Prepare shop fabrication piping">

<activity identifier="make_production_schedule" inscope="no">
  <name>Make production schedule</name>
  <description>Develop a time-based list of
production tasks.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="procure_piping_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Procure piping materials</name>
  <description>Purchase or acquire necessary
piping materials that are used for prefabricating piping assemblies.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="receive_piping_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Receive piping materials</name>
  <description>Process the receipt of the
necessary materials, by the piping prefabricator, that are used for
prefabrication of piping assemblies.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="19" node="A42332" title="Shop fabricate piping">

<activity identifier="cut_pipe" inscope="no">
  <name>Cut pipe</name>
  <description>Execute an operation or series of operations
to divide a straight pipe into pieces in accordance with the lengths specified
in piping prefabrication documents.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="prepare_end" inscope="no">
  <name>Prepare end</name>
  <description>Execute an operation or series of
operations to make the ends of a pipe suitable for connection.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_primary_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Produce primary spool piece</name>
  <description>Assemble the main part of
a spool piece connecting pipes and other piping materials. This process forms
simple connection such as welding straight pipes to flanges.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="produce_final_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Produce final spool piece</name>
  <description>Assemble a spool piece to
its final form, connecting a primary spool piece, pipes and other piping
materials.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="20" node="A42333" title="Inspect shop fabricated piping">

<activity identifier="inspect_welding" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspect welding</name>
  <description>Examine and analyze welded part of
prefabricated spool pieces for manufacturing defects in accordance with the
inspection procedure. Welding is generally the most important inspection item
for prefabricated piping.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="inspect_dimension" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspect dimension</name>
  <description>Examine and analyze the dimensions of
prefabricated spool pieces for manufacturing defects in accordance with the
inspection procedure.</description>
</activity>
</page>

<page number="21" node="A42334" title="Complete and ship shop fabricated piping">

<activity identifier="clean_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Clean prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Process prefabricated spool
pieces to remove weld sputter, rust and other debris from their surfaces, to be
ready for painting and for shipping.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="paint_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Paint prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Apply coatings of paint to
the necessary parts of prefabricated spool pieces to protect them from rusting.
</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="protect_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Protect prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Protect and pack
prefabricated spool pieces to be ready for shipping.</description>
<example>Protection of bevelled ends or flange faces using plastic
caps, wood plates or adhesive tape is made to avoid damage during
transportation and handling.</example>
</activity>

<activity identifier="tag_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Tag prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Attach an identifying label
to each prefabricated spool piece to distinguish it.</description>
</activity>

<activity identifier="load_prefabricated_piping" inscope="no">
  <name>Load prefabricated piping</name>
  <description>Place spool pieces on the
transport for shipping to a plant.</description>
</activity>
</page>

  <!-- IDEF0 Arrow definitions (inputs controls outputs mechanism) -->
  <icoms>

<icom identifier="assembly_jigs_and_tools" inscope="no">
  <name>Assembly jigs and tools</name>
  <description>Miscellaneous fixtures, guides and
tools that are used for assembling prefabricated piping, which make
prefabrication works easy and accurate.
  </description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="as-built_documents" inscope="yes">
  <name>As-built documents</name>
  <description>Site plans, detailed equipment
descriptions, electrical instrumentation diagrams, and P&amp;IDs that record
the actual condition of a plant at a specific point in time.</description>
<note>These documents aid in meeting government documentation and
safety requirements. Frequently, they are simply corrections or modifications
to existing design documents delivered to construction.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="authorization_plan" inscope="no">
  <name>Authorization plan</name>
  <description>High level plan, justification, and
forecast for design and construction of a plant. The authorization plan
describes how funds, people, and resources are to be allocated for the plant
project.</description>
<note>It is a document used internally and is sometimes called a
white paper.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="automation_tools" inscope="no">
  <name>Automation tools</name>
  <description>The collection of software and hardware
tools used to assist the activities involved in the life cycle of a process
plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="basic_laws" inscope="no">
  <name>Basic laws</name>
  <description>Those elements of natural and human laws affecting
any activity in the life cycle of a process plant.
  </description>
  <example>These laws include operating rules and guidelines as
established by U.S. federal regulatory agencies such as the Occupational Safety
and Health Administration (OSHA), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA),
and the Food and Drug Administration (FDA).
  </example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="bending_machine" inscope="no">
  <name>Bending machine</name>
  <description>Machines that form curves in straight pipes.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="bent_pipe" inscope="no">
  <name>Bent pipe</name>
  <description>Pipes that are curved in accordance with the radii
specified in piping prefabrication documents.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="bids" inscope="no">
  <name>Bids</name>
  <description>Commercial proposal by supplier for provision of
equipment, supplies, or services.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="capital_appropriation" inscope="no">
  <name>Capital appropriation</name>
  <description>Authorization of funding for capital
project or expenditure.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_request" inscope="no">
  <name>Change request</name>
  <description>A request made by an user of data to revise
the original or current version of something due to errors, omissions, or other
reasons, such as new requirements.</description>
<note number="1">A request is followed by review, analysis, and approval.
Change requests are tracked in terms of cost and schedule (a kind of
mini-project within project).</note>
<note number="2">Change requests may be made against a supplier list,
process, plant, procedure, and design basis.</note>
<note number="3">Change request originators include construction and
operations.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_request_design" inscope="no">
  <name>Change request (design)</name>
  <description>A request made by an user of data to
revise the original or current version of the design of something due to
errors, omissions, or other reasons.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_request_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Change request (plant)</name>
  <description>A request made by an user of data to
revise the original or current version of the design of the plant due to
errors, omissions, or other reasons.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_request_procedure" inscope="no">
  <name>Change request (procedure)</name>
  <description>A request made by an user of data
to revise the original or current version of a procedure due to errors,
omissions, or other reasons.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="change_request_supplier_list" inscope="no">
  <name>Change request (supplier list)</name>
  <description>A request made by an user of
data to revise the original or current version of the supplier's list due to
errors, omissions, or other reasons.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="chemical_properties" inscope="yes">
  <name>Chemical properties</name>
  <description>Chemical data needed by the process
engineer during design.</description>
<note><p>This data includes, but is not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>boiling point;</li>
<li>critical pressure;</li>
<li>critical temperature;</li>
<li>density;</li>
<li>enthalpy;</li>
<li>entropy;</li>
<li>flash point;</li>
<li>heat of vapourization;</li>
<li>melting point;</li>
<li>molecular weight;</li>
<li>specific heat;</li>
<li>thermal conductivity;</li>
<li>viscosity</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="cleaned_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Cleaned spool piece</name>
  <description>Prefabricated spool pieces that have been
processed to remove weld sputter, rust and other debris from 
their surfaces.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="codes" inscope="no">
  <name>Codes</name>
  <description>Widely recognized, accepted, and sometimes legally
mandated rules that apply during the life-cycle of the plant. These rules
govern life-cycle activities such as design, fabrication, and operation, and
characteristics such as safety. Codes are consensus documents and
specifications and are sometimes a subset of regulatory 
requirements.</description>
<example>The ANSI 31.x series of codes.</example>
<note>The design basis data specified will guide the code
application, i.e., how the code is applied. (ANSI 31.3 allows overpressurizing
for short periods of times to accommodate specific design basis scenarios.)
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioned_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Commissioned plant</name>
  <description>A plant that has been proven to be
operational through commissioning procedures.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="commissioning_procedures" inscope="no">
  <name>Commissioning procedures</name>
  <description>Step-by-step explanation of
start-up actions required to commission the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="company_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Company requirements</name>
  <description>Those managerial decisions that place
constraints on the operations of the company, that give direction or emphasis
on areas for development, or that dictate decisions outside the local decision
making paths. The embodiment of policies and regulations that govern the
operations of a company.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="construction_design_specification" inscope="no">
  <name>Construction design specification</name>
  <description>A contractual document
that gives the criteria and standards to be used in the construction of the
plant.</description>
<example>The specification contents include detailed construction
drawings, plant layout, equipment lists, isometric models, piping and
instrumentation diagrams, specifications for the construction phase of the
project, and pre-commissioning, acceptance and approval, and testing
procedures.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="construction_documentation" inscope="no">
  <name>Construction documentation</name>
  <description>All information related to the
construction of the process plant.</description>
<example>Documentation includes as-built reports, equipment
certification, nameplate information of installed equipment, operating manuals,
testing procedures, field changes, and photographs of as-built units, modules,
and plant.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="construction_plan" inscope="no">
  <name>Construction plan</name>
  <description>A description of the method(s) to be used
for building or fabricating a plant or plant item.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="construction_services" inscope="no">
  <name>Construction services</name>
  <description>Constructor activities and abilities
to be used to construct the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="control_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Control requirements</name>
  <description>Requirements and criteria specified in
operating procedures and safety requirements imposed on the mechanisms and
systems that monitor and control plant operation.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="corporate_standards" inscope="no">
  <name>Corporate standards</name>
  <description>Procedures, instructions, or
specifications that may be used in the execution of a plant project and are
standardized within an organization. Corporate standards are not project
specific, but may be used (and possibly customized) by a variety of projects.
Corporate standards are developed over a long period of time as standard,
recommended, or best practice.</description>
<example>Kinds of standards include safety, design, and
maintenance.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="cutting_machine" inscope="no">
  <name>Cutting machine</name>
  <description>Cutting machine of straight pipes. NC band
saw machine is used for piping CAM system.</description>
</icom>


<icom identifier="delivery_dates" inscope="no">
  <name>Delivery dates</name>
  <description>Scheduled date for delivery of procured items
to meet or support construction.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="design_basis" inscope="no">
  <name>Design basis</name>
  <description>A document provided by
the plant owner or developed by the architecture, engineering, and construction
(AEC) contractors that establishes or defines the information and data that
Plant engineering is to be based upon. It consists of guidelines and
requirements, corporate standards, codes, references to regulatory agreements,
form of deliverables, and plant or production capacity.</description>
<example><p>The design basis includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>design safety philosophy;</li>
<li>environmental requirements;</li>
<li>plant inputs (e.g., fuel, feedstock);</li>
<li>plant license and permit requirements;</li>
<li>plant operating requirements;</li>
<li>plant process requirements;</li>
<li>plant product or output (type and capacity);</li>
<li>site parameters (geographical, meteorological, soils, hydrological);</li>
<li>type of plant.</li>
</ul>
<p>It also addresses performance objectives for the plant such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>capacity;</li>
<li>engineering quality;</li>
<li>environmental;</li>
<li>investment and project economics;</li>
<li>safety and health;</li>
<li>schedule;</li>
<li>product and plant quality;</li>
<li>product and raw material storage;</li>
<li>project execution;</li>
<li>technology.</li>
</ul>
</example>
<note number="1">Performance objectives usually take the form of a written
document owned and maintained by the project team (consisting of members from
the business, engineering, construction, and plant site).</note>
<note number="2">The definition for design basis is from an owner's
perspective.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="design_strategy" inscope="no">
  <name>Design strategy</name>
  <description>A description of major steps required to
complete enough design to obtain a budget estimate for business calculations as
well as to begin the identification of process unknowns that may or may not
require piloting. It encompasses building technology, mechanical technology,
utility technology, automation technology, schedules, scope, standards and
regulations, process definition, control philosophies, costs, benefits and
timings, and project approach (e.g., architectural engineering, construction
management, internal).</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="disassembled_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Disassembled plant</name>
  <description>All equipment items remaining after the
disposal of a process plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="disposal_documentation" inscope="no">
  <name>Disposal documentation</name>
  <description>All information related to the
disposal of the process plant including acceptance and approval procedures used
in disposing all hazardous materials, residues, insulation, wiring, piping,
vessels, rotating equipment, site cleanup and restoration reports, and
photographs.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="electrical_instrumentation_and_control_design_final" inscope="yes">
  <name>Electrical, instrumentation and control design (final)</name>
  <description>The
design of electrical, instrumentation and control of the plant, to its final
state.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="electrical_instrumentation_and_control_documents" inscope="yes">
  <name>Electrical, instrumentation and control documents</name>
  <description>All
documents, information and drawings that are the result of the design activity
for the electrical system and the instrumentation and control system within a
plant. These documents provide a record of the electrical system and
instrumentation and control system design.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="end_preparation_machine" inscope="no">
  <name>End preparation machine</name>
  <description>Machines to prepare ends of pipes
suitable for connection.</description>
<example>Beveling and finishing are two types of end preparations.
</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="end_prepared_pipe" inscope="no">
  <name>End prepared pipe</name>
  <description>Pipes with ends that are prepared for
connection, such as bevel end, screwed end or straight end.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="energy" inscope="no">
  <name>Energy</name>
  <description>All utilities required in the production of useful
products through the operation of a process plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="engineering_design_construction_and_operation_changes" inscope="yes">
  <name>Engineering design, construction and operation changes</name>
  <description>Changes to the design of the plant arising from errors, omissions, new
requirements, or other reasons during plant design, construction, or operation.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_skeleton" inscope="no">
  <name>Equipment skeleton</name>
  <description>Skeleton design of equipment outline to be
utilized for the design of layout and piping details.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="environmental_impact_assessment" inscope="no">
  <name>Environmental impact assessment</name>
  <description>Evaluation of project's or
plant's affect on the environment.</description>
<note>A report is usually required by an environmental regulatory
agency before construction can begin.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_characteristics_functional" inscope="yes">
  <name>Equipment characteristics (functional)</name>
  <description>Describe or specify
the functional requirements for the equipment: what it is supposed to do. They
are items of information that describe: the service provided to the process by
the equipment.</description>
<example>For a pump, such information might include a descriptive
name or title, such as 1502-B Condensate Return Pump B.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_characteristics_performance" inscope="yes">
  <name>Equipment characteristics (performance)</name>
  <description>Describe or specify
the performance requirements for the equipment: how much it is supposed to do
it. They are items of information that describe the effect that equipment has
on the process or other operational information.</description>
<example>For a pump, such information might include flow rate,
total developed head, and efficiency.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_characteristics_process" inscope="yes">
  <name>Equipment characteristics (process)</name>
  <description>A subset of equipment
functional data that describe the contribution to the process desired from
equipment. Such data is specified prior to the actual selection of specific
equipment to fulfill the purpose.</description>
<example>For a pump, such information might include flow rate,
total developed head, and efficiency.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_characteristics_required" inscope="yes">
  <name>Equipment characteristics (required)</name>
  <description>Needed functional,
performance, physical, or process attributes of an item that have a name and
measurable value.</description>
<example>For a pump, such information might include flow rate,
total developed head, and efficiency.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_id" inscope="yes">
  <name>Equipment id</name>
  <description>An identifier assigned to a piece of equipment.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="equipment_list" inscope="yes">
  <name>Equipment list</name>
  <description>A list of equipment in the process plant.</description>
<example><p>An equipment list includes, but not limited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>contract numbers (e.g., purchase, install);</li>
<li>drawing references (e.g., P&amp;IDs, plant arrangements);</li>
<li>electrical load and type;</li>
<li>identifier (e.g., tag);</li>
<li>location (e.g., building, elevation, area, column row);</li>
<li>name;</li>
<li>service requirements (e.g., air, water, structural base, electrical power,
control circuitry);</li>
<li>spare requirements.</li>
</ul>
</example>
<note>The equipment list may not include all equipment. It does
not include miscellaneous equipment and devices (e.g., y-pattern strainers,
inline flow meters, instruments) or valves.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="guidelines_and_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Guidelines and requirements</name>
  <description>Specifications, instructions, and
mandates specified by management that shall be followed in the plant project.
These guidelines and requirements may be project specific. Guidelines are more
generally applicable than requirements, which tend to be specific in terms of
what must be done.</description>
<note><p>Originators and users of guidelines and requirements are:</p>
<ul>
<li>architectural and engineering;</li>
<li>construction management;</li>
<li>constructor;</li>
<li>contractor (basic practices);</li>
<li>engineering and construction;</li>
<li>engineering, procurement, and construction;</li>
<li>owner.</li>
</ul>
<p>These categories are not mutually exclusive.</p></note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="heat_and_mass_calculations" inscope="no">
  <name>Heat and mass calculations</name>
  <description>Calculations performed based on
design basis, unit operations, fuel or materials in the process, along with
associated chemical properties to optimize plant and operational cost.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="HVAC_design_documents" inscope="yes">
  <name>HVAC design documents</name>
  <description>All documents, information and drawings
that are the result of the design activity for the HVAC system within a plant.
These documents provide a record of the HVAC system design.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="information_databases" inscope="yes">
  <name>Information databases</name>
  <description>Those elements of information
collections comprising literature references, physical and transport
properties, symbology sets, equipment specifications, and equipment costs that
assist in the conception, design, construction, operation, and disposal of a
process plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="initial_information" inscope="no">
  <name>Initial information</name>
  <description>Any knowledge available at the start of
the process to build or modify a process plant.</description>
<example>This includes information about the site, regulatory
agreements, owner requirements, and approved suppliers.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="innovation" inscope="no">
  <name>Innovation</name>
  <description>New ideas and concepts generated internally or
through the public domain to solve problems or to enhance 
the quality of work.</description>
<note>Some ideas and concepts may become goods, services, and
systems that there is a societal requirement for. To some degree, innovation is
fundamental to all activities involved with the process, however, particular
emphasis is placed on activities that require generation of new ideas and
concepts from abstract entities as inputs.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspected_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspected spool piece</name>
  <description>Assembled spool pieces after they
successfully have completed the inspection process.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspection_plan" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspection plan</name>
  <description>The description of anticipated activities
necessary for surveillance of suppliers, fabricators, and assemblers to verify
compliance to contractual specifications, codes, and good practice.</description>
<note>The plan usually lists the items to be inspected, the place
where the inspections are expected to occur, anticipated frequency of
inspection and type of activity to be undertaken at each inspection. The
reporting procedure for the surveillance results is usually included in the
developed inspection plan.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspection_procedure" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspection procedure</name>
  <description>The process steps, measurement items,
allowances and other inpection tools and materials used to execute the
inspection process.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspection_report" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspection report</name>
  <description>Documentation of the results of inspection.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspection_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspection requirements</name>
  <description>All requirements, regulations and
codes that are applied at inspection.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspection_requirements_decommissioning" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspection requirements (decommissioning)</name>
  <description>Requirements
imposed by a regulatory agency related to the inspection of the plant during
the decommissioning process.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="inspection_results" inscope="no">
  <name>Inspection results</name>
  <description>Reports that result from inspection and
supplier surveillance activities.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="licensed_technologies" inscope="no">
  <name>Licensed technologies</name>
  <description>Patented or proprietary processes or
design information purchased or licensed from an outside source, such as a
process processor, supplier, or fabricator.</description>
<note>This technology may range from laboratory synthesis data
through unit operation process data to complete, detailed plant designs or
equipment items and modules.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="line_schedule_and_list" inscope="yes">
  <name>Line schedule and list</name>
  <description>A subset of information presented on
the P&amp;ID, and possibly the heat and mass balance, that describes the
characteristics of pipelines required for a given process.</description>
<note>This information is used by the piping designer during the
detail design. It is analogous to the equipment list.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="manual_and_machine_processing_condition" inscope="no">
  <name>Manual and machine processing condition</name>
  <description>Manual or automatic
machining parameter settings to process piping materials.</description>
<example>Some processing conditions for a welding machine are
volt, ampere, seal gas flow rate, or welding speed . Some processing conditions
for an automatic cutting machine are end to end cut length, cutting speed, and
end dimensions.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="management_authorizations_and_controls" inscope="no">
  <name>Management authorizations and controls</name>
  <description>Management
authorization, imperatives, directives, and procedures for initiating and
executing plant management activities.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="operating_philosophy" inscope="no">
  <name>Operating philosophy</name>
  <description>The plant owner's operational goals.</description>
<example>Operational goals include methods of production,
technology, plant safety, and plant availability.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="operating_procedures" inscope="no">
  <name>Operating procedures</name>
  <description>Documentation that covers many
different phases and aspects of plant operation that is necessary to run the
plant safely.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="other_piping_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Other piping materials</name>
  <description>Miscellaneous materials, except
straight pipes, that are used for fabricating piping assemblies, and become
parts of fabricated piping assemblies.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="owner_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Owner requirements</name>
  <description>An initial statement of plant
requirements provided by the owner.</description>
<note>Owner requirements are an aggregation of items such as
design requirements and client general specifications. The owner requirements
may be provided at any level of abstraction from very general to very specific.
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="packing materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Packing materials</name>
  <description>Materials necessary for protecting
prefabricated spool pieces during shipping.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="painted_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Painted spool piece</name>
  <description>Spool pieces with the necessary parts
coated with paint to protect from rusting.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="personnel" inscope="no">
  <name>Personnel</name>
  <description>The individuals responsible for performing the
life-cycle activities of the process plant.</description>
<example>These individuals include discipline experts, skilled
workers, and labourers.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_3D_model" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping 3D model</name>
  <description>A 3-dimensional computer model of the
spatial configuration of the piping in the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_and_instrumentation_diagram" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping and instrumentation diagram (P&amp;ID)</name>
  <description>A schematic
diagram that shows engineering details of the equipment, instruments, pipes,
valves, and their connectivity and sequence.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_and_instrumentation_diagram_AFD" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping and instrumentation diagram (AFD)</name>
  <description>The process
definition is firm. Instrumentation needs to be added.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_and_instrumentation_diagram_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping and instrumentation diagram (design)</name>
  <description>Instrumentation
details are included. All lines and valves have been sized. All valving, vents
and drains are included. Instrumentation and loops are indicated, but final
instrumentation may not have been selected.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_and_instrumentation_diagram_final" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping and instrumentation diagram (final)</name>
  <description>The complete
P&amp;ID has been approved for release by engineering for construction and has
been stamped by a registered professional engineer. It is a last version of the
design P&amp;ID. It contains all changes that were incorporated during the
physical design of the systems. It reflects the plant as it was, or will be,
constructed.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_and_instrumentation_diagram_preliminary" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping and instrumentation diagram (preliminary)</name>
  <description>Conveys the
flow of the fluids from equipment to equipment in the system. It shows the
valves that are used to control the flow. The major fluid containing lines have
been sized.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_arrangement" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping arrangement</name>
  <description>The 3D spatial configuration of the
piping design in the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_inspection_documents" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping inspection documents</name>
  <description>All documents, information and
drawings that are the result of piping detail design and are used for piping
inspection.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_installation_documents" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping installation documents</name>
  <description>All documents, information and
drawings that are the result of piping detail design and are used for piping
installation.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_material_takeoff" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping material takeoff</name>
  <description>The collection of piping materials
of the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping materials</name>
  <description>All necessary materials that are used when
fabricating piping assemblies, and become parts of fabricated piping
assemblies.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_prefabrication_documents" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping prefabrication documents</name>
  <description>All documents, information
and drawings that are the result of piping detail design and are used for
piping prefabrication.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_route_design" inscope="no">
  <name>Piping route design</name>
  <description>The design of the path in which the
piping is laid out between equipment items in the plant.</description>
<note>The piping route is usually expressed by plan view only.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="piping_specification" inscope="yes">
  <name>Piping specification</name>
  <description>Consensus or mandate technical
descriptions of piping that controls the design, prefabrication and fabrication
of piping.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Plant</name>
  <description>A portion of an installation (or the entire
installation) required to operate to produce products.</description>
<example>Products produced include chemicals, pharmaceuticals,
electrical power, petroleum, and similar products.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant_design_documentation" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plant design documentation</name>
  <description>All documents related to the
process of designing the process plant.</description>
<note>Plant design documents include the approved design
methodologies, basic data describing physical properties and their correlations
used in the design, kinetic data and kinetic models used in the design,
corrosion data and methodology used in selecting materials of construction,
supplier performance data, capital and operating cost estimates, and
appropriations requests.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant_items" inscope="no">
  <name>Plant items</name>
  <description>An item or piece of equipment that may be used
as a component of the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant_life-cycle_documentation" inscope="no">
  <name>Plant life-cycle documentation</name>
  <description>The collection of all project
management, design, contractual, regulatory, and disposal documents produced
during the life cycle of a process plant.</description>
<note number="1">This includes all data retained past the end of the plant
life cycle.</note>
<note number="2">This is within the scope of ISO 15926-2:2003.
This part of ISO 10303 support the input or output of data
relevant to a particular stage in the life-cycle of a plant
from a repository of such data.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant_operation_and_maintenance_documentation" inscope="no">
  <name>Plant operation and maintenance documentation</name>
  <description>The
collection of documents relating to the operation and maintenance of process
plant.</description>
<note>These documents include operating records and plant data,
safety and accident reports, maintenance reports, disposal records for all
residual materials generated during the operation of the plant, and economic
information related to product sales.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant_performance_requirements" inscope="yes">
  <name>Plant performance requirements</name>
  <description>A quantitative description of
the quantity and quality of a product to be produced by the plant in a yearly
time period.</description>
<note>Performance requirements are usually stated as units of
product per unit time. Additional qualifications are made regarding the quality
of the Plant, such as time between major shutdowns for continuous processes,
percent uptime required, and expected yield.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plant_records" inscope="no">
  <name>Plant records</name>
  <description>The documentation of information related to
plant disposal, restoration, turnover, and regulatory approvals.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plot_plan" inscope="no">
  <name>Plot plan</name>
  <description>The arrangement design of the main equipment,
buildings and structures of the plant.</description>
<note>The plot plan is usually expressed by plan view only.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="plot_plan_preliminary" inscope="no">
  <name>Plot plan (preliminary)</name>
  <description>An initial arrangement design of the
main equipment, building and structures of the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="prefabricated_piping_products" inscope="no">
  <name>Prefabricated piping products</name>
  <description>Spool pieces that are the
final the products of prefabricator. These spool pieces have been
prefabricated, inspected and packed, and become prefabricator's final products.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="prefabricated_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Prefabricated spool piece</name>
  <description>Spool pieces in their final form
prior to inspection.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="pre-commissioned_plant" inscope="no">
  <name>Pre-commissioned plant</name>
  <description>A plant that is completed and ready
for check out. Mechanical systems are complete, transfer of ownership and
operation remain.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="primary_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Primary spool piece</name>
  <description>Assemblies of the main parts of spool
pieces that consist of pipes and other piping materials. Primary spool pieces
are usually formed by simple connections, such as by welding straight pipes to
flanges.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="process_control_logic" inscope="no">
  <name>Process control logic</name>
  <description>Prose or diagrammatic explanation of
mechanisms or systems that monitor and control a process.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="process_control_logic_preliminary" inscope="no">
  <name>Process control logic (preliminary)</name>
  <description>Initial prose or
diagrammatic explanation of mechanisms or systems that monitor and control a
process developed during conceptual process design.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="process_flow_diagram" inscope="yes">
  <name>Process flow diagram (PFD)</name>
  <description>A schematic document describing
the equipment units and their interconnections, major process control
functions, and major stream characteristics including physical and transport
properties, material flows, and energy flows.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="processing_machines_and_tools" inscope="no">
  <name>Processing machines and tools</name>
  <description>Various kind of machines and
tools which are used for manufacturing prefabricated piping such as cutting
machine, welding machine, jigs and tools.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="procured_item" inscope="no">
  <name>Procured item</name>
  <description>Plant item that has been obtained from a
supplier for incorporation into the plant.</description>
<note><p>States or status of procured items include:</p>
<ul>
<li>in-fabrication;</li>
<li>accepted;</li>
<li>shipped;</li>
<li>delivered-to-site.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="procurement_schedule_and_material_list" inscope="no">
  <name>Procurement schedule and material list</name>
  <description>A schedule that
describes when procured materials will be received, and a list of procured
materials and their quantities and other pertinent procurement information.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="production_schedule" inscope="yes">
  <name>Production schedule</name>
  <description>A time-based list of production tasks.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="project_authorizations_and_controls" inscope="no">
  <name>Project authorizations and controls</name>
  <description>Management
authorization, imperatives, directives, and procedures for initiating and
executing project activities.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="project_control_and_approval_documentation" inscope="no">
  <name>Project control and approval documentation</name>
  <description>A set of
documents that define the standard procedures, standard software modules, or
standard forms adopted to ensure that all activities in the project comply with
organizational constraints. The documents indicate how all activities are to be
implemented and approved and identify all constraints that must be met.</description>
<note>The constraints include financial limitations, accounting,
legal and regulatory restrictions, socio-economic factors, and business
practices throughout the plant life cycle.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="project_financial_plan" inscope="no">
  <name>Project financial plan</name>
  <description>Document that states how much the
plant will cost to construct, how it is to be paid for, and when payments are
to be made. It is a general financing and cash flow document.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="project-specific_documents" inscope="no">
  <name>Project-specific documents</name>
  <description>Procedures, standards,
guidelines, specifications, and codes created specifically for the plant
project. These documents may call out, add to, modify, or tailor a standard.
Portions of these documents are derived from the design basis.</description>
<note>Project-specific documents evolve through stages like
P&amp;IDs and other design documentation.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="protected_and_packed_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Protected and packed spool piece</name>
  <description>spool pieces that are
protected and packed to be ready for shipping.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="purchase_agreement" inscope="no">
  <name>Purchase agreement</name>
  <description>Contract between two parties to provide
a service or item for a designated payment.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="purchase_order" inscope="no">
  <name>Purchase order</name>
  <description>A directive issued to suppliers to acquire
materials.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="qualified_construction_firms" inscope="no">
  <name>Qualified construction firms</name>
  <description>List of construction firms
that are capable and acceptable to construct the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="received_piping_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Received piping materials</name>
  <description>Straight pipe and other piping
materials that are brought to the piping prefabricator that are used to
prefabricate the piping.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="regulatory_agreements" inscope="no">
  <name>Regulatory agreements</name>
  <description>Mutual agreement between the owner or
operators and regulatory agencies.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="regulatory_authorizations" inscope="no">
  <name>Regulatory authorizations</name>
  <description>Approval from regulatory agencies
to initiate activities.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="regulatory_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Regulatory requirements</name>
  <description>International, national or regional laws,
codes, or standards that impact various activities related to the process
plant.</description>
<note>Regulatory requirements may apply to, but are not limited
to, permitting, engineering, construction, operations and decommissioning.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="repair_order" inscope="no">
  <name>Repair order</name>
  <description>Directive to repair a rejected product after
inspection.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="request_for_management_approval" inscope="no">
  <name>Request for management approval</name>
  <description>A document submitted to
management requesting either approval to continue a particular activity of the
project or requesting the procedure to use to solve a particular problem.</description>
<note>Approval requests may, at times, include a request that the
company appropriate monies for a particular activity.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="residual_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Residual materials</name>
  <description>All chemicals and equipment, excluding
useful products, remaining in the environment at the end of the plant life
cycle.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="resources" inscope="no">
  <name>Resources</name>
  <description>The technology, people, and tools used to carry
out the plant life-cycle activities.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="resources_existing" inscope="no">
  <name>Resources (existing)</name>
  <description>Currently available technology,
people, and tools used to carry out the plant life-cycle activities.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="safety_and_hazardous_operations_analysis" inscope="no">
  <name>Safety and hazardous operations analysis</name>
  <description>The results of the
evaluation of the plant design with respect to safety and hazardous operations.
Identifies possible causes of faults and their consequences, and recommends
remedies.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="safety_and_hazardous_operations_analysis_preliminary" inscope="no">
  <name>Safety and hazardous operations analysis (preliminary)</name>
  <description>The
initial results of the evaluation of the plant design with respect to safety
and hazardous operations.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="safety_compliance_reports" inscope="no">
  <name>Safety compliance reports</name>
  <description>Documentation of analyses and
evaluations of the plant performed with respect to safety considerations.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="safety_system_specification" inscope="no">
  <name>Safety system specification</name>
  <description>Job specific document related to
plant safety.</description>
<note>This specification may be developed from applying the design
safety philosophy to plant design.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="schedules" inscope="no">
  <name>Schedules</name>
  <description><p>A time-based list of project tasks that
describes:</p>
<ul>
<li>what is supposed to happen;</li>
<li>when it is supposed to happen;</li>
<li>task sequence and dependencies;</li>
<li>restraints and constraints;</li>
<li>float;</li>
<li>critical path.</li>
</ul>
</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="schematic_diagrams" inscope="yes">
  <name>Schematic diagrams</name>
  <description>A physically non-dimensional, 2D
graphical representation of the functional design of a system that does not
(necessarily) encompass physical information.</description>
<example><p>Types of schematic diagrams include:</p>
<ul>
<li>PFD;</li>
<li>P&amp;ID;</li>
<li>electrical single line;</li>
<li>motor control;</li>
<li>control loops;</li>
<li>HVAC;</li>
<li>plumbing;</li>
<li>input output.</li>
</ul>
</example>
<note>Schematic diagrams evolve through stages like P&amp;IDs and
other design documentation.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="schematic_diagrams_preliminary" inscope="yes">
  <name>Schematic diagrams (preliminary)</name>
  <description>An initial physically
non-dimensional, 2D graphical representation of the functional design of a
system that does not (necessarily) encompass physical information developed
during conceptual plant design.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="shipping_report" inscope="no">
  <name>Shipping report</name>
  <description>Documentation to notify customers of
shipping information about the shipment of spool pieces.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="short_pipe" inscope="no">
  <name>Short pipe</name>
  <description>Short straight pipes that are cut from straight
pipes.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="site_information_existing" inscope="no">
  <name>Site information (existing)</name>
  <description>Information about the physical
location where the plant will be constructed and the conditions of any plant on
the site (if one exists).</description>
<example><p>Site information includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>geological data, such as before and after terrain contours, and
subterranean structure, and seismic activity;</li>
<li>meteorological data such as seasonal wind profile, precipitation, snowfall,
and ambient temperature;</li>
<li>road data;</li>
<li>cadastre (property lines) zones;</li>
<li>utilities.</li>
</ul>
</example>
<note>A kind of site information included in the scope of this
part of ISO 10303 is verified field dimensions. They are parameters that
specify the physical and spatial characteristics of an existing item or
component in a plant that have been verified by measurements taken by a second,
independent agency. For example, field dimensions provided by the Plant owner
for piping tie-in locations (coordinate locations and sizes) are considered as
&quot;verified&quot; when duplicated by the AEC representative. If
discrepancies are discovered during verification of the field dimensions, the
initial and verification measurement processes must be repeated to assure
verified dimensions.</note>
<note number="2">Existing plant conditions are the characteristics of the
existing plant(s) relevant to the revamp, retrofit, or expansion Plant project.
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="spatial_layout" inscope="no">
  <name>Spatial layout</name>
  <description>The detailed arrangement design of equipment,
buildings and structures of the plant.</description>
<note>The layout is usually expressed by both plan and elevation
view.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="societal_requirements" inscope="no">
  <name>Societal requirements</name>
  <description>The expressed need or demand by
society, on either a local, national, or global scale, for products, services,
or processes.</description>
<note>In some instances, a market study may project the expected
demand or price of a product or service required by some element of society.</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="specifications_and_standards" inscope="no">
  <name>Specifications and standards</name>
  <description>Consensus or mandated technical
descriptions of plant hardware or systems that control the design or
construction of a plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="spool_piece_for_repairing" inscope="no">
  <name>Spool piece (for repairing)</name>
  <description>Assembled spool
pieces after the welds have completed successfully the inspection process.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="spool_piece_after_welding_inspection" inscope="no">
  <name>Spool piece (after welding inspection)</name>
  <description>Defective assembled spool pieces
returned to the prefabrication process for repair after inspection.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="standards_documents" inscope="no">
  <name>Standards documents</name>
  <description>Consensus or mandated technical records
of requirements and specifications for plant hardware or systems that control
the design or construction of a plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="standard_practice" inscope="no">
  <name>Standard practice</name>
  <description>Fabrication practices standardized by a
company, industry, national, or international standards organization that are
used for manufacture.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="standard_procurement_procedure" inscope="no">
  <name>Standard procurement procedure</name>
  <description>The steps and materials to
execute the procurement process that are standardized by a manufacturer.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="starting_materials" inscope="no">
  <name>Starting materials</name>
  <description>All necessary equipment components or
consumable goods necessary to construct and operate the process plant for the
production of useful products.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="status" inscope="no">
  <name>Status</name>
  <description>A report of the current state of a task, design,
action, or schedule. It is a quality assurance feedback mechanism.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="straight_pipe" inscope="no">
  <name>Straight pipe</name>
  <description>Circular straight tubes that are used for
fabricating piping, and become parts of fabricated piping assemblies.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="stream_data" inscope="yes">
  <name>Stream data</name>
  <description>Chemical composition, physical state, and mass
quantities of process flows.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="structure_design_documents" inscope="no">
  <name>Structure design documents</name>
  <description>All documents, information and
drawings that are the result of the design activity for the structures within a
plant. These documents provide a record of the structural design of the plant.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="supplier_documentation" inscope="no">
  <name>Supplier documentation</name>
  <description>Drawings, manuals, calculations, etc.
received from a company concerning items procured from the company, that
provides information concerning design details or performance of the procured
items.</description>
<note><p>Statuses assigned to supplier documentation include:</p>
<ul>
<li>preliminary (in-process design information);</li>
<li>certified (information from the supplier is warranted to correctly describe
the as-delivered functional or physical data);</li>
<li>released for fabrication or construction.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="suppliers_list" inscope="no">
  <name>Suppliers list</name>
  <description>A list of companies that provide commodities
or services to an organization.</description>
<note><p>Kinds or statuses of supplier lists include:</p>
<ul>
<li>approved;</li>
<li>recommended;</li>
<li>partnered.</li>
</ul>
</note>
</icom>

<icom identifier="system_design_final" inscope="yes">
  <name>System design (final)</name>
  <description>System design, expressed by flow and
control information and equipment performance data, to its final state.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="system_design_preliminary" inscope="yes">
  <name>System design (preliminary)</name>
  <description>At the conceptual level, this is
an initial definition and representation of the physical components or items of
the system.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="system_layout_preliminary" inscope="no">
  <name>System layout (preliminary)</name>
  <description>At the conceptual level, this is
an initial definition and representation of the spatial configuration or
arrangement of the system, showing all the major components of the system.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="system_layout_and_design" inscope="yes">
  <name>System layout and design</name>
  <description>The definition and representation
of the physical components or items and spatial configuration of the system in
sufficient detail to support construction.</description>
<note number="1">This definition results from the use of the system design
basis, P&amp;IDs, specifications, and other documentation or information.
</note>
<note number="2">The definition of the term &quot;system&quot; is broader
than common usage, e.g., it encompasses structural systems.</note>
<note number="3"><p>System layout and designs can be viewed or categorized
according to the following breakdowns:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>evolutionary phase:</p>
<ul>
<li>Initial;</li>
<li>Design;</li>
<li>Final;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>system type:</p>
<ul>
<li>Piping;</li>
<li>HVAC;</li>
<li>Electrical;</li>
<li>Instrumentation and Control;</li>
<li>Structural and Civil;</li>
<li>Architecture;</li>
<li>Safety.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>functional views:</p>
<ul>
<li>Conceptual arrangement;</li>
<li>Spatial information;</li>
<li>Schematic diagram;</li>
<li>Piping and instrumentation diagram (includes piping connectivity and
sequencing).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</note>
<example>The final HVAC spatial information system design and
layout will specify the definition, physical dimensions, location coordinates,
and characteristics for all HVAC components that occupy space in the Plant.
Only those physical dimensions, location coordinates, and characteristics
required to specify the spatial instance of each component are included in this
definition.</example>
</icom>

<icom identifier="system_layout_and_design_preliminary" inscope="yes">
  <name>System layout and design (preliminary)</name>
  <description>The initial
definition and representation of the physical components or items and spatial
configuration of the system.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="tagged_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Tagged spool piece</name>
  <description>Spool pieces that have identifying labels
attached to distinguish them.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="tagged_spool_piece" inscope="no">
  <name>Tagged spool piece</name>
  <description>Spool pieces that have identifying labels
attached to distinguish them.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="threading_machine" inscope="no">
  <name>Threading machine</name>
  <description>Machines to prepare screw ends at the ends
of pipes.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="time_and_cost_estimate" inscope="no">
  <name>Time and cost estimate</name>
  <description>Projected or forecasted cost and
length of time to design, produce, or procure a plant item, obtain a service,
or achieve some goal.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="unit_operations" inscope="yes">
  <name>Unit operations</name>
  <description>Design basis and owner requirements that
define the basis for conceptual process design.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="useful_products" inscope="no">
  <name>Useful products</name>
  <description>The materials or energy generated through
the operation of the process plant that are sold to customers for a profit.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="weld_inspection_report" inscope="no">
  <name>Weld inspection report</name>
  <description>Documentation of the results of
inspection of individual welds.</description>
</icom>

<icom identifier="welding_machine" inscope="no">
  <name>Welding machine</name>
  <description>Welding machines to assemble pipes and
other piping materials, to produce primary spool pieces which have usually
simple form, such as straight pipe plus flange, single axis rotated welding
machine.</description>
</icom>

</icoms>
  
</idef0>
