<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: application_protocol.xml,v 1.3 2008/04/06 12:07:45 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE application_protocol SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/application_protocol.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkapdoc_main.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!-- 
     To view the application document in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<!-- The XML for the AP documents
     name :
       is the name/directory of the Application protocol, all lower case with no whitespace

     module_name :
       is the name of the top level implementation module, the AP module

     title :
       is the title of the AP document

     part :
       ISO 10303 part number of the AP document

     purpose :
       Used to complete the first sentence in the introduction
         "This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol (AP) for ....."
       and clause 4
         "This clause specifies the information required for ...."

     wg.number :
       SC4 N-number of the AP document

     wg.number.supersedes :
       the SC4 N-number of the document that this AP document supercedes

     version :
       version of AP document 

     status :
       AP document status

     language :
       E for English langauge

     publication.year :
       year of publication of AP document

     published :
       y if published
-->
<application_protocol
   name="systems_engineering"
   module_name="ap233_systems_engineering"
   title="Systems engineering"
   part="233"
   purpose="systems engineering data"
   wg.number="00000"	
   wg.number.supersedes="2277" 
   version="1"
   status="CD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   rcs.date="$Date: 2008/04/06 12:07:45 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.3 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

<keywords>
    Application protocol, issue management, program management, project management, 
    risk management, systems engineering, system behaviour, system modelling, 
system_structure </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the application protocol. -->
<abstract>
		<p>
   This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol for the representation of 
   systems engineering design data. It defines the context, scope and information 
   requirements for various development stages during the design of a system. This 
   part of ISO 10303 is applicable to any form of system, including aircraft, cars, 
   ships, railways, and plant.  </p>
			</abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
		<projlead ref="ap233.projlead2"/>
		<editor ref="ap233.editor2"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
	<purpose>
		<p>
   This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol for the representation of 
   systems engineering design data. It defines the context, scope and information requirements 
   for various development stages during the design of a system. This part of ISO 10303 is 
   applicable to any form of system, including aircraft, cars, ships, railways, and plant.  </p>
   
  <p><b>Documenation Guide</b></p>  
  <ol> 

  <li>An overview of "What Systems Engineering Is" follows this guide.</li>

  <li>Process standards for systems engineering have been developed over the past 2 decades. A 
  review of these, including ISO 15288 has lead the Ap233 development team to  
  an Application Activity Model (AAM) that attempts to span the information modelling needs of all.
  The AAM is in <clause_ref linkend="aam"/>
  <note>See Tim King's AAM report section 4.2, page 20 where Tim defines the background used 
  for Ap233's AAM.  DERA reference may be at INCOSE-Connect.  A few associated notes here would be good.</note></li>

  <li>The Ap233 consensus building procress lead to the need to create a single "Concept Model" 
  and semaintic dictionary that documented agreements in a harmonized and consistent manner. 
  The cpncept model became the foundation for the ISO - Ap233 and OMG - SysML developement work.  
  The model is provided in 
  Annex <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:Concept Model for Systems Engineering">K</clause_ref>
  and the Semanic Dictionary is in 
  Clause <clause_ref linkend="definition:Application activity model">3</clause_ref></li>

  <li><b>The content of 
  Annex <clause_ref linkend="usage_guide:Application protocol implementation guide">J</clause_ref> 
  is currently undefined.</b> Perhaps this would be a good place to highlight the usage of reference data. 
  The DEXLIB repository contains presentation ideas to build upon and harmonize with.  Currently it 
  contains stuff that has not yet been reorganized and moved.</li>

  <li>Ap233 builds upon the modular architecture of the STEP repository.  This uses atomic level 
  modules to create higher level capabilities.that can both act standalone as implementation modules 
  or joined with others to create higher level capabilities. These are outlined in 
 <clause_ref linkend="inforeqt:Information requirements">Clause 4</clause_ref></li>

 <li>Below the implementation module viewing level of abstraction connectivity between the atomic 
  level STEP modules becomes exceedingly complex.  As an aid to seeing into this complexity a 
  set of loosely defined concepts with natural language meaning are identified.  These are 
  used to logically group modules. They are presented graphically in a manner that shows both 
  USE FROM connectivity and where the Extensible selects are defined.  This work is 
  contained in Annex F of <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide"/>.</li>

  <li>Hyperlinks are extensively applied throughout the documentation.</li>

  </ol>

    <p><b>What Systems Engineering Is</b></p>

   <p>Systems Engineering is <i>An interdisciplinary collaborative approach to derive, evolve, 
   and verify a life cycle balanced system solution that satisfies customer expectations and 
   meets public acceptability.</i> (IEEE 1220-1984) </p>

   <p><i>Systems Engineering is an interdisciplinary approach and means to enable the realization 
   of successful systems. It focuses on defining customer needs and required functionality early 
   in the development cycle, documenting requirements, then proceeding with design synthesis and 
   system validation while considering the complete problem.</i> (INCOSE)</p>

   <p>The complete problem spans:</p>
   <ul>
   <li>stakeholder needs;</li>
   <li>requirements;</li>
   <li>the enterprise and competitors;</li>
   <li>concept;</li>
   <li>design</li>
   <li>design optimization by trade studies;</li>
   <li>design validation and verification;</li>
   <li>manufacture;</li>
   <li>product validation and verification;</li>
   <li>test;</li>
   <li>maintenance;</li>
   <li>disposal;</li>
   <li>training and support;</li>
   <li>cost and schedule;</li>
   <li>program management.</li>
   </ul>

   <p><i>Systems Engineering integrates all the disciplines and specialty groups into a team effort 
   forming a structured development process that proceeds from concept to production to operation. 
   Systems Engineering considers both the business and the technical needs of all customers with 
   the goal of providing a quality product that meets the user needs.</i> (INCOSE)</p>
   
   <p>Systems Engineering makes extensive use of specification of all interfaces, performance 
   analysis, and trade studies to ensure that the system is near optimal for and will be accepted 
   by stakeholders and the marketplace. It is applicable to anything for which a well defined 
   boundary can be established whether mechanical, electrical, electronic, information, chemical, 
   biological, social or organizational.</p>
   
   <p><b>What AP233 Is</b></p>
   
   <p>AP233 is an information model that captures the concepts used in Systems Engineering, as 
   <clause_ref linkend="purpose:figure:se1:1">Figure 1</clause_ref> shows. 
   These concepts may be represented by a variety of symbols and each set of such 
   symbols can be combined into an number of different views. A particular set of symbols and views 
   constitutes a language. Tools automate the use of such a language to represent and model systems. 
   For any language a number of different tools may exist and they may not be able to exchange data 
   even using the same language unless they have compatible schema for storing that language. Thus a 
   single set of concepts results in a plethora of languages and tools.</p>

		<figure id="se1" number="1"> 
		<title>AP233 Information model</title>
			<img src="Slide9.gif"/>	
		</figure>

		
    <p>The tools are used by engineers. Frequently it is the organization that establishes the process, 
    a specification of the views and development order that shall be followed, that the engineers 
    shall follow. Two organizations using the same toll may or may not use equivalent views in doing 
    their work.</p>

    <p>In general there is no single tool that can support all the work that must be done so the 
    tools are most efficient when put in an environment that enables them to exchange the information 
    artifacts that the engineers produce using the tools. Often different tools incorporated in a 
    single environment cannot exchange information. Very often the organizations in a supply chain 
    or working together on a single project as a consortium will have different environments 
    incorporating different sets of tools. Yet all members of the supply chain or consortium need 
    to efficiently share data rigorously and at low cost.</p>

    <p>The application protocol, like AP233 for Systems Engineering, provides a solution to this 
    problem. Each tool needs an interface that interconnects the tool with the AP. The interface 
    transforms the data artifacts from the tool for correct storage in the AP and transforms data 
    supplied by the AP for use by the tool.</p>

    <p>In this way AP233 supports information exchange among organizations even though their 
    environments contain different tools.  AP233 is the glue for organizations working together 
    in a consortium or a supplier chain.</p>
    
   <p><b>What AP233 Contains</b></p>
   
   <p><clause_ref linkend="purpose:figure:se2:2">Figure 2</clause_ref> 
   shows the basic capabilities of AP233. It is divided into two main parts, Program 
   Management and System Requirements/Design. Major capabilities are listed in each box. The 
   relevant kinds of tools that are applicable surround each box. The two main parts of the work 
   are interconnected by risk analysis, issue resolution, and management authorization and review. 
   Where these capabilities share concepts, i.e. where they are semantically equivalent, there can 
   be exchange of information artifacts among any of the tools through the tool interfaces and the 
   AP233 information model.</p>


		<figure id="se2" number="2"> 
		<title>AP233 content and associated tools</title>
		<img src="Slide10.gif"/>	
		</figure>

   <p>The same transfer is possible where there is semantic identity with downstream design, 
   manufacture, test, and maintenance tools. There are many ISO 10303 Application Protocols 
   (AP’s) for a variety of industrial businesses such as, geometry, circuit board and chip 
   development, ship building, building construction, furniture design and manufacture, maintenance, 
   etc.  A large number of different tools are used by these businesses and interface through their 
   own AP’s. All of these AP’s have been made modular and share, as much as possible, the same modules 
   This approach is vital for connecting systems engineering tools to downstream tools and it makes 
   possible the use of AP233 as an integrating AP across all the others.</p>

   <p>The shared modularity has also required that the AP233 modules use naming conventions that 
   were developed a decade or more ago by developers in other disciplines. The consequence is that 
   AP233 contains names in the detailed EXPRESS code that will seem foreign to practicing systems 
   engineers. It also means that many modules will use a different common module for widely needed 
   representation of entities like number or a weighting factor. Thus the reader who looks at a 
   particular module may not see there an entity that he knows belongs there because it resides 
   in a shared module and is connected to the module he is reading. Efficient use of the EXPRESS 
   language also means that the connection to the common module may go through a chain of classes 
   and subclasses; it may be very indirect for the reader. </p>

   <p>For the reasons above, this introduction does not attempt to show the reader the details of 
   the EXPRESS code. Rather this introduction attempts to: </p>
	<ol>
	<li>describe AP233 as a container of concepts shared by tools; </li>
	<li>list  number of the capabilities AP233; </li>
	<li>show kinds of tools that can interface with one another through AP233;</li>
	<li>show the major mappings of capabilities onto the modules that constitute the information module.</li>
	</ol>

   <p>Those who wish to investigate the modules in detail can use this Introduction as a guide to 
   that adventure. 
   <clause_ref linkend="purpose:figure:se3:3">Figure 3</clause_ref>
   shows a top level view of the module hierarchy. It is important to be 
   aware that the boxes under a higher box do not necessarily completely compose it. Rather there 
   may be additional things in the box above. This is not intuitive to those accustomed to hardware 
   development, but it is a result of the software languages.</p>

   		<figure id="se3" number="3"> 
		<title>Top level hierarchy of AP233 modules</title>
		<img src="Slide11.gif"/>	
		</figure>

   <p>The capabilities of Figure 2. map into modules of Figure 3. as identified below. Be 
   aware that these are not leaf cell modules. There may be structure below them, and they may 
   connect to modules above and below through type extensions. This makes reading the code or 
   the graphic EXPRESS-G diagrams difficult, but it is the nature of the language. </p>

   <p><b>Program management capabilities</b></p>
    <ul>
   <li>all of these capabilities map to modules under <module_ref linkend="program_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>issues map to <module_ref linkend="issue_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>organization structure maps to <module_ref linkend="organization_structure:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>project breakdown maps to <module_ref linkend="project_breakdown:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>project management information maps to <module_ref linkend="project_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>project management resource information maps to <module_ref linkend="project_management_resource_information:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>risk maps to <module_ref linkend="risk_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>schedule maps to <module_ref linkend="project_breakdown:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>work breakdown information maps to <module_ref linkend="work_structure:introduction"/>; </li>
   <li>configuration management maps in a complex manner to capabilities in <module_ref linkend="product_data_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>product data management (PDM) maps in a complex manner to capabilities in <module_ref linkend="product_data_management:introduction"/>.</li>
   </ul>

   <p><b>System requirements and design capabilities</b></p>

   <ul>
   <li>all of these capabilities map to modules under <module_ref linkend="system_modelling:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>requirements map to <module_ref linkend="requirement_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>allocation of requirements to system elements map to <module_ref linkend="requirement_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>moments of effectiveness and trade studies map to capability under <module_ref linkend="decision_support:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>configuration management maps to <module_ref linkend="product_data_management:introduction"/> under  <module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>product data management (PDM) maps to <module_ref linkend="product_data_management:introduction"/> under  <module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>interface to analysis maps to capabilities under  <module_ref linkend="decision_support:introduction"/>;</li>  
   <li>function based behaviour maps to <module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:introduction"/> under <module_ref linkend="system_behaviour:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li>state based behaviour maps to <module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:introduction"/> under <module_ref linkend="system_behaviour:introduction"/>.</li>
   <li>system hierarchies for the design system, the realized system and all interfaces map to 
   capabilities under <module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction"/>;</li>
   </ul>
</purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope 
      If from_module is YES then XSL will copy the in scope statement from the module.
      The XSL will automatically insert:
          "This part of ISO 10303 specifies the use of the integrated
           resources necessary for the scope and information requirements for "
      The context is the text that completes the sentence.
     -->
 <inscope from_module="YES" context="representation of systems engineering data.">
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope
      If from_module is YES then XSL will copy the out scope statement from the module
     -->
 <outscope from_module="YES">
 </outscope>

 <normrefs/>
 
<definition>
   <term id="ap233_element">element</term>
   <def>
     that which is discernable by the reproducible measurement of its characteristics
     <note>The semantic term element includes matter, energy and information.  The term 
     product from ISO 10303-Part 1 STEP definitions defines product as: a thing or 
     substance produced by a natural or artificial process. This part of ISO 10303 
     needs to define the informational attributes associated with the entity named 
     "product" as defined within ISO 10303-1017 - Product Identification. This entity 
     has attributes that enable one to capture: id, name and description.  ISO 10303-1017 
     provides the definition: A Product is the identification of a product or of a type 
     of product. It is a collector of data common to all revisions of the product. Element 
     appears to be a legitimate subclass of product because this part requires reproducible 
     measurement of element.</note>
     <example>Any thing from microscopic particles to galaxy clusters is an element.  
     Any thing with a finite existence from galaxies with billion-year lives to trans-uranic 
     elements with lifetimes less than nano-seconds. Counter-example: Things like ghosts, 
     devils, the Loch Ness monster, the city of Atlantis are not discernable by reproducible 
     measurement and are excluded. Research and development things that do not yet have 
     reproducible measurements and process control are excluded. For example, silicon for 
     electronic devices would be excluded in 1900. </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_category">category</term>
   <def>
     categories provide the grouping of elements into a set based on defined 
     properties that serve as selection criteria for which elements of all those
     in the universe belong in that set
     <note>This is one of the forms of generalization/specialization. This is 
     <b>not inheritance</b> as used in object-oriented software languages. Physical 
     elements of matter and energy do not inherit their properties. Rather they posses 
     the properties of themselves and can be identified by measurement of those properties.</note>
     
     <example>Explanation: It is categorization that enables us to define alternatives 
     and create taxonomies for libraries. </example>
     <ul>
     <li>Inclusive/Complete Category: Any Element of the super category may 
     reside in any number of the sub-categories and all members of the super-category 
     are members of at least one of the sub-categories.</li></ul>
     <example>the super category is all apples raised on a particular farm. The subcategories 
     are used for sorting and include: good apples, bruised apples, marked apples, rotten 
     apples, and wormy apples.</example>
     <ul>
     <li>Inclusive/Incomplete Category: Any Element of the super category may reside in any 
     number of the sub-categories and only some members of the super-category are members 
     of the sub-categories.</li></ul>
     <example>the super category is all fruit raised on a particular farm. The subcategories 
     are used for sorting and include: good apples, bruised apples, marked apples, rotten 
     apples, and wormy apples.</example>
     <ul>
     <li>Exclusive/Complete Category:  Any Element of the super-category may reside in one 
     and only one of the sub-categories and all members of the super-category are members 
     of at least one of the sub-categories.</li></ul>
     <example>An automobile has in its decomposition tree an engine. For this automobile 
     any of three engines: 140 HP, 180 HP, and 220 HP. The superclass of engine is exhausted 
     by the subclasses and the subclasses are independent.</example>
     <ul>
     <li>Exclusive/ Incomplete Category:  Any Element of the super-category may reside in 
     one and only one of the sub-categories and only some members of the super-category are
     members of the sub-categories.</li></ul>
     <example>All of the automobile engines under current manufacture by GM and its 
     subsidiaries are considered as candidates for three engines that will be used in a new car.</example>
   </def>
 </definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_domain of interest">domain of interest</term>
   <def>
   all elements of interest to the problem at hand
   <note>These include the system, its environment, external systems of interest in the environment, 
   stakeholders, enabling things, things that may cause failure, and all other things of interests.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_system">system</term>
   <def>
   an element with a well defined boundary with respect to all other elements, outside of it and 
   in the domain of interest, with which it interacts
   <note>A system is composed of interacting systems. The emergent behaviors and properties of a 
   system are the result of the properties and behaviors of the sub-systems and their interactions. 
   These interactions may be highly nonlinear.
   </note>
   <note> Systems decompose hierarchically; they are systems of systems. </note>
   <example>A car has a well defined boundary with respect to its environment, and the 
   relationships are both static and dynamic. Similarly the engine has the same kinds of 
   relationships and so does the fuel injector of the engine. 
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_system view">system view</term>
   <def>  
   a collection of elements and related information about the system that are useful and 
   defined for a particular purpose in a particular context
  <note>Engineers involved in specification, design, manufacturing and maintenance need a 
  particular collection of information to do their work. An engineer working on the 
  cooling system of an engine needs information about a particular set of parts, behaviors 
  and properties that are particular to that engineering problem. The set of possibly 
  useful system views is very large.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_environment">environment</term>
   <def>  
   all elements external to the system that interact with it
   <note>It is often possible to limit the parts of the environment needed for development 
   purposes to those external systems that are neighbors to the system. </note>
   <note> The environment includes not only the external systems that couple with it for 
   useful purposes, but it also includes all external systems that may interact in a manner 
   that causes failure.    </note>
   <example>Elements in the environment need not have well defined boundaries as do systems.  
   A laptop computer can connect to a power grid. But for the design of the laptop it is 
   not important to consider the power grid as a system. It is simpler to consider it as 
   an element with an interface that the laptop connects to when needed.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_stakeholder">stakeholder</term>
   <def>people, organizations and institutions that are a part of the system environment 
   because the system provides some benefit to them and they have an interest in the system
  <note>Stakeholders include; for example, the producers, owners, operators, users, 
  and maintainers of the system.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_stakeholder_need">stakeholder need</term>
   <def>the benefits that the stakeholders wish to be satisfied by or delivered by 
   the system when it is implemented and functioning  
   <note>At the top level of development these needs drive the requirements for the 
   system and the optimization criteria for its development.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_property">property</term>
   <def>any named measurable or observable attribute, quality or characteristic of an element
 <note>Property is usefully decomposed into several categories – the measurable characteristics 
 in normal use, the measurable characteristics that require additional instrumentation for 
 measurement, and the observable characteristics. It is a systems engineering best practice 
 to separate behavior from structure (function from form) and to allocate behavior to structure 
 based on trade studies among alternatives.
   </note>
   <example>The acceleration of a car is in the first category. behavior.  This characteristic 
   can be observed in the normal operation of the car. The weight of the car is not directly 
   observable in the use of the car.  It requires that the car be placed on a scale to record 
   the measurable characteristic. The fact that a car has four wheels, a steering wheel on 
   either the left or the right side, and a sun roof are observable characteristics.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_system requirement">system requirement</term>
   <def>a statement of properties that a system shall exhibit or shall not exhibit when completed
    <note>Requirements are derived from requirements in a many-to-many relationship.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_reference document">reference document</term>
   <def>a statement of the document source of information concerning an element or a property of 
   an element, including the tensor characteristics, units, values, value probability 
   distribution, or symmetry
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_behavior">behavior</term>
   <def>what an element is to do or is not to do in response to excitations it receives from the 
   external elements in its environment
  <note>This is the subclass of property that includes measurable characteristics in normal use. 
  It encompasses the response of the system to excitation by things in its environment. In some 
  other engineering disciplines it is the analysis with differential equations that is called 
  behavior. That is not what is meant here. Here, in AP233, behavior is a model representation 
  of a functional requirement: it is what the system is to do.
   </note>
   <example>Make a fender is a behavior with several function steps, inputs of sheet steel, 
   power, paint primer, paint and the output of a fender. Ring is the behavior of a bell or 
   tuning fork. The "Q" of the bell or tuning fork is a physical property of the bell 
   and its environment.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_function based behavior">function based behavior</term>
   <def>a description of behavior based on function and transformation without reference to state
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_physical property">physical property</term>
   <def>what an element exhibits or does not exhibit in response to excitation and 
   stimulation from auxiliary measurement entities that are not part of its context 
   <note>This is the subclass of property that encompasses measurable characteristics that 
   require additional instrumentation to measure them. They cannot be established from responses 
   to the enviropnment alone. All of the "properties" used in analysis with differential 
   equations fall into this category.
   </note>
   <example>Responses of an element like mass, power consumption, mean time between failure, 
   etc. are critically important and appear in requirements. They are not measured by responses 
   to excitation from their environment.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_structure">structure</term>
   <def>the decomposition, interconnection and other static relationship among the parts of the system
   <note>Physical properties are budgeted to structure using analysis methods, and the emergent 
   performance is calculated using the same methods. Behavior is allocated to the structure. Form 
   and function are separated conceptually so that the design can be optimized by considering 
   several different structures that can provide the desired emergent behavior and properties.
   </note>
   <example>In a real example of optimization the engineer examines not just the maximum or minimum, 
   but looks at the trend in data in that region to be sure the solution is robust. That is, the 
   design solution must not degrade rapidly with small variances in the variables of design.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_part">part</term>
   <def>static parts of the system including their interconnection and interconnection descriptions
  <note>Parts have physical properties assigned to them. Many engineering domains think of these as 
  components, but manufacturing thinks of them as assemblies because they build assemblies.  <i>Assembly 
  is a standard ISO naming convention. It may be desirable to alias this name.</i> </note>
   <note>Physical properties are budgeted to structure using analysis methods, and the emergent 
   performance is calculated using the same methods. Behavior is allocated to the structure. Form 
   and function are separated conceptually so that the design can be optimized by considering several 
   different structures that can provide the desired emergent behavior and properties.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_link">link</term>
   <def>a particular kind of part that is used when it is helpful not to model or specify its details
   <note>Link must be provided in the concept model because a number of application tools use the 
   concept. Links ultimately are fully specified and become a system-assembly.
   </note>
   <example>In a pumping system it may be useful to define the pumps and tanks while representing the 
   piping as links without detail. At some point in the design detail like diameter, flow impedence, 
   pressure rating, and corrosion resistance must be defined. At his point the link becomes a part.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_port">port</term>
   <def>a connection point on a part in the part decomposition hierarchy
   <note>Systems interconnect with one another port-to-port. Ports couple to desired things 
   in the environment and also to the ports of things that cause failure, threaten security 
   or safety. The alias for port is interface connection, this is the term that is used in AP239. </note>
   <note>When a system interacts with its environment, the boundary between the system and 
   the environment is the collection of all interacting ports.
   </note>
   <example>Consider a ultrasonic transmitting transducer coupled to a water tank and a receiver 
   transducer coupled to the tank. The transmitter port connects to a water port and couples 
   sound energy into the water. The intensity at any point is a result of the impedance match 
   between the two ports, the radiation pattern of the transducer, and the attenuation and 
   dispersion in the water. The receiving transducer is attached to another port of the water. 
   The received signal is dependant on the relative impedance of the two ports, the sound 
   distribution in the water, and the radiation pattern of the receiving transducer. This example 
   is often oversimplified as "broadcast" neglecting the port to port conditions and the properties 
   of the medium and neglecting the ports. 
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_interconnection">interconnection</term>
   <def>a listing of the ports that interconnect with one another
   <note>The interconnection may exist for structural reasons without any flow from port to port. 
   The interconnection may exist because functions are assigned to particular assemblies, and the 
   output from one function is an input to the other function. In this case the ports and their 
   interconnection must exist to support flow. The alias for interconnection is interface 
   connection, the term used in AP239.
   </note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_interface specification">interface specification</term>
   <def> a description of a port of a part that includes the geometric description, input/output 
   description, protocols that must be met, assemblies of parts required to join two ports, 
   allowable defect characteristics, etc. including the emergent properties of the interface 
   that are the result of the two ports interacting, and are not associated with either
  <note>Parts interact physically through direct physical contact, exchange of elements, and 
  through forces they exert such as gravity, compression or torque. Thus input/output is bound 
  to ports and described by interfaces. The interface may consist of more than the two ports 
  and may involve an assembly of parts as in the case of two flanges that are assembled with 
  six bolts and an O-ring. The interface may also require detailed description to define what 
  occurs there or how it is maintained. 
   </note>
   <example>For two ports to connect, their interfaces must be compatible. The current carrying 
   capacity of a plug and a socket is a result of the surface area of contact, the contact 
   force, the wiping action on plugging them together, and the surface conductivity of both. 
   This is an emergent property that is not assignable to either port individually.
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_function">function; transformation</term>
   <def>the entity in the context of modeling that transforms an input set of elements 
   into a set of output elements that may be the same or measurably different from the input set
   <note>It is a part of behavior. This is what functions do in mathematics where the 
   input/output are variables. In software the input/output is data. In systems engineering 
   the input/output are elements, matter, energy, and information. An internal function is a 
   kind of function that is allocated to and implemented by the system/structure. An external 
   function is a kind of function that is allocated to and implemented by elements in the environment. 
   </note>
   <example>The function may be "burn gasses" with an input of two moles of hydrogen and one 
   mole of oxygen. The output will be one mole of water, distinctly different from the inputs 
   and a lot of energy. This function may be followed by a function "cool to 90 degrees 
   centigrade". The input had pressure and volume proportional to temperature; the output 
   is now liquid with a well-defined volume, an isotropic compressibility and a viscosity. If 
   the next function is "cool to –10 degrees centigrade", then the viscosity goes away and the 
   compressibility becomes a fourth rank tensor relating stress to strain. 
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_timing">timing</term>
   <def>a time interval assigned to a function that defines the duration of activity of the 
   function or the probability distribution for the duration
   <note>Many probability distributions are used in systems engineering. These may include: 
   normal, log-normal, Bernoulli, beta, binomial, negative binomial, chi squared, discrete 
   uniformed, erlang, exponential, F, gamma, geometric, laplace, poisson, T, triangular, 
   uniform, weibull.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_script">script</term>
   <def>an executable textual language statement assigned to a function to define how 
   that function executes
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_function port">function port</term>
   <def>a logical entity to whch input/output is bound
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_queue">queue</term>
   <def>a storage entity on a function port that accumulate input/output until needed by the function
   <note>Triggering input/output is stored in a "first in first out" queue so that the earliest 
   trigger received activates the function. Non-triggering input/output is stored in a "last in 
   first out" queue so that the most  recent input is used by the function to ensure the input is fresh.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_regular function port">regular function port</term>
   <def>a function port that accepts input/output that does not trigger the function
   <note>The constructs regular function port and control function port allow input/output to 
   trigger some function but not others.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_control function port">control function port</term>
   <def>a function port that accepts input/output that triggers the function
   <note>The constructs regular function port and control function port allow input/output to 
   trigger some function but not others.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_resource">resource</term>
   <def>the amount of input available to a function or the amount of
   output available from it; or, the amount of property of a system available to a function
 <example>There exists some number of missiles available to a missile battery available for 
 the function "Shoot". </example>
  <example>The function "transmit message" may be allocated to a satellite system, a fiber 
  optic line, a microwave link, etc. Each of these alternatives has some value of the property 
  "bandwidth" that may be used by the function.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_function exit">function exit</term>
   <def>a function based behavior construct that links a functional decomposition to the exit
   paths identified for the parent function
  <example>If function exit is decomposed, there are function exit constructs corresponding 
  to the two exit paths in the higher level function. When one of the exit constructs is 
  encountered, execution of the decomposition is complete and control is passed to the 
  corresponding exit path at the higher level.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_input output">input output</term>
   <def>elements consumed by a function are inputs and those generated by a function are outputs
 <note>The name input/output or I/O is used because a given I/O entity is generated by one 
 function and consumed by another. It is a part of behavior. In the general case outputs are 
 different things than inputs, and physical properties, behaviors, values, variances and 
 probability distributions can all change. In this general definition "function" is an element 
 of type information and cannot be realized in the physical world except through elements of 
 type matter or energy that exhibit that function. In the physical world things transform other 
 things. It is this fact of reality that results in the allocation of function to structure 
 which is really a statement that this particular structure entity exhibits this particular 
 function and it will be used to provide that transformation. The thought pattern is to think 
 of the desired transformation, function, to consider alternative things that might be used to 
 provide it, and to select among these, using a trade study based on optimization.</note>
   <example>I/O may trrigger functions and it may terminate functions.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_function ordering">function ordering</term>
   <def>imposes how/when functions execute, which may be sequential, concurrent, traversed 
   iteratively, or lie on separate alternative path
  <note>David <b>some word-smithing has been done, please check</b> </note>
   <note>It is a part of behavior. There are several ways to represent function ordering. It 
   may be done with ordering operators and triggering input/output as in classical behavior 
   diagrams or it may be done with events, states, and transitions as done in state machines 
   and state charts. For this fine level of detail it is necessary to intercompare the 
   detailed models in SEDRES with those in the concept model and those emerging from UML 2.0 development.
   </note>
   <example>A function is activated when all preceeding threads of functions are complete. 
   At this point the function examines its inputs. If all triggering inputs are present the 
   function proceeds to do its work. If one or more triggering inputs is absent, the function 
   waits for them before doing its work. Triggers that arrive while the functions are running 
   are stored in a first in first out queue. Ordinary input/output that arrives while a function 
   is deactivated is stored in a last in first out queue. If the function is running it is 
   discarded.  A function is deactivated when it completes its work or is deactivated by input/output.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_ordering operations">ordering operations</term>
   <def>function ordering constructions that establish how the functions are ordered
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_replicate">replicate</term>
   <def>an ordering_operation that replicates a function used many times
   <note>Especially useful for distributed systems in which a particular function is realized 
   in many places</note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_and">and</term>
   <def>an ordering operation pair that establishes concurrency among functions
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_and out">and out</term>
   <def>an ordering operation that shows the branching our among concurrent functions
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_and in ">and in</term>
   <def>an ordering operation that shows the path rejoining among concurrent functions
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_iterate">iterate</term>
   <def>an ordering operation that repeats a function or group of functions 
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_iterate limit">iterate limit</term>
   <def>an ordering operation that establishes the set over which the iteration is performed
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_loop">loop</term>
   <def>an ordering operation that repeats a function or group of functions some number of times
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_loop limit">loop limit</term>
   <def>the number or expression for the number of repetitions in a loop 
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_loop exit">loop exit</term>
   <def>the ordering operation that terminates a loop and provides correct continuation of the execution path
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_sequence">sequence</term>
   <def>an ordering operator that establishes sequence among functions
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_or">or</term>
   <def>an ordering operator pair that establishes alternative paths for a group of functions
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_or out">or out</term>
   <def>the ordering operation that establishes branching of functions and their alternative paths
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_or in">or in</term>
   <def>the ordering operation that establishes the rejoin of alternative paths
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_multi exit function">multi exit function</term>
   <def>a special function with multiple exit conditions that can serve the same purpose as "or out"
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_probability">probability</term>
   <def>a set of numbers, of sum equal to 1.0, that can be assigned to the several exit paths of 
   an "or out" to establish the relative frequenty that each path is taken </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_activation rules">activation rules</term>
   <def>the set of rules used by an execution engine in a tool to execute the function based behavior
   <note>The same behavior model can produce different execution results if the rules of execution 
   differ between two tools that exchange data. These are the entities that allow recording of the 
   rules used by the tool putting data into the data model.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_start rules">start rules</term>
   <def>the activation rules that establish when a function begins to execute
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_run rules">run rules</term>
   <def>the activation rules that establish how the function executes
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_terminate_rules">terminate rules</term>
   <def>the activation rules that establish the conditions under which a function ceases to execute
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_internal function">internal function</term>
   <def>a kind of function that is allocated to and implemented by system/structure
   <note> For each input/output there are two such functions, one that generates it and one that 
   consumes it.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_external function">external function</term>
   <def>a kind of function that is allocated to and implemented by elements in the environment
   <note>These functions act as sources and sinks of input/output</note>
   <note>Input/output is associated with one function.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_unit">unit</term>
   <def>establishes the standard of measure against which the values of physical properties 
   shall be stated
   <note>Several different standards of units are in use around the world. It is essential 
   to state the standard in use.</note>
   <example>Failure is assured when different groups use different units without making the 
   necesaary transformations.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_property value">property value</term>
   <def>a numeric value assigned to a physical property
   <note>Numeric values, real numbers, can be given as a mean and variance, a probability 
   distribution of values or as a histogram. Many probability distributions are used in 
   systems engineering. These may include: normal, log-normal, Bernoulli, beta, binomial, 
   negative binomial, chi squared, discrete uniformed, erlang, exponential, F, gamma, geometric, 
   laplace, poisson, T, triangular, uniform, weibull.</note>
 <example>Property values are useful in making comparisons and decisions, in verification, and 
 in validation. Comparisons and decisions can only be made if there are both mean values and 
 variances available. Mean values alone are insufficient.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_required budgeted property value">required budgeted property value</term>
   <def>a property value allocated to a part by a requirement, or budgeted to that part by analysis
   <note>Values that shall be met are stated in requirements. The laws of science and 
   engineering interrelate the values of properties and are used to calculate the values 
   appropriate for the parts based on the required value for the whole.</note>
   <example>A requirement may state that a space probe shall weigh no more than 150 pounds. 
   In that case the masses of the subsystems must add up to no more than 150 pounds. It is best 
   practice to budget values to the subsystems for guidance of the engineers working on the subsystems.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

   
<definition>
   <term id="ap233_calculated property value">calculated property value</term>
   <def>a property value of a whole calculated or estimated from the values of the parts 
   that assemble to make the whole
   <note>The laws of science and engineering interrelate the values of properties and are 
   used to calculate the values for the whole based on the designed values for the parts.</note>
   <example>As the designers do their work they arrive at design values for the parts. 
   These values will generally differ from the budgeted values because the designers have 
   detailed information unavailable before. It is necessary to calculate the properties of 
   the whole based on these design values to ensure that requirements are satisfied by the 
   proposed design. The mass of the space probe should be 150 pounds or less, based on the 
   design data.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_target budget property value">target budget property value</term>
   <def>a temporary property value used by a designer as the design work proceeds and 
   different design alternatives are considered
   <note>As a designer considers several alternatives to meet ysystem requirements, it 
   is necessary to carry along temporary property values to accomplish the design work.</note>
   <example>A designer may have been budgeted 40 pounds for his subsystem. He may find 
   a design solution that weighs 38 pounds. In the design process he may consider 
   alternatives that turn out to weigh 36 , 38,  41, and 43 pounds. These are temporary 
   targets. When he examines other budgets he must meet for the subsystem, the designer 
   may conclude that the 38 pound alternative is the best found.</example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_measured property value">measured property value</term>
   <def>a property value established by measurement of an actual part
   <note>These measurements are often made when actual parts first become available. They 
   verify that the parts meet their requirements.  They also verify the quality of analysis 
   models used during design.</note>
   <example>A part like a turbine blade has a number of important properties critical to 
   the performance of a jet engine, These include aerodynamic efficiency, weight, moment 
   of inertia, vibration spectra, mean time between failure, and corrosion resistance. 
   Important properties are predicted durng design with analysis. Measurement is made as 
   soon as possible.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_model parameter">model parameter</term>
   <def>a formally declared variable of the analytical model provided for an external 
   application to populate at execution time in a computing environment
   <note>Physical properties are represented in equations by parameters.</note>
   <example>In Spice, temperature is a model parameter that may be set at the execution time. </example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_parameter assignment">parameter assignment</term>
   <def>provides actual values for characteristics declared formally by the model parameter
   <note>Some parameters are left in parametric form and are calculated. 
   Others are supplied values to fully specify the equations.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_analytical representation">analytical representation</term>
   <def>the association of specific properties of specific system assemblies with an 
   analytical model in order to unambiguously characterize the performance of a specific part
   <note>To perform a calculation it is necessary to associate parameters with other 
   elements of equations.</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_analytical model">analytical model</term>
   <def>provides a mathematical description of the properties of a system
   <note>An analytical model may be a library model. </note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_functional requirement">functional requirement</term>
   <def>states what the shall be done by the system to which it is allocated
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_performance requirement">performance requirement</term>
   <def>states a time duration or a time probability for the completion of a functional 
   requirement or a function as a modeling element
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_physical property requirement">physical property requirement</term>
   <def>states a physical property that shall be exhibited by the system or system asseembly 
   to which it is assigned
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_interface requirement">interface requirement</term>
   <def>states the characteristics of the interface to which it is assigned
   <note>It includes the geometric description, input/output description, protocols that 
   must be met, assemblies of parts required to join two ports, allowable defect characteristics, etc.</note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_imposed design requirement">imposed design requirement</term>
   <def>states particular elements that shall be used in the desiign of the system or part
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_reference requirement">reference requirement</term>
   <def>states a reference to a source of additional requirements that shall be met by the 
   system or part
   <note>The referenced source may be a requirements document, government requirements for 
   safety, security, environmental quality, etc., or a state or federal law</note>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_reference source">reference source</term>
   <def>any requirements document, government regulation or law that contains applicable requirement
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_effectiveness measure">effectiveness measure</term>
   <def>states an optimization condition that a system shall meet
   <note>Requirements define the domain of the solution; that is, the solution space. The effectiveness 
   measures drive the solution to a particular region in that space. The effectiveness measures 
   are tightly related to stakeholder needs. 
   </note>
   <example>The requirements differences between a PC and a laptop are largely in the laptop 
   optimization conditions for minimum weight, minimum thickness, and maximum battery life. 
   These critiera are some of those that customers (one of the kinds of stakeholder) consider 
   in deciding what to purchase. 
   </example>
   </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_optimization direction">optimization direction</term>
   <def>states the direction of optimization, maximize or minimize, for an effectiveness measure 
   <example>For a laptop computer weight and thickness are minimized and battery life is maximized.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_weight">weight</term>
   <def>relative importance of a particular effectriveness measure
   <note>Weights are often expressed in a numerical form.</note>
   <example>They fix the relative importance in trade off weight, 
   thickness, and battery life. How many minutes of battery life are worth how many tenths of a 
   pound in weight.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_regularization function">regularization function</term>
   <def>an analytic expression that combines effectiveness measures with weights to produce a single 
   number for the goodness of a design option
   <note>This corresponds to the regularization function used in optimal control design and in 
   statistical optimization of processes. </note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_verification requirement">verification requirement</term>
   <def>statement of how a system design or instance shall be shown by the development 
   organization using test, analysis, inspection ,  demonstration, simulation, similarity, 
   sampling, or other method to meet a requirement allocated to the system
    <note>This is a requirement on the development organization and not on the system. </note>
    <note>This is performed to confirm that the deployed system will meet the requirements</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_verification event">verification event</term>
   <def>occurrence (with date, performer and result) of a comparison of a requirement against 
   the test, analysis, or inspection results of a design or instance of a system
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_verification procedure">verification procedure</term>
   <def>describes the process used to compare a requirement against the test, analysis, 
   or inspection results of a design or instance of a system
    <example>For a complex digital 
   system the procedure may require the application of a suite of test vectors to the digital 
   system along with environmental tests involving temperature stress and vibration. </example>
   <example> 
   For a complex metal system the the procedure may require the application of several nondestructuve 
   tests to ensure that there are no flaws preset that will cause failure</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_verification configuration">verification configuration</term>
   <def>arrangement of system and infrastructure necessary to perform the test, analysis, or 
   inspection of a design or instance of a system
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_verification plan">verification plan</term>
   <def>the schedule of tasks, task durations, start times, end times, task inputs, task 
   outputs, goals, and resources (both personnel and infrastructure) to perform the test, 
   analysis, or inspection of a design or instance of a system
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_organization">organization</term>
   <def> description of the roles of persons in a group or team 
    ordered definition list.
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_issue">issue</term>
   <def>any question raised concerning the system or the system development
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_risk">risk</term>
   <def>likelihood and impact of failure to meet any technical or development program goal
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_verification result">verification result</term>
   <def>describes the result of a verification  event
    <example>For a complex digital system the procedure may require the application of a suite of 
    test vectors to the digital system along with environmental tests involving temperature stress 
    and vibration.  The result describes the test coverage and the tests passed and failed</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_validation requirement">validation requirement</term>
   <def>statement of how a system requirement, design or instance shall be shown by the development 
   organization to meet stakeholder seeds 
    <note>This is to confirm that the requirements are suitable for the marketplace. </note>
   <example>Proctor and Gamble recently acquired an electric toothbrush product, SpinBrush, from four 
   cleveland area entrepreneurs. Out of a panel of twenty four consumers, twenty three raved about 
   the product. Sales have been sufficient to boost Proctor and Gamble to number 1 position in US oral care.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_validation event">validation event</term>
   <def>occurrence (with date, performer and result) of a comparison of a requirement against the 
   stakeholder needs
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_validation procedure">validation procedure</term>
   <def>describes the process used to compare a requirement against stakeholder needs
    <note>This is a requirement on the development organization and not on the system.</note>
    <note>The procedures may include stakeholder and market surveys, and test marketing</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_validation infrastructure">validation infrastructure</term>
   <def>arrangement of requirement information and related infrastructure necessary to check the 
   corresondance with stakeholder needs and market realities
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_validation plan">validation plan</term>
   <def>the schedule of tasks, inputs, outputs, goals, and resources, both personnel and infrastructure 
   to perform the comparison of requirements against stakeholder Needs
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_validation result">validation result</term>
   <def>describes the result of the validation event
    <note>Entire new product lines 
   have been abandoned after completed development because of unsatisfactory consumer panel 
   responses and unsatisfactory test marketing</note>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_design view">design view</term>
   <def>a partial view of the system that captures only design information; it 
   contains no information about realized, manufactured things that may have lot numbers or serial numbers
   <note>Several different design hierarchues can exist for different purposes. The hierarchy 
   appropriate for manufacturing may conatin more elemnts than the one for engineering design by 
   including materials used in manufacture. The hierarchy for verification of first system built 
   may be different than others because of the need to build parts of the system for early 
   testing to reduce technical risk.</note>
   <example>This definition corresponds to the SC4 convention of separately representing design 
   and realization. SC4 uses the name Part to represent design .</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_realization view">realization view</term>
   <def>a partial view of the system that captures only information relating to realized things 
   that may have lot numbers or serial numbers
   <note>Several different realization hierarchies can exist for different purposes. The hierarchy 
   appropriate for manufacturing may conatin more elemnts than the one for maintenance because 
   that discipline emphasizes line replaceable units.</note>
   <example>This definition corresponds to the SC4 convention of saeparately 
   representing design and realization. SC4  uses Product_as_realized to represent realized things.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_functional breakdown">functional breakdown</term>
   <def>a particular collection of functional and other entities collected for a particular 
   engineering purpose
   <note>These collections allow an engineer to examine functionality for special purposes, 
   picking those elements needed from the prototypical design and realization views.</note>
   <example>An engineer may wish to study the cooling system of a car engine and require a 
   collection of entities distributed through the prototypical design or realization hierarchies.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_system breakdown">system breakdown</term>
   <def>a particular collection of system and other entities collected for a particular 
   engineering purpose
   <note>These collections allow an engineer to examine subsystems for special purposes, 
   picking those elements needed from the prototypical system, design and realization views.</note>
   <example>An engineer  may wish to study the cooling system of a car engine and require 
   a collection of entities distributed through the prototypical design or realization hierarchies.</example>
    </def>
</definition>

<definition>
   <term id="ap233_physical breakdown">physical breakdown</term>
   <def>a particular collection of realized things and other entities collected  for a particular 
   engineering purpose
   <note>These collections allow an engineer to examine physical realizations for special 
   purposes, picking those elements needed from the prototypical system, design and realization views.</note>
   <example>An engineer  may wish to study the cooling system of a car engine and require a 
   collection of entities distributed through the prototypical design or realization hierarchies.</example>
    </def>
</definition>


 <abbreviations/>

 <!-- Clause 4  -->
	<inforeqt>
		<fundamentals>
		<!-- to be replaced with Cmaps -->
			<data_plan>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_intro1.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail0.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail1.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail2.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail3.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail4.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail5.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail6.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="data_plan_detail7.xml"/>
			</data_plan>
			<description>
			<p><i>To be written.</i></p>
			</description>
		</fundamentals>

		<reqtover module="ap233_systems_engineering">
			<description>
			<p><module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:introduction">ISO 10303-433</module_ref>
	defines the full information model for this part of ISO 10303 by providing a single root 
	for all of the modules normatively referenced. </p>
			<p>The Ap233 information model has been built up using a modular approach.  This both joins atomic 
			level modules together in a hierarchial manner and then adds an additonal networking level of 
			connectivity that links the generic concepts of the hierarchial tree together in a manner that
			enables the realization of in scope capabilities.</p>
			
			<p>The large number of atomic level modules and their associated connectivity create a most 
			challenging complexity presentation problem.  The Ap233 development team has found it useful to 
			group all modules relative to a set of about 20 concepts with loosely defined natural language 
			meaning.  These sets are graphically presented as "Concept maps", see 
			<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concept_map"/>.  The maps show both module to module 
			connectivity and where extensible select types are defined.  All concept maps are collected together in 
			<module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">ISO 10303-433 Annex F</module_ref>.</p>
			
			<p>Readers with a mathematics background find that matrix analysis provides good visualization insight. 
			<clause_ref linkend="inforeqt:figure:imcm">Figure 4-1</clause_ref> provides a module "uses" vs. 
			module "used by" matrix at the implmentation module - concept group concept map level of granularity.
			Modules within a row index module group use modules within the <b>X</b> flagged column module groups.</p>
			
     <figure id="imcm" number="4-1">
        <title>Implementation module concept group concept map uses-used by matrix</title>
        <img src="im_cm_matrix.png"/>
      </figure>
			
      			<p>The matrix shows that approxmately half of the module groups are hierarchical while the rest are
			extensively networked.  The following row/column notation is used for the module groups that have
			hierarchical connectivity</p>	
			<ul>
			<li>IM-FBB - <module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:introduction">function_based_behaviour</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-SBB - <module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:introduction">state_based_behaviour</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Behaviour - behaviour concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-SysB - <module_ref linkend="system_behaviour:introduction">system_behaviour</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-System - system concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-SysS - <module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction">system_structure</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-Req - <module_ref linkend="requirement_management:introduction">requirement_management</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-Des - <module_ref linkend="decision_support:introduction">decision_support</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Issue-Risk - issue-risk-group concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-SysM - <module_ref linkend="system_modelling:introduction">system_modelling</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-Pjm - <module_ref linkend="project_management:introduction"> project_management</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-Iss - <module_ref linkend="issue_management:introduction"> issue_management</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-Rsk - <module_ref linkend="risk_management:introduction"> risk_management</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>IM-Pgm - <module_ref linkend="program_management:introduction"> program_management</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>Ap233 - <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:introduction">ap233_systems_engineering</module_ref>.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>The following row/column notation is used for the module groups that have
			networked connectivity</p>
			<ul>
			<li>CM-Representation - representation concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Authorization - authorization concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-MRI - Management resource informaton concepts</li>
			<li>CM-Project - project concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Schedule - schedule concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Activity - activity concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Resource - resource concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-When - when concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Where - where concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Why - why concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-Who - who concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-What - what concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-How - how concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>;</li>
			<li>CM-What-geo what geometry concepts, ISO 10303-433 Clause <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">F</module_ref>.</li>
			</ul>
						
			<p>This Clause provides a still higher level view into the complexity problem.  Here concept maps for each 
			implementation module are presented.  These remove all redundancies that exsit in the actual EXPRESS 
			arm model. They just identify the modules and extensible types used grouped relative to the high level 
			concepts presented in 
			<module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">ISO 10303-433 Annex F</module_ref>.  This 
			presentation allows the reader/reviewer to see and then focus on just what is relevant to 
			each implmentation module.  Hyperlinks are provided that go down to the deepest detail.</p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>

		<reqtover module="system_modelling">
			<description>
<p>  
<module_ref linkend="system_modelling:introduction">
ISO 10303-1477</module_ref>
defines the information model for system modelling. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="system_behaviour">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="system_behaviour:introduction">
ISO 10303-1448</module_ref>
defines the information model for system behaviour. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="state_based_behaviour">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:introduction">
ISO 10303-1371</module_ref>
defines the information model for state based behaviour. </p>

   <p>
     The top level networking view of Ap233 modules and extensible selects used to enable the state 
     based behaviour implementation module is shown in 
     <clause_ref linkend="inforeqt:figure:fbb">figure 4-1</clause_ref>.  The associated USE FROM detail is 
     provided in <module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:4_interfaces">ISO 10303-1371 Clause 4.1</module_ref>  
     and the associated members of each extensible select type list are provided in 
     <module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:4_types">ISO 10303-1371 Clause 4.2</module_ref>.
     <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">ISO 10303-433 Annex F</module_ref> 
     collects all concept maps identified.</p>
     
     <note>In order to reduce presentation complexity <clause_ref linkend="inforeqt:figure:fbb">Figure 4-2</clause_ref> 
     has all USE FROM redundancy appearing in 
     <module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:4_interfaces">ISO 10303-1371 Clause 4.1</module_ref> removed.</note>

     <figure id="sbb" number="4-2">
        <title>State based behaviour modules used and extensible selects</title>
        <img src="im_sbb.png"/>
      </figure>

   
      <p>Problems with mim short form compile.  All compile error messages stem from inherited resources:</p>  
 
      	<ol>
	<li>Same as in Clause 4.2.6 - Function based behaviour</li>
	</ol>

			</description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="function_based_behaviour">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:introduction">
ISO 10303-1453</module_ref>
defines the information model for function based behaviour. </p>

   <p>
     The top level networking view of Ap233 modules and extensible selects used to enable the function 
     based behaviour implementation module is shown in 
     <clause_ref linkend="inforeqt:figure:fbb">figure 4-3</clause_ref>. The associated USE FROM detail is 
     provided in <module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:4_interfaces">ISO 10303-1453 Clause 4.1</module_ref>  
     and the associated members of each extensible select type list are provided in 
     <module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:4_types">ISO 10303-1453 Clause 4.2</module_ref>.
     <module_ref linkend="ap233_systems_engineering:f_usage_guide">ISO 10303-433 Annex F</module_ref> 
     collects all concept maps identified.</p>

      <figure id="fbb" number="4-3">
        <title>Function based behaviour modules used and extensible selects</title>
        <img src="im_fbb.png"/>
      </figure>
   
   <p>Problems with mim short form compile.  All compile error messages stem from inherited resources:</p>   
   <ol>
   <li>SCHEMA ISO13584_expressions_schema; see .exp file line 815
TYPE ERROR:  Return value not compatible with function return type;</li>
   <li>SCHEMA ISO13584_IEC61360_dictionary_schema; see .exp file line 776
TYPE ERROR:  Actual parameter at position 1 in length function call not compatible with formal;</li>
   <li>SCHEMA ISO13584_IEC61360_dictionary_schema; see .exp file line 791
TYPE ERROR:  No right hand selected types compatible for +;</li>
   <li>SCHEMA ISO13584_IEC61360_dictionary_schema; see .exp file line 791
TYPE ERROR:  Right hand side of assignment not compatible with left;</li>
   <li>SCHEMA ISO13584_IEC61360_language_resource_schema; see .exp file line 64
TYPE ERROR:  Actual parameter at position 1 in length function call not compatible with formal;</li>
   <li>SCHEMA ISO13584_IEC61360_language_resource_schema; see .exp file line 85
TYPE ERROR:  Actual parameter at position 1 in length function call not compatible with formal.</li>
   </ol>

      <p>Problems with mim long form compile.  Compile error message stems from RULE validate_dependently_instantiable_entity_data_types FOR
      (action,action_relationship,application_context,application_context_element,
      classification_role,document_type,document_usage_constraint,effectivity,mapped_item,
      product_context,product_definition_context_role);</p>   
   <ol>
   <li>line 3465        all_instances := action + action_relationship + application_context + application_context_element + classification_role + document_type + document_usage_constraint + effectivity + mapped_item + product_context + product_definition_context_role;</li>
   </ol>
   
   </description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="system_structure">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction">
ISO 10303-1450</module_ref>
defines the information model for system structure. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="decision_support">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="decision_support:introduction">
ISO 10303-1486</module_ref>
defines the information model for decision support. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="program_management">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="program_management:introduction">
ISO 10303-1466</module_ref>
defines the information model for program management. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>


		<reqtover module="project_management">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="project_management:introduction">
ISO 10303-1433</module_ref>
defines the information model for project management. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>

		<reqtover module="risk_management">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="risk_management:introduction">
ISO 10303-1467</module_ref>
defines the information model for risk management. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>

		<reqtover module="issue_management">
			<description>
<p>
<module_ref linkend="issue_management:introduction">
ISO 10303-1489</module_ref>
defines the information model for issue management. </p>
			</description>
		</reqtover>

	</inforeqt>
<!--  Terminology map
  <terminology_map>
   mapping of a business to term to an AP term 
    <term_map>
      <description>
        @@@@ description of the mapping @@@
      </description>
      <business_term term_id="@@@@"/>
      <ap_term term_id="@@@@" application_protocol="@@@@"/>
      <module_term term_id="@@@@" module="@@@@"/>
    </term_map>
  </terminology_map> -->
  

 <!-- Activity Model -->
	<aam>
		<idef0>
			<imgfile file="aamidef01.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef02.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef03.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef04.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef05.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef06.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef07.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef08.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef09.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef10.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="aamidef11.xml"/>
		</idef0>
	</aam>

 <!--  Annex C -->
<imp_meths>
<imp_meth general="n" part="21">
  <description>
   @@@@
  </description>
</imp_meth>
</imp_meths>

 <usage_guide>

   <annex_clause title="Introduction">
   <b><i>Haven't decided what to do here yet.  Now it just contains stuff that has not yet 
   been properly placed or organized.</i></b>
   </annex_clause>
   


   <p><b>AP233 Technical foundation</b></p>
 
    <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of systems engineering.</p>
     
   <p>This part of ISO 10303 uses the set of application modules
      for product data management information (the "PDM Modules"). These are
      based on the "PDM Schema" <a href="http://www.pdm-if.org/pdm_schema/"/> that was developed to 
      achieve harmonization between application protocols ISO 10303-203, ISO
      10303-214 and ISO 10303-232.</p>
      
   <p>This part of ISO 10303 has its conceptual base founded in "Concept model" that can be 
   downloaded at
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/Concept_Model.ppt?revision=1.1"/>.
   and its companion semantic dictionary can be downloaded at
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/Concept_Model_Semantic_Dictionary.xls?revision=1.1"/>.
   </p>
   
   <p>These two interwoven documents have been extensively reviewed by the ISO 
   AP233 development team, members of the International Council on Systems Engineering (INCOSE) and
   members of the Object Management Groups (OMG).  The work was performed via the the leadership efforts of
   INCOSE's Model Driven Design working group
   <a href="http://www.incose.org/practice/techactivities/wg/mdsd/"/>.  
   This group has, in its efforts to extend best practices of System Engineering into software engineering succeed 
   in initiating the SysML project within the OMG and assisting with that activity. The home page for the SysML 
   partners is <a href="http://www.sysml.org"/>. The memo of understanding between the 2 groups (INCOSE and OMG) 
   can be downloaded at:
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/OMG-INCOSE-MOU.doc"/>.
   </p>
   
   <p>In mid 2005 AP233 Working draft 1 (AP233-WD1) was delivered.  This delivery captured all that was needed for AP233
   from the perspective of a systems engineer.  Since delivery the STEP/EXPRESS modeling expert 
   group within the AP233 team has been enhancing and restructuring AP233 WD1. The net result, defined herein,
   is much better from the perspective of "information modelling".  However, it is much more 
   difficult to penetrate from the perspective of a systems engineer reviewer.</p>
   
   
   <p><b>Connecting AP233 WD1 with AP233 CD (Committee Draft)</b></p>
   
   <p>The following few paragraphs attempt to bridge the connectivity gap by tracing ap233's evolution and making
   appropriate connects to the stepmod modules used by AP233.</p>
   
   <p>The following 2 figures provide a very high level over view of AP233 WD1 from an organizational and 
   application points of view:   </p>
		<figure> <title>AP233 module organization</title>
			<img src="Slide1.gif"/>	
	</figure>
		<figure> <title>AP233 module application </title>
			<img src="Slide2.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   <p>Figure 3 provides a concept map AP233 as it is presented herein</p>
   
   	<figure> <title>AP233_arm_Concept_Map</title>
			<img src="AP233_arm_Concept_Map.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
   <p>Relative to Figure 3, the top level modules that enable all of AP233's current capability 
   are listed below.  Within each see Annex F for additional discussion and follow hyperlinks
   provided down to the most atomic level of detail:</p>
   <ul>
   <li><module_ref linkend="decision_support:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="issue_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="organization_structure:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="program_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="project_breakdown:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="project_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="project_management_resource_information:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="requirement_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="risk_management:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="schedule:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_behaviour:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_modelling:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction"/>;</li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="work_structure:introduction"/>. </li>
   </ul>

   <p>It should be rather evident from a comparison between Figures 1 and 3 that there has been 
   significant box rearrangement <i>with no significant change in content</i>.  A few not so 
   obvious points need to be stated.</p>
   
   <ul>
   <li>The information model is now partitioned into a program management arm and a system 
   modelling arm.</li>
   <li>In AP233 WD1 "system of systems" is identified.  This is now all covered within the "System
   structure arm".</li>
   <li>In AP233 WD1 many boxes are labeled "connector".  The function that these boxes enabled is now 
   hidden but enabled via the EXPRESS model's Extensible SELECT TYPE capability.</li>
   <li>Figure 2 attempts to show system engineering information modelling connectivity stemming
   from the systems engineer's need to satisfy requirements and enable interfaces.
   Much of this work is also hidden but enabled via the EXPRESS model's Extensible SELECT TYPE 
   capability.
   </li>
   </ul>
   
   <p>The subject domains of validation, verification, test and measurement are covered 
   in the concept model. </p>
   
   <p>Included within this work is the subject of "issues".  A number of 
   early attempts to define and bound this module have been made.  The collected notes on this 
   subject can be downloaded at
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/system_management/Issue%20module%20collected%20notes.ppt?revision=1.1"/>.  </p>
   
   <p>The initial ideas for the system of systems work can be found in Chapter 15 of David Oliver's book "Engineering 
   Complex Systems with Models and Objects".  This can be freely downloaded at 
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/system_engineering/Engineering%20Complex%20Systems%20%28book%29.pdf?revision=1.1"/>.
   </p>

   <p>It is a challenge to encompass all of System Engineering in one standard.  Fortunately documents that reflect a generation of experience supporting 
   real world projects exists.  The following work has been used to guide various aspects of current work so as to make 
   AP233 as complete as possible.</p>

   <p>The first is 
   Vitech Corp's.<a href="http://www.vitechcorp.com/"/> schema for their CORE software product.
   This can be downloaded at 
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/system_engineering/Vitech%20Corp%20CORE%20Schema.zip?revision=1.1"/>.  
   This schema has grown through a generation of system engineering customer support.</p>

   <p>The second is the 
   Department of Defense (US) Architectural framework (DoDAF). The following DoD reference source material
   can be downloaded as a single zip file from:
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/system_engineering/DoDAF%20architecture.zip?revision=1.1"/> </p><ol>
   <li>The DoD Architecture Framework (DoDAF) Version 1.0 (.pdf)  Memorandum by John P. Stenbit, February 9, 2004. 
   The DoDAF Version 1.0 defines a common approach for DoD architecture description, development, presentation, and 
   integration for both warfighting operations and business processes. The DoDAF Version 1.0 supersedes the C4ISR 
   Architecture Framework, Version 2.0 dated December 18, 1997. The DoDAF Version 1.0 is partitioned into two 
   volumes and a deskbook - see links provided directly below:</li>
   <li>DoDAF Version 1.0 - Volume I (.pdf) Provides 
   definitions, guidelines, background material.  </li>
   <li>DoDAF Version 1.0 - Volume II (.pdf) Describes each architecture 
   product.</li>
   <li>DoDAF Version 1.0 - Deskbook (.pdf) Provides supplementary "how to" information relating to 
   architectures.</li></ol>
   
   <p>NOTE: The full set of entities and relationships that exist in tools in use are in scope; while 
   relationships identified are out of scope.  These are unbounded, unknown, and not possible to establish.
   </p>
   
   <p><b>Extend lists for Extensible select types</b></p>
  
  <p>The STEP modules and their associated entities provide modelling capability for a wide
  variety of concepts.  To enable any useful capability these concepts need to be coupled 
  together.  This is done directly via entity attributes or indirectly by what 
  the author views as a publish and subscribe capability.  Type extend lists can be loosely 
  viewed as subscription lists for this capability.</p>
  
  <p>The raw data used to define AP233 type extend lists is contained in a matrix format.  
  This matrix can be downloaded at 
  <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/AP233_pg28_extend_matrix_copy.xls?revision=1.1"/>
  From the data contained within this matrix a series of top level type extend lists are 
  created.  The mapping from matrix data to lists is not 100% deterministic.  The final
  set of lists can be downloaded at
  <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/AP233_top_pg28_extend_copy.exp?revision=1.1"/>
  </p>
  
  <p>These type extend lists when placed in the top level AP233 provide all necessary 
  information model connectivity at the top level.  AP233 however is built up by aggregating 
  the capabilities of many Implementation Modules.  These, too, need type extend lists to 
  enable information coupling at their respective layers of abstraction.  These are possible 
  to derive directly from the set of top level lists that can be downloaded. The algorithm 
  for the creation of these lists is quite simple.  It simply places the full list in an 
  Implementation Module, runs an EXPRESS error checker and then removes all entities that 
  create an error. What remains are all type extends relevant to the Implementation Module. 
  The process is repeated for all Implementation Modules.</p>


   
   
    <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-233: systems engineering">
    <p>This is the Application protocol that collects all Implementation modules together
    into a unified whole.</p>
    
    <p>It is important to note that a modular approach has been applied.  Each Implementation module
    can be implemented stand-alone.  As Implentation modules are joined to form higher level 
    Implementation modules within the context of systems engineering they must be networked
    together.  This is done via the use of the EXPRESS modeling language "Extensible Select" capability.
    Each Implentation module that joins lower level Implementation modules has an extensive set of 
    associated extensible select lists that provide the necessary degree of information networking</p>
    
    <p>Reference Systems enginerring "Process" standards" Our AAM derived from this quagmire
    with ISO 15288.  Also reference INCOSE, NASA, David's book plus Mike and Davids favorite</p>
    
    <p>The Application Activity Model (AAM) for Ap233 was developed in the 1998-2000 time frame when 
    ISO 15288 was nearing completion.  ISO 15288 established a common framework for describing systems 
    engineering for system life cycle processes.  Other standards also existed.  Rather than tie Ap233 
    to one particular systems engineering process standard a common information modelling need thread 
    that supported all was sought.  The AAM presented in <clause_ref linkend="aam"/> reflects this effort.
    </p>
    
    <p>With this common information modelling need thread as a base it was essential to establish a semantic 
    foundation upon which Ap233 could evolve. This work is reflected in the Ap233 Concept model that became the 
    semantic foundation for both AP233 and SysML. The Concept model is presented 
    in <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:Concept Model for Systems Engineering">Concept Model for Systems Engineering</clause_ref>.</p>

    
    <p>Hyperlink to Concept model</p>
    
    <p>Hyperlink to Ap 433</p>
      </annex_clause>

    <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-433: systems engineering">
    <p>This is the top level Implementation modules it collects all lower level implementaiton 
    modules together.  It is directly referenced by ISO 100303-233.</p>
       <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1466 program management">
              <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1466 project management">
	      </annex_clause>
              <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1467 risk management">
	      </annex_clause>
              <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1489 issue management">
	      </annex_clause>
       </annex_clause>
       <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1477: system modelling">
              <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1448 system behaviour">
	      </annex_clause>
		      <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1453 function based behaviour">
		      </annex_clause>
		      <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1371 state based behaviour">
		      </annex_clause>
              <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1450 system structure">
	      </annex_clause>
              <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1486 decision support">
		      <annex_clause title="ISO 10303-1348 requirement management">
		      </annex_clause>
		      <annex_clause title="Enabling analysis">
		      </annex_clause>
		      <annex_clause title="Enabling trade-off">
		      </annex_clause>
		      <annex_clause title="Enabling verification and validation">
		      </annex_clause>
	      </annex_clause>
       </annex_clause>  
       <annex_clause title="Useful hyperlinks">
	     <ol>
		<li> <a href="http://syseng.omg.org/UML_for_SE_RFP.htm"/> </li>
		<li> <a href="www.omgsysml.org/MBSE_Methodology_Survey_RevA.pdf"/> </li>
		<li> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_engineering"/> </li>
	    </ol>
       </annex_clause>  
    </annex_clause>
 </usage_guide>
 
 
<!--  Annex K Technical discussion  -->
 
 <tech_disc>
 
<annex_clause title="Concept model for systems engineering">
<p>This annex provides the concept model for systems engineering that was the foundation for 
developing this part of ISO 10303.  Together with the terms defined in 
clause <clause_ref linkend="definition:Application activity model">3</clause_ref> of this part, 
this model defines the breath and scope of capability while also providing the semantic reference 
base and model based requirements that were used to drive development of this part of ISO 10303.</p>
 
<p>The definitions in clause 3 explain meanings in natural language. The model captures the 
multitude of relationships in a graphic form so that the relationships can be scanned. 
Figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug13"> K-1</clause_ref> provides a guide for interpreting the 
models prsented in this annex.    
</p>
		<figure id="ug13" number="K-1"> 
		<title>Key to diagrams</title>
		<img src="ug_figure13.png"/>	
		</figure>

<annex_clause title="Top level model">
<p>The model defined in figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug1"> K-2</clause_ref>
is patterned after UML 1, with indications of semantics that are missing from the language.
The model needs to be read with reference to the definitions in the semantic dictionary. It 
starts with Element that is any thing on which repeated measurements can be made for the 
engineering purposes of interest. This is  a necessary definition because otherwise it is not 
possible to verify that a design or implementation meets its requirements. Element is built from 
Element in a hierarchy. The aggregation symbol has a small "C" in it to show that what is meant 
is a decomposition into all of the parts. The special notation is used because this concept is
missing from UML 1.</p>
		
		<figure id="ug1" number="K-2"> 
		<title>Top level concept model</title>
		<img src="ug_figure1.png"/>	
		</figure>
 
<p>The Domain of Interest constitutes all the things of interest to the application.</p>

<p>System is a kind of Element and thus it is built of systems in a hierarchy and it must have 
measurable characteristics that are repeatable. What makes the System unique is that it has well 
defined relationships with all of the things with which it interacts. The collection of those 
things is its Environment. To have a system it is necessary to characterize what is in the 
system and what is in the environment along with the static and dynamic interactions between 
system and environment. The Environment contains Elements and Systems.</p>
<p>
Different persons in engineering, manufacturing, maintenance, and management need different 
sets of information about the system. Manufacturing personnel need to know about all the 
materials, nuts and rivets that go into the system and how they assemble together. Maintenance 
personnel need to have diagnostic information and deal with replaceable units of the system. 
There are a very large number of such useful collections of information, each with its own 
context.  System View provides for the collection of such sets of information, each set in a 
particular context.</p>
<p>
An important subset of things in the environment are the Stakeholders. These are all the persons 
and organizations with a need, preference, or interest in the system. Stakeholders may include 
manufacturer, owner, user of owner's services, user of the system, operator, maintainer, 
government regulator. Stakeholder Need represents their need, preference, interest, etc. 
in the system. If the System is designed and implemented well, then it satisfies these needs 
in a manner that is superior to competitive systems. It sells in the marketplace.</p>
<p>
A Property is a named measurable or observable attribute, quality or  characteristic of an 
se_thing. If you can measure it or observe it it is called a property. Properties have units, 
values, variances and probability distributions associated with them.  They may be looked up 
in handbooks of properties of standard materials, they may be calculated from the structure 
of the thing, or they may be measured directly. In general they are tensors and may be a 
function of time. Because of the multiple ways of arriving at a property and its values, 
it is important to have a Reference Document that establishes the source of the information.</p>
<p>
A Requirement is a statement of a Property that a System shall exhibit.  The relationship to 
System is handled by allocating the requirement to the system that shall exhibit that property. 
This formality allows the engineer to consider alternative allocations to different systems 
that may fulfill the requirement. It is fundamental to trade-off among solutions. Requirements 
originate from Stakeholder Needs. As the design proceeds in levels of detail, requirements are 
derived from other requirements. These "derived from" relationships are preserved as traceability 
relationships. In a real world problem requirements will be changed from time to time. It is 
critical to trace from a requirement that has changed to other requirements impacted by that change.</p>
<p>
It is useful to distinguish among three kinds of properties.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<b>Structure</b> the description of how a system decomposes into its parts and how the 
parts assemble to make the whole.</li>
<li>
<b>Behavior</b> what the system does in response to the things in its environment. This 
includes both desired responses that satisfy needs, and prevention of undesired responses 
(failures) that can cause injury, destruction, or loss.</li>
<li>
<b>Physical Property</b> includes all the measurable or observable attributes, qualities or 
characteristic of an Element that cannot be observed in interaction with the environment. 
Additional instruments or tools are required to make the measurement or observation. Mass 
may require a scale for weighing, index of refraction may require use of an optical instrument.</li></ul>
<p>
These three kinds of properties are described separately and then interrelated. This 
principle supports the consideration of alternatives
</p>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(1) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_element"> element</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(2) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_category"> category</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(3) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_domain of interest"> domain of interest</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(4) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_system"> system</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(5) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_system_view"> system_view</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(6) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_environment"> environment</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(7) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_stakeholder"> stakeholder</clause_ref></i> Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(8) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_stakeholder need"> stakeholder need</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(9) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_property"> property</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(10) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_system requirement"> system requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(11) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_reference document"> reference document</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(12) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_behaviour"> behaviour</clause_ref> </i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(13) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_physical property"> physical property</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(14) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_structure"> structure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="System static structure">
<p>Figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug2"> K-3</clause_ref> provides a graphical 
depiction of the system's static structure. Structure is built from Part, Port, and Interface 
Specification. Structure decomposes  hierarchically. This forces Part and Port to also 
decompose hierarchically. </p>
		<figure id="ug2" number="K-3"> 
		<title>System static structure</title>
		<img src="ug_figure2.png"/>	
</figure>

<p>
The Part is simply a part or component list. The name used  follows the STEP manufacturing 
point of view of looking at a part or component and talking about it as an assembly because 
their job is to assemble it.</p>
<p>
Each Part (part or component) attaches to others at particular locations. These locations are 
called Ports. This is a familiar idea when one thinks of the port on a power cord that plugs 
into a port on the wall to get electric power. It also applies to the surface of a bridge, a 
port, that interacts with wind, is a port. In the second case the concept is less intuitive and 
more formal. Ports connect to ports.</p>
<p>
Interconnection specifies which ports attach to which other ports. Together Part, Port, and 
Interconnection specify how parts go together to constitute the whole. This description 
does not include Behavior or Physical Properties.
</p>
<p>
Each port has associated with it a description, an Interface Specification, that describes 
the geometry, forces, transferred material or energy or information, protocols, how to 
assemble to it, and tests that may be required of the port-to-port connection. For two 
ports to be interconnected  their interfaces must be compatible. 
</p>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(14) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_structure"> structure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
<li><i>(15) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_part"> part</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(16) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_link"> link</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(17) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_port"> port</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(18) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_interconnection"> interconnection</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(19) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_interface specification"> interface specification</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Structure, behavior and physical property">
<p>
Structure, Behavior and Physical Properties are described separately. Behavior and Physical 
Properties are allocated or budgeted to Part to complete the description.
</p>
<p>
Behavior is built from Function, I/O (Input/Output), and Function Ordering as shown in 
figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug3"> K-4</clause_ref>. Any Element may 
be I/O (Light blue shows an entity comes from figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug1"> K-2</clause_ref>). A 
Function is a entity of transformation that changes a set of inputs to a set of outputs. 
Function Ordering orders the functions such that it is possible to represent sequence, 
concurrency, branching, and iteration.
</p>
<p>
There are two major forms of representing Behavior. Function based behavior, independent 
of state, emerged in systems engineering in the 1970's. It provides for completed functions 
to enable succeeding functions, for I/O to trigger functions, and for ordering operators 
to represent sequence, branching, and iteration. The SEDRES model represents this with a 
Petrie net model. UML 2.0 contributors may be using a Petrie Net model. If so, then these 
two models need careful comparison.
</p>

	<figure id="ug3" number="K-4"> 
	<title>Behavior</title>
		<img src="ug_figure3.png"/>	
</figure>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(1) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_element"> element</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(4) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_system"> system</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(6) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_environment"> environment</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(12) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_behaviour"> behaviour</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_function"> function</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(21) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_I/O"> I/O</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
<li><i>(22) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_function ordering"> function ordering</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Description function based behavior">
<p>
A model for Function Based Behavior is given in figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug12"> K-4</clause_ref>. I/O may trigger functions, 
starting or terminating functions. I/O that triggers is coupled to the function by 
binding to a Function Control Port. I/O that does not trigger is bound to a Regular 
Function Port. I/O arriving while a function is active is stored in a queue unless 
it is terminating I/O.
</p>
<p>
Function ordering uses a set of operators: AND to define concurrency, Multi-exit 
Function or OR to represent alternative paths, a sequence operator, and LOOP, Iterate, 
and Replicate constructs. LOOP and ITERATE require limits to control their termination. 
Scripts are used to provide detailed control of function ordering. Probabilities are 
assigned to Or Out to facilitate execution of the behavior to produce time lines or 
Monte Carlo simulation.
</p>
<p>
After tools are to exchange behavior information that includes timing, the tool 
interpretation engines may execute the models to produce time lines or perform Monte 
Carlo calculations. These results will differ unless the tools agree on function activation rules. 
</p>
</annex_clause>

	<annex_clause title="Resource">
<p>
Resource is: 
</p>
<ul>
<li>the amount of input available to a function or the amount of output available from it.</li>
<li> or the amount of property of a system available to a function.</li>
</ul>
<example>There exists some number of missiles available to a missile battery available 
for the function "Shoot".</example>
<example>
The function "transmit message" may be allocated to a satellite system, a fiber optic 
line, a microwave link, etc. Each of these alternatives has some value of the property 
"bandwidth" that may be used by the function.</example>
<p>
Function - Resource Relationships
</p>
<p>
Captures: Captures indicates the resource that this object requires (but does not destroy) 
during execution. Resources are captured when the execution of the function begins and 
released when the function completes execution.  
</p>
<p>
Consumes: Consumes indicates the resource that this object requires (and destroys) during 
execution. Resources are consumed when the execution of the function begins. 
</p>
<p>
Produces: Produces indicate the resource that is generated by the function. Resources are 
produced when the execution of the function completes.
</p>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Function activation rules">
<p>
The representative set of activation rules are shown in figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug4"> K-5</clause_ref> are defined as follows:
</p>
	<figure id="ug4" number="K-5"> 
	<title>Function based behavior</title>
	<img src="ug_figure4.png"/>	
	</figure>
<p>
Start Rule - A function is activated and begins its work if and only if all preceding 
functions and threads of functions have completed and all inputs that trigger the 
function are present at the function control ports. A function begins work if and only 
all resources to be utilized by that function are available. Otherwise it waits.
</p>
<p>
Run Rule -  Trigger signals received while a function is active are stored in queues. 
</p>
<p>
Terminate Rule - Functions complete generation of all their outputs, terminate, and 
pass activation to the next function when the time interval allocated to them expires. 
Functions complete production of all resources and return any resources that were 
captured during execution.</p>
<p>
I/O Queuing Rules
</p>
<p>
A representative set of queuing rules follows:
</p>
<p>
Triggering I/O that arrives at function is stored in a FIFO queue. On its next activation 
the function uses the I/O first stored in the queue. 
</p>
<p>Non-trigger signals received while a function is active are discarded. Non-trigger 
signals received while a function is dormant are stored in    LIFO queues. It is the 
last I/O received that is used.
</p>
<p>

The Function Exit Construct
</p>
<p>
A Function Exit construct links a functional decomposition to the exit paths identified 
for the parent function. For example, assume you have a Multi-exit Function with two exit 
paths. If this is the leaf-level of your model, scripting (or probabilities if no script 
is defined) selects which path to take.
</p>
<p>
However, if this function is decomposed, there are Function Exit constructs corresponding 
to the two exit paths in the higher level function. When one of the Exit constructs is 
encountered, execution of the decomposition is complete and control is passed to the 
corresponding exit path at the higher level.
</p>
<p>
State based behavior emerged from automata theory and has matured into State Charts that 
provide for state explosion in highly concurrent models. SEDRES has a representation for 
this and has demonstrated model transfer between Statemate and Teamwork Real Time tools.
</p><p>
In the UML community Action Semantics are to provide a basis for state based behavior. 
These two approaches require careful correlation. The concept model here does not go 
beyond the very general notion of function ordering, but notes the critical importance 
of correlation among emerging detailed models.</p>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(12.1) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_function based behaviour"> function based behaviour</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.1) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_timing"> timing</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.2) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_script"> script</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.3) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_function port"> function port</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.4) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_queue"> queue</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.5) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_regular function port"> regular function port</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.6) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_control function port"> control function port</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.7) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_regular function port"> regular function port</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(20.8) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_function exit"> function exit</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.1) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_ordering operations"> ordering operations</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.2) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_replicate"> replicate</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.3) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_and"> and</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.4) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_and out"> and out</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.5) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_and in"> and in</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.6) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_iterate"> iterate</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.7) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_iterate limit"> iterate limit</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.8) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_loop"> loop</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.9) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_loop limit"> loop limit</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.10) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_loop exit"> loop exit</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.11) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_sequence"> sequence</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.12) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_or"> or</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.13) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_or out"> or out</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.14) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_multi-exit function"> multi-exit function</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.15) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_or in"> or in</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.16) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_probability"> probability</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.17) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_activation rules"> activation rules</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.18) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_start rules"> start rules</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.19) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_run rules"> run rules</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(22.20) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_terminate rules"> terminate rules</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Structure and physical properties">
<p>
Physical Property, its relationship to the Structure hierarchy and to analysis is shown figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug5"> K-6</clause_ref>. The key concept is that 
performance, behavior and physical properties of 
the whole results from the structure, the behavior and physical properties of the parts. 
They are not related to a class tree.
</p>
		<figure id="ug5" number="K-6"> 
		<title>Structure and physical property</title>
		<img src="ug_figure5.png"/>	
		</figure>

<p>
System Assemblies in the Part tree all have Physical Properties such as mass, power 
consumption, geometry, MTBF, drag coefficient, etc. The Physical Properties are assigned 
to a particular Part. A Physical Property has a name and an ID that identifies it 
uniquely. For example, many different System Assemblies have the Physical Property mass. 
Consequently each of these assigned Physical Properties needs an ID. Each has an 
associated unit in which it is measured.
</p>
<p>
A Physical Property assigned to a particular Part has values. The value may be expressed 
as a mean, a mean with variance, a probability distribution, or a histogram. All of these 
values are a result of a set of measurements and analysis of the data. The value goes 
through a series of versions as the system definition evolves. The Part is declared to 
have a Required or Budgeted Value.  The Part may have a Target Budget Property Value 
used as a guide or target as designers consider alternatives. A Part, as a whole, may 
have a Calculated Property Value based on analysis of the properties, behaviors and 
interactions of its parts. When a Part is built, it may have a Measured Property Value. 
</p>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(13) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_physical property"> physical property</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(14) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_structure"> structure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
<li><i>(15) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_part"> part</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(17) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_port"> port</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(18) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_interconnection"> interconnection</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(19) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_interface specification"> interface specification</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
<li><i>(25) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_unit"> unit</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(26) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_property value"> property value</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(27) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_required/budgeted property value"> required/budgeted property value</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(28) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_calculated property value"> calculated property value</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(29) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_targeted budget property value"> targeted budget property value</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(30) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_measured property value"> measured property value</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(31) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_model parameter"> model parameter</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(32) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_parameter assignment"> parameter assignment</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(33) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_analytical representation"> analytical representation</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(34) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_analytical model"> analytical model</clause_ref></i> - definition is in Clause 3.6. </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>


<annex_clause title="Calculated property values - analytical modeling">
<p>
Any one assembly is an interconnection of assemblies one tier down in the tree. The emergent 
properties of any assembly are a result of the properties, interconnection,and interaction of 
the sub-assemblies from which it is built. The relationships may be very non-linear in the 
physical world as observed with phenomena like combustion and friction.
</p>
<p>
 The basic relationships for analytical modeling of emergent properties and budgeting of 
 properties are shown in Figure 5. A set of engineering equations or estimates, analytical  
 models, are used by systems engineers to budget properties to the interacting sub-assemblies 
 as a guide to designers at the lower level. When designs for all of the sub-assemblies are 
 available, their individual properties and interactions are better defined. The same 
 equations are used to calculate the emergent properties of the complete assembly. The 
 fidelity of the calculations increases as the work proceeds.
</p>
<p>
A Part, as a whole, may have a Calculated Property Value based on analysis of the 
properties, behaviors and interactions of its parts. This is accomplished by estimation 
or by an analysis that solves the relevant engineering equations. This makes it necessary 
to represent physical properties as parameters in the equations of the relevant analysis 
model. Model Parameter provides this parameterization. It has an attribute of its of the 
unit of measure applicable to the analysis. This may be different from the unit assigned 
to Physical Property. The reference_document attribute specifies the standard document 
that contains the reference for the Model_parameter. A default value and valid range 
can be specified when needed.
</p>
<p>
Parameter_assignment assigns parameters to model_parameter that in turn is a  parameter 
for analytical_model. Analytical_representation has a set of parameter_assignments and 
is modeled by one or several analytical models. be solved, Analytical _representation. 
The several Analytical_models provide answers at different levels of fidelity and with 
different efforts of computation. AM_port connects the analytical results back to the 
appropriate location in the part hierarchy. 
</p>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Emergent properties and budgeting of properties example"> 
<p>
One may wish to develop a car that can accelerate from zero to sixty  miles per hour 
in 6.5 seconds or less. This is a required emergent property of the car with elements shown in 
figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug6a"> K-7</clause_ref>.  This behavior 
is a result of the power of the drive train, the air resistance of the body, the total 
mass of the car, and the friction of the tires on the road. These parameters are 
inter-related by a second order differential equation.
</p>
<p>
The differential equation is first used to budget target values of mass, power, drag 
coefficient, and tire friction to the appropriate components as targets for the designers. 
When the designs are available with definite property values, the same equations are used 
to calculate the emergent property, time for acceleration from zero to sixty mph for the car.  
</p>
<p>
Note that there may be several distinctly different approaches to the solution of what 
sub-components to use. Thus it is useful for the assembly to have relationships that 
indicate if it is an alternative or is selected as a solution, if it meets requirements, 
and what its regularization function value may be as the basis of selecting a particular 
solution from among the alternatives.  
</p>
		<figure id="ug6a" number="K-7"> 
		<title>Automobile example</title>
		<img src="ug_figure6a.png"/>	
</figure>

		<figure id="ug6" number="K-8"> 
		<title>Engineering equations</title>
		<img src="ug_figure6.png"/>	
</figure>
<p>
The table in figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ugt1"> K-9</clause_ref> provides 
a crude map of how the equations in figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug6"> K-8</clause_ref> map into the concept model 
defined in Figure 4 for the car example. Only the properties of car have been mapped. 
Note there are two analytical models. One is very simple and assumes constant traction 
once the car is in motion and rolling friction applies. The second is of higher fidelity 
and uses traction vs. Rpm. from actual engine data, including transmission gear changing.
</p>
		<figure id="ugt1" number="K-9"> 
		<title>Equation to concept model mapping</title>
		<img src="ug_table1.png"/>	
</figure>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Model parameter">
<p>
A Model_parameter is a formally declared variable of the analytical model provided 
for an external application to populate at execution time in a computing environment. 
</p>
<example>
In Spice, temperature is a Model_parameter that may be set at the execution time. 
</example>
<p>
Parameter_assignment
</p>
<p>
Parameter_assignment provides actual values for characteristics declared formally 
by the Model_parameter.
</p>
<p>
Analytical_representation
</p>
<p>
An Analytical_representation is the association of specific properties of specific 
System Assemblies with an Analytical_model in order to unambiguously characterize the 
performance of a specific Part.
</p>
<note>
This entity accomplishes a function similar to the parameter assignment part of a 
statement in a Spice netlist, or a function or subroutine call in a computer program. 
This capability is useful where the parts in the library have many parameters, not 
all of which apply to each simulation model that could be used for the part. This 
entity matches up the correct parameter values with the correct model.</note>
<note>The properties specified should be in accordance with the capabilities and 
limitations of the Analytical_model. That is, the mathematical formulations in the 
Analytical_model apply over limited ranges of real product characteristics and 
environmental characteristics.</note>
<note>This part of ISO 10303 does not standardize qualification of Analytical_representations 
for an intended usage.
</note>
<p>
Analytical_model
</p>
<p>
Provides a mathematical description of the properties of a system. An Analytical_model 
may be a Library_model.
</p>
<note>In this part of ISO 10303 an Analytical_model includes the variable declarations 
of the mathematical description but may not include the assignment of actual values 
for the variables declared. 
</note>
<note>
This part of ISO 10303 provides support for computer systems to verify type consistency 
between product data defined in this part of ISO 10303 and product data captured by 
Analytical_models. 
</note>
<note>
This part of ISO 10303 describes the interfaces (ports) to an Analytical_model and 
provides  support for type checking of the units used for the parameters that may be 
assigned values for an Analytical_model.
</note>
<example>
Consider the case where actual values are not included: the Analytical_model for a 
resistor that is coded in pseudocode. When the Analytical_model is referenced by an 
analytical_representation, literals will be supplied for items declared in the 
interface; both connections and their parameters, and the simulator will ensure that 
types are compatible. 
</example>
<p>
Probability Distributions
</p>
<p>
Probabilities are applied to the values of physical properties, and to the performance 
requirement time duration assigned to functions. A list follows of representative 
probability distributions used in systems engineering tools: . 
<i>Normal, Log-normal, Bernoulli, Negative Binomial, Beta, Poission, Binomial, T,
Chi squared, Triangular, Discrete uninformed, Uniform, Erlang, Weibull
Expoonetial, F, Gamma, Geometric, Laplace.</i>
</p>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Allocation of requirements">
<p>
Depending upon their content, requirements are allocated to different parts of the 
information model. Requirements describing functions are allocated to functions, etc. 
This is a useful way of classifying requirements for the purpose of creating a logically 
consistent model or description of a system.
</p>
<p>
Within systems engineering there is no single standardized way of classifying requirements 
and many different classifications for different purposes are in use.  The classification 
given in figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug7"> K-10</clause_ref> 
is defined as shown because it is useful for the purpose allocating or assigning requirements.
</p>
<p>
It is not possible to enforce any process with an information model and AP233 is intended 
to support both pest practices and other practices in use. Hence, any collection of 
requirements may contain compound requirements, contradictory requirements, and non-feasible 
requirements. Consequently the generalization/specialization of figure 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug7"> K-10</clause_ref> is non-exhaustive and inclusive. 
</p>
		<figure id="ug7" number="K-10"> 
		<title>Classification of requirements for the purpose of allocation</title>
		<img src="ug_figure7.png"/>	
		</figure>

<p>
Figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug8"> K-11</clause_ref> provides a summary of the 
allocation relationships depicted.
</p>
<ul>
<li>
 Requirements are assigned to functions
</li>
<li>
 Performance Requirements are assigned to functions
</li>
<li>
 Function is allocated to Part (red used because of line crossings)
</li>
<li>
 I/O is bound to ports (red used because of line crossings)
</li>
<li>
 Interface Requirements are assigned to Interfaces
</li>
<li>
 Physical Property Requirements are assigned to Part
</li>
<li>
 Imposed Design is assigned to the Part on which it is imposed
</li>
<li>
Reference Requirements point to a Reference Source that may contain requirements of 
all the kinds in the classification
</li>
</ul>

		<figure id="ug8" number="K-11"> 
		<title>Requirement allocations</title>
		<img src="ug_figure8.png"/>	
		</figure>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(10) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_system requirement"> system requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(27) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_required/budgeted property value"> required/budgeted property value</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(28) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_reference source"> reference source</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(35) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_functional requirement"> functional requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(36) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_performance requirement"> performance requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(37) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_physcial property requirement"> physcial property requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(38) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_interface requirement"> interface requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(39) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_imposed design requirement"> imposed design requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(40) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_reference requirement"> reference requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(42) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_effectiveness measure"> effectiveness measure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(43) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_optimization direction"> optimization direction</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(44) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_weight"> weight</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(45) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_regularization function"> regularization function</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6. </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>


<annex_clause title="Physical property and time">
<p>
Figure <clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug10"> K-14</clause_ref>
shows the model for physical property and figure
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug11"> K-15</clause_ref> shows the model for time. 
</p>
<p>
Continuous Time is a dimension along with three spatial dimensions used by science and 
engineering to describe reality using math. It has no past, present or future.
</p>
<p>
 Present Time recognizes a standard of year, month, week, day, hour, minute, and second to 
 represent past, present, and future. It is the basis of plans and schedules.
</p>
<p>
Time Interval provides a time duration that may be assigned to a task or function to represent 
how long the task will take for completion.
</p>
<p>
 Start Time is a Present Time that states where in Present Time a Time Interval begins.
</p>
<p>
 Stop Time is a Present Time that states where in Present Time a Time Interval ends.
</p>
<p>
Discrete Time is time represented by clock pulses of negligible duration.    In this 
approximation events occur on each clock pulse.
</p>
<p>
Time is one of the most accurately measured quantities that we have. Current accuracy of 
measurement is about one part in 10 -13. Research underway may extend this to 10 -17. 
Many properties now have primary standards based in part on time.
</p>
		<figure id="ug9a" number="K-12"> 
		<title>Physical property</title>
		<img src="ug_figure9a.png"/>	
		</figure>

		<figure id="ug9b" number="K-13"> 
		<title>Time breakdown</title>
		<img src="ug_figure9b.png"/>	
		</figure>
		
<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(13) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_physical property"> physical property</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Other models important to systems engineering management">.
<p>
The models for verification, validation and risk are shown in figures
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug10"> K-14</clause_ref>,  
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug11"> K-15</clause_ref> and 
<clause_ref linkend="tech_disc:figure:ug12"> K-16</clause_ref> 
</p>

<note>
These graphical concept models where developed early in the Ap233 creation process.  The elegance of the Ap233 
model that has evolved has enabled all that is outlined within these figure to be accomplished in a manner
that does not obviously mirror the detail shown.
</note>
		<figure id="ug10" number="K-14"> 
		<title>Verification</title>
		<img src="ug_figure10.png"/>	
		</figure>

		<figure id="ug11" number="K-15"> 
		<title>Validation</title>
		<img src="ug_figure11.png"/>	
		</figure>

		<figure id="ug12" number="K-16"> 
		<title>Risk</title>
		<img src="ug_figure12.png"/>	
		</figure>

<annex_clause title="Semanic dictionary">
<ul>
<li><i>(7) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_stakeholder"> stakeholder</clause_ref></i> Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(8) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_stakeholder need"> stakeholder need</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(10) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_system requirement"> system requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(46) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_verification requirement"> verification requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(47) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_verification event"> verification event</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(48) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_verificationn procedure"> verificationn procedure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(49) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_verification configuration"> verification configuration</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(50) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_verification plan"> verification plan</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(51) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_organization"> organization</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(52) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_issue"> issue</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(53) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_risk"> risk</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(54) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_verification requirement status"> verification requirement status</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(55) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_validation requirement"> validation requirement</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(56) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_validation event"> validation event</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(57) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_validation procedure"> validation procedure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(58) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_validation infrastructure"> validation infrastructure</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(59) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_validation plan"> validation plan</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
<li><i>(60) <clause_ref linkend="definition:ap233_validation requirement status"> validation requirement status</clause_ref></i> - Clause 3.6; </li>
</ul>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

<annex_clause title="Category">.
<p>
The decomposition tree for Part is more than a simple parts tree. At any node one may 
introduce a category of parts. For example, an automobile may have several different engines 
that can be used in the automobile, each providing a different level of economy and performance.
</p>
<p>
Categories are a grouping of elements into a set based on defined properties that serve as 
selection criteria for which elements of all those in the universe belong in that set Explanation: 
It is categorization that enables us to define alternatives and create taxonomies for libraries. 
This is one of the forms of  generalization/specialization. Note that this is NOT INHERITANCE as 
found in object-oriented software languages. Physical elements, matter and energy, do not inherit 
their properties. Rather they posses the properties of themselves and can be identified by 
measurement of those properties. For a discussion of these issues in computer science see the work 
of Barbara Liskov and her CLU language.
</p>
<note>The subcategories may be exclusive or inclusive and the subcategories may exhaust the super 
category or not there are four such possibilities 
</note>
<p>
Category is the basic concept in the physical world to support specialization - generalization.
</p>
</annex_clause>
</annex_clause>

 </tech_disc>
	<bibliography>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISOIEC8859-1_1987"/>
		
		<bibitem published="y">
<!--		<bibitem id="ISO-IEC-15288">  -->
		<orgname>ISO</orgname>
		<stdnumber>ISO/IEC 15288-2002</stdnumber>          
		<stdtitle>Systems engineering; Systems life cycle processes </stdtitle>             
		</bibitem>


		<bibitem published="y">
		<pubdate>2002</pubdate>
		<stdtitle> Relationships between Common Graphical Representations in Systems Engineering</stdtitle> 
		<subtitle>Jim Long, ViTech Corporation  http://www.vitechcorp.com/library/papers.php</subtitle> 
		</bibitem>

		<bibitem published="y">
		<pubdate>1998</pubdate>
		<stdtitle> Systems Engineering and Analysis</stdtitle> 
		<subtitle>Benjamin S. Blanchard and Wolter J. Fabrycky</subtitle> 
		</bibitem>

		<bibitem published="y">
		<pubdate>1997</pubdate>
		<stdtitle> Engineering Complex Systems with Models and Objects</stdtitle> 
		<subtitle>David W. Oliver, Timothy P Kelliher and James G. Keegan, Jr.</subtitle> 
		</bibitem>

</bibliography>
  </application_protocol>
