<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
	name="ap210_interconnect_design_for_microwave" 
	name.french="Conception d'interconnexion pour micro-onde pour l'AP 210"
	part="1618" version="1" sc4.working_group="3" wg.number="2019" wg.number.arm="2020" wg.number.arm_lf="2021" wg.number.mim="2022" wg.number.mim_lf="2023" wg.number.supersedes="1652" wg.number.arm.supersedes="1653" wg.number.mim.supersedes="1654" wg.number.arm_lf.supersedes="1716" wg.number.mim_lf.supersedes="1717" checklist.internal_review="2075" checklist.project_leader="2076" checklist.convener="2077" status="TS" language="E" publication.year="2006" publication.date="2006-09-15" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2006/02/23 15:18:34 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.22 $" development.folder="dvlp">
    <keywords>
    module, elelctrical, interconnect, embedded, microwave, requirement, shape, specification, geometric dimensioning, geometric tolerance, fabrication requirement, design view, usage view, layered electrical product design, signal prioritizatin, routing, wiring, boundary element method
 </keywords>
    
    <contacts>
        <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
        <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
    </contacts>
    <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of interconnect design for microwave.
This data is similar to Class 9, with the exception that the metallization may be considered
to be microstrip or stripline, with a specified shape element of the cross-section(i.e., point,
edge, cutting plane) acting as the terminal(terminal pair, port) of the line or component. Use
of formal external definitions is provided to link in models with the product definition data.
Analytical model terminals may be typed as having distributed parameters. This data identifies
those elements that do not meet design requirements. This data includes both design view
and usage view of the interconnect product. Support for specification of signal prioritization is
provided. Support for specifying the explicit network topology to be implemented is provided.
Configuration management information and design management information is provided. This
data includes at least one geometric representation.
   </p>
 </purpose>
    <inscope>
      <li>two dimensional layered interconnect substrate;</li>
      <li>configuration management data;</li>
      <li>design management data;</li>
      <li>three dimensional layered interconnect substrate;</li>
      <li>three dimensional molded interconnect substrate;</li>
      <li>material conductivity classification;</li>
      <li>as-routed connections;</li>
      <li>embedded components;</li>
      <li>test points;</li>
      <li>tolerance based cutout design;</li>
      <li>tolerance based cavity design;</li>
      <li>as-required connections;</li>
      <li>partially routed connections;</li>
      <li>pre-defined printed templates for design re-use;</li>
      <li>geometric properties for trace layout;</li>
      <li>geometric properties for pad taper layout;</li>
      <li>explicit definition of terminals of the interconnect substrate;</li>
      <li>explicit definition of cavities and cutouts of the interconnect substrate required for components;</li>
      <li>mapping between the explicit definition of terminals and internal design features;</li>
      <li>printed template definitions with terminals defined using boundary element method;</li>
      <li>printed template definitions with terminals defined with an edge;</li>
      <li>printed template definitions with terminals defined with a cross-section area.</li>
      <!--        
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="ap210_interconnect_design:1_scope">Ap210 interconnect design</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1617.</li>
-->
      <li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="ap210_interconnect_design:1_scope">Ap210 interconnect design</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1617.</li>
   </inscope>
<!--    
   <outscope>
        <li>xxxx</li>
    </outscope>
-->
    <arm>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </arm>
    <arm_lf/>
    <mapping_table>
        
    </mapping_table>
    <mim>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </mim>
    <mim_lf/>    
</module>
