<collection_page page_type="main">
	<h2>
		<a name="defns">3 Terms, definitions and abbreviated terms</a>
	</h2>
	<h2>3.1 Terms defined in ISO 10303-31</h2>
	<p>
         For the purposes of this document,
         the following terms defined in 
         ISO 10303-1
         apply:
      </p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			<a name="term_abstract_test_case">abstract test case</a>;
         </li>
		<li>
			<a name="term_abstract_test_method">abstract test method</a>;
         </li>
		<li>
			<a name="term_conformance_testing">conformance testing</a>;
         </li>
		<li>
			<a name="term_test_purpose">test purpose</a>;
         </li>
		<li>
			<a name="term_verdict">verdict</a>;
         </li>
		<li>
			<a name="term_verdict_criteria">verdict criteria</a>;
         </li>
	</ul>

	<h2>3.2 Other terms and definitions</h2>
      For the purposes of this document, 
      the following terms and definitions apply:
      
      <h4>3.2.1<br/>
		<a name="term_abstract_test_suite">abstract test suite</a>
	  </h4>
	  a part of this International Standard that contains the set of abstract
      test cases necessary for conformance testing of an implementation of an application protocol.

      <h4>3.2.2<br/>
		<a name="term_application">application</a>
	  </h4>
	  a group of one or more processes creating or using product data.

      <h4>3.2.3<br/>
		<a name="term_application_activity_model">application activity model</a><br/>AAM
	  </h4>
	  a model that describes an application in terms
      of its processes and information flows.

      <h4>3.2.4<br/>
		<a name="term_application_context">application context</a>
	  </h4>
	  the environment in which the integrated resources are interpreted
      to support the use of product data in a specific application.

      <h4>3.2.5<br/>
        <a name="term_application_interpreted_construct">application interpreted construct</a><br/>AIC
	  </h4>
	  logical grouping of interpreted constructs that supports
      a specific function for the usage of product data across multiple application contexts

      <h4>3.2.6<br/>
		<a name="term_application_interpreted_model">application interpreted model</a><br/>AIM
	  </h4>
	  an information model that uses the integrated
      resources necessary to satisfy the information requirements and constraints of an application reference
      model, within an application protocol.

      <h4>3.2.7<br/>
		<a name="term_application_object">application object</a>
	  </h4>
	  an atomic element of an application reference model that defines a
      unique concept of the application and contains attributes specifying the data elements of the
      object.

      <h4>3.2.8<br/>
		<a name="term_application_module">application module</a><br/>AM
	  </h4>
	  reusable collection of a scope statement, information requirements, mappings and <a href="term-module interpreted model">module interpreted model</a> that supports a
      specific usage of product data across multiple application contexts
      	 
      <h4>3.2.9<br/>
		<a name="term_application_protocol">application protocol</a><br/>AP
	  </h4>
	  a part of this International Standard that specifies an application
      interpreted model satisfying the scope and information requirements for a specific
      application.
      <br/>NOTE - This definition differs from the definition used in open system interconnection (OSI) standards.
      However, since this International Standard is not intended to be used directly with OS1
      communications, no confusion should arise.

      <h4>3.2.10<br/>
		<a name="term_application_reference_model">application reference model</a><br/>ARM
	  </h4>
	  an information model that describes the information
      requirements and constraints of a specific application context

      <h4>3.2.11<br/>
		<a name="term_application_resource">application resource</a>
	  </h4>
	  an integrated resource whose contents are related to a group of
      application contexts.

      <h4>3.2.12<br/>
		<a name="term_assembly">assembly</a>
	  </h4>
	  a product that is decomposable into a set of components or other assemblies
      from the perspective of a specific application.

      <h4>3.2.13<br/>
		<a name="term_common_resources">common resources</a>
	  </h4>
	  collection of information models, specified in EXPRESS language, that can be reused to specify application specific information
      models within the domain of industrial data
  	  <p class="note">
		<small>
			<a name="note_2">NOTE</a>
            The resource constructs defined by application modules are those defined in their MIM schema.</small>
	  </p>

      <h4>3.2.14<br/>
		<a name="term_component">component</a>
	  </h4>
	  a product that is not subject to decomposition from the perspective of a
      specific application.

      <h4>3.2.15<br/>
		<a name="term_conformance_class">conformance class</a>
	  </h4>
	  a subset of an application protocol for which conformance may be
      claimed.

      <h4>3.2.16<br/>
		<a name="term_conformance_option">conformance option</a>
	  </h4>
	  a subset of an application protocol for which conformance may be
      claimed in addition to the conformance claimed for a conformance class. ???

      <h4>3.2.17<br/>
		<a name="term_conformance_requirement">conformance requirement</a>
	  </h4>
	  a precise, text definition of a characteristic required to
      be present in a conforming implementation.

      <h4>3.2.18<br/>
		<a name="term_data">data</a>
	  </h4>
	  a representation of information in a formal manner suitable for communication,
      interpretation, or processing by human beings or computers.

      <h4>3.2.19<br/>
		<a name="term_data_exchange">data exchange</a>
	  </h4>
	  the storing, accessing, transferring, and archiving of data.

      <h4>3.2.20<br/>
		<a name="term_data_specification_language">data specification language</a>
	  </h4>
	  a set of rules for defining data and their relationships
      suitable for communication, interpretation, or processing by computers.

      <h4>3.2.21<br/>
		<a name="term_exchange_structure">exchange structure</a>
	  </h4>
	  a computer-interpretable format used for storing, accessing, transferring,
      and archiving data.

      <h4>3.2.22<br/>
		<a name="term_generic_resource">generic resource</a>
	  </h4>
	  an integrated resource whose contents are context-independent.

      <h4>3.2.23<br/>
		<a name="term_implementation_method">implementation method</a>
	  </h4>
	  a part of this International Standard that specifies a technique
      used by computer systems to exchange product data that is described using the EXPREESS
      data specification language [ISO 10303- 11].

      <h4>3.2.24<br/>
		<a name="term_information">information</a>
	  </h4>
	  facts, concepts, or instructions.

      <h4>3.2.25<br/>
		<a name="term_information_model">information model</a>
	  </h4>
	  a formal model of a bounded set of facts, concepts or instructions
      to meet a specified requirement.

      <h4>3.2.26<br/>
		<a name="term_integrated_resource">integrated resource</a><br/>IR
	  </h4>
	  a part of this International Standard that defines a group of
      resource constructs used as the basis for product data.

      <h4>3.2.27<br/>
		<a name="term_interpretation">interpretation</a>
	  </h4>
	  the process of adapting a resource construct from the integrated resources
      to satisfy a requirement of an application protocol. This may involve the addition
      of restrictions on attributes, the addition of constraints, the addition of relationships among
      resource constructs and application constructs, or all of the above.

	  <h4>3.2.28<br/>
		<a name="term_module_interpreted_model">module interpreted model</a><br/>MIM
	   </h4>
	   information model that uses the common resources necessary to satisfy the information requirements and constraints of an application
       reference model,  within an application module
      	 
      <h4>3.2.29<br/>
		<a name="term_pics_proforma">PICS proforma</a>
	  </h4>
	  a standardized document in the form of a questionnaire, which, when
      completed for a particular implementation, becomes the protocol implementation conformance
      statement.

      <h4>3.2.30<br/>
		<a name="term_presentation">presentation</a>
	  </h4>
	  a recognizable visual representation of product data.

      <h4>3.2.31<br/>
		<a name="term_product">product</a>
	  </h4>
	  a thing or substance produced by a natural or artificial process.

      <h4>3.2.32<br/>
		<a name="term_product_data">product data</a>
	  </h4>
	  a representation of information about a product in a formal manner
      suitable for communication, interpretation, or processing by human beings or by computers.

      <h4>3.2.33<br/>
		<a name="term_product_information">product information</a>
	  </h4>
	  facts, concepts, or instructions about a product.

      <h4>3.2.34<br/>
		<a name="term_product_information_model">product information model</a>
	  </h4>
	  an information model which provides an abstract description
      of facts, concepts and instructions about a product.

      <h4>3.2.35<br/>
		<a name="term_protocol_implementation_conformance_statement">protocol implementation conformance statement</a><br/>PICS
	  </h4>
	  a statement of which
      capabilities and options are supported within an implementation of a given standard. This
      statement is produced by completing a PICS proforma.
		
      <h4>3.2.36<br/>
		<a name="term_resource_construct">resource construct</a>
	  </h4>
	  a collection of EXPRESS language entities, types, functions, rules
      and references that together define a valid description of an aspect of product data.

      <h4>3.2.37<br/>
		<a name="term_structure">structure</a>
	  </h4>
	  a set of interrelated parts of any complex thing, and the relationships between them.

      <h4>3.2.38<br/>
		<a name="term_unit_of_functionality">unit of functionality</a><br/>UOF
	  </h4>
	  a collection of application objects and their relationships that
      defines one or more concepts within the application context such that removal of any component
      would render the concepts incomplete or ambiguous.

	<h2>
		<a name="abbrv">3.3 Abbreviated terms
            </a>
	</h2>
	<p>
         For the purposes of this document, the following abbreviated terms
         apply:
         
      </p>
	<table width="80%">
		<tr>
			<td>AIC</td>
			<td>application interpreted construct</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>AM</td>
			<td>application module</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>ARM</td>
			<td>application reference model</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>IR</td>
			<td>integrated resource</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>STEP</td>
			<td>Standard for the Exchange of Product Model Data ???WE REALLY WANT THIS???</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>SMRL</td>
			<td>STEP Module and Resource Library</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>URL</td>
			<td>uniform resource locator</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</collection_page>
