<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../xsl/part1000/collection_page.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection_page [
<!ENTITY % characters SYSTEM "characters.ent"> 
%characters; 
]>
<collection_page page_type="main">
  <h2 id="overview">3 Overview of ISO 10303</h2>
  <h3 id="overview_purpose">3.1 Purpose</h3>
  <p>The purpose of ISO 10303 is to specify a form for the unambiguous representation and exchange of computer-interpretable <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product_data">product data</link> throughout the life of a <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link>. This form is independent of any particular computer system. This form enables consistent implementations across multiple <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link> and systems. ISO 10303 permits different <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> to be used for storing, accessing, transferring, and archiving <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product_data">product data</link>. Implementations can be tested for conformance.</p>
  <h3 id="overview_scope">3.2 Scope of ISO 10303</h3>
  <p>ISO 10303 provides a representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> along with the
    necessary mechanisms and definitions to enable <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product_data">product data</link> to be exchanged. The exchange
    is among different computer systems and environments associated with the complete <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link>
    lifecycle, including <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link> design, manufacture, use, maintenance, and final disposition.</p>
  <p>The following are within the scope of ISO 10303:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link>, including components and assemblies;</li>
    <li>exchange of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product_data">product data</link>, including storing, transferring, accessing, and archiving.</li>
  </ul>
  <h3 id="overview_principles">3.3 Fundamental principles</h3>
  <p>ISO 10303 separates the techniques of representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> from the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> used for <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_data_exchange">data exchange</link>.</p> 
  <p>The representation techniques provide a single representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> common to many <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link>. This common representation can be tailored to meet the needs of specific <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link>. An <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link> specifies the representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> for one or more <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link>.</p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 specifies the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> that support the exchange of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product_data">product data</link>
    defined in <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocols</link>.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 defines a formal <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_data">data</link> specification language, EXPRESS which is used to specify the
    representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link>. The use of a formal language provides unambiguous and
    consistent representation and facilitates development of implementations.
    The representation of product information may be annotated with a literal definition for each construct.
    ISO 10303 provides a methodology and framework for <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_testing">conformance testing</link> of implementations.	
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_IRs">3.3.1 Integrated resources</h4>
  <p>
    The specification of a representation of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> is provided by a set of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_integrated_resource">integrated resources</link>.
    Each <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_integrated_resource">integrated resource</link> comprises a set of descriptions applicable to <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product_data">product data</link>, written in EXPRESS
    known as <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_resource_construct">resource constructs</link>. One set may be dependent on other sets for its definition.
    Similar information for different <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link> is represented by a single <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_resource_construct">resource construct</link>.
  </p> 
  <p>
    The <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_integrated_resource">integrated resources</link> in this International Standard are divided into two groups: <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_generic_resource">generic resources</link> and <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_resource">application resources</link>.
    The <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_generic_resource">generic resources</link> are independent of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link> and can reference other resources.
    The <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_resource">application resources</link> can reference other resources and can add other <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_resource_construct">resource constructs</link>
    for use by a group of similar <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link>. 
    The integrated resources can reference product data descriptions written using EXPRESS from other International Standards.
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_resource">Application resources</link> do not reference other
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_resource">application resources</link>.
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_app_support">3.3.2 Support for applications</h4>
  <p>
    The <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_integrated_resource">integrated resources</link> define a generic <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information_model">information model</link> for <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link>. They are
    not sufficient to support the information requirements of an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">application</link> without the addition of
   <link ref="2_defs.htm#term__application"> application</link> specific constraints, relationships and attributes.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 defines <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocols</link> in which the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_integrated_resource">integrated resources</link> are interpreted to meet
    the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_product">product</link><space/><link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> requirements of specific <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">applications</link>. The interpretation is achieved by
    selecting appropriate <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_resource_construct">resource constructs</link> and refining their meaning, by specifying any appropriate
    constraints, relationships, and attributes. This <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_interpretation">interpretation</link> results in an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_interpreted_model">application interpreted model</link>.
    The <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_interpreted_model">application interpreted model</link> is documented as part of an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link>.
  </p> 
  <p>
    Wherever a <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_resource_construct">resource construct</link> is used to represent the same <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> requirement in different
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocols</link>, the same <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_interpretation">interpretation</link> of the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_resource_construct">resource construct</link> is used. 
    Interpreted resource constructs which are used in more than one <link ref="2_defs.htm.term_application_protocol">application protocol</link> can be documented as <link ref="2_defs.htm.term_application_interpreted_construct">application interpreted constructs</link>. <link ref="2_defs.htm.term_application_module">Application modules</link> are another means of assuring consistent interpretation.  In an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_module">application module</link> the harmonized requirements are documented along with the interpreted resource constructs.  Application interpreted constructs and application modules are discussed in more detail in clause 4. 
  </p> 
  <p>
    The scope and 
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> requirements of the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">application</link> are specified in the terminology of the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">application</link>.
    The <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link> provides a mapping to show how the interpretation of the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_integrated_resource">integrated resources</link>
    is used to meet the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_information">information</link> requirements of the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application">application</link>.
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_impl_methods">3.3.3 Implementation methods</h4>
  <p>
    Each <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation method</link> included in ISO 10303 is specified by a mapping from the EXPRESS
    language onto the formal language used for the method. The mapping is independent
    of the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link>. The mapping is expressed in a formal notation. At least three
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> for ISO 10303 have been identified.	
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_impls">3.3.4 Implementations</h4>
  <p>
    An <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link> may specify one or more applicable <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> from the
    set of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> in ISO 10303. An implementation shall apply one or more of
    the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation methods</link> specified in the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link> to the
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_interpreted_model">application interpreted model</link>.
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_conf_test">3.3.5 Conformance testing</h4>
  <p>
    Conformance of an implementation to an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link> is specified by the
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_requirement">conformance requirements</link> in the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link>.
  </p> 
  <p>
    A set of tests, specified in an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_abstract_test_suite">abstract test suite</link>, may be defined for each <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_application_protocol">application protocol</link>. When
    associated with an <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_abstract_test_method">abstract test method</link>, these tests can be used to assess the conformance of an
    implementation. The overall framework for conformance assessment is specified in ISO 10303-31.
    An <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_abstract_test_method">abstract test method</link> for each <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_implementation_method">implementation method</link> is specified in one of the
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_testing">conformance testing</link> methodology and framework series of parts of ISO 10303.
  </p> 
  <p>
    The scope of <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_testing">conformance testing</link> of a specific implementation is the requirements specified
    for the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_clas">conformance class(es)</link> claimed for the implementation in the
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_protocol_implementation_conformance_statement">protocol implementation conformance statement</link> (PICS). The tests are selected from the <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_abstract_test_suite">abstract test suite</link>, based on the
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_clas">conformance class</link> claimed by the implementation. Test 
    results provide the basis for conformance assessment.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 contains <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_abstract_test_suite">abstract test suites</link> and defines <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_abstract_test_method">abstract test methods</link> for performing
    <link ref="2_defs.htm#term_conformance_testing">conformance testing</link> to provide a basis for test results that are repeatable, comparable, and auditable.
    Inclusion of conformance testing procedures in ISO 10303 is intended to promote widespread
    acceptance of test results.	
  </p>

</collection_page>
