<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../xsl/part1000/collection_page.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection_page [
<!ENTITY % characters SYSTEM "characters.ent"> 
<!ENTITY % terms SYSTEM "terms.ent"> 
%characters; 
%terms; 
]>
<collection_page page_type="main">
  <h2 id="overview">3 Overview of ISO 10303</h2>
  <h3 id="overview_purpose">3.1 Purpose</h3>
  <p>The purpose of ISO 10303 is to specify a form for the unambiguous representation and exchange of computer-interpretable &tr-product-data; throughout the life of a &tr-product;. This form is independent of any particular computer system. This form enables consistent implementations across multiple &tr-applications; and systems. ISO 10303 permits different &tr-implementation-methods; to be used for storing, accessing, transferring, and archiving &tr-product-data;. Implementations can be tested for conformance.</p>
  <h3 id="overview_scope">3.2 Scope of ISO 10303</h3>
  <p>ISO 10303 provides a representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information; along with the
    necessary mechanisms and definitions to enable &tr-product-data; to be exchanged. The exchange
    is among different computer systems and environments associated with the complete &tr-product;
    lifecycle, including &tr-product; design, manufacture, use, maintenance, and final disposition.</p>
  <p>The following are within the scope of ISO 10303:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information;, including components and assemblies;</li>
    <li>exchange of &tr-product-data;, including storing, transferring, accessing, and archiving.</li>
  </ul>
  <h3 id="overview_principles">3.3 Fundamental principles</h3>
  <p>ISO 10303 separates the techniques of representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information; from the &tr-implementation-methods; used for &tr-data-exchange;.</p> 
  <p>The representation techniques provide a single representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information; common to many &tr-applications;. This common representation can be tailored to meet the needs of specific &tr-applications;. An &tr-application-protocol; (&tr-AP;) specifies the representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information; for one or more &tr-applications;.</p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 specifies the &tr-implementation-methods; that support the exchange of &tr-product-data;
    defined in &tr-APs;.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 defines a formal &tr-data; specification language, EXPRESS which is used to specify the
    representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information;. The use of a formal language provides unambiguous and
    consistent representation and facilitates development of implementations.
    The representation of product information may be annotated with a literal definition for each construct.
  </p>
  <p>
    ISO 10303 provides a methodology and framework for &tr-conformance-testing; of implementations.	
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_IRs">3.3.1 Integrated resources</h4>
  <p>
    The specification of a representation of &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information; is provided by a set of &tr-integrated-resources; (&tr-IRs;).
    Each &tr-IR; comprises a set of descriptions applicable to &tr-product-data;, written in EXPRESS
    known as &tr-resource-constructs;. One set may be dependent on other sets for its definition.
    Similar information for different &tr-applications; is represented by a single &tr-resource-construct;.
  </p> 
  <p>
    The &tr-IRs; in ISO 10303 are divided into two groups: &tr-generic-resources; and &tr-application-resources;.
    The &tr-generic-resources; are independent of &tr-applications; and may reference other resources.
    The &tr-application-resources; may reference other resources and may add other &tr-resource-constructs;
    for use by a group of similar &tr-applications;. 
    The integrated resources may reference product data descriptions written using EXPRESS from other International Standards.
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_app_support">3.3.2 Support for applications</h4>
  <p>
    The &tr-IRs; define a generic &tr-information-model; for &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information;. They are
    not sufficient to support the information requirements of an &tr-application; without the addition of
   &tr-application; specific constraints, relationships and attributes.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 defines &tr-APs; in which the &tr-IRs; are interpreted to meet
    the &tr-product;<space/>&tr-information; requirements of specific &tr-applications;. The interpretation is achieved by
    selecting appropriate &tr-resource-constructs; and refining their meaning, by specifying any appropriate
    constraints, relationships, and attributes. This &tr-interpretation; results in an &tr-application-interpreted-model; (&tr-AIM;).
    The &tr-AIM; is documented as part of an &tr-AP;.
  </p> 
  <p>
    Wherever a &tr-resource-construct; is used to represent the same &tr-information; requirement in different
    &tr-APs;, the same &tr-interpretation; of the &tr-resource-construct; is used. 
    Interpreted resource constructs which are used in more than one &tr-AP; can be documented as &tr-application-interpreted-constructs; (&tr-AICs;). &tr-Application-modules; (&tr-AMs;) are another means of assuring consistent interpretation.  In an &tr-AM; the harmonized requirements are documented along with the interpreted resource constructs.  Application interpreted constructs and application modules are discussed in more detail in Clause <link ref="4_arch">4</link>. 
  </p> 
  <p>
    The scope and 
    &tr-information; requirements of the &tr-application; are specified in the terminology of the &tr-application;.
    The &tr-AP; provides a mapping to show how the interpretation of the &tr-IRs;
    is used to meet the &tr-information; requirements of the &tr-application;.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 provides business object models that present
    complex models in a form that is more understandable to 
    application experts.
  </p>
  <h4 id="overview_impl_methods">3.3.3 Implementation methods</h4>
  <p>
    Each &tr-implementation-method; included in ISO 10303 is specified by a mapping from the EXPRESS
    language onto the formal language used for the method. The mapping is independent
    of the &tr-AP;. The mapping is expressed in a formal notation. At least three
    &tr-implementation-methods; for ISO 10303 have been identified.	
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_impls">3.3.4 Implementations</h4>
  <p>
    An &tr-AP; may specify one or more applicable &tr-implementation-methods; from the
    set of &tr-implementation-methods; in ISO 10303. An implementation shall apply one or more of
    the &tr-implementation-methods; specified in the &tr-AP; to the
    &tr-AIM;.
  </p> 
  <h4 id="overview_conf_test">3.3.5 Conformance testing</h4>
  <p>
    Conformance of an implementation to an &tr-AP; is specified by the
    &tr-conformance-requirements; in the &tr-AP;.
  </p> 
  <p>
    A set of tests, specified in an &tr-abstract-test-suite; (&tr-ATS;), may be defined for each &tr-AP;. When
    associated with an &tr-abstract-test-method; (&tr-ATM;), these tests can be used to assess the conformance of an
    implementation. The overall framework for conformance assessment is specified in <std-ref>ISO 10303-31</std-ref>.
  </p>
  <p>
    An &tr-ATM; for each &tr-implementation-method; is specified in one of the
    &tr-conformance-testing; methodology and framework series of parts of ISO 10303.
  </p> 
  <p>
    The scope of &tr-conformance-testing; of a specific implementation is the requirements specified
    for the &tr-conformance-classes; claimed for the implementation in the
    &tr-protocol-implementation-conformance-statement; (&tr-PICS;). The tests are selected from the &tr-ATS;, based on the
    &tr-conformance-class; claimed by the implementation. Test 
    results provide the basis for conformance assessment.
  </p> 
  <p>
    ISO 10303 contains &tr-abstract-test-suites; and defines &tr-abstract-test-methods; for performing
    &tr-conformance-testing; to provide a basis for test results that are repeatable, comparable, and auditable.
    Inclusion of conformance testing procedures in ISO 10303 is intended to promote widespread acceptance of test results.	
  </p>

</collection_page>
