<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../xsl/part1000/collection_page.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection_page [
<!ENTITY % characters SYSTEM "characters.ent"> 
<!ENTITY % terms SYSTEM "terms.ent"> 
%characters; 
%terms; 
]>
<collection_page page_type="main">
  <h2 id="info_obj">6 Information object registration scheme</h2>
  <p>
In order to provide unambiguous identification of schemas and other information objects in an
open information system, ISO 10303 employs the registration technique defined
in <std-ref>ISO/IEC 8824-1</std-ref>. This technique identifies objects by their assignment to a tree structure
whose root is ISO itself. Each node in the tree is identified by a sequence of integers corresponding
to the index of the leaf under each node. Nodes that identify agencies that can further specify
inferior nodes are called registration authorities. There is provision in this technqiue for having
registration provided by national bodies and other identified organizations (including private
corporations). A registration authority is automatically granted to the technical committee or
subcommittee that prepares a standard in order to identify objects within the standard. Thus,
ISO nnnnn is identified by the object identifier:
  </p> 
  <p align="center">
    { 1 0 nnnnn }
  </p> 
  <p>
    Here the initial 1 indicates ISO; the 0 following it identifies the object as a standard, and the
    number following that is the number of the standard. <std-ref>ISO/IEC 8824-1</std-ref> also defines identifiers to
    stand in the place of these numbers; "iso" has the value 1 and "standard" has the value 0.
    For multi-part standards, the next number is required to be the part number. 
  </p> 
  <p>
    For the purposes of identifying information objects unambiguously within an open information system, 
    standards produced by ISO TC 184/SC 4 adopt the convention that the value for iso and the value for standard shall not
    be included in the text of the standard for clarity. By convention, the value following the part number 
    shall be version number. 
    By convention, the value of the version number of the first edition shall be 1. 
    The value 0, if used at all, is reserved to refer to DIS documents. 
    A draft document shall not be given its own unique version number.
    Thus, this part of ISO 10303 is identified by the object identifier:
  </p> 
  <p align="center">
    { iso standard 10303 part(l) version(2) }
  </p> 
  <p>
    Here, the values for iso and standard are not displayed; the value of the part number is given explicitly, but the notation allows us to associate a
    term with this value, thereby providing some semantics. The notation for values of this type is
    defined in <std-ref>ISO/IEC 8824-1</std-ref>, and the predefined assignments are specified in <std-ref>ISO/IEC 8824-1</std-ref>.
  </p> 
      <p class="note">NOTE&nbsp;1&sp3;In the past, the value 0, was used to refer to DIS documents.
      This practice is now deprecated. Instead, the value given for the version number of a draft document
      is the version number that the document will have upon publication.</p>
      <p class="note">NOTE&nbsp;2&sp3;The number 0 does not represent the first position in the sequence 0, 1, 2, .... It represents the lack of a position in the sequence 1, 2, 3, .... So even a DIS for a second edition might have a value of 0 for the version number.</p>
      <p class="example">
	<p>EXAMPLE&sp3;ISO 10303-203 edition 1 was published as an international standard in 1994. Technical corrigendum (TC) 1 to edition 1 was published in 1996, and TC 2 was published in 1998. Amendment 1 was published in 2000, and TC 3 was published in 2004. A new, modular version of the &tr-AP;, ISO/TS 10303-203 edition 1, was published in 2005. The modular version was promoted to an international standard, ISO 10303-203 edition 2, in 2010. The version numbers under this scenario would be:</p>
	<ul>
	  <li>version 1: ISO 10303-203:1994;</li>
	  <li>version 2: ISO 10303-203:1994/Cor 1:1996;</li>
	  <li>version 3: ISO 10303-203:1994/Cor 2:1998;</li>
	  <li>version 4: ISO 10303-203:1994/Amd 1:2000;</li>
	  <li>version 5: ISO 10303-203:1994/Cor 3:2004;</li>
	  <li>version 6: ISO/TS 10303-203:2005;</li>
	  <li>version 7: ISO 10303-203:2010.</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
  <p>
    For the purposes of identifying information objects unambiguously within an open information
    system, ISO TC 184/SC 4 adopts the following conventions:
  </p> 
  <ul>
    <li>
      The value following the version number is used to identify the type of information object
      defined within the part. The value 1 shall be used to indicate that the object so identified is an EXPRESS schema.
    </li>
    <li>
      <p>The value following the object type is an integer that identifies the instance of the object
      type so identified.</p>
      <p>Where applicable, one of the following values shall be used:</p>
      <ul>
	<li>1: &tr-ARM; short form;</li>
	<li>2: &tr-AIM; short form (for monolithic &tr-AP;); &tr-MIM; short form (for modular &tr-AP;);</li>
	<li>3: &tr-ARM; long form;</li>
	<li>4: &tr-AIM; long form (for monolithic &tr-AP;); &tr-MIM; long form (for modular &tr-AP;).</li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li>
      To meet the syntactic requirements of <std-ref>ISO/IEC 8824-1</std-ref>, each occurrence of an underscore
       in a schema name shall be replaced with a hyphen when defining this value.
  <p class="example">
    EXAMPLE&sp3;In <std-ref>ISO 10303-41</std-ref>, several schemas are defined. The application_context_schema can be identified by the value:
  <p align="center">
    { iso standard 10303 part(41) version(l) object(l) application-context-schema(l) }
  </p> 
    and the product_definition_schema can be identified by the value:
  <p align="center">
    { iso standard 10303 part(41) version(l) object(l) product-definition-schema(2) }
  </p>
  </p> 
    </li>
  </ul>
</collection_page>
