<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../xsl/part1000/collection_page.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE collection_page [
<!ENTITY % characters SYSTEM "characters.ent"> 
<!ENTITY % terms SYSTEM "terms.ent"> 
%characters; 
%terms;
]>
<collection_page page_type="main">
      <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
      <p>
         ISO 10303 is an International Standard for the computer-interpretable 
         representation of &tr-product-information; and for the exchange of &tr-product-data;.
         The objective is to provide a neutral mechanism capable of describing
         &tr-products; throughout their life cycle. This mechanism is suitable not only
         for neutral file exchange, but also as a basis for implementing and
         sharing &tr-product; databases, and as a basis for archiving.
         The information generated about a product during its design, manufacture,
         use, maintenance, and disposal is used for many purposes. 
         The use may involve many computer systems, including some that may be
         located in different organizations. In order to support such uses,
         organizations need to be able to represent their product information in a
         common computer-interpretable form that is required to remain complete and
         consistent when exchanged among different computer systems.
      </p>
      <p>
         This part of ISO 10303 is an overview of ISO 10303. It specifies the overall scope of ISO 10303 and describes the ISO 10303 architectures and structure. It describes the various series of parts of ISO 10303 and the relationships among them.
      </p>
<p>This edition incorporates the following modifications:</p>
<ul>
	<li>inclusion of &tr-application-interpreted-constructs;;</li>
	<li>inclusion of &tr-application-modules;;</li>
   <li>inclusion of &tr-business-object-models;;</li>
   <li>inclusion of additional &tr-implementation-methods;;</li>
	<li>permission for &tr-integrated-resources; to reference constructs written using EXPRESS from other International Standards;</li> 
	<li>corrections to part numbering scheme;</li>
	<li>extension of &tr-information; object registration to be usable on other standards;</li>
   <li>inclusion of usage guides;</li>
   <li>additional definitions.</li> 
</ul>
</collection_page>
