<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.38 2014/01/27 18:43:22 darla Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="draughting"
   name.french="Dessins techniques"
   part="101"
   version="3"
   object.reg.version="4"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="6152"
   wg.number.express="6153"
   wg.number.supersedes="4831"
   wg.number.express.supersedes="4832"
   checklist.internal_review="6154"
   checklist.project_leader="6155"
   checklist.convener="6156"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2014"
   publication.date="2014-05-01" 
   published="n"
   previous.revision.year="2011"
   previous.revision.cancelled="NO"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2014/01/27 18:43:22 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.38 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    resource, application protocol, documentation, drawing, draughting, product data representation, presentation
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>	ISO 10303-101 establishes the resource structures, entities and relationships
		necessary for the accommodations, preservation and exchange of product definition data
		supporting the draughting function, as semantically defined in a draughting application
		protocol - the guide to exchanges using STEP.
	</p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="simon.frechette"/>
   <editor ref="lothar.klein"/>
 </contacts>
<changes>
	<change_edition version="2">
		<description>
			Also changes of technical corrigendum 1 of edition 1 are listed here.
		</description>
		<schema.changes schema_name="draughting_element_schema"> 
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object type="REFERENCE_FROM" name="presentation_appearance_schema"/>
				<modified.object type="REFERENCE_FROM" name="presentation_resource_schema"/>
				<modified.object type="REFERENCE_FROM" name="geometry_schema"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="annotation_plane_element"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="des_invisible_item"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="plane_or_planar_box"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="annotation_plane"/>
				<modified.object type="RULE" name="annotation_curve_subtypes"/>
				<modified.object type="RULE" name="annotation_occurrence_subtypes"/>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object type="REFERENCE_FROM" name="presentation_definition_schema"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="draughting_callout_element"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="dimension_curve"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="draughting_callout"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="dimension_callout"/>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>

	</change_edition>

	<change_edition version="3">
		<schema.changes schema_name="draughting_element_schema"> 
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="tessellated_annotation_occurrence"/>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object type="REFERENCE_FROM" name="geometry_schema"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="dimension_curve_directed_callout"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="projection_directed_callout"/>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
      
</changes>

 


 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
	 <p>
    This part of ISO 10303 specifies the system-independent representation of digital CAD data resulting from the
	application of draughting practices in the drawing depiction of product definition data.
   </p>
	<p>
     The drawing definition schema specifies the resources necessary for the identification, description,
	 organization, and administration of drawing and drawing sheet versions.
	</p>
	<p>
	 The draughting element schema specifies the resources representing basic draughting elements such as
	 dimension lines, projection lines, leader lines and the use of these resources in combination with other
	 annotation curves, symbols, and text to depict information found on the drawing sheet.
	</p>
	<p>
	 The draughting dimension schema specifies the resources necessary for the use of basic draughting
	 elements, in combination with other annotation curves, symbols, and text, to depict dimensions,
	 tolerances, and dimension-related information on a drawing sheet.
	</p>
	<p>
		The objective of this part is the system-independent representation of digital CAD data resulting from the
		application of draughting practices in the drawing depiction of product definition data. This part of ISO 10303 provides
		for the representation of draughting information not provided for in other integrated resource Parts of ISO
		10303. Where necessary, it provides the draughting semantic extension to information represented in
		those Parts.
	</p>  
   <p>
   	Requirements and practices regarding the draughting-specific use, appearance, and specific aggregation
	of curves, symbols, and text are specified in draughting-practices standards regarding technical drawings,
	such as those compiled in ISO Standards Handbook <i>Technical drawings</i> [5].
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->

 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
        <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="The relationship of the schemas of this part to the ISO 10303 integration architecture (1 of 1)"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>	information regarding the definition, description, and administration of a drawing and the sheets of a drawing;</li>
   <li>	elementary draughting annotations and their aggregation with more general annotations for the 
   		depiction of facts and requirements concerning the product or interpretation of a drawing;
   </li>
   <li> draughting annotations used in the depiction of dimensions, tolerances, and related dimension measurement information. </li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>	management information such as changes that create drawing versions, approvals, contracts under
		which draughting work is done, security classification, persons responsible, and the roles of
		responsibility of these persons, provided in ISO 10303-41;
   </li>
   <li>	views and the viewing mechanism for depiction of the shape, provided in ISO 10303-46;</li>
   <li>	styled generic annotations, i.e. curves, symbols, text and sectioning (crosshatching), provided in ISO 10303-46;</li>
   <li>	coordinate systems for the location of annotations, and their relationships, provided in ISO 10303-42 and ISO 10303-43.</li>
 </outscope>

<!-- Normative references -->
 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref129-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_dimension_line"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_extension_line"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_leader_line"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_terminator"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref639-2.1998"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_protocol"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_resource"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_formal"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_generic_resource"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_presentation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_resource_construct"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.1994"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-42">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_curve"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-46">
 		<term.ref linkend="annotation"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref16792">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_annotation_plane"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 </normrefs>

<!-- Definitions -->
 <definition>
 	<term id="callout">callout</term>
 	<def>
 		depiction of requirements and information about a product
 	</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 	<term id="draughting_drafting">draughting</term>
 	<def>
 		activity of selecting and configuring appropriate representations of
		product data for the human-interpretable presentation in the form of a drawing
 	</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 	<term id="drawing_sheet">drawing sheet</term>
 	<def>
 		subdivision of a drawing having the same identifier as the drawing and its own
		sheet number
		<note>A drawing sheet can contain part or all of the text or pictorial presentations of the
		drawing.</note>
 	</def>
 </definition>

<!-- 
 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="drawing_definition_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<p>  		
   		The subject of the <b>drawing_definition_schema</b> is the identification, description, organization, and
		administration of drawing revisions. 
		It identifies drawing revisions and drawing sheet revisions that comprise a drawing.
		It describes the relationship between revisions of drawings and sheets.
		In short, this schema provides resources for the definition and management of the drawing.
	</p>
   </introduction>
   
   <!-- Fundamental concepts and assumptions -->
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		A drawing is a draughting-specific presentation of information about a product including information used
		to interpret the presentation.
		A drawing can be partitioned or divided into a number of drawing sheets.
		Drawings are configured and administered by versions.
		Each drawing, including its drawing sheets, may have many versions.
		Versions of drawings and drawing sheets are known as revisions.
		A drawing is a revision whether it be initial or the result of change.
		If any drawing sheet is added, changed, or deleted, a new revision of the drawing may be established.
		The ability to identify and describe a drawing revision is provided, independently of organizational practices.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		A revised drawing or drawing sheet is considered a successor of the original drawing or drawing sheet.
		The revisions of a drawing or drawing sheet may be sequentially ordered.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		Drawing and drawing sheet revisions may have a draughting-specific title or description. 
   		A draughting title may change for subsequent revisions of the drawing or drawing sheet.
   	</p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="drawing_definition_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="drawing_definition_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
   
</schema>

<schema name="draughting_element_schema" version="3">

	<!-- Introduction -->
	<introduction>
	 <p>
		The subjects of the <b>draughting_element_schema</b> are the basic draughting elements used on drawings 
		to convey information about the product being depicted.
		Text using draughting-specific fonts and character sets is used to convey product and product-processing requirements and 
		to make references to other requirements documents.
		Curves with draughting-specific thicknesses (widths) and dash patterns are used to clarify the depiction of a product shape.
		Images of the shape are annotated with curves representing feature centres, path of motion, and location of cutting planes.
		The draughting activity also uses many symbols to convey requirements for characteristics such as surface texture and welds.
		These draughting curves, text, and symbols are often combined to form a complete presentation of a requirement and are
		referred to as a draughting callout.
	 </p>
	 <p>
	 	Draughting often applies a requirement to a specific area of the depicted product shape.
	 	In such instances other draughting curves, such as leader lines, projection lines, and dimension lines, are used to direct the
		requirement to the place of application.
	 </p>
	 <p>
	 	This schema specifies the basic draughting elements and their combinations used to annotate the depicted
		product shape and convey information regarding interpretation of the drawing.
	 </p>
	</introduction>
	
	<!-- Fundamental concepts and assumptions -->
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		The draughting activity, regardless of the engineering discipline, specializes generic annotation curves, symbols, and text.
   		The specialization of annotation curves is based on the need to identify certain curves according to existing draughting standards.
   		Further, the specialization makes it possible to assign curve presentation styles according to those same standards.
   		The specialization of generic annotation text is based on the draughting need to specify draughting-specific fonts and character sets.
   		The specialization of generic annotation symbols is based on the need for draughting symbols to be comprised of draughting-specific curves and text.
   	</p>
   	<p> 
   		The three most common draughting-specific annotation curves are the dimension line, leader line, and projection line (also known as an extension line or witness line).
   		These draughting annotation curves are not limited to their stated geometric type.
   		A leader line referring to a feature on a drawing, such as a dimension, object, or outline, is really a series of one-to-many curve segments, 
   		not necessarily line segments. 
   		This fact is also true of the projection line and dimension line.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		Dimension lines, leader lines, and projection lines can be shared by more than one callout.
   	</p>
   		<example>
   			A single instance of a leader line can be used to direct (refer) a callout, containing a
			dimension value and tolerance, while also directing a second callout, containing a geometric tolerance of
			location, to the same feature of size (see Figure 2).
   		</example>
   	<p>
   		Dimension lines and leader lines cannot exist independently of a callout. 
   		Only the projection line can exist independently (without directing a callout).
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		A callout directed by means of both a leader line and a projection line is both a leader-directed callout
		and a projection-directed callout.
   	</p>	
   	<figure number="2">
		   <title>Leader line shared by dimension and tolerance</title>
		   <img src="leader_line_shared_dimension_tolerance.gif"/>
	</figure>
	<p>
		A terminator symbol (e.g., arrowhead) is another concept of existing draughting-practices standards.
		A terminator symbol may be used to terminate a leader line, or it may be used to show the extent of the
		dimension and the direction of measurement when placed along a dimension line.
		Although referred to as an arrow or arrowhead, some draughting practices standards specify other symbols, 
		such as a dot, box, or slash to terminate a leader line or indicate a dimension extent.
		Therefore, this concept has been generalized as a terminator symbol.
	</p>
	<p>
		A draughting callout is a collection of draughting- or presentation-specific annotation curves, text, and
		symbols depicting information or requirements about the product or drawing itself.
		This part of ISO 10303 supports callouts which may contain text, symbols, or curves that are directed to 
		a feature (a place on a drawing) by a leader line, a projection line, a dimension line, or a combination of these.
		A callout whose text, symbols, or curves are directed by means of both a leader line and a projection line 
		is both a leader-directed callout and a projection callout.
	</p>
	<p>
		Draughting Application Protocols may further specialize resources found in this schema or in ISO 10303-46 
		to obtain draughting concepts not explicitly provided.
	</p>
   </fund_cons>
   
<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="draughting_element_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="draughting_element_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
   
</schema>

<schema name="draughting_dimension_schema" version="1">

	<!-- Introduction -->
	<introduction>
	 <p>
		The subject of the <b>draughting_dimension_schema</b> is the dimension-related information.
		Through use of this schema it is possible to identify a collection of annotation curves, symbols, 
		and text as those which present information about a dimension value and its unit of measure.
		This includes those collections which graphically depict the extent and direction of measure.
		It is also possible to maintain relationships, such as a common datum or baseline, between dimension presentations.
	 </p>
	</introduction>
	
	<!-- Fundamental concepts and assumptions -->
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		The draughting presentation of dimensions and their related information is accomplished using specialized
		combinations of draughting elements, such as annotation curves, text, and symbols.
		The combinations of annotation curves, text, and symbols used for presenting dimension information, 
		are the same combinations used elsewhere in draughting, except that the information being presented is 
		that of a dimension.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The presentation of dimension information may be independent of or directed to the draughting
		presentation of the feature being dimensioned by such draughting elements as leader lines, projection
		lines, or dimension lines.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		Dimension lines direct information about the dimension size or location and depict graphically the extent
		of the dimension and the direction of measurement.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		A dimension graph is a combination of draughting elements that incorporate a dimension line, depicting
		the extent and direction of a dimension measurement.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		Dimension graphs may be successively positioned in a sequence. If so, they may share projection lines.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The type of the dimension graph does not always match the nature of the dimension being presented.
   		An angular dimension graph always presents an angular dimension, but a diameter dimension may be
		presented by a linear form of the dimension graph as well as by the diameter form of the dimension graph.
   	</p>
   	<note>
   		Figure 9 gives examples of two forms of the dimension graph; both graphically present the same
		diameter dimension.
   	</note>
   	<figure number="9">
		   <title>Dimension graphs</title>
		   <img src="dimension_graphs.gif"/>
	</figure>
	<p>
		Draughting Application Protocols may further specialize resources found in this schema or in ISO 10303-46 
		to obtain draughting concepts not explicitly provided.
	</p>
   </fund_cons>
   
<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
    
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="draughting_dimension_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="draughting_dimension_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
   
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="DRWDFN" entity="drawing_definition"/>
 	<shortname name="DRWRVS" entity="drawing_revision"/>
 	<shortname name="DRRVSQ" entity="drawing_revision_sequence"/>
 	<shortname name="DRSHRV" entity="drawing_sheet_revision"/>
 	<shortname name="DSRS" entity="drawing_sheet_revision_sequence"/>
 	<shortname name="DSRU" entity="drawing_sheet_revision_usage"/>
 	<shortname name="DRGTTL" entity="draughting_title"/>
 	<shortname name="DMNCRV" entity="dimension_curve"/>
 	<shortname name="LDRCRV" entity="leader_curve"/>
 	<shortname name="PRJCRV" entity="projection_curve"/>
 	<shortname name="TRMSYM" entity="terminator_symbol"/>
 	<shortname name="DMCRTR" entity="dimension_curve_terminator"/>
 	<shortname name="LDRTRM" entity="leader_terminator"/>
 	<shortname name="DRGCLL" entity="draughting_callout"/>
 	<shortname name="DRCLRL" entity="draughting_callout_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="LDDRCL" entity="leader_directed_callout"/>
 	<shortname name="PRDRCL" entity="projection_directed_callout"/>
 	<shortname name="DCDC" entity="dimension_curve_directed_callout"/>
 	<shortname name="DMNCLL" entity="dimension_callout"/>
 	<shortname name="DMNGRP" entity="dimension_graph"/>
 	<shortname name="DGPCU" entity="dimension_graph_projection_curve_usage"/>
 	<shortname name="DMGRSQ" entity="dimension_graph_sequence"/>
 	<shortname name="ANNPLN" entity="annotation_plane"/> 	
 	<shortname name="TSANOC" entity="tessellated_annotation_occurrence"/> 	
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->
 <bibliography>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10209-1"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_10303-21"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_10303-22"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISOSTD-HDBK-12"/>
 </bibliography>

</resource>

