<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.8 2004/03/03 21:27:08 panetto Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module name="ap236_furniture_catalogue_and_interior_design" part="436" version="1" sc4.working_group="3" wg.number="1337" wg.number.arm="1338" wg.number.mim="1339" checklist.internal_review="1307" checklist.project_leader="1308" checklist.convener="1314" status="CD-TS" language="E" publication.year="2003" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2004/03/03 21:27:08 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.8 $" development.folder="dvlp">
	<keywords>
    module, furniture product, interior design, catalogue
 </keywords>
	<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
	<contacts>
		<projlead ref="ap236.projlead"/>
		<editor ref="ap236.editor"/>
	</contacts>
	<!-- Introduction -->
	<!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
	<purpose>
		<p>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol for the representation of furniture catalogues 
	and of the data managed during the design of pieces of furniture and during the study of their inclusion in rooms.
	It satisfies an industrial need to exchange and to integrate product data with furniture decoration projects.</p>
		<p>
     This part of ISO 10303 provides a
     comprehensive capability to describe a set of furniture products specified by its variants and price list that could be chosen by retailers to provide specific 
	pieces of furniture to their customers.
     </p>
		<p>
     Further modules are included to support the representation
     of structured requirements.
   </p>
		<p>
	This part of ISO 10303 provides a comprehensive vision about furniture product data catalogues exchange 
	between furniture manufacturers and furniture retaillers/distributors.
   </p>
		<p>
			The capabilities provided by this part of ISO 10303 is shown in Figure <module_ref linkend="ap236_furniture_catalog_and_interior_design:introduction:figure:f1">1</module_ref>.
     </p>
		<figure id="f1" number="1">
			<title>
				The concepts</title>
			<img src="figure1.png"/>
		</figure>
		<p>
     The vision shows how relevant information required for furniture products catalogues can be managed
     in an integrated form. This data can be decomposed in  <!--Ruben three-->the following main components:
   </p>
		<ul>
			<li> the product data structure that represents simple and complex products bill of materials (BOM); </li>
			<li> the product specifications that specifies the different variant combinations a product is allowed to have before being sold; </li>
			<li>geometric representation of products;</li>
			<li>expressions;</li>
			<li> and the building room specification where furniture products could fit.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
      Hyperlinks to the key higher level modules in AP236 are shown below.
      Further information on their content can be found in the modules themselves.
    </p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				<module_ref linkend="parameterized_catalog_data_information_and_shape_representation:introduction">
          parameterized catalog data information and shape representation
        </module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1355).
      </li>
			<li>
				<module_ref linkend="furniture_interior_decoration:introduction">
          furniture interior decoration
        </module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1354);
      </li>
		</ul>
		<p>A furniture catalogue contains a list of references of pieces of furniture that are proposed to customers or to distributors. A catalogue provides a commercial view of the products of a furniture supplier but it does not represent the design information of the pieces of furniture. This application protocol enables to represent both kinds of information, using distinct data structures.</p>
		<p>It also provides information about the planned usage of components in a product model.</p>
		<p>The core of the product model is catalogue information. This information is connected to other parts in order to define the geometry of the pieces of furniture, to deal with boolean expressions of operands, to select a set of product features and to define a simple decoration project.</p>
		<p> The application module <module_ref linkend="parameterized_catalog_data_information_and_shape_representation:introduction">ISO 1303-1355</module_ref> (Parameterized catalog data information and shape representation) provides the definition for the main information data of a catalogue,
such as the definition of a product (and its different versions) and its specifications (the features of a piece of furniture that the customer can chose in order to select
one product from another. The structure of the product (modular pieces of furniture or just pieces of furniture that can be decomposed in its components),
the effectivity of the catalogue itself or the prices of the products, documents (hardcopies or digital files) that gives additional information about the product
such as detailed information, pictures, technical drawings, and a classification of the products in order they could be found easily in a catalogue depending on different search criteria; 
the properties of the product (not selectable by the user). It specifies the main concepts for representing a catalogue specification in the <module_ref linkend="product_class:introduction">ISO 1303-1103</module_ref> (Product class).
It also adds to the catalogue data information the capability of including the geometry of the products. It includes application modules for the representation of geometric models, surface conditions, geometric tolerances, dimensions that characterize the shape of product components, through subtypes of the generic type <express_ref linkend="elemental_geometric_shape:arm:Elemental_geometric_shape_arm.Geometric_model">Geometric Model</express_ref>.</p>
		<p> Moreover, this application module provides the specification of boolean expressions of operands selected in a set of product features. The application module <module_ref linkend="numerical_interface:introduction">ISO 1303-1344</module_ref> (Numerical_interface) provides all that capabilities together with the ability to specifies product properties, such as a property named 'price', with different kind of expressions that could reuse other properties values.</p>
		<p> The application module <module_ref linkend="furniture_interior_decoration:introduction">ISO 1303-1354</module_ref> (Furniture interior decoration) adds the capability of create a simple decoration project. In this conformance class the definition of geometry for the products should be defined in order the products could be located in space correctly. The piece of furniture, located in a <module_ref linkend="building_structure:introduction">Building structure</module_ref> (ISO 10303-1145), is specified by an instance of <express_ref linkend="building_item:arm:Building_item_arm.Building_element">Building element</express_ref> in the module <module_ref linkend="building_item:introduction">ISO 1303-1144</module_ref> (Building_item).</p>
	</purpose>
	<!-- Items in scope -->
	<inscope>
		<li>product data definition;</li>
		<li>catalogue product stucture;</li>
		<li>modular products;</li>
		<li>variants and options;</li>
		<li>classification and specification control;</li>
		<li>dimensions of shape elements;</li>
		<li>price lists;</li>
		<li>product configuration;</li>
		<li>multi-language support;</li>
		<li>approval;</li>
		<li>effectivity;</li>
		<li>documents definition and assignment;</li>
		<li>product identified by its manufacturing configuration;</li>
		<li>advanced boundary representation, faceted boundary representation, manifold surfaces with topology, geometrically bounded surface, geometrically bounded wireframe 2d and 3d geometry, wireframe with topology, and constructive solid geometry;</li>
		<li>geometric validation properties, for the assessment of the quality of conversions that occur in a transfer of geometric data;</li>
		<li>surface conditions;</li>
		<li>geometric tolerance;</li>
		<li>parameterized properties for products based on expressions and using other property values;</li>
		<li>establishment of relationships between variables and properties;</li>
		<li>room space definition and representation;</li>
		<li>product placement and interior decoration project.</li>
	</inscope>
	<!-- Items out of scope   -->
	<outscope>
		<li>work management data;</li>
		<li>products constraints based on expressions; </li>
		<li>variants and options based on expressions.</li>
	</outscope>
	<!--
	<normrefs/>
	<definition/>
	<abbreviations/>
	-->
	<!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
	<arm>
		<!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
		<!-- Units of functionality -->
		<uof name="Furniture_catalogue">
			<description>
	 	The <b>Furniture_catalogue</b> UoF specifies the data types needed to represent furniture products, their structure, their variants and their finishing.
     </description>
		</uof>
		<uof name="Interior_design">
			<description>
	 	The <b>Interior_design</b> UoF specifies the data types needed to represent The information that constitutes the specification for the evaluation and the manufacturing of a decorated room.
     </description>
		</uof>
		<!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm>
	<!-- ARM long form (optional) -->
	<!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          arm_lf.xml
          armexpg_lf1.gif
          armexpg_lf1.xml -->
	<!-- 
	<arm_lf>
		Note ARM long form EXPRESS is in arm_lf.xml 
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg_lf1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm_lf>
	-->
	<!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
	<!--
	<mapping_table>
		<ae entity="xx"/>
	</mapping_table>
	-->
	<!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
	<mim>
		<!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim>
	<!-- MIM long form (optional) -->
	<!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          mim_lf.xml
          mimexpg_lf1.gif
          mimexpg_lf1.xml -->
	<!-- 
	<mim_lf>
		Note MIM long form EXPRESS is in mim_lf.xml 
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg_lf1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim_lf>
	-->
	<bibliography>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>IEEE Std 1320.1-1998</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Standard for Functional Modeling Language &mdash; Syntax and Semantics for IDEF0. IEEE 1998.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO/CD 4157-2</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>"Construction Drawings &mdash; Designation Systems &mdash; Part 2 Designation of Rooms and other Spaces". ISO TC10/SC8 N339.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO/IEC 8824-1:1995</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Information technology &mdash; Open systems interconnection &mdash; Abstract syntax notation one (ASN.1) &mdash; Part 1: Specification of basic notation.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-1:1994</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 1: Overview and fundamental principles.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-11:1994</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 11: Description methods: The EXPRESS language reference manual.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-31:1994</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 31: Conformance testing methodology and framework: general concepts.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-41:2000</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 41: Integrated generic resource: Fundamentals of product description and support.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-214:2001</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 214: Core data for automotive mechanical design processes.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-215: 2001</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 215:Ship arrangements.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 10303-225: 2001</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Industrial automation systems and integration &mdash; Product data representation and exchange &mdash; Part 225:Building elements usings explicit shape representation.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
			<stdnumber>ISO 13584-20</stdnumber>
			<stdtitle>Parts library &mdash; Logical model of expressions.</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
	</bibliography>
</module>
