<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.30 2006/11/20 10:34:33 rugarcia Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!--       To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml       -->
<module 
	name="ap236_furniture_catalog_and_interior_design" 
	name.french="Catalogue de meubles et d&#233;coration d'int&#233;rieur relatif &#xe0; l'AP236" 
	part="436" 
	version="1" 
	sc4.working_group="12" 
	wg.number="2184" 
	wg.number.arm="2185" 
	wg.number.mim="2187" 
	wg.number.arm_lf="2186" 
	wg.number.mim_lf="2188" 
	checklist.internal_review="2189" 
	checklist.project_leader="2190" 
	checklist.convener="2191" 
	status="TS" 
	language="E" 
	publication.year="2006" 
	publication.date="2006-07-26" 
	published="y" 
	rcs.date="$Date: 2006/11/20 10:34:33 $" 
	rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.30 $" 
	development.folder="dvlp">
	
	<keywords>     
		module, 
		product, 
		interior design, 
		catalog  
	</keywords>
	<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
	<contacts>
		<projlead ref="ap236.projlead"/>
		<editor ref="ap236.editor"/>
	</contacts>
	<!-- Introduction -->
	<purpose>
		<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation of the data that 
		identify and characterize products offered to market and of their components. This application 
		module provides specifications suitable for the representation of any kind of such products.
		In particular, this application module enables the representation of products proposed to market 
		with a great number of variants and whose composition is characterized due to the selection 
		among a set of different product features. 
		</p>
		<example>
		Examples of such products are the products developed by the furniture industry, the automotive 
		industry and the commercial airplane industry.
		</example>
		<p>
		This application module specifies the data types and their constraints. It specifies the conformance 
		class 1 of ISO 10303-236.
		</p>
		<p>
		A catalogue contains a list of references of different commercial products that are proposed to 
		customers or to distributors. A catalogue provides a commercial view of the products of a supplier 
		or manufacturer but it does not represent the design information of the commercial products.
		</p>
		<p>
		It also provides information about the planned usage of components in a product model.
		</p>
		<p>
		It provides also specifications suitable for the representation of geometric models, surface conditions, 
		geometric tolerances, dimensions that characterize the shape of product components as well as their 
		spacial location in order to represent a decoration project.     
		</p>
		<p>
		The core of the product model is catalogue information. This information is connected to other parts in 
		order to define the geometry of the products and to select a set of product features.
		</p>
		<p> 
		This application module provides the definition for the main information data of a catalogue,such as the 
		definition of a product (and its different versions) and its specifications (the features of a product that 
		the customer can chose in order to select one product from another). The structure of the product 
		(the product itself or the decomposition of the product in its components), the effectivity of the catalogue 
		itself or its products, the effectivity of the prices of the products, documents (hardcopies or digital files) 
		that gives additional information about the product such as detailed information, pictures, technical 
		drawings, and a classification of the products in order they could be found easily in a catalogue 
		depending on different search criteria; the properties of the product (not selectable by the user). 
		It specifies the main concepts for representing a catalogue specification in the 
		<module_ref linkend="product_class:introduction">ISO/TS 10303-1103</module_ref> (Product class).
		</p>
		<p>
		It also adds to the catalog data information the capability of including the geometry of the products. 
		It includes application modules for the representation of geometric models, surface conditions, 
		geometric tolerances, dimensions that characterize the shape of product components, through subtypes 
		of the generic type 
		<express_ref linkend="elemental_geometric_shape:arm:Elemental_geometric_shape_arm.Geometric_model">
		Geometric Model</express_ref>.
		</p>
		<p>
		In particular, this application module enables the representation of products proposed to market with a 
		great number of variants and whose composition is characterized with expressions of operands selected 
		in a set of product features.
		</p>
		<note>
		This application module is an extension of the Catalog_data_information module,
				<module_ref linkend="catalog_data_information:introduction">ISO/TS 10303-1351</module_ref>.

		</note>
		<p>
		This application module specifies the schema associated with conformance class 2 of application protocol 
		ISO 10303-236.
		</p>
	</purpose>
	<!-- Items in scope -->
	<inscope>
		<li>representation of catalog product data definition;</li>
		<li>supporting of catalog product stucture;</li>
		<li>possibility of variants and options for product representations;</li>
		<li>products classification and products specification associated control;</li>
		<li>produtcs dimensions;</li>
		<li>price lists based on products identification and associated characteristics;</li>
		<li>product configuration based on diferent characteristics;</li>
		<li>multi-language support;</li>
		<li>approval status of the products;</li>
		<li>effectivity for data validation;</li>
		<li>documents definition and assignment;</li>
		<li>product manufacturing configuration;</li>
		<li>advanced boundary representation, faceted boundary representation, manifold surfaces with topology, 
		geometrically bounded surface, geometrically bounded wireframe 2d and 3d geometry, wireframe with 
		topology, and constructive solid geometry;</li>
		<li>product geometry including advanced boundary representation, faceted boundary representation, 
		manifold surfaces with topology, geometrically bounded surface, geometrically bounded wireframe 2d and 
		3d geometry, wireframe with topology, and constructive solid geometry;</li>
		<li>product geometric validation properties, for the assessment of the quality of conversions that occur in 
		a transfer of geometric data;</li>
		<li>product geometric tolerance;</li>
		<li>parameterized properties for products based on expressions and using property values;</li>
		<li>establishment of relationships between product variables and properties;</li>
		<li>components of building elements for decoration projects;</li>
		<li>building elements for decoration projects such as walls, beams and columns;</li>
		<li>space elements for decoration projects such as rooms and gangways;</li>
		<li>construction elements which define the structure of buildings for decoration projects;</li>
		<li>location of building items in the decoration project;</li>
		<li>product placement for definition of interior decoration project.</li>
	</inscope>
	<!-- Items out of scope   -->
	<outscope>
		<li>work management data;</li>
		<li>products constraints based on expressions; </li>
		<li>variants and options based on expressions.</li>
	</outscope>
	<normrefs>
		<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1351.2006"/>
	</normrefs>
	<!--<definition/> 	<abbreviations/> 	-->
	<!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
	<arm>
		<!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
		<!-- Units of functionality -->
		<uof name="Furniture_catalogue">
			<description> 	 	
			The <b>Furniture_catalogue</b> UoF specifies the data types needed to represent products, their structure, 
			their variants and their finishing.      
			</description>
		</uof>
		<uof name="Interior_design">
			<description> 	 	
			The <b>Interior_design</b> UoF specifies the data types needed to represent The information that constitutes 
			the specification for the evaluation and the manufacturing of a decorated room.     
			</description>
		</uof>
		<!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm>
	<arm_lf/>
	<!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
	<!-- 	<mapping_table> 		<ae entity="xx"/> 	</mapping_table> 	-->
	<!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
	<mim>
		<!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim>
	<mim_lf/>
	<bibliography>
		
		<bibitem.inc ref="IEEE-IDEF0-1998"/>	
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-31.1994"/>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-41.2000"/>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-214"/>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-215.2001"/>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-225.2001"/>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-236"/>		
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-1103"/>		
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO4157-2.1998"/>
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO13584-20.1998"/>

	</bibliography>
</module>
