<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.6 2003/08/07 21:20:31 abf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="shape_appearance_layers"
   part="1009"
   version="2"
   wg.number=""
   wg.number.supersedes="N668"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="y"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/08/07 21:20:31 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.6 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, appearance assignment, styled element, visual attributes, layers
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="salmodules.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="salmodules.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: --> <purpose>
   <p>
This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for assignment of visual attributes and layers to shape models, geometric and topological elements. 
</p>
<p>
A set of application modules can be combined to provide the capability to assign shape elements to layers and visual attributes, such as colours and curve fonts, to geometric and topological elements.  
For additional information, see Annex F of this technical specification of ISO 10303. 
   </p>
<p>   
This edition incorporates modifications of the previous edition. 
</p>
<p>The following ARM EXPRESS constructs have been removed:</p>
<ul><li>
USE FROM of module Elemental_topology.
</li>
</ul>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>assignment of layers to shape items;</li>
<li>assignment of visual attributes to shape items;</li>
<li>assignment of colour to surfaces;</li>
<li>assignment of visual attributes to curves belonging to surfaces.
</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
 <li>definition of views on which shape models, geometric elements or annotation are presented;</li>
<li> specification of shape models.</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
   <!-- Units of functionality -->
   <uof name="Shape_appearance">
     <description>This UoF specifies information related to definition of visual attributes which may be assigned to shape items. In addition, it specifies contexts which allow for context-dependent assignment of visual attributes.
     </description>
     <uof.ae entity="Shape_appearance"/>
          <uof.ae entity="Shape_appearance_context"/>
   </uof>

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>

   <ae entity="Shape_appearance">
			<aimelt>(surface_usage_style)</aimelt>
			<source>ISO 10303-46</source>
	 

  
	  <aa attribute="appearance_style" assertion_to="Surface_appearance_wireframe"> 
		<aimelt>PATH</aimelt> 
 
				<refpath>surface_style_usage &lt;-
				presentation_style_assignment.styles[i]
				presentation_style_assignment
				presentation_style_assignment.styles[i] -&gt;
				presentation_style_select=surface_style_usage
				surface_style_usage</refpath>
 
	  </aa> 
	  
	  <aa attribute="appearance_style" assertion_to="Surface_colour"> 
		<aimelt>PATH</aimelt> 
				<refpath>surface_style_usage &lt;-
				presentation_style_assignment.styles[i]
				presentation_style_assignment
				presentation_style_assignment.styles[i] -&gt;
				presentation_style_select=surface_style_usage
				surface_style_usage</refpath> 
	  </aa> 

   </ae> 

 <ae entity="Shape_appearance_context">
			<aimelt>representation</aimelt>
			<source>ISO 10303-43</source>
	
  
	  <aa attribute="context_for_appearance" assertion_to="Representation"> 
		<aimelt>PATH</aimelt> 
				<refpath>representation &lt;-
				presentation_style_by_context.style_context
				presentation_style_by_context
				presentation_style_by_context.style_context -&gt;
				style_context_select=representation
				representation</refpath> 
	  </aa> 


</ae> 
  
   
   
   
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>


<usage_guide><p>The purpose of this application module is to bring together a set of application modules to provide the capability to assign shape elements to layers and visual attributes, such as colours and curve fonts, to geometric and topological elements. Figure E.1 shows the other application modules, and the dependencies between them, necessary to provide the shape appearance and layers capability. CAD vendors have developed test cases to assess their implementations of this application module
</p>
<p>
As depicted in figure F.1, the scope addressed in the Shape appearance layer application module requires eight other application modules. Appearance assignment, Foundation representation, General surface appearance, Elemental topological shape and Layer assignment are interfaced directly (see the USE FROM statements in clause 5). Colour, Elemental geometric shape and Curve appearance are included by virtue of the fact that the EXPRESS USE FROM interface declaration treats data types declared within or USE'd by the foreign schema as if declared locally.
</p>
<p>
The Shape appearance and layers application module can be combined with any other application module, application interpreted construct or application protocol whose EXPRESS interpreted schema includes subtypes of entities geometric_representation_item or topological_representation_item. This is illustrated in figure F.2. 
</p>
<example>To illustrate this generic approach, the Shape appearance and layers application module has been used to extend the capabilities of ISO 10303-203. Figure F.3 shows the short from of the EXPRESS schema used by CAD vendors for implementation.</example>

<p>
Figure F.4 shows an instance diagram of the population that meets a specific requirement: the assignment of colour to a geometric model (manifold_solid_brep). Figure F.5 illustrates the corresponding ISO 10303-21 file segment.
</p>
<note>The entity manifold solid_brep is outside the scope of the Shape appearance and layers application module. It is a subtype of solid_model which is a subtype of geometric_representation_item. This illustrates the point that this application module provides capability that can be reused in combination  with different application protocols or geometric application interpreted constructs.</note>


</usage_guide>
</module>
