<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../xsl/ap_doc/aam_descriptions.xsl"?>

<!--
     $Id: aam.xml,v 1.1 2002/11/14 18:00:32 goset1 Exp $
-->

<!DOCTYPE idef0 SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/aam.dtd">
<idef0>
	<viewpoint>a furniture wholesaler</viewpoint>
	<page number="1" node="A-0" title="Furniture industry activities.">
		<activity identifier="A0" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Furniture industry activities
			</name>
			<description>
				Furniture industry activities.
			</description>
		</activity>
	</page>
	<page number="2" node="A0" title="Furniture industry activities.">
		<activity identifier="A1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Furniture industry activities
			</name>
			<description>
				Processes of the product life cycle related to furniture industry.
			</description>
		</activity>
	</page>
	<page number="3" node="A1" title="Sell products.">
		<activity identifier="A2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Sell products
			</name>
			<description>
				Supply manufacturered products to an end user, as specified in an order prepared by a retailer according to the product specifications described by the manufacturer's catalogue (A0).
			</description>
		</activity>
	</page>
	<page number="4" node="A2" title="Create furnishing project.">
		<activity identifier="A21" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Create furnishing project
			</name>
			<description>
				Specify the essential elements and properties of a furnishing project in the form of lists of essential characteristics such as dimension, space distribution, etc... (A2).
			</description>
		</activity>
	</page>
	<page number="5" node="A4" title="Process the order.">
		<activity identifier="A41" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Process the order
			</name>
			<description>
				The manufacturer assesses the order according to commercial and technical criteria. If the order is rejected then the customer is informed of the reasons for rejection. If the order is accepted then the order information is passed to the production department and the customer is notified of the order acceptance (A4).
			</description>
		</activity>
	</page>
	<icoms>
	<!--
     A-0 diagram
	-->	
		<icom identifier="Design products" inscope="no">
			<name>
				Design products
			</name>
			<description>
				Define the requirements for new products taking into account factors including market situation, existing products, applicable standards, manufacturing and assembly requirements, and recyclability. Commercial and creative departments are involved; external designers may also be contracted to contribute to the design process (A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Develop products" inscope="no">
			<name>
				Develop products
			</name>
			<description>
				Produce detailed technical designs for products in form of CAD models, technical drawings, and other documents. Sometimes prototypes are required for production. Once the design is approved the price lists are prepared. There is collaboration between the technical and manufacturing departments in this phase (A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Manufacture products" inscope="no">
			<name>
				Manufacture products
			</name>
			<description>
				Produce furniture items from raw materials in order to obtain the final product to meet defined quality requirements. This activity consists of production programming, process planning and product manufacturing. Technical drawings are the information generated during design and development. Manufacturing resources are human resources (such as CNC operator and programmer) and physical resources (such CNC machinery, CAD/CAE systems, and tools) necessary for product manufacturing (A-03).
			</description>
		</icom>
	<!--
     A0 diagram
	-->		
		<icom identifier="Ship price list and catalogue" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Ship price list and catalogue
			</name>
			<description>
				Send the current product catalogue and associated prices. This activity ships the fees and catalogues to the Shops following the internal manufacturer's policy. Nowadays it is carried out by mail, in diskette or CD but it is intended to get the information in the future from the www through Internet services (A1).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Compile and send the order" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Compile and send the order
			</name>
			<description>
				Prepare and deliver the specifications required by a manufacturer to fulfil the requirements of a retailer or end user for a decoration project. These specifications include the decoration project design, the retailer's commercial data, requested delivery date, and terms of payment. This activity is undertaken by the retailer's commercial department when the retailer's offer is accepted by the end user (A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Deliver products" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Deliver products
			</name>
			<description>
				Transfer manufactured products from the manufacturer to the retailer, according to the manufacturing planning instructions (A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
	<!--
     A2 diagram
	-->	
		<icom identifier="Define space for furnishing project" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Define space for furnishing project
			</name>
			<description>
				Specify the space dimensions for a furnishing project (A21).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Select CAD library" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Select CAD library
			</name>
			<description>
				Identify the types of furniture items together with options such as finishes and accessories that are to be used in the CAD-deco system to create a decoration project (A22).
				NOTE	The CAD library selection process depends on the CAD-deco system used, but in general, it is carried out in several steps:
					select a catalogue, furnishing type, or product line; 
					select a manufacturer from the available libraries in the retailer's system;
					select a programme; each manufacturer groups products in different catalogues, where all the items in a programme have similar features;
					select finish(es), such as the style of the pieces of furniture, different colours, and different types of handle.
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Position objects for composition" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Position objects for composition
			</name>
			<description>
				Select items that are available in the CAD library and add them to decoration project definition in the context of the space(s) that are being furnished. The location of each selected item is specified (A23).
				NOTE	The items can be taken from manufacturers' catalogues, 'standard' items, or defined for the actual composition with particular features, non lineal items. Standard items have basic attributes:
					surrounding dimensions (height, width, depth);
					box or front division;
					materials (finishing);
					fixed (dimensions changes are not allowed) or special.
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Prepare offer for end user" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Prepare offer for end user
			</name>
			<description>
				Generate the costs associated with the items specified for the decoration project. The costs can be consulted at any time during the project design. Modifications can be carried out based on design or budgetary constraints (A24).
			</description>
		</icom>
	<!--
     A4 diagram
	-->	
		<icom identifier="Compile order information" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Compile order information
			</name>
			<description>
				Compile order information: Apply the manufacturer's order filter policy to select the processable orders (A41).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Verify retailer's credit" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Verify retailer's credit
			</name>
			<description>
				Each manufacturer has a customer data base with the relevant data from each retailer, updating periodically their data (A42).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Verify technical data" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Verify technical data
			</name>
			<description>
				All the data are checked once the technical information is isolated, first of all the completeness of data and possible coding errors, later, the technical feasibility (A43).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Process rejected order" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Process rejected order
			</name>
			<description>
				When a project has technical or credit irregularities is sent to this activity (A44).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Calculate special case" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Calculate special case
			</name>
			<description>
				Determine the budget and delivery date for special products that are included in a decoration project, so that the retailer can calculate the final project budget (A45).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="Process accepted order" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				Process accepted order
			</name>
			<description>
				Analyze an order and derive the information necessary to initiate the necessary processes such as production, logistics, and planning (A46).
			</description>
		</icom>



		<icom identifier="accepted offer" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				accepted offer
			</name>
			<description>
				Specification of the budget for a decoration project that has been reviewed and accepted by the end user (output from A2/A24, input to A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="CAD deco system" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				CAD deco system
			</name>
			<description>
				A computer aided design system used by a retailer or by a manufacturer to design decoration projects (mechanism for A2/A21, A22, and A23).		</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="CAD library" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				CAD library
			</name>
			<description>
				Selection of furniture items according to manufacturer, product line, and style. The CAD library items are available to use in a decoration project (output from A22, input to A23).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="CAD system" inscope="no">
			<name>
				CAD system
			</name>
			<description>
				Computer hardware and software that supports the computer aided design of products by providing functions for defining the geometry (2D or 3D) and technological properties (mechanism for A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="CAD system" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				CAD system
			</name>
			<description>
				Computer hardware and software that supports the computer aided design of products by providing functions for defining the geometry (2D or 3D) and technological properties (mechanism for A43, and A45).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="cancellation" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				cancellation
			</name>
			<description>
				Rejection of an order (input to A46).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="commercial department" inscope="no">
			<name>
				commercial department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible of the distribution of commercial information and for filtering and compiling order information (control on A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="company objectives" inscope="no">
			<name>
				company objectives
			</name>
			<description>
				The set of achievements foreseen by a company. These objectives will affect directly technical and commercial policies to be applied to the design process (control on A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="creative department" inscope="no">
			<name>
				creative department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible of the development of new ideas for bringing the new product to market (mechanism for A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="credit acceptance" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				credit acceptance
			</name>
			<description>
				Confirmation of the retailer's financial status, including credit rating and payment history (output from A42, control on A43).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="delivered products" inscope="no">
			<name>
				delivered products
			</name>
			<description>
				Products shipped to the retailer (output from A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="delivery date" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				delivery date
			</name>
			<description>
				Date when the products required for a decoration project are to be shipped to the retailer (output from A41, input to A43).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="design information" inscope="no">
			<name>
				design information
			</name>
			<description>
				Functionality, geometry, and technological properties (output from A-01, input to A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="designer" inscope="no">
			<name>
				designer
			</name>
			<description>
				Person in charge of defining the design information of a product (mechanism for A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="end user data" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				end user data
			</name>
			<description>
				Information about who sends the order to buy a product (input for A0).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="end user requirements" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				end user requirements
			</name>
			<description>
				Information supplied by the end user indicating the desired functional and physical characteristics of the items to be included in a decoration project, including the style, materials, and colours (input to A2/A21, and A22).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="furnishing constraints" inscope="no">
			<name>
				furnishing constraints
			</name>
			<description>
				The rules imposed by a manufacturer and controlled by a CAD-deco systems influence or determine the selection of items for a decoration project (control on A2/A21, A22, andA23).
				EXAMPLE	Furnishing constraints can include location rules, joining rules among pieces, limits on combinations of styles, colours, and finishes, and price list rules.
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="furnishing project design" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				furnishing project design
			</name>
			<description>
				Information that defines the products needed for a furnishing project in the context of the space(s) they will be placed in. This information can include different views of the furnished space(s), such as plan, elevation, and perspective drawings (output from A2/A23).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="furnishing project cost" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				furnishing project cost
			</name>
			<description>
				Budget proposed to the end user (output from A23, input to A24).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="internal information" inscope="no">
			<name>
				internal information
			</name>
			<description>
				Data which is related to and is useful only for a company (input to A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufactured products" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufactured products
			</name>
			<description>
				Products ready for shipping following the order indications and data (output from A-03, input to A0/A5).
			</description></icom>
		<icom identifier="manufactured products" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufactured products
			</name>
			<description>
				Products ready for shipping following the order indications and data (output from A-03, input to A0/A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's selling policy" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturer's selling policy
			</name>
			<description>
				Rules for delivering information to different retailers based on geographic and/or commercial relationships (control on A0/A1).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's commercial department" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufacturer's commercial department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible of the distribution of commercial information to the manufacturer's clients and for filtering and compiling order information (mechanism for A0/A1, and A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's commercial department" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturer's commercial department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible for filtering and processing orders from retailers (mechanism for A0/A1, and A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's internal computer system" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufacturer's internal computer system (mechanism for A41, and A42).
			</name>
			<description>
				General software for administration and production management.
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's notification" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufacturer's notification
			</name>
			<description>
				An acceptance or rejection notification send by a manufacturer to a retailer. The notification will be positive (acceptance) if all technical and commercial constraints and requirements are satisfied (output from A4/A44, and A46, control on A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's notification" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturer's notification
			</name>
			<description>
				An acceptance or rejection notification send by a manufacturer to a retailer. The notification will be positive (acceptance) if all technical and commercial constraints and requirements are satisfied (output from A4/A44, and A46, control on A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's rules" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufacturer's rules
			</name>
			<description>
				Rules defined for special products, such as increments over the normal price that apply to manufacturing modifications to standard designs (control on A45).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's technical department" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufacturer's technical department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible for technical verification of orders and for analysis and response to requirements for special or non-standard products (mechanism for A4/A43, and A45).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturer's technical department" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturer's technical department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible for technical verification of orders and for analysis and response to requirements for special or non-standard products (mechanism for A4/A43, and A45).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturers' samples" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturers' samples
			</name>
			<description>
				Examples of different manufacturers' products used by the retailer to show end users the characteristics of different products, such as their materials, colour, finish, and quality (mechanism for A2/A22).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturing constraints" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturing constraints
			</name>
			<description>
				The imposed rules which influence or determine the development of products (control on A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturing orders" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturing orders
			</name>
			<description>
				Requests of manufacturing a product after being designed and developed (output from A-02, input to A-03).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturing planning" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturing planning
			</name>
			<description>
				The set of instructions that apply to the manufacturing process, including distribution routes, controls and transport indications (output from A-02, control on A-03, and A0/A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturing requested changes" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				manufacturing requested changes
			</name>
			<description>
				 Modifications which are needed in order to manufacture the product (output from A-02, control on A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="manufacturing resources" inscope="no">
			<name>
				manufacturing resources
			</name>
			<description>
				Provision of the available material and human resources which are necessary for producing the product (mechanism for A-03).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="market survey" inscope="no">
			<name>
				market survey
			</name>
			<description>
				Research process whose objective is to find out what the market demands or how it will react from certain products (input to A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="order filter policy" inscope="no">
			<name>
				order filter policy
			</name>
			<description>
				The set of technical and commercial filters that are applied to an order before the rejection or acceptance process. These specify the restrictions and controls that determine whether an order is accepted into the manufacturer's systems (control on A0/A4/A41, A42, and A44).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="order information to production" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				order information to production
			</name>
			<description>
				Notification that specifies the products to be produced, packaged and shipped in response to an order, and initiates the production process for those products (output from A0/A4/A46, control on A-03, control on A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="order" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				order
			</name>
			<description>
				Specification of a number of furniture items to be produced and delivered to a retailer or end user. The order is prepared by the retailer with the help of the CAD-deco system to obtain the budget and the views needed for the particular project.
				NOTE 1	Orders are conventionally sent by letter or fax from the retailer to the manufacturer; increasingly email and other forms of e-commerce are being used.
				NOTE 2	An order consists of three basic parts:
					retailer's data such as name and address;
					the decoration project design, consisting of the documents needed to describe the project completely;
					identification of the items Article description; quantity, code, description, price, etc.
				When the project contains special products (products that are not catalogued products) the order may also include sketches indicating dimensions, notes, etc. (output from A3, input to A4/A41).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="planning system" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				planning system
			</name>
			<description>
				Software tool used to automate the production planning process including the creation of process plans and the determination of manufacturing sequences (mechanism for A44, and A46).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="price list" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				price list
			</name>
			<description>
				A list of the prices of a determined number of products (output from A-02, input to A0/A1).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="price list and catalogue rules" inscope="no">
			<name>
				price list and catalogue rules
			</name>
			<description>
				The constraints imposed by a manufacturer and controlled by a CAD-deco system that influence or determine the selection of items for a decoration project based on price (control on A24).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="price list and catalogue" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				price list and catalogue
			</name>
			<description>
				Description of the furniture items that can be supplied by a manufacturer together with prices and other information necessary for ordering, including name, code, dimensions, drawings, and photographs (output from A1, control on A2/A22).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="product catalogue" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				product catalogue
			</name>
			<description>
				A document that identifies the products that a manufacturer can make including the available options and possible combinations. The product catalogue consists of textual and graphical descriptions of the manufacturer's products (including sketches, diagrams, and photographs) and can be published on paper or in electronic form (output from A-01, input A0/A1).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="product requeriments" inscope="no">
			<name>
				product requeriments
			</name>
			<description>
				Restrictions which should be taken into account in order to produce a product (input to A-01).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="prototypes" inscope="no">
			<name>
				prototypes
			</name>
			<description>
				The models or patterns from which subsequent copies are made, or improved specimens are developed (output from A-03, input to A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="quality control" inscope="no">
			<name>
				quality control
			</name>
			<description>
				Mechanism which evaluate and optimize the quality or reliability of a product or process (control on A-03).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="raw material" inscope="no">
			<name>
				raw material
			</name>
			<description>
				Crude unprocessed or partially processed material used as a feedstock for a processing operation (input to A-03).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="rejected order form" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				rejected order form
			</name>
			<description>
				A document sent by a manufacturer to a retailer specifying the reasons for the rejection of an order (output from A42, input to A44).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="rejected technical project" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				rejected technical project
			</name>
			<description>
				A project that can not be produced for technical reasons (output from A43, input to A44).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="requested delivery date" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				requested delivery date
			</name>
			<description>
				The preferred date, specified by a retailer, on which goods are to be delivered to an end user (input to A0/A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="requested terms of payment" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				requested terms of payment
			</name>
			<description>
				The preferred commercial conditions, specified by the retailer, for the purchase of goods from a manufacturer (input to A0/A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="retailer data" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				retailer data
			</name>
			<description>
				The name and address of the retailer together with other information including company and government identifiers (input to A0/A1).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="retailer's data" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				retailer's data
			</name>
			<description>
				The name and address of the retailer together with other information including company and government identifiers (output from A41, input to A42).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="retailer's commercial department" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				retailer's commercial department
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible for determining an end user's requirements, creating a decoration project definition meeting those requirements, preparing an offer to the end user, and compiling and sending an order to a manufacturer (mechanism for A0/A3, and A2/A21, A23, and A24).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="sketches for space definition" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				sketches for space definition
			</name>
			<description>
				It can be in several ways; technical drawings of the room to furnish, hand made sketches or oral information from the buyer (input to A2/A21).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="space and materials" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				space and materials
			</name>
			<description>
				When the end user information space is defined (shape and measures) introducing real dimensions, identifying walls, doors, windows and accidents and defining material qualities for floor, ceiling, doors, etc (output from A21, input to A23).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="special case conditions acceptance" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				special case conditions acceptance
			</name>
			<description>
				When a project has 'special' products, out of catalogue; with cuts, horizontal, vertical, -both longer or shorter than usual-, with a different shape, etc., the budget is calculated based on manufacturer's rules and most cases the budget is produced by the commercial manufacturer's department. Then this acceptance notification is sent to the manufacturer (output from A3, input to A4/A45).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="special case conditions" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				special case conditions
			</name>
			<description>
				Budget and delivery date for the special project are sent back to the Retailer waiting for acceptance (output from A4/A45, control on A46, and A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="special case conditions" inscope="no">
			<name>
				special case conditions
			</name>
			<description>
				Special budget for special products including delivery date (output from A4/A45, control on A46, and A3).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="special products" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				special products
			</name>
			<description>
				In case the project has special products is needed to be sent to the calculate special case activity with the information concerning with the special items (output from A43, input to A45, and A46).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="standard products" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				standard products
			</name>
			<description>
				When the project consists of standard product, from the catalogue a completeness and feasibility check is carried out and if the result is positive it is sent to the process accepted order activity, in other case it is sent to the process rejected order activity (output from A43, input to A46).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="standards" inscope="no">
			<name>
				standards
			</name>
			<description>
				Rules applicable to the furniture industry as a whole, or to a specific furniture company in order to ensure commonality between products and tools. These rules can be international standards (e.g., ISO, IEC), national standards (e.g., AFNOR, ANSI, DIN), or company policies (control on A-01, and A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="technical data" inscope="yes">
			<name>
				technical data
			</name>
			<description>
				Information for the project to be develop, drawings, material indications, sketches, etc (output from A41, input to A43).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="technical drawings" inscope="no">
			<name>
				technical drawings
			</name>
			<description>
				Descriptive pictures which are necessary to manufacture a product (output from A-02, input to A-03).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="technical office" inscope="no">
			<name>
				technical office
			</name>
			<description>
				Personnel responsible of the development of the technical drawings (mechanism for A-02).
			</description>
		</icom>
		<icom identifier="transport resources" inscope="no">
			<name>
				transport resources
			</name>
			<description>
				Vehicles available in the company for expedition and transport of the products to Retailers (mechanism for A5).
			</description>
		</icom>
	</icoms>
</idef0>
