<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.5 2004/11/10 23:06:21 abhpf Exp $ --><!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd"><!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com --> <!--      To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml      --><module   name="organization_structure"   name.french=""   part="1435"   version="1"   sc4.working_group="12"   wg.number="00000"   wg.number.arm=""   wg.number.mim=""   checklist.internal_review=""   checklist.project_leader=""   checklist.convener=""   status="WD"   language="E"   publication.year=""   publication.date=""   published="n"   rcs.date="$Date: 2004/11/10 23:06:21 $"   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.5 $"   development.folder="dvlp"> <keywords>    module, systems engineering, organization, project management </keywords><!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope --> <abstract>    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation      of information needed to manage the life cycle process of developing and using      a system such that qualified persons and organizations can be assigned to projects.</li> </abstract> <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml --> <contacts>   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/> </contacts> <!-- Introduction --> <!-- The introduction should start as shown: --> <purpose>   <p>     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation      of information needed to manage the life cycle process of developing and using      a system such that qualified persons and organizations can be assigned to projects.</p>      <p>Systems Engineering encompasses the design and specification of systems, and    the planning and management of the engineering processes that design, manufacture,    field, and support that system. This module captures information concerning    organizations and persons associated with those organizations along with useful    relationships to experience and qualifications. That information is needed to manage    the life cycle process of developing and using a system such that qualified persons    and organizations can be assigned to projects.   </p>   <p>This AP233 business case module is constructed from several ISO/TS Application    modules:</p>   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="organization_type:introduction"/>    captures the definition of the types of organizations    that project management deals with.</p>   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="person_organization:introduction"/>    captures definitions of a person and an    organization with related information. It captures the definition of a relationship    between two organizations and the identification of a person in the context of an    organization. It captures the definition of an address for persons or organizations,    and the assignment of an address to a person in an organization or to an organization.</p>   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="experience:introduction"/>    captures the kinds of experience that is relevant to a    project. It associates experience with persons and organizations.</p>   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="position_in_organization:introduction"/>    captures the definition of a position    in an organization and the definition of types of positions. It captures the    several relationships among positions and organizations.</p>   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="qualifications:introduction"/>    provides the information needed by management to    match persons and organizations to projects based on the skills needed for tasks,    and the qualifications of the people/organizations. It captures the identification    of qualifications and the association of qualifications with a person or an organization.</p>   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="type_of_person:introduction"/>    captures the definition of a type of person and    the relationships between definitions of a type of person. It captures the association    of a type of person in a role with an activity or product data, the classification of    types of person, and the specification of required attributes for a type of person    including qualifications and experience. It does not capture information relating to    an individual person.</p> </purpose> <!-- Items in scope --> <inscope>   <li>representation of the information to define and relate information    associated with organization;</li>   <li>definition of person an organization;</li>      <li>definition of type of organization and relationship between two organizations;</li>      <li>definition of position type in organization;</li>      <li>relationship between position, person and organization;</li>      <li>identification of experience and qualification of person an organization;</li>      <li>identification and association of experience, qualifications and position with person an organization.</li>  </inscope> <!-- Items out of scope --> <outscope>   <li>association of person an organization with activity or product data;</li>      <li>identification and characterization of person an organization associated schedule;</li>   <li>identification and characterization of person an organization associated work;</li>   <li>identification and characterization of person an organization associated project breakdown;</li>   <li>identification and characterization of person an organization associated project management information resources;</li>   <li>the relationships between project breakdown and project management information resources, schedule and work structure. </li></outscope><!-- <normrefs/> <definition/> <abbreviations/>--> <!-- Clause 4 ARM  --> <arm>   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->   <express-g>     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>     <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>   </express-g> </arm> <!-- ARM long form (optional) --> <!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:          arm_lf.xml          armexpg_lf1.gif          armexpg_lf1.xml --> <arm_lf>   <!-- Note ARM long form EXPRESS is in arm_lf.xml -->   <express-g>     <imgfile file="armexpg_lf1.xml"/>   </express-g> </arm_lf> <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification --> <mapping_table>   <ae entity="xx"/> </mapping_table> <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM --> <mim>   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->   <express-g>     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>   </express-g> </mim>  <!-- MIM long form (optional) --> <!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:          mim_lf.xml          mimexpg_lf1.gif          mimexpg_lf1.xml --> <mim_lf>   <!-- Note MIM long form EXPRESS is in mim_lf.xml -->   <express-g>     <imgfile file="mimexpg_lf1.xml"/>   </express-g> </mim_lf></module>