<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: mkmodule.js,v 1.41 2004/10/11 20:17:49 thendrix Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="organization_structure"
   part="1435"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="00000"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems engineering, organization, project management
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of information that provides relationships, 
     functional roles, skill qualification and documentation.</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of information that provides relationships, 
     functional roles, skill qualification and documentation.</p> 

     <p>Systems Engineering encompasses the design and specification of systems, and 
   the planning and management of the engineering processes that design, manufacture, 
   field, and support that system. This module captures information concerning 
   organizations and persons associated with those organizations along with useful 
   relationships to location and qualifications. That information is needed to manage 
   the life cycle process of developing and using a system such that qualified persons 
   and organizations can be assigned to projects.
   </p>

   <p>This AP233 module is constructed from several ISO/TS Application modules, The 
   associated rational for inclusion follows:</p>
   <p>The Organization Type Module captures the definition of types of organizations 
   that project management deals with.</p>
   <p>The Person Organization Module captures definitions of a person and an 
   organization with related information. It captures the definition of a relationship 
   between two organizations and the identification of a person in the context of an 
   organization. It captures the definition of an address for persons or organizations, 
   and the assignment of an address to a person in an organization or to an organization.</p>
   <p>The Certification Module captures any type of person or organization certification 
   relevant to the project management.</p>
   <p>The Experience Module captures the kinds of experience that is relevant to a 
   project. It associates experience with persons and organizations.</p>
   <p>The Location Module captures the location of products, resources, and activities 
   for the purpose of managing projects. The location information may be geographic, 
   postal information, or based on codes or zones. The locations may refer to other 
   locations. </p>
   <p>The Location Assignment Module captures the association of location with a 
   product, event, activity, or person for the purpose of managing projects. It 
   captures the vapd use of an association of a location with organization, organization 
   type, position, position-type, type of person, and person in organization.</p>
   <p>The Person Organization Assignment Module captures the associations of an 
   organization with activity or product data and the association of a person in an 
   organization with activity or product data.</p>
   <p>The Position In Organization Module captures the definition of a position 
   in an organization and the definition of types of positions. It captures the 
   several relationships among positions and organizations.</p>
   <p>The Quapfication Module provides the information needed by management to 
   match persons and organizations to projects based on the skills needed for tasks, 
   and the quapfications of the people/organizations. It captures the identification 
   of quapfications and the association of quapfications with a person or an organization.</p>
   <p>The Type of Person Module captures the definition of a type of person and 
   the relationships between definitions of a type of person. It captures the association 
   of a type of person in a role with an activity or product data, the classification of 
   types of person, and the specification of required attributes for a type of person 
   including quapfications and experience. It does not capture information relating to 
   an individual person.</p>
   
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>######## Editorial note: Following list must be condensed down</li>
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Certification</li>
    <li>definition of a certificate;</li>
   <li>assignment of a certificate to activity or product data </li>
   <li>assignment of a certificate to a person and/or an organization  </li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Experience</li>
   <li>the identification of experience</li>   
   <li>the association of experience with a person or an organization</li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Location</li>
   <li>the geographic position of products, resource items or activities;</li>   
   <li>the specification of location by use of organizational based codes;</li>   
   <li>the specification of location by postal address, including nested addresses;</li>   
   <li>the specification of location by product based codes, or zone within a product, including nested locations;</li>   
   <li>the location relative to another location.</li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Location assignment</li>
  <li>the association of location with a product, event, activity, or person;</li> 
   <li>the valid use of a association of a location with other data.</li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Organization type</li>
   <li>the definition of type of organization.</li>
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Person organization</li>
   <li>definition of a person;</li>   
   <li>definition of an organization;</li>   
   <li>definition of a relationship between two organizations;</li>   
   <li>identification of a person in the context of an organization;</li>   
   <li>definition of an address for persons or organizations;</li>   
   <li>assignment of an address to a person in an organization or to an organization.</li>
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Person organization assignment</li>
   <li>association of an organization with activity or product data;</li>   
   <li>association of a person in an organization with activity or product data.</li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Position in organization</li>
   <li>the definition of a position in an organization;</li>   
   <li>the definition of type of position;</li>   
   <li>the relationship between positions and organizations;</li>   
   <li>the relationship between positions;</li>   
   <li>the relationship between a position and a person, an organization, or a person in an organization.</li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Qualification</li>
   <li>the identification of qualifications;</li>   
   <li>the association of qualifications with a person or an organization.</li> 
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Type of person</li>
   <li>the definition of a type of person;</li>   
   <li>the relationships between definitions of a type of person;</li>   
 <li>######### Editorial note: From Organization structure information type extends enabled by entities of the 
 Organization structure arm’s USE FROM schemas</li>
   <li>the association of a type of person in a role with an activity or product data;</li>   
   <li>the classification of types of person;</li>   
   <li>the specification of required attributes for a type of person including qualifications and experience.</li>
   <li>The association of certification with an organization structure item</li>   
   <li>The association of location to an organization structure item</li>   
   <li>The association of organization or person in organization to a describing attribute of an organization structure item</li>   
   <li>The association of position in an organization structure to an organization or person in organization assignment</li>   
   <li>The association of type of person in an organization structure to a person or position</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>xxxx</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
