<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.5 2003/01/13 13:59:52 seanbarker Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="observation"
   part="1258"
   version="1"
   wg.number="1579"
   wg.number.arm="1580"
   wg.number.mim="1581"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/01/13 13:59:52 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.5 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

<express language_version="2"
   description.file="arm_descriptions.xml"
/>

 <keywords>
    module
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="seanbarker"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of Observation.
     An observation provides a place to note down the relation of an observed fact to thing which it describes, and link it to any consequence that may result. It is intended to be used in two ways. Firstly, it provides a general mechanism to link the unexpected to the well defined world of the product and its design. Secondly, it provides a defined mechanism for reporting observations within the context of the standard, given that the set of observations required will vary between products and organisations.</p>
     <p>For example, a crack may occur in the wall of a container. Observation allows the fact that the crack has appeared to simply be noted. Subsequent inspections required by the organisation may then want to record the size of the crack. Since a crack is not a design feature, this cannot be done directly in the design data for the container, nor do the design data standards allow for multiple historical observations
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>historical observations;</li>
   <li>the association of an observation to the thing observed;</li>
   <li>the association of an observation to its context;</li>
   <li>the association of an observation to the actual activity taking place when it was observed;</li>
   <li>the association of the observation with the observer;</li>
   <li>the association of the observation to its consequences;</li>
   <li>the association of observations with each other;</li>
   <li>the aggregation of observations;</li>
   <li>the record of the date and time that the observation was made;</li>
   <li>the classification of the observation;</li>
   <li>the formal verification or confirmation of the observation.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>recording predicted or required information, including predicted or required properties or any design information.</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
   <!-- Units of functionality -->
   <uof name="Observation">
     <description>
     </description>
     <uof.ae entity="Observation"/>
     <uof.ae entity="Observation_relationship"/>
     <uof.ae entity="Observation_consequence"/>
   </uof>

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
