<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../make-menu.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><html>
   <head>
      <this-is section="samples" page="dotnetsamples" subpage=""/>
      <!--
           Generated at 2010-10-29T18:20:48.427+01:00--><title>Saxonica: XSLT and XQuery Processing: Example applications for .NET</title>
      <meta name="coverage" content="Worldwide"/>
      <meta name="copyright" content="Copyright Saxonica Ltd"/>
      <meta name="title"
            content="Saxonica: XSLT and XQuery Processing: Example applications for .NET"/>
      <meta name="robots" content="noindex,nofollow"/>
      <link rel="stylesheet" href="../saxondocs.css" type="text/css"/>
   </head>
   <body class="main">
      <h1>Example applications for .NET</h1>
      <p>The <code>/samples/cs</code> directory contains somer sample applications written in C#, 
designed to illustrate use of the Saxon API available in the <code>Saxon.Api</code> namespace.
In particular there are three programs <code>ExamplesHE.cs</code>, <code>ExamplesPE.cs</code>,
and <code>ExamplesEE.cs</code> relevant to Saxon-HE, Saxon-PE, and Saxon-EE respectively; each shows
various ways of invoking XSLT, XQuery, XPath, and schema validation where appropriate. The idea
is that you should be able to cut and paste a suitable fragment of code into your own application
as a quick way of getting started.</p>
      <p>The main value of these samples is in reading the source code rather than in actually running them;
however, running them is also a good check that your installation has been set up correctly.
a quick look at the comments in the source should enable you to see how they are executed.
Note that they all require the environment variable <code>SAXON_HOME</code> to be set to the directory
where Saxon is installed: this is used to find the sample data files.</p>
      <p>The example applications can be run from the command line. They take the following arguments:</p>
      <ul>
         <li>
            <p><b>-dir:<i>samples</i></b> - provides the name of the samples directory from the saxon-resources
        download. The default uses the SAXON_HOME environment variable - but it's normally best to supply this
        parameter explicitly.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p><b>-ask:<i>yes|no</i></b> - with ask:yes (the default), the application prompts after each test to ask if you
        want to continue.</p>
         </li>
         <li>
            <p><b>-test:<i>testname</i></b> - supplies the name of the test you want to run, or "all" (the default) to indicate
        all tests.</p>
         </li>
      </ul>
      <p>Also in the same directory is an application <code>TestRunnerProgram.cs</code> which is a test harness
     for running the XSLT, XQuery, and XSD test suites published by W3C (in the case of XSLT, the test data is available
     to W3C members only).</p>
      <table width="100%">
         <tr>
            <td>
               <p align="right"/>
            </td>
         </tr>
      </table>
   </body>
</html>