<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.30 2006/11/20 10:31:39 rugarcia Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module name="catalog_data_information_and_shape_representation" 
	name.french="Informations de donn&#233;es de catalogue et repr&#233;sentation de formes" 
	part="1352" 
	version="1" 
	sc4.working_group="12" 
	wg.number="2164" 
	wg.number.arm="2165" 
	wg.number.mim="2167" 
	wg.number.arm_lf="2166" 
	wg.number.mim_lf="2168" 
	checklist.internal_review="2189" 
	checklist.project_leader="2190" 
	checklist.convener="2191" 
	status="TS" 
	language="E" 
	publication.year="2006" 
	publication.date="2006-07-26" 
	published="y" 
	rcs.date="$Date: 2006/11/20 10:31:39 $" 
	rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.30 $" 
	development.folder="dvlp">
	<keywords>
	products catalogs, 
	shape representation, 
	geometric models, 
	surface conditions, 
	geometric tolerances, 
	dimensions
	 </keywords>
	<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
	<contacts>
		<projlead ref="ap236.projlead"/>
		<editor ref="ap236.editor"/>
	</contacts>
	<!-- Introduction -->
	<purpose>
		<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation of the data that identify 
		and characterize products offered to market and of their components. This application module provides 
		specifications suitable for the representation of any kind of such products. In particular, this application 
		module enables the representation of products proposed to market with a great number of variants and 
		whose composition is characterized due to the selection among a set of different product features. 
		</p>
		<example>
		Examples of such products are the products developed by the furniture industry, the automotive industry 
		and the commercial airplane industry.
		</example>
		<p>
		This application module specifies the data types and their constraints. It specifies the conformance class 
		1 of ISO 10303-236.
		</p>
		<p>
		A catalogue contains a list of references of different commercial products that are proposed to customers 
		or to distributors. A catalogue provides a commercial view of the products of a supplier or manufacturer but 
		it does not represent the design information of the commercial products.
		</p>
		<p>
		It also provides information about the planned usage of components in a product model.
		</p>
		<p>
		The core of the product model is catalogue information. This information is connected to other parts in order 
		to define the geometry of the products and to select a set of product features.
		</p>
		<p> 
		This application module provides the definition for the main information data of a catalogue, such as the 
		definition of a product (and its different versions) and its specifications (the features of a product that the 
		customer can chose in order to select one product from another). The structure of the product (the product 
		itself or the decomposition of the product in its components), the effectivity of the catalogue itself or its 
		products, the effectivity of the prices of the products, documents (hardcopies or digital files) that gives 
		additional information about the product such as detailed information, pictures, technical drawings, and a 
		classification of the products in order they could be found easily in a catalogue depending on different search 
		criteria; the properties of the product (not selectable by the user). It specifies the main concepts for representing 
		a catalogue specification in the <module_ref linkend="product_class:introduction">ISO/TS 10303-1103</module_ref> 
		(Product class). It also adds to the catalog data information the capability of including the geometry of the products. 
		It includes application modules for the representation of geometric models, surface conditions, geometric 
		tolerances, dimensions that characterize the shape of product components, through subtypes of the generic 
		type <express_ref linkend="elemental_geometric_shape:arm:Elemental_geometric_shape_arm.Geometric_model">
		Geometric Model</express_ref>.
		</p>
		<note>
		This application module is an extension of the Catalog_data_information module,
				<module_ref linkend="catalog_data_information:introduction">ISO/TS 10303-1351</module_ref>.
		</note>
		<p>
		This application module specifies the schema associated with conformance class 2 of application protocol ISO 
		10303-236.
		</p>
	</purpose>
	<!-- Items in scope -->
	<inscope>
		<li>representation of catalog product data definition;</li>
		<li>supporting of catalog product stucture;</li>
		<li>possibility of variants and options for product representations;</li>
		<li>products classification and products specification associated control;</li>
		<li>product dimensions;</li>
		<li>price lists based on products identification and associated characteristics;</li>
		<li>product configuration based on diferent characteristics;</li>
		<li>multi-language support;</li>
		<li>approval status of the products;</li>
		<li>effectivity for data validation;</li>
		<li>documents definition and assignment;</li>
		<li>product identified by its manufacturing configuration;</li>
		<li>product geometry including advanced boundary representation, faceted boundary representation, 
		manifold surfaces with topology, geometrically bounded surface, geometrically bounded wireframe 
		2d and 3d geometry, wireframe with topology, and constructive solid geometry;</li>
		<li>product geometric validation properties, for the assessment of the quality of conversions that occur in a 
		transfer of geometric data;</li>
		<li>surface conditions;</li>
		<li>geometric tolerance.</li>
	</inscope>
	<!-- Items out of scope -->
	<outscope>
		<li>work management data.</li>
	</outscope>
	<!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
	<arm>
		<!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
		<!-- Units of functionality -->
		<uof name="CC2">
			<description>
			The CC2 UOF specifies the data structure needed for the representation of complex marlketed products, 
			of their components, of their shape, of their properties and of their documentation.
			</description>
		</uof>
		<!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm>
	<!-- ARM long form (optional) -->
	<arm_lf/>
	<!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
	<mapping_table>
		<sc constraint="subtype_exclusiveness_geometric_model" entity="Geometric_model">
			<rules>subtype_exclusiveness_shape_representation_geometry</rules>
			<source>ISO 10303-1352</source>
		</sc>
	</mapping_table>
	<!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
	<mim>
		<!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg2.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim>
	<!-- MIM long form (optional) -->
	<mim_lf/>
	<bibliography>	
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-236"/>	
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-1103"/>	
	</bibliography>
</module>
