<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.13 2007/01/14 21:26:19 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!--      To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml      -->
<module
   name="system_modelling"
   part="1477"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="3"
   wg.number=""
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   wg.number.arm_lf=""
   wg.number.mim_lf=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   publication.date=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2007/01/14 21:26:19 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.13 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">
<keywords>module, systems engineering, system behavior, system structure, trade study </keywords>
<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope --> 
<abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the variety of general model classifications used to
      support model-based systems engineering.  This includes all models used to
      characterize the physical structure and its behavior and the full range of
      models used to support system engineering trade studies.</li>
</abstract> 
<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml --> 
<contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead2"/>  
   <editor ref="phil.spiby"/> 
</contacts> 
<!-- Introduction --> 
<!-- The introduction should start as shown: --> 
<purpose>
  <p>
    This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
    representation of the variety of general model classifications used to
    support model-based systems engineering.  This includes all models used to
    characterize the physical structure and its behavior and the full range of
    models used to support system engineering trade studies.
  </p> 
  
  <p><b>Hyperlink to Annex F for AP233 concept model introductory material associated 
  with system modelling capabilities enabled within AP233 and its connectivity to 
  modules used.</b></p> 
  
</purpose> 
 <!-- Items in scope --> 
 <inscope>
   <li>System behaviour</li>
   <li>System structure</li>
   <li>Decision support</li>
   <li>Requirements, analysis, trade studies</li>
   <li>Verification and validation</li>
   <li>Configuration management</li>
   <li>Grouping</li>
 </inscope>
 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>Program and project management data</li>
 </outscope>
<!-- <normrefs/>
 <definition/>
 <abbreviations/>
-->
 
<!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <!-- <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg3.xml"/> -->
   </express-g>
 </arm>
 
 <!-- ARM long form (optional) --> 
<!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files: 
           arm_lf.xml 
           armexpg_lf1.gif 
           armexpg_lf1.xml --> 
<arm_lf> 
 <!-- Note ARM long form EXPRESS is in arm_lf.xml --> 
 <express-g> 
  <imgfile file="armexpg_lf1.xml"/> 
 </express-g> 
</arm_lf> 


<!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>
 
<!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

<!-- MIM long form (optional) --> 
<!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files: 
          mim_lf.xml 
          mimexpg_lf1.gif 
          mimexpg_lf1.xml --> 
<mim_lf> 
 <!-- Note MIM long form EXPRESS is in mim_lf.xml --> 
 <express-g> 
  <imgfile file="mimexpg_lf1.xml"/> 
 </express-g> 
</mim_lf> 
 
  <usage_guide>
  
    <p>
    This module is one of AP233's two top level modules.  Its focus is on the
    variety of modeling paradigms used to represent the physical and functional
    system along capabilites used to support associated verification, validation and
    trade studies. It links to but does not include capabilities that support the
    managment activities of systems engineering.
   </p>
      
  
   <p>Figure 1 provides a concept map AP233 as it is presented herein</p>
   
   	<figure> <title>AP233_arm_Concept_Map</title>
			<img src="AP233_arm_Concept_Map.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
   <p>Relative to the concept of system modelling, the top level modules that enable all of 
   AP233's current capapbility are listed below.  Within each see Annex F for additional 
   discussion and follow hyperlinks
   provided down to the most atomic level of detail:</p>
   <ul>
   <li><module_ref linkend="decision_support:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="function_based_behaviour:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="requirement_management:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="state_based_behaviour:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_behaviour:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_modelling:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_structure:introduction"/></li>
   </ul>
   
   <p>At the next concept modelling level of abstraction down, the following modules are
   of prime importance to enabling AP233's system modeling capability.  Within each see scope 
   statements and Clause 4.</p>

   <ul>
   <li><module_ref linkend="activity_as_realized:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="analysis_assignment:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="behaviour_description_assignment:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="extended_task_element:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="group:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="interface:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="measure_of_effectiveness:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="product_as_individual:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="product_breakdown:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="task_element:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="verification_and_validation:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="system_identification_and_version:introduction"/></li>
   <li><module_ref linkend="verification_and_validation:introduction"/></li>
   </ul>
   
   <!-- 
   
   Insert front end of SE Handbook chapter 33 here
   
   -->
   
   <p>What follows is a set of definitions and a model that closely aligns with how systems are 
   modeled by engineers, how they are treated in science, and how they are represented in 
   differential and partial differential equations.  This provides the highest level view of 
   AP233.  If defines AP233's information modelling requirements from the perspective of hindsight.  
   It is the high level view of the framework that has been enabled.</p>
   
   <p>Figure 2 below and associated definition list provides a graphical model that captures 
   the definitions and relationships associated with a system model.</p>
   
      
   	<figure> <title>SE Handbook Chapter 33 Figure 3</title>
			<img src="SE_Handbook_Slide3.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
   <p>Anything is that which can be observed, conceived, or imagined.  This definition includes 
   not just observable reality, but also the subjects of dreams, hallucinations, stories, and 
   imagination.</p>
   
   <p>An Engineering_Thing is that for which observable, measurable, and reproducible properties 
   or attributes can be obtained. An Engineering_Thing is a subclass of Anything.  Responsible 
   engineering is based on the ability to predict performance from the observable properties of 
   the things engineers will use. The advance of technology is the expansion of our knowledge of 
   these properties.</p>

   <p>An Observable_Characteristic are observable, measurable and reproducible properties of an 
   Engineering_Thing. An Engineering_Thing has Observable_Characteristic. The advances of science 
   and engineering in the last 300 years are based on careful observation and measurement. The 
   reproducibility of the results is checked by independent experimentation. The rapidity of 
   advance follows from rapid and widespread publication of result with rapid independent 
   confirmation or denial of the results.</p>

   <p>An Emergent property is a synonym for Observable_Characteristic.  It is used in the context 
   quantifying the observable, measurable and reproducible properties of a system</p>

   <p>The Environment is all of the Engineering_Things that need to be considered for a 
   particular problem. The Environment contains some of the totality of Engineering_Things. 
   It contains just those that need to be considered for the problem at hand. The black diamond 
   is a SysML and UML standard symbol for “part of” “or “some of”. It is a decomposition of the 
   whole into some of its parts. For any engineering problem it is essential to consider everything 
   that is important to the problem and to exclude things from consideration that would be a waste 
   of resources to investigate. </p>

   <p>A Boundary is a separation of a space (solution space or mathematical space) of 
   Engineering_things into regions. The boundary partitions Environment into regions of interest 
   to the engineer. Problems can be simplified and solutions found more quickly if they can be 
   partitioned into strongly interacting, weakly interacting or independently acting parts. </p>

   <p>) A System is an Engineering_Thing that exhibits a well defined Boundary. A system is a 
   subclass of an Engineering_Thing.  It inherits a relationship to Observable_Characteristic.
   A system a Boundary; stystems are built from Systems (systems of systems form a hierarchy) and 
   Systems connect with Systems. For a thing to be a system it must exhibit observable and 
   reproducible properties and have a boundary that separates it from all the other things in 
   the environment. It is essential to know what is inside the system and what is outside.</p>

   <p>An Interface is a region ( e.g. point, surface or volume) of connection between two 
   Engineering_things. A System has  Interface and Interface has Observable_Characteristic.  
   There are points, surfaces, and volumes of any System that connect it to other 
   things. These interfaces are important for maintenance, for moving it during manufacture, 
   for logistics and installation, for testing, and for attaching to larger systems.</p>

   <p>The Observable_Characteristic associated with an interface also needs discussion. 
   Current passing through the electrical interfaces of a battery in a flashlight is not a 
   property of those interfaces but rather the result of the EMF of the batteries and the 
   impedance of the circuit. The spring force holding the batteries in place is an 
   Observable_Characteristic. This spring force only exists when the batteries are 
   installed in place. When you plug your laptop into an electric outlet, the value of 
   current that flows is not a property of the interface. The maximum safe current through 
   the interface is such a property as is the force required to plug and unplug the connector. 
   These are emergent properties that come into existence when two things are interconnected.</p>

   <p>A System/System_Interface is an Interface between two Systems.  A System/System_Interface 
   is a subclass of Interface</p>

   <p>Environment/System_Interface is aInterface between a System and an Engineering_thing in 
   the Environment. An  Environment/System_Interface is a subclass of Interface.  A Boundary is 
   built from (composed of) all the Environment/System_Interface.  A system has many interfaces 
   for many different purposes. The total or collection of all these important interfaces 
   defines the boundary of the system.</p>

   <p>A System View is a partial description of a System using some of the associated 
   Observable_Characteristic. A System View is part of (3) Observable_Characteristic.  A
   System View describes System.  Most engineering problems consider only some portion of a 
   system, relative to some small set of engineering domains and some particular issues. </p>

   <p>Context is the point of view or focus of interest taken in dealing with a system. A 
   System View has a Context. Most engineering problems consider only some portion of a 
   system and particular issues associated with those portions. </p>

   <p>Analysis is the observation, measurement, or calculation of the Emergent_Property of 
   a whole based on the Emergent_Property of the parts.  Emergent property is a synonym for
   Observable_characteristic.  Analysis determines the Emergent_Property of a System because 
   of its inheritance from Engineering_Thing. It is the progress of science in providing 
   rigorous laws and models for determining the reproducible and observable characteristics of 
   Engineering_Thing that has given us our analysis capabilities.</p>

      <p>Figure 3 below and associated definition list provides a graphical model that captures 
   the definitions and relationships associated with a requirements and trades model.</p>
   
      
   	<figure> <title>SE Handbook Chapter 33 Figure 4</title>
			<img src="SE_Handbook_Slide4.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
   <p>Stakeholder is the people, organizations and institutions that receive some benefit from a 
   System and have an interest in the system. A Stakeholder is a part of the Environment.
   A Stakeholder is an Engineering_thing. They include, for example, the producers, 
   producer employees, competitors, sellers, advertisers, transporters, owners, customers, 
   regulators, operators, users, maintainers, and disposers of the system.</p>

   <p>Stakeholder_need defines the benefits the Stakeholder desires to receive from or to be 
   delivered by the system when it is implemented and functioning. The Stakeholder has 
   Stakeholder_need. At the top level of development these Stakeholder_needs drive the 
   requirements for the system and the optimization criteria for its development.</p>

   <p>A Business is the purposeful activity of a person or group of persons to supply products 
   and services to themselves or others. Both local and global commerce are based on the existence 
   of a multitude of businesses engaged in the exchange of products and services.  </p>

   <p>A Business_strategy is the science, art, and plan for employing the economic, sales, 
   marketing, contracting, development, purchasing, advertising, logistics, sourcing, 
   psychological, and  political, capabilities of a (15) Business or a consortium of 
   Businesses to achieve a set of goals.  A Business has a Business_strategy. How successfully 
   a business meets its goals in a competitive marketplace is dependent on the completeness 
   and efficiency of its business strategy. </p>

   <p>A System_alternative defines the many different solutions to the problem of designing 
   and implementing the system. The System is a subclass of System_alternative. In the 
   development of a system there are many System_alternatives that could be used. The 
   solution space is large. The design problem is to pick a nearly optimal solution that 
   will succeed in the marketplace. It is this choice from among the System_alternatives 
   that is the system.</p>

   <p>A Requirement is a statement of an Emergent_property that a System_alternative shall 
   exhibit to be considered as a solution for a System.  A Requirement is a statement of an 
   Emergent_property that a System shall exhibit. This follows logically from the definition 
   of Requirement and a particular System_alternative becoming the system. A Requirement is 
   derived from Stakeholder_need.  A Requirement is derived from Business_strategy
   A child Requirement is derived from a parent Requirement and traces to it.  A Requirement 
   is evaluated with Analysis.  A requirement is a statement about a solution for a system 
   or one of its interfaces that describes a response to excitation, a time duration for the 
   response or a physical property value like mass that shall be met by the solution. Since 
   the system will be one of these solutions, it is both the collection of alternative 
   solutions and the one picked to be the system that shall “meet” the requirements. 
   The interaction with the stakeholders may be very informal, it may be a summary of 
   sales and marketing data, or it may be the result of a formal interaction with 
   stakeholders using a mathematical based process like Analytical Hierarchical Process, (AHP).</p>

   <p>A Measure_of_effectiveness is a requirement for the optimization of the system. 
   Measure_of_effectiveness is a Requirement. Measure_of_effectiveness provides the optimization 
   criteria for selecting a single solution from among all System_alternative. As a result of 
   inheritance  a Measure_of_effectiveness  is derived from Stakeholder_need.  It is also 
   derived from Business_strategy.  A child Measure_of_effectiveness  is derived from a parent 
   Measure_of_effectiveness  and traces to it.  A Measure_of_effectiveness is evaluated with 
   Analysis..The optimization of the whole system by choosing the “best” among 
   System_alternative is a most important aspect of MOE’s. The fact that MOE’s are derived 
   from parent MOE’s means that the subsystems are optimized for optimization of the entire 
   system to fit the marketplace. This is not optimization the subsystems themselves 
   independent of the whole system. System optimization for the marketplace is a major purpose 
   of systems engineering and a significant competitive advantage. The (19) Measure_of_effectiveness 
   has the same relationships as (18) Requirement by inheritance. Modeling the MOE’s as a 
   subclass of (18) Requirement provides these relationships. It also provides for 
   traceability and identification of parent-child derived relationships. </p>

   <p>Weight is a numerical factor that gives a relative importance to each item in a set of items. 
   Each Measure_of_effectiveness has Weight. Many decisions involve several decision criteria. 
   In the general case these are not of equal importance. A numerical weight is often assigned 
   to the decision criteria to specify their relative importance. Usually a larger number 
   implies greater importance.</p>

   <p>Optimization_direction is a statement of whether the optimization direction associated 
   with a particular MOE is to maximize or minimize. Each Measure_of_effectiveness has 
   Optimization_direction. Every MOE will need to be either maximized or minimized.</p>

   <p>A Regularization_function is an analytical function that for each System_alternative 
   combines MOE’s with their weight and  Optimization_direction to calculate a single 
   optimization figure of merit for each System_alternative.A Measure_of_effectiveness is 
   evaluated for System_alternative. Once the elderly couple has established their home 
   buying criteria and the compromise weights for these, they need to apply them to the 
   many homes they see offered for sale. The analytical approach is to apply a regularization 
   function for each of these homes. The resulting value for each home is its figure of 
   merit. Note that many decisions are made without this analytical approach by applying 
   an intuitive figure of merit, “I like this one best”, to the homes offered, the 
   System_alternatives.</p>

   <p>The AHP analytical formulation is very similar to that of optimal control theory and 
   statistical optimization that use a function, often called a cost function, to fulfill
   a similar role. In all three of these cases: selection of (17) System_alternative, 
   optimal control and statistical optimization, the optimum solution found depends upon 
   the form of the regularization function that is used.</p>

  </usage_guide>
 
</module>