<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.3 2003/03/04 09:18:47 davidleal Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="maths_space"
   part="1091"
   version="1"
   wg.number="1878"
   wg.number.arm="1879"
   wg.number.mim="1880"
   checklist.internal_review="1995"
   checklist.project_leader="1996"
   checklist.convener="1997"
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/03/04 09:18:47 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.3 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, mathematics, space, set
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap221.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="ap221.projeditor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module to record a mathematical space.  A mathematical space is a set of mathematical values that can be either finite or infinite.  A mathematical space can be used as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>to identify a set of property values;</p>
<example>The set of property values that is the set of
temperatures between 20 degrees Celsius and 30 degrees Celsius is identified by
the set of real values between 20.0 and 30.0 with respect to the Celsius scale.
</example>
<example><p>The set of properties that is the set of spatial
positions within the metal of beam 'XB_001' is defined by the set of real
triples within 'my subset of the space of real triples' with respect to metres
and a my coordinate system.</p>
<p>'My subset of the space of real triples' is defined as the image of a
function from:</p>
<ul>
<li>the unit cube which is a parameter space for beam 'XB_001'; to </li>
<li>the space of real triples which are Cartesian coordinates for space. </li>
</ul>
</example>
</li>
<li><p>to identify a set of features within a physical object;</p>
<example>The set of points within beam 'XB_001' is identified
by the set of real triples within the unit cube with opposite corners (0, 0, 0)
and (1, 1, 1). This unit cube is a parameter space for 'XB_001'.</example>
</li>
</ul>
<p>An infinite set of mathematical values cannot (clearly) be explicitly
enumerated. Instead an infinite set is defined implicitly as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>as the image or graph of a mathematical function; or</p>
</li>
<li><p>by parameterisation.</p>
<example>The set of real values within a unit cube can be defined by
specifying the mathematical values that lie at the corners of the cube. </example></li>
</ul>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
<li><p>the definition of a mathematical space that is a real or integer interval;</p>
<note number="1">This capability is defined completely in ISO 10303-50.  This part of 
ISO 10303 merely references the capability and does not add any additional
semantics.</note>
</li>
<li><p>the definition of a finite mathematical space by enumerating its
members.</p>
<note number="2">This capability is defined completely in ISO 10303-50.  This part of 
ISO 10303 merely references the capability and does not add any additional
semantics.</note>
</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
<li><p>the relationship between a mathematical space and a property space that
it identifies;</p>
<note number="3">Information about the coordinate systems and units of measure that can be
used to interpret a mathematical value within a mathematical space as a
description of a property value within a property space is within the scope
of the <module_ref linkend="property_identification:1_scope">Property_identification</module_ref> application module.</note>
</li>
<li><p>an individual mathematical value that is not a mathematical space;</p>
</li>
<li><p>mathematical expressions;</p></li>
<li><p>mathematical functions.</p></li>
 </outscope>

<normrefs>
<normref.inc normref="ref10303-50.2001"/>
<normref.inc normref="ref10303-54.2002">
      <term.ref linkend="class"/>
   </normref.inc>
</normrefs>

 <!-- <definition/> -->

 <abbreviations/>
 
 

  <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
   <!-- Units of functionality -->
   <uof name="Maths_space">
     <description>
<p>The Maths_space UoF defines a set of mathematical values.</p>
<note>A Maths_space can be specified as the range or domain of
a mathematical function.</note>
<note>A Maths_space is purely mathematical and does not have
units of measure or a coordinate system.</note>
     </description>
     <uof.ae entity="Maths_space"/>
   </uof>

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="Maths_space">
     <aimelt>maths_space</aimelt>
     <source>ISO 10303-50</source>
   </ae>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
