<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="express_model.xsl"?>
<!--
# $Id: express_model.xml,v 1.8 2004/10/25 16:10:46 joshualubell Exp $

# EXPRESS MODEL DECLARATION MODULE

# This set of declarations defines the EXPRESS-2 Model as of the
#      date shown in the Formal Public Identifier (FPI) for this entity.
# 
#      This set of declarations may be referred to using a public external
#      entity declaration and reference as shown in the following two lines:
# 
# <!ENTITY % express.model PUBLIC "-//TC184 SC4//DTD EXPRESS Model 20010901">
# %express.model;
# 
#      If the parameter entity description.content used within this set 
#      of declarations is to be given non-default values, the appropriate 
#      declaration should be given before calling in this package 
#      (i.e., before the "%express.model;" reference).

# This file was developed by Eurostep and supplied to NIST under contract.
# Authors:
#    Rob Bodington
#    David Price
#    Nigel Shaw
#    Phil Spiby
# Reviewed by:
#    Josh Lubell
-->

<article xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <articleinfo>
    <author>
      <firstname>Joshua</firstname>
      <surname>Lubell</surname>
      <affiliation>
	<orgname>National Institute of Standards and Technology</orgname>
	<orgdiv>Manufacturing Systems Integration Division</orgdiv>
      </affiliation>
      <email>lubell@nist.gov</email>
    </author>
    <title>STEP Modules Repository EXPRESS Model (STEPmod)
Specification</title>
    <pubdate>$Date: 2004/10/25 16:10:46 $</pubdate>
  </articleinfo>
  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>

The STEP Modules Repository is a collection of reusable XML building
blocks for developing standards from information models defined in
EXPRESS. An integral part of the repository's XML vocabulary is its
representation of EXPRESS language constructs, i.e. its EXPRESS
model. This specification shall refer to this EXPRESS model portion of
the repository's XML vocabulary as <emphasis>STEPmod
EXPRESS</emphasis>.

    </para>
<para>

STEPmod EXPRESS was originally defined using a Document Type
Definition (DTD) because, at that time, more expressive XML schema
languages such as the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) XML Schema
definition language (XSD) and RELAX NG were not mature standards, and
software tools supporting these languages were unstable. Although XSD
has since become a W3C standard and RELAX NG has since become an ISO
standards, the current XML schema for STEPmod EXPRESS does not use any
of the expressive power offered by these languages. This may change in
the future. For example, XSD and RELAX NG both provide stronger
datatyping than DTD, and RELAX NG can enforce co-occurrence
constraints between XML attributes. Both of these capabilities would
be useful for improving the validation of STEPmod EXPRESS XML
instances.

</para>
<para>

STEPmod EXPRESS takes a middle-of-the-road approach regarding the
level of granularity of the XML markup with respect to to the EXPRESS
language. High level EXPRESS structures such as data types, their
attributes, and inheritance relationships are marked up. Expressions,
on the other hand, are not. As a result, STEPmod EXPRESS is suitable
for applications such as EXPRESS schema browsers as well as partial
mappings to other modeling languages such as UML and OWL.

</para>
  </section>
<!--  <xi:include href="schemadoc.xml"/> -->
</article>
