<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.10 2003/07/07 16:51:24 robbod Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="ap239_product_life_cycle_support"
   part="439"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="3"
   wg.number="1236"
   wg.number.arm="1237"
   wg.number.mim="1238"
   wg.number.arm_lf="1239"
   wg.number.mim_lf="1240"
   checklist.internal_review="1241"
   checklist.project_leader="1242"
   checklist.convener="1243"
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/07/07 16:51:24 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.10 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, Product life cycle support, Integrated Logistic Support,
   Maintenance
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope 
 <abstract>
    <li>xxxxxzzzz</li>
 </abstract> -->

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="plcs.projeditor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of product life cycle support.  It provides a
     comprehensive capability to describe a set of products needing support and
     the work needed to sustain such products in an operational condition. 
   </p>
   <p>
     The module enables the creation and management through time of an
     Assured set of Product and Support Information (APSI) which can be used to
     specify and control required support activities throughout a product's
     life.  This information is assumed to be subject to configuration change
     management to sustain the information needed to support the product in line
     with the changing product, over its full life cycle. 
   </p>

   <p>
     Capability is also provided to describe the resources required,
     provided and used to deliver support, and to record the history of the
     product usage, state and work done.  This concept is illustrated by Figure
     <module_ref
       linkend="ap239_product_life_cycle_support:introduction:figure:f1">
       1
     </module_ref>.
   </p>
   <figure id="f1">
     <title>The PLCS Vision</title>
     <img src="figure1.png"/>
   </figure>

   <p>
     The module was developed to represent the data associated with complex
     engineering assets, such as aircraft, ships or weapon systems, which may
     exist either as a product design, or as an actual product. It can also be applied to
     much simpler products such a pump or an amplifier. The range of target
     products is shown by Figure
     <module_ref
       linkend="ap239_product_life_cycle_support:introduction:figure:f2">
       2
     </module_ref>.
     The shaded area represents main industry focus for this module. This
     is characterized by complex high value products with long life cycles
     and demanding in-service support requirements.
    </p>
    <figure id="f2">
      <title>Market segmentation</title>
      <img src="figure2.png"/>
    </figure>
    
    <p>
      Most of the capability provided by this module is contained in
      sub-ordinate modules.  The top of the AP239 module hierarchy is shown in
      Figure
     <module_ref
       linkend="ap239_product_life_cycle_support:introduction:figure:f3">
       3
     </module_ref>.
    </p>
    <figure id="f3">
      <title>Abstraction of module hierarchy</title>
      <img src="figure3.png"/>
    </figure>
    <p>
      The specific capabilities added by this module is the collection of
      AP239 modules to a single root. 
    </p>
    <!--
    <ul>
      <li>
        The collection of AP239 modules to a single root;
      </li>
      <li>
        The declaration of a relationship between data recording the
        occurrence of an activity and that reporting the state of a
        product;
      </li>
    </ul> -->
  </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   
   <li>
     Product Assembly
     <ul>
       <li>
         the representation of parts, their versions, their definitions, and their
         management information, such as dates, that are assigned to them;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of assignments of an identifier and alias
         identifications to parts and their versions;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of characterization views of a version of a part; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of the data that identify a product and the
         categories of products it belongs to;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of relationships between versions of products; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of context-dependent relationships between
         definitions of product versions;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of the composition of an assembly as parent-child
         relationships between views on products;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of the shape of an assembly as the composition of the
         shape representation of its components;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of valued properties to a part or to an assembly; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of documentation to a part or to an assembly.  
       </li>
     </ul>
   </li>

   <li>
     Through life Product
     <ul>
       <li>
         the identification of positions within an assembly of parts to which
         component parts may be attached;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification of parts that are attached to identified positions
         within an assembly;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification and representation of a breakdown of a product
         or product_as_individual;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of the replacement of a product by another; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation and classification of documents and document
         information that may apply to part definition information;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of properties of objects, their values and types,
         and classifications;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of information that records the identification of
         an existing or potential future artifact - an actual product whose
         properties can only be known by observation or by derivation from
         observations;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of interfaces between products; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of the life cycle phase of existing interfaces
         between actual products (as realized), and includes planned interfaces
         between planned products;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of relationships between requirements and items to
         which they are assigned, and between requirements and the items which are
         their source;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of the information that identify a requirement and
         versions of requirements;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of characterization views of a requirement version; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of relationships between requirements which are
         expressed as relationships between requirement view definitions, for
         example, the relationships are dependent on the version of the requirement
         and the view of that version;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of a type of state; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of an observed state; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification of the configuration of a product for a given product concept; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the specification of effectivity constraints applied to configuration of a product. 
       </li>
     </ul>
   </li>

   <li>
     Specification and planning of activities
     <ul>
       <li>
         the specification of tasks as a sequence of instructions encoded as text; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the specification of tasks as a structured set of instructions; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of pre-and post-conditions to a task or a stage
         within a task;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of properties with task specifications; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification of products to which tasks are assigned; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the specification of conditions under which a task falls due; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification of resources required by tasks; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification of products, or categories of products, as resource items;
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of a position within an organization;
       </li>
       <li>
         the representation of a type of person with qualifications and experience;
       </li>
       <li>
         the identification of locations at which a resource may exist or
         an activity occur; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of a location with a task or resource;
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of dates, times, people, approvals and other
         management data with task specifications;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the association of a justification and a probability with a task
         assignment to a product, or a resource assignment to a task;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the capability to capture plans and schedules; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the control of work through requests and work orders; 
       </li>
     </ul>
   </li>
   

   <li>
     Activity history
     <ul>
       <li>
         the recording of the usage of a product; (where usage is treated as an activity);
       </li>
       <li>
         the recording of the activities performed on a product; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the recording of the use of resources during usage of a product; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the recording of the use of resources during activities performed on a product; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the recording of observations against a product or its support solution; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the relationship of the record of an activity to the work order, work
         request and work definition from which it arose.  
       </li>
     </ul>
   </li>


   <li>
     Product history
     <ul>
       <li>
         the recording of the assignment and conditional evaluation of an
         individual state as an activity;  
       </li>
       <li>
         the recording of the assignment of an individual state as justified; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the behaviour or history of product data capable of having individual state; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the behaviour or history of product data capable of having state; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the location of product data; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the observation of product data; 
       </li>
       <li>
         the recording of state for the context-dependent relationship
         between two product definitions.
       </li>
     </ul>
     <note>
       Further detail on the scope of this part may be obtained from the scope
       statements of used modules. 
     </note>
   </li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>
     the representation of business transactions for orderings, supplying
     or transporting the resources needed for product support.
   </li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
   <normref.inc module.name="product_as_individual">
     <term.ref linkend="product_actual"/>
   </normref.inc>
 </normrefs>

 <definition>
   <term id="apsi_def">Assured set of product and support information</term>
   <def>
     the set of information needed to develop and deliver support for a
     specific product that is subject to configuration change management. 
   </def>
 </definition>

 <definition>
   <term id="plc">product life cycle</term>
   <def>
     the complete process of designing, manufacturing, operating and
     supporting a product, including its final disposal.
   </def>
 </definition>

 <definition>
   <term id="plc">product life cycle support</term>
   <def>
     the support of a product throughout the product life cycle.
   </def>
 </definition>

 <abbreviations>

   <abbreviation id="APSI">
     <acronym>APSI</acronym>
     <term>Assured set of Product and Support Information</term>
   </abbreviation>

   <abbreviation id="APSI">
     <acronym>PLCS</acronym>
     <term>Product Life Cycle Support</term>
   </abbreviation>
 </abbreviations>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>

 <!-- ARM long form (optional) -->
 <!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          arm_lf.xml
          armexpg_lf1.gif
          armexpg_lf1.xml -->

 <arm_lf>
   <!-- Note ARM long form EXPRESS is in arm_lf.xml -->
 </arm_lf>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table/>


 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

 <!-- MIM long form (optional) -->
 <!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          mim_lf.xml
          mimexpg_lf1.gif
          mimexpg_lf1.xml -->
   <!-- Note MIM long form EXPRESS is in mim_lf.xml -->
   <mim_lf/>




</module>
