<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module name="ap210_device_functional_and_physical_characterization" part="1612" version="1" sc4.working_group="3" wg.number="00000" wg.number.arm="" wg.number.mim="" checklist.internal_review="" checklist.project_leader="" checklist.convener="" status="CD-TS" language="E" publication.year="" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2005/02/02 09:40:53 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.10 $" development.folder="dvlp" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <keywords>
    module, piece part model, pin map, black box, package, functional data, component, shape parameter, domain discipline, nodal representation, netlist, library
 </keywords>
    
    <contacts>
        <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
        <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
    </contacts>
    <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of device functional and physical characterization.
Device Data includes following information: device black box model, package data, functional
data, environmental constraints, performance data, simulation models. Formal encapsulation of
external data type definitions is made for parametric data and analysis models. Pin mapping
is provided to ensure consistency between device views. Shape, material, technology, tolerance
on shape and on parameters, units are included. Shapes included may be categorized according
to discipline (e.g. thermal analysis, vibration analysis), and analysis environment (e.g., design,
assembly, end-user). Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing is included. The functional
data includes two distinct data sets: hierarchical functional decomposition into behavioural
elements embedded in a network represented at each level by a nodal formulation; collection of
device terminals (e.g., connector terminals, printed circuit board interface areas, jumper ends)
that implement the functionality of a network node. Configuration management information
and design management information is provided. This data includes at least one geometric
representation.
   </p>
 </purpose>
    <inscope>
        <li>black box models;</li>
        <li>pin mapping between functional and physical view;</li>
        <li>mapping to simulation model;</li>
        <li>classification of shape purposes for black box models;</li>
        <li>nodal based behavioural representation;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of AP210_product_data_management_arm;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of Characteristic_arm;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of Chemical_substance_arm;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of Functional_assignment_to_part_arm;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of Network_functional_design_view_arm;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of Packaged_part_black_box_model_arm;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of Part_feature_grouping_arm.</li>
    </inscope>
    <outscope>
        <li>white box models</li>
        <li>design definition</li>
    </outscope>
    <arm>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </arm>
    <arm_lf/>
    <mapping_table>
        
    </mapping_table>
    <mim>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </mim>
</module>
