<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module name="ap210_package_functional_and_physical_characterization" part="1624" version="1" sc4.working_group="3" wg.number="1670" wg.number.arm="1671" wg.number.mim="1672" wg.number.arm_lf="1728" wg.number.mim_lf="1729" checklist.internal_review="1740" checklist.project_leader="1741" checklist.convener="1742" status="CD-TS" language="E" publication.year="" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2005/02/10 02:44:19 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.15 $" development.folder="dvlp" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <keywords>
    module, electrical, container, package, case style, material, encapsulant, simulation model, geometric model, terminal, lead, pin, feature, orientation, two dimensional, three dimensional
 </keywords>
    
    <contacts>
        <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
        <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
    </contacts>
    <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of package functional and physical characterization.
Package Data includes following information: Case style, material identification, environmental
constraints, performance data, simulation models. Formal encapsulation of external data type
definitions is made for parametric data and analysis models. Terminal identification is provided
to ensure consistency between 2D and 3D geometric models. Package body material is included.
Terminals may have core and surface materials. Shape, material, technology, tolerance on
shape and on parameters, units are included. Extensive support for orientation synchronization
between enterprises is provided. Shapes included may be categorized according to discipline
(e.g, thermal analysis, vibration analysis), and analysis environment (e.g., assembly, end-user).
Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing is included. Complex packages may be treated by
the design owner as an interconnect product and publish the information in package as the
customer view. Formal Reference information to a defining document is provided. Configuration
management information and design management information is provided. This data includes
at least one geometric representation.
   </p>
 </purpose>
    <inscope>
        <li>package physical characterization;</li>
        <li>package geometric functional characterization;</li>
        <li>package terminal functional characterization;</li>
        <li>package body geometrical characterization;</li>
        <li>package body material characterization;</li>
        <li>package terminal material characterization;</li>
        <li>mapping to package simulation model for mechanical analysis;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="characteristic:1_scope">Characteristic</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1654;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="chemical_substance:1_scope">Chemical substance</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1655;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="package:1_scope">Package</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1707;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="part_feature_grouping:1_scope">Part feature grouping</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1713.</li>
    </inscope>
    <outscope>
        <li>algorithmic definition of mechanical analysis model of package</li>
        <li>piece part internal functionality description</li>
    </outscope>
    <arm>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </arm>
    <arm_lf/>
    <mapping_table>
        
    </mapping_table>
    <mim>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </mim>
    <mim_lf/>    
</module>
