<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.20 2011/10/18 04:07:56 jhaenisch Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="ap242_business_object_model"
   part="1818"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="2817"
   wg.number.arm="2816"
   wg.number.mim="2812"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   publication.date=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2011/10/18 04:07:56 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.20 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, business objects
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>xxxxx</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="xxx"/>
   <editor ref="xxx"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Change history -->
 <!-- If the module is not a first edition, then document the change history -->
 <!-- If the module is a first edition, then comment out this section -->


 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the Business Object model for ISO 10303-242, Managed model based 3d engineering.
     The information model of this part of ISO 10303 is on a higher
level of granularity than the ARM of ISO 10303-242 to be better
suited for the communication with and understandability by 
experts of the domains aerospace, defense and automotive. It consists of
Business Objects that represent major concepts and information
requirements of a subset of ISO 10303-242, Model based 3d
engineering. It uses the vocabulary of the STEP modules where this
vocabulary reflects the terminology of the domain experts;
otherwise, new vocabulary is introduced. The relationship between
the Business Object model and the ARM of ISO 10303-242 is
explained in this part of ISO 10303. A
technical discussion of the Business Object model is contained in
Annex H of ISO 10303-242.
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>application objects in ISO 10303:242-managed mode-based 3d engineering</li>
<li>business terminology used to describe capabilities at a higher level of abstraction that current terminology used in ISO 10303</li> 
<li>business terminology that will facilitate the development of application programmer interfaces for ISO 10303:242 managed model-based 3d engineering</li>
</inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>application programmer interface specific terminology</li>
<li>terminology related to other parts of ISO 10303</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->
<abbreviations>
<abbreviation id="BO">
     <acronym>BO</acronym>
     <term>business object</term>
   </abbreviation>
</abbreviations>
 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

<uof name="Activities">
    <description>
   The Activities capability represents information concerning the management of activities. The capability allows the representation of activities and their associated methods.  
<ul><li>Activity</li>
<li>Activity_assignment</li>
<li>Activity_method</li>
<li>Activity_method_relationship</li>
<li>Activity_method_work_request_association</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Approval, Contract, Project and Alias">
    <description>
This capability represents the product and activity management information Approval, Contract, Project and Alias.
These concepts are defined and their assignment to product and activity data is specified. Various types of relationships are provided among Approvals and among Projects.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Alias_identification;</li>
<li>Approval;</li>
<li>Approval_assignment;</li>
<li>Approval_relationship;</li>
<li>Certification;</li>
<li>Contract;</li>
<li>Contract_assignment;</li>
<li>Project;</li>
<li>Project_assignment;</li>
<li>Project_relationship.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Document Identification">
    <description>
This capability represents information concerning the management of documents and their versions.  A managed document is under revision control, and may distinguish various representation definitions of a document version.  The document version represents the minimum identification of a managed document under revision control.  Base document identification is always associated with at least one document version.  Multiple document versions of a base document identification may be related together to represent document version history, or to state that one document version is derived from another document version. Documents may be classified according to specific criteria.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Document;</li>
<li>Document_category;</li>
<li>Document_version;</li>
<li>Document_version_relationship.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Document Structure and Properties">
    <description>
This capability represents information concerning the relationships between document definitions and files, and the association of properties to documents and files.
Document structure on representation and file level is supported by defining relationships between Document_definitions or Files.

Document properties can be associated to representations of documents as well as to individual files. If document properties are assigned to representations of documents, the characteristics apply as well to all the constituent files of the document representation in most cases.  Some properties with numeric values, such as 'file size' and 'page count', applied to the document representation will not correspond to an individual file in a multiple file document representation, but to the sum of all the files that make up the particular document representation definition.  
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Digital_document_definition</li>
<li>Digital_file;</li>
<li>Document_assignment;</li>
<li>Document_content_property;</li>
<li>Document_creation_property;</li>
<li>Document_definition;</li>
<li>Document_definition_relationship;</li>
<li>Document_format_property;</li>
<li>Document_location_identification;</li>
<li>Document_size_property;</li>
<li>Document_type_property;</li>
<li>External_source_identification;</li>
<li>File;</li>
<li>File_location_identification;</li>
<li>File_relationship;</li>
<li>Hardcopy;</li>
<li>Named_size;</li>
<li>Physical_document_definition;</li>
<li>Physical_model_definition;</li>
<li>Physical_representation;</li>
<li>Rectangular_size.</li></ul>  
    </description>
</uof>
<uof name="Effectivity">
    <description>
    The Effectivity capability represents information concerning the validity of data. Implicit propagation of data specifying validity is not available. The validity of data can be expressed by effectivities that specify, for example, time ranges within which data may be used. Explicit dates or dates expressed by events can be used in order to represent the relevant points in time. Validity may also be expressed for individual parts, which are identified by serial numbers.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Dated_effectivity</li>
<li>Effectivity</li>
<li>Effectivity_assignment</li>
<li>Effectivity_relationship</li>
<li>Lot_effectivity</li>
<li>Serial_effectivity</li>
<li>Time_interval_effectivity</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="External Models and References">
    <description>
This capability represents information concerning the management of externally defined models and their relationships. The external can be either an not further specified model, a 3D geometric model, or a two dimensional image. This capability further provides reference mechanisms to classes or properties defined in external libraries.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>External_geometric_model;</li>
<li>External_model;</li>
<li>External_model_relationship;</li>
<li>External_picture;</li>
<li>Library_reference;</li>
<li>Plib_class_reference;</li>
<li>Plib_property_reference.</li></ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Information Rights">
    <description>
This capability specifies the application of Information rights.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>definition of an information right;</li>
<li>historical record of granting and revoking a right to a person or organization;</li>
<li>association of the right to particular information items;</li>
<li>approval of the general grant of the right;</li>
<li>approval of a specific grant of a right against particular items of information;</li>
<li>identification of the contract under which the right is granted;</li>
<li>relationship of information usage rights to each other.</li></ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Materials">
    <description>
This Capability enables the representation of material by means of its properties and the association of material 
with products. The representation of the chemical structure of material is out of scope of this Capability.
<p>The following fundamental concepts and assumptions apply:</p>
<ul><li>material properties are defined by the environment that they are measured in;</li>
<li>such environments are described in terms of other types of properties;</li>
<li>material properties characterize some aspects of the behaviour of a product;</li>
<li>material properties are assigned to one or several materials, which may 
be associated with one or several products.</li>
</ul>
The following engineering considerations should be taken into account when using this Capability:
<ul><li>Material properties may be determined from measurements on the product as a whole, on a sample taken from 
the product in some way such as cutting, or an entirely separate test piece prepared by processing in the same 
way as the product. The application of the results derived from a test piece to the whole product is dependent on 
the relationship to the sample to the product because, as a result of the manufacturing process, the product 
may neither be homogeneous nor isotropic.</li>
<li>The values of most properties of a product are influenced by the effect that the manufacturing process has had on 
the product. The manufacturing process may affect the type and amounts of the units that make up the product and their 
form and arrangement. These units may be atoms, molecules or other aggregates of these in discrete forms such as crystals, 
fibres or volumes of semi-crystalline or glassy solids. The arrangement of the units is the material structure of the 
product.</li>
<li>The material structure of a solid product may be either homogeneous or heterogeneous, or a mixture of solids, 
such as in composite structures. A complete specification of the structure includes the relationship of any preferentially 
aligned elements of the structure to each other and to the product.</li>
</ul>
The following examples show how this Capability may be used:
<example number="1">A manufacturer may make a product to a specification and, instead of reporting actual measurements from a specific batch of the product, he may report the nominal value indicated in the specification.</example>
<example number="2">A chemist may perform calculations using assumed values of bond strengths to predict the strength of a polymer that has never been synthesised.</example>
<example number="3">An engineer performing a finite element analysis on a part might assign property values to predict potential product performance as a function of the property.</example>
<example number="4">A designer may specify material characteristics to achieve the required functionality of a part or to satisfy aesthetic or similar requirements.</example>
The following business objects are used by this Capability:
<ul><li>Data_environment;</li>
<li>Material_identification;</li>
<li>Material_property;</li>
<li>Material_property_assignment;</li>
<li>Material_property_definition.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Mating">
    <description>
This capability enables the representation of machining specific relationships among product and activity data.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make_from_relationship;</li>
<li>Process_state_relationship;</li>
<li>Same_time_machining_relationship;</li>
<li>Tool_part_relationship.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Multi Linguism">
    <description>
This Capability enables the representation of the language used in text attributes and the association of translations to these texts. Languages can be specified by a country and language code according to ISO 3166-1 resp. ISO 639-2. This information may be used to identify the language in which a text attribute is expressed. Translations in particular languages may be associated with a text attribute.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Attribute_translation_assignment</li>
<li>Language</li>
<li>Language_indication</li></ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Part View Definition">
    <description>
This capability provides the ability to represent basic product management information. It includes information about different views on part versions.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Part_view_definition</li>
<li>Part_version_view</li>
<li>General_part_version_view</li>
<li>Application_context</li></ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Person, Organization, Date and Time">
    <description>
This capability represents information concerning organizations and people in organizations as they perform functions related to other product data and data relationships.  A person shall exist in the context of some organization.  An organization or a person in an organization is then associated with the data or data relationship in some role indicating the function being performed. Both people and organizations may have addresses associated with them. Date and time can be used in combination with persons and organizations or directly associated with product data. Date and time information consists of simple calendar dates or time stamps more complex definitions like spans of time or events.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Address;</li>
<li>Date_and_person_assignment;</li>
<li>Date_and_person_organization;</li>	
<li>Date_time;</li>
<li>Date_or_date_time_assignment;</li>
<li>Duration;</li>
<li>Event;</li>
<li>Event_assignment;</li>
<li>Event_relationship;</li>
<li>Organization;</li>
<li>Organization_in_contract;</li>
<li>Organization_or_person_in_organization_assignment;</li>
<li>Organization_relationship;</li>
<li>Person;</li>
<li>Person_in_organization;</li>
<li>Person_in_organization_relationship;</li>
<li>Retention_period;</li>
<li>Time_interval_assignment;</li>
<li>Time_interval.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Physical Part">
    <description>
This capability provides the ability to represent information about physically realized parts, assembly structures of physically realized parts and results gained by testing physically realized parts of assemblies.
<ul><li>Physical_instance;</li>
<li>Physical_assembly_relationship;</li>
<li>Physical_instance_test_result.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>

<uof name="Planned and Evaluated Characteristics">
    <description>
This Capability represents information concerning the implementation of requirements. Design intent can be described by a set of properties with relation to a requirement (planned characteristics). The result of an evaluation of the design can be logged (evaluate characteristics).
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>product properties based on a specific product definition that are planned for a specific end use or manufacturing environment;</li>
<li>results of the evaluation of a specific product definition in a specific end use or manufacturing environment;</li>
<li>classification of the evaluation type;</li>
<li>classification of the evaluation result;</li>
<li>identification of the requirement for the evaluation;</li>
<li>details of the test or evaluation procedure.</li></ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Process Plans and Operations">
    <description>
This capability enables the representation of process related data. This includes process plans, versions of process plans with version tracking, process operations and properties of processes.
A process plan is decomposed into one or more occurrences of process operations. Process plans and process operations establish relationships among raw materials, in-process items, and final items, as well as the relationship between the items and the tools used to manufacture them.
Additionally, the representation of the connection of parts in various kinds of mating is part of this capability.

<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul>
<li>Process_operation_definition;</li>
<li>Process_operation_definition_relationship;</li>
<li>Process_operation_input_or_output;</li>
<li>Process_operation_occurrence;</li>
<li>Process_operation_occurrence_relationship;</li>
<li>Process_operation_resource_assignment;</li>
<li>Process_plan;</li>
<li>Process_plan_relationship.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Requirements">
    <description>
This capability is for the representation of the data that identify a requirement and versions of requirements. 
The concept of a "requirement", in this context, relates chiefly to the exchange and sharing of data between requirements engineering applications such as those used in the systems engineering and related industrial domains. 
<ul><li>Requirement;</li>
<li>Requirement_version;</li>
<li>Requirement_assignment;</li>
<li>Requirement_satisfaction_assertion;</li>
<li>Requirement_source_association;</li>
<li>Requirement_version_relationship  (ABS);</li>
<li>Requirement_sequence_relationship;</li>
<li>Requirement_tracing_relationship;</li>
<li>Requirement_collection_relationship;</li>
<li>Requirement_decomposition_relationship;</li>
<li>General_requirement_version_relationship;</li>
<li>Text_specification;</li>
<li>Design_constraint;</li>
<li>Design_constraint_association;</li>
<li>Design_constraint_relationship.</li></ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Specification">
    <description>
This capability provides the capability to describe products with a large number of variants.
<example> Examples for automotive products are passenger cars, trucks, busses, or engines or components of these products.</example> 
Because of the large number of variants there is no unique identification for each of the variants that could be produced. The main concepts that are used to handle this large number of variants are the following:
<ul><li>product classes are used to identify sets of similar products to be offered to the market;</li>
<li>specifications are used to describe characteristics of the products;</li>
<li>specification categories are used to group similar characteristics of the products;</li>
<li>specification expressions are used to control the usage of a part within a product and to represent conditions for product classes;</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>

<uof name="Work Management and Changes">
    <description>
This capability represents information concerning work order and work request information. The capability allow to collect and structure work requests in order to elaborate work order that justify change activities.
<ul><li>Work Order;</li>
<li>Work Request;</li>
<li>Work Request Relationship;</li>
</ul>
   </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Assembly Structure">
    <description>
    <p>
This capability enables the representation of relationships between objects to build up various kinds of structures.
    </p>
    <p>
The structures are defined for part definitions, for part instances that are particular occurrences of part definitions, or between part definitions and part instances.
    </p>
    <p>
Part instances are used to identify an occurrence of a component in an assembly structure, e.g., to identify the elements of an alternative solution.
    </p>
    <p>
Among these structures there is a hierarchical assembly structure to represent the relationships be-tween constituents and the assembly.
    </p>
      
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul>
<li>Assembly_component_relationship;</li>
<li>Assembly_definition;</li>
<li>Assembly_relationship_substitution;</li>
<li>Axis_placement;</li>
<li>Axis1_placement;</li>
<li>Axis2_placement_2d;</li>
<li>Axis2_placement_3d;</li>
<li>Cartesian_coordinate_space_2d;</li>
<li>Cartesian_coordinate_space_3d;</li>
<li>Cartesian_coordinate_space;</li>
<li>Cartesian_point;</li>
<li>Collected_part_relationship;</li>
<li>Collection_definition;</li>
<li>Direction;</li>
<li>Explicit_transformation_2d;</li>
<li>Explicit_transformation_3d;</li>
<li>General_assembly_component_relationship;</li>
<li>General_part_version_view_instance_relationship;</li>
<li>General_part_version_view_relationship;</li>
<li>Geometrical_relationship;</li>
<li>Implicit_transformation_2d;</li>
<li>Implicit_transformation_3d;</li>
<li>Next_higher_assembly;</li>
<li>Part_instance;</li>
<li>Part_version_view_instance_relationship;</li>
<li>Part_version_view_relationship;</li>
<li>Promissory_usage;</li>
<li>Quantified_part_instance;</li>
<li>Replaced_version_view_relationship;</li>
<li>Selected_part_instance;</li>
<li>Single_part_instance;</li>
<li>Specified_part_instance;</li>
<li>Template_instance;</li>
<li>Transformation_2d;</li>
<li>Transformation_3d;</li>
<li>Transformation.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Breakdown">
    <description>
    <p>
This Capability enables the representation of parent-child structures, so-called breakdowns. A breakdown consists of breakdown elements. Different types of breakdowns and breakdown elements are distinguished, such as functional and physical. Breakdowns may be views of actual product structures with relations to only some of their constituents.
    </p>
    <p>
This Capability also enables the representation of alternative solutions, such as final, supplier or technical solutions. These are implementations of functional and physical breakdown elements.
    </p>	
    <p>
Finally, part instances, that is, occurrences of parts in certain locations, can be associated with breakdown elements by means of this Capability 
    </p>
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alternative_solution;</li>
<li>Alternative_solution_relationship;</li>
<li>Breakdown;</li>
<li>Breakdown_element;</li>
<li>Breakdown_version;</li>
<li>Breakdown_version_relationship;</li>
<li>Component_placement;</li>
<li>Functional_breakdown;</li>
<li>Functional_breakdown_element;</li>
<li>Functional_breakdown_element_association;</li>
<li>Functional_breakdown_element_decomposition_relationship;</li>
<li>Functional_breakdown_element_relationship;</li>
<li>General_breakdown;</li>
<li>General_breakdown_element;</li>
<li>General_breakdown_element_decomposition_relationship;</li>
<li>General_breakdown_element_relationship;</li>
<li>General_part_instance_relationship;</li>
<li>Instance_placement;</li>
<li>Part_instance_relationship;</li>
<li>Physical_breakdown;</li>
<li>Physical_breakdown_element;</li>
<li>Physical_breakdown_element_decomposition_relationship;</li>
<li>Physical_breakdown_element_relationship;</li>
<li>Realization_or_occurrence_relationship;</li>
<li>Replaced_usage_relationship;</li>
<li>Supplier_solution;</li>
<li>Technical_solution.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Configuration">
    <description>
This capability provides mechanisms to identify a single manufacturable product out of a large num-ber of variants. The main concepts that are used to handle this identification of a single manufacturable product are the following:
<ul>
<li>Product configurations are used to identify a manufacturable product out of a possibly large number of variants of a product class by its associated specifications without having an explicit representation of the product, e.g., a customer order for a car.</li>
<li>Product design association is used to associate an implicit representation of a manufacturable product (Product_configuration) with its explicit representation (Part_version).</li>
<li>Manufacturing configuration is used to specify the validity of occurrences of parts (Part_instance) with regard to manufacturing aspects in the context of an implicit as well as an explicit representation of a manufacturable product (Product_configuration, Part_version).</li>
<li>Configurations are used to configure part instances, alternative solutions, breakdown elements, and process plans in the context of the conditions (Class_condition_association, Class_specification_association) under which they are valid.</li>
</ul>
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul>
<li>Configuration;</li>
<li>Dated_configuration;</li>
<li>Lot_configuration;</li>
<li>Manufacturing_configuration;</li>
<li>Product_configuration;</li>
<li>Product_configuration_relationship;</li>
<li>Product_design_association;</li>
<li>Serial_configuration;</li>
<li>Time_interval_configuration.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Part and Version Identification">
    <description>
This capability provides the ability to represent basic product management information. It includes information about parts that are either piece parts, raw materials, products, software, or tools, and about versions of them.
<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alternate_part_relationship;</li>
<li>Part;</li>
<li>Part_category;</li>
<li>Part_version;</li>
<li>Part_version_relationship.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>
<uof name="Shape Association and Structure">
    <description>
This Capability represents information to associate parts with shape and with the role of this shape. A shape description may consist of several portions that may be related and their roles.

<p>The following business objects are used by this Capability:</p>
<ul><li>Part_shape;</li>
<li>Shape_description_associationt;</li>
<li>Shape_element;</li>
<li>Shape_element_relationship.</li>
</ul>
    </description>
  </uof>


   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg3.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg4.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg5.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg6.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg7.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg8.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg9.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg10.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg11.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg12.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg13.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg14.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg15.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg16.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg17.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg18.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg19.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg20.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg21.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg22.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg23.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg24.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg25.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg26.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg27.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg28.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg29.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg30.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg31.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg32.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg33.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg34.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg35.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg36.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg37.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg38.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg39.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg40.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg41.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg42.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg43.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg44.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg45.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg45.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg46.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg47.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg48.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg49.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg50.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg51.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg52.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg53.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg54.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg55.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>

   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>


 <!-- Clause 6 Module reference data -->
<!--
 <refdata>
   <refdata_subclause title='Classifications of x'>
   </refdata_subclause>
 </refdata>
-->

</module>
