<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.1 2004/10/25 18:12:22 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="project_management_resource_information"
   part="1434"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="00000"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2004/10/25 18:12:22 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.1 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems enginmeering, project management, management resource information
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the assignment of certification, classification, 
     contract, timing, documentation, effectivity, justification and 
     security data to product and activity data.</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the assignment of certification, classification, 
     contract, timing, documentation, effectivity, justification and 
     security data to product and activity data.</p>

   <p>The Project_management_resource_information_arm contains information entities that 
   are used in many of the other arms. They are collected here as a resource for project 
   management as a whole. They include items like time, classification, conditions, 
   external sources, documents, effectivity, and validity. </p>

   <p>It contains definition of a date according to the Gregorian calendar, definition 
   of a point in time in a day, time offset from UTC, identification of a time interval, 
   and representation of a relationship between two time intervals. It associates a time 
   interval with product or activity data. </p>
 
   <p>It contains the assignment of classification information to product or activity data. </p>

   <p>It contains conditions specified by a textual description with a logical result, 
   and supports use of external entities as input to a condition expression It contains 
   condition assignment, and condition relationships. </p>

   <p>It contains the identification of a document and the identification of a version 
   of a document in both digital and physical forms. It contains document location and 
   document relationships. </p>

   <p>Both activities and products may be valid only for a period of time or in a 
   particular context. This arm contains the identification of a domain of validity for 
   other entities. This may be represented as an interval of serial numbers, an interval 
   of time, or as a batch lot of product. It contains the definition of a relationship 
   between two validity domains. </p>

   <p>Often products, versions of product, line replaceable units, manufacturing 
   procedures, or repair procedures are applicable only under specific conditions 
   represented by effectivity. This arm contains effectivity and its application to 
   product or activity data. </p>

   <p>This arm contains the identification of external sources for a particular item or activity. 
   It contains the association of an item to an external source where it can be provided. </p>
 
      <note>Issue: Contract_arm, Document_assignment_arm, Justification_arm, and 
   Security_classification_arm are redundant with arms in Work_structure_arm. 
   Why should the same modules appear more than once in our module sets? 
   Certification_arm, and Location_arm appear in Organization_structure_arm. </note>
   <note>I have written the introduction without including the in scope statements of 
   these redundant modules since they are described in the introduction to WS-arm and 
   OS-arm.</note>

   </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>######## Editorial note: Following list must be condensed down</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Attribute_classification_arm; </li>
   <li>the association of a value, represented by a class, to an attribute on  an entity.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Certification_arm; </li>
   <li>definition of a certificate;</li>
   <li>assignment of a certificate to activity or product data.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Classification_assignment_arm;    </li>
   <li>assignment of classification information to product or activity data.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Condition_arm;    </li>
   <li>condition specified by a textual description with a logical result;</li>
   <li>use of external entities as input to a condition expression;</li>
   <li>condition assignment;</li>
   <li>condition relationships.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Contract_arm; </li>
   <li>creating and identifying the contract;</li>
   <li>associating activity or product data to the contract.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Date_time_arm; </li>
   <li>definition of a date according to the Gregorian calendar;</li>
   <li>definition of a point in time in a day;</li>
   <li>time offset from UTC.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Document_and_version_identification_arm; </li>
   <li>definition of a date according to the Gregorian calendar;</li>
   <li>definition of a point in time in a day;</li>
   <li>time offset from UTC.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Document_and_version_identification_arm </li>
   <li>identification of a document;</li>
   <li>identification of a version of a document.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Document_assignment_arm; </li>
   <li>assignment of documents to product or activity data;</li>
   <li>assignment of parts or sections of documents to product or activity data.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Document_definition_arm; </li>
   <li>definition of a document version in a digital format such as an electronic file;</li>
   <li>definition of a document version in a non-digital format such as paper copy;</li>
   <li>specification of the data locating the components of a Document_definition in a  
digital or physical storage system.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Document_structure_arm; </li>
   <li>relationships between files;</li>
   <li>relationships between document definitions.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Effectivity_arm; </li>
   <li>identification of a validity domain;</li>
   <li>identification of a validity domain as an interval of serial numbers;</li>
   <li>identification of a validity domain as an interval of time;</li>
   <li>identification of a validity domain as a batch lot of product;</li>
   <li>definition of a relationship between two validity domains.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Effectivity_application_arm; </li>
   <li>application of effectivity to product or activity data.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From External_item_identification_assignment_arm; </li>
   <li>identification of an external source for a particular item;</li>
   <li>identification on an item in the context of an external source where it can be found.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Justification_arm;</li>
   <li>the provision of one or more justifications for something;</li>
   <li>the specification and identification of what is being justified and in what context;</li>
   <li>the specification of relationships between justifications;</li>
   <li>the association of the justification to the supporting evidential data on which it 
is based.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Location_arm;     </li>
   <li>the geographic position of products, resource items or activitties;</li>
   <li>the specification of location by use of organizational based codes;</li>
   <li>the specification of location by postal address, including nested addresses;</li>
   <li>the specification of location by product based codes, or zone within a product, 
including nested locations;</li>
   <li>the location relative to another location.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Security_classification_arm; </li>
   <li>definition of a security classification level;</li>
   <li>asignment of a security classification level to activity or product data.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Time_interval_arm; </li>
   <li>identification of a time interval;</li>
   <li>characterization of a bounded time interval;</li>
   <li>representation of a relationship between two time intervals.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Time_interval_assignment_arm; </li>
   <li>association of a time interval with product or activity data.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>xxxx</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
