<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.4 2006/04/25 15:58:43 radack Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd" [
	<!ENTITY subtype "&lt;=">
	<!ENTITY ref-from "&lt;-">
]>
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module name="simplified_cataloguing" part="1137" version="1" sc4.working_group="12" wg.number="00000" wg.number.arm="" wg.number.mim="" checklist.internal_review="" checklist.project_leader="" checklist.convener="" status="WD" language="E" publication.year="2006" publication.date="2006-01-25" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2006/04/25 15:58:43 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.4 $" development.folder="dvlp">
	<keywords>
    module, cataloguing
 </keywords>
	<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
	<!--
 <abstract>
    <li>xxxxx</li>
 </abstract>
-->
	<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
	<contacts>
		<projlead ref="ap203ed2.projlead"/>
		<editor ref="gerald.radack"/>
	</contacts>
	<!-- Introduction -->
	<!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
	<purpose>
		<p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation of catalogue data. A catalogue record for an item consists of the identification of the class to which an item belongs, and a set of "property-value pairs". A property value may be either a string, an enumeration value (an externally defined string), a currency amount, or a measurement.  Cataloguing concepts are defined in an external dictionary and referenced via globally unique identifiers.  The following are considered cataloguing concepts:
   </p>
		<ul>
			<li>class;</li>
			<li>property;</li>
			<li>feature;</li>
			<li>data type;</li>
			<li>unit of measure;</li>
			<li>qualifier of measure (e.g., minimum, maximum, nominal);</li>
			<li>enumeration value;</li>
			<li>currency.</li>
		</ul>
		<note>For compatibility with existing STEP implementations, SI units represented in the customary manner and are not referenced to an external dictionary.  Since SI units are standardized and well-known, an explicit reference is not considered necessary.</note>
		<note>For compatibility with existing STEP implementations, the data type of a property value (typically captured as a representation_item), is not referenced to an external dictionary.  Since a small, well-known set of data types is being used, an explicit reference is not considered necessary.</note>
	</purpose>
	<!-- Items in scope -->
	<inscope>
		<li>representation of a catalogue data set;</li>
		<li>representation of the class to which an item belongs;</li>
		<li>representation of simple property values, including enumerated, string, currency, and measure;</li>
		<li>representation of composite property values;</li>
		<li>representation of units of measure for measure property values;</li>
		<li>representation of qualifiers for measure property values;</li>
		<li>representation of enumeration values;</li>
		<li>association of property values to specific features of a product;</li>
		<li>representation of external identifiers for concepts class, property, feature, representation, unit of measure, qualifier of measure, enumeration value and currency.</li>
	</inscope>
	<!-- Items out of scope -->
	<outscope>
		<li>representation of a dictionary containing definitions for concepts class, property, feature, representation, unit of measure, qualifier of measure, enumeration value and currency referenced from this module;</li>
		<li>the schema and format for identifiers used to reference externally defined concepts;</li>
		<li>the resolution mechanism for identifiers used to reference externally defined concepts.</li>
	</outscope>
	<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->
	<!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
	<arm>
		<!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
		<!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm>
	<!-- ARM long form (optional) -->
	<!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          arm_lf.xml
          armexpg_lf1.gif
          armexpg_lf1.xml -->
	<arm_lf>
		<!-- Note ARM long form EXPRESS is in arm_lf.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg_lf1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm_lf>
	<!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
	<mapping_table>
	</mapping_table>
	<!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
	<mim>
		<!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim>
	<!-- MIM long form (optional) -->
	<!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          mim_lf.xml
          mimexpg_lf1.gif
          mimexpg_lf1.xml -->
	<mim_lf>
		<!-- Note MIM long form EXPRESS is in mim_lf.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg_lf1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim_lf>
</module>
