<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.25 2015/09/29 18:15:36 kevletu Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!--
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="ap209_multidisciplinary_analysis_and_design"
   name.french="Conception et analyse pluridisciplinaire de l'AP209"
   part="409"
   version="2"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="9795"
   wg.number.supersedes="8579"
   wg.number.arm="9796"
   wg.number.arm.supersedes="8580"
   wg.number.arm_lf="9798"
   wg.number.arm_lf.supersedes="8581"
   wg.number.mim="9797"
   wg.number.mim.supersedes="8582"
   wg.number.mim_lf="9799"
   wg.number.mim_lf.supersedes="8583"
   checklist.internal_review="9810"
   checklist.project_leader="9811"
   checklist.convener="9816"
   status="TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2015-12"
   publication.date="2015-12-15"
   published="y"
   previous.revision.year="2014"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2015/09/29 18:15:36 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.25 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module,analysis, design, computational fluid dynamics, finite element analysis
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li><p>This part of ISO 10303 describes information for the multidisciplanary analysis and design of complex parts, including composites</p></li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="keithhunten"/>
   <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
 </contacts>
 <changes>
 	<change version="2">
 		<arm.changes>
 			<arm.deletions>
 				<modified.object name="Collection_identification_and_version_arm" type="USE_FROM"/>
 				<modified.object name="Foundation_state_definition_arm" type="USE_FROM"/>
 			</arm.deletions>
 		</arm.changes>
 		<mim.changes>
 			<mim.deletions>
 				<modified.object name="Collection_identification_and_version_mim" type="USE_FROM"/>
 				<modified.object name="Foundation_state_definition_mim" type="USE_FROM"/>
 			</mim.deletions>
 		</mim.changes>
 	</change>
 </changes>
 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>

This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol (AP) for the exchange of computer-interpretable composite and metallic
structural product definitions, including product shape, associated finite element analysis (FEA) models
and analysis results, and the material properties of these products.
</p><p>
The shape of a composite or metallic product definition includes the part and its constituents, including
any ply shapes necessary for FEA node and mesh generation of boundary definitions. This information
is suitable for the automated generation of composite material properties and geometric properties for
finite elements. The shape definitions for design and analysis are each independently configuration
controlled.
</p>
<p>
The finite element model idealizes a product or aspects of a product so that it may be analyzed to validate
the structural performance and structural integrity of a product.Finite elements of homogenous (isotropic) metallic and adhesive material properties are treated in this
part of ISO 10303 as a subset of anisotropic composite material response. The differences between these
two material response idealizations are: 1) a simplified material response, and 2) having no associated
composite constituent information.</p><p>

Assembly information provides the relationships necessary to identify analysis boundary conditions, and
when combined with part geometry, topology, and finite element analysis output, provides the input
necessary for detail analyses such as those for fastened structural joints.
This part of ISO 10303 satisfies the need for exchange of information between the iterative design and
analysis stages of the product life cycle. Product configuration information provides the audit trail
necessary to control the designed shape, its associated finite element model, and any related analysis
shape information during these iterative stages of the product life cycle.
This application protocol defines the context, scope, and information requirements for the exchange of
the information necessary to perform the design through analysis stages of the life cycle of composite
and metallic structural parts, and specifies the integrated resources necessary to satisfy these
requirements.
</p>
<p>Changes in this document include increased integration with other parts of ISO 10303 because of its migration to the modular architecture. Additionally, new capabilities have been added. The second Edition of ISO 10303-209 (AP209) has integrated a generic Engineering Analysis capability complimented by specific CFD and generalized mesh based numerical analysis capabilities to the AP209 Edition 1 classical Finite Element Analysis capabilities. The CFD capability is based upon the NASA/AIAA CGNS standard and the Volvo Aero EAR-model work. The generalized structured and unstructured analysis and mesh capabilities are based upon work done in the Generic Engineering Analysis Model (GEM) project from the European Union. In addition there is a complete discrete/continuous mathematical field representation capability that has been added based upon the David Taylor Labs/Boeing DT-NURBS package. All of these added capabilities have been integrated into the ISO 10303 common resources Parts 10303-50, 10303-51, 10303-52, 10303-53, 10303-107, and 10303-110 as a basis for use in Application Protocols. The intent is that AP209E2 will now address a much wider set of multi-disciplinary analysis and optimization problems.</p>

 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>

<li>products that are mechanical parts and assemblies;</li>
<li>product definition data and configuration control data pertaining to the design and analysis phases of a product's development;</li>
<li>a change to a design and an analysis, including information to identify the change, at a point in the life cycle when tracking a change is necessary;</li>
<li>representation of an instance of a part in an assembly through its usage in a sub-assembly;</li>
<li>three dimensional shape representations of a part that includes:
<ul>
<li>geometrically and topologically bounded wireframe models;</li>
<li>geometrically bounded surface models;</li>
<li>topologically bounded solid models with facetted, elementary and advanced faces;</li>
<li>non surface bounded solid models including constructive solid geometry, curve swept and other swept solids, thickened face solid;</li>
<li>solids with construction history;</li>
<li>topologically bounded manifold surface and subsurface and non manifold surface models;</li>
<li>topologically bounded compound models.</li>
      </ul>
      </li>
<li>the representations for design and analysis disciplines and the association of their nominal design shape, idealized analysis shape, and analysis shape representations;</li>
<li>geometric validation properties to allow the translation of geometric shape representations (advanced boundary representation and faceted boundary representation solids) to be checked for quality;</li>
<li>geometric and dimensional tolerances applied to geometric shape representations;</li>
<li>materials and their composition of chemical substance;</li>
<li>the identification of material specifications from internal and external sources and their properties for a specific operating environment;</li>
<li>composite material structure and shape;</li>
<li>the association of the constituents of composite and metallic parts with the constituent shape model;</li>
<li>the depiction of composite laminate tables describing the material, stacking sequence, ply orientation, and constituents of the composite or a portion of the composite with a defined shape;</li>
<li>catalogue data characterised by property value pairs;</li>
<li>three dimensional presentation of product data:
<ul>

<li>arranging geometric elements in layers and groups and assigning colours;</li>
<li>presentation styles for points, curves, surfaces and sections, including hatching and tiling;</li>
<li>saved views of particular camera positions and sections;</li>
<li>textual annotation and notes applied to geometric elements;</li>
<li>presentation of geometric and dimensional tolerances.</li>
      </ul>
      </li>
<li>a generic framework to represent mesh and mesh-less engineering analyses;</li>
<li>digital data on structured and unstructured analysis model grids;</li>
<li>linear static finite element analysis;</li>
<li>linear modes and frequencies finite element analysis;</li>
<li>the finite element analysis model, analysis controls, and analysis results information;</li>
<li>the plane stress and simple plane strain types of linear static and linear modes and frequencies finite element structural analyses;</li>
<li>data describing steady or unsteady fluid dynamics flow-fields;</li>
<li>data describing the fluid dynamics model including analysis model grid description, grid inter-connectivity, boundary conditions, and modeling parameters;</li>
<li>data from solutions of equation sets commonly used in fluid dynamics analysis: Navier- Stokes equations, Euler equations, linear and nonlinear potential flow equations, small disturbance equations, boundary layer equations, and stream function equations;</li>
<li>single-phase flow of a liquid or a gas;</li>
<li>laminar flow, transitional flow, turbulent flow (direct representation of turbulence, or represented by Reynolds-averaged data);</li>
<li>incompressible or compressible flow;</li>
<li>unsteady flow;</li>
<li>perfect gas, or variable chemical composition (equilibrium flow, frozen flow, or finite-rate chemical reactions);</li>
<li>data regarding the exchange of energy by molecular transport including convection, conduction, and advectation;</li>
<li>rotating flowfields (e.g., turbomachinery);</li>
<li>inertial and rotating frames of reference;</li>
<li>Newtonian transport laws;</li>
<li>reference to product geometry from the fluid dynamic flow fields;</li>
<li>administrative information necessary to track the approval and configuration control of the analysis of a product;</li>
<li>transfer of partial fluid dynamics data;</li>
<li>the graphical presentation of:
<ul>
<li>analysis model maps;</li>
<li>analysis output information displays on top of the analysis model mesh;</li>
<li>line drawings or images which document the part aspects subjected to detail analysis. </li>
      </ul>
      </li>
<li>the tabular presentation of:
<ul>

<li>the analysis assumptions such as those for structural idealizations, materials, boundary conditions, and applied loadings;</li>
<li>critical locations in analysis models and the associated detail analysis performed.</li>
      </ul>
      </li>


 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the business information for the management of a design and analysis project;</li>
<li>product definition data and configuration control data pertaining to any life cycle phase other than design and analysis;</li>
<li>alternate representation of the information by disciplines outside of design and analysis such as manufacturing;</li>
<li>the explicit graphical presentations derivable from design or analysis product representations.</li>

 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>

 <!-- ARM long form (optional) -->
 <!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          arm_lf.xml
          armexpg_lf1.gif
          armexpg_lf1.xml -->
 <arm_lf/>
   <!-- Note ARM long form EXPRESS is in arm_lf.xml
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg_lf1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm_lf>-->

 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>-->

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
      <imgfile file="mimexpg2.xml"/>
      <imgfile file="mimexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

 <!-- MIM long form (optional) -->
 <!-- If not required, delete this section and the following files:
          mim_lf.xml
          mimexpg_lf1.gif
          mimexpg_lf1.xml -->
 <mim_lf/>

 <!-- <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg_lf1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 <mim_lf> -->


 <!-- Clause 6 Module reference data -->
<!--
 <refdata>
   <refdata_subclause title='Classifications of x'>
   </refdata_subclause>
 </refdata>
-->

</module>
