<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id:  $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="state"
   part="56"
   version="1"
   wg.number="1820"
   wg.number.express="1821"
   checklist.internal_review="1822"
   checklist.project_leader="1823"
   checklist.convener="1824"
   status="CD"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/04/11 01:02:17 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.23 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
	 resource, state observed, state type, state
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="albert.leyson"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
	   The <b>state_type_schema</b> identifies a type of state by specifying the criteria that shall be satisified 
	   for something to be in a state of that type. 
  </p>
  <example>
       A state is defined by the presence 
	   of an identified fault in a product.
  </example>
  <p>
	   The <b>state_observed_schema</b> identifies an observed state and the link to the thing or things that are in the state. 
	  
	   Observed states may correspond to a period in the life of product data 
	   when the criteria defining the state type either are or will be satisfied. 
	   States are not limited to products but may apply to activities, people, and organizations.
	   
	   An observed state records that one or more items were in a defined state_type for a part of their life.  
	   The item to which an observed state applies is determined by using applied_state_assignment. 
	   An observed state may apply to products, activities, people, organizations or to other items of interest, 
	   as defined by Application Protocols or Modules that use this resource part. 


   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="Relationship between schemas in ISO 10303-56"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>definition of state;</li>
   <li>definition of what is needed for a state to exist;</li>
   <li>relationship between two or more states;</li>
   <li>history of state;</li>
   <li>relationship between a state and the product, activity, people or organization that it affects.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the classification of states.</li>
 </outscope>
 
<definition>
    <term>state</term>
    <def>The condition in which something does or could exist.
	<note>All possible states of an item are types of state, which are  
 	identified as a specific <b>state_type</b> in <b>state_type_schema</b>.  
 	As an item is realized or observed to enter any one of the <b>state_type</b>s, 
 	the item acquires an individual <b>state</b> or <b>state_observed</b> in 
 	<b>state_observed_schema</b>. 
	</note>  
	</def>
	</definition>
<!--
 <normrefs/>



 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="state_type_schema">
	<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name\name_of_schema.xml -->
	<introduction>
		The <b>state_type_schema</b> represents the existence of possible states or types of state an individual item may acquire.
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	   <p>
		   
	   </p>
	   <p>
		   State type captures some unique aspect or aspects that identify and characterise 
		   a potential observed state to which reference needs to be made.  A state type defines 
		   a state that an individual item may be observed or predicted to possess for a period 
		   of time.   Different individuals may be in the state defined by a state type for 
		   different time periods, some of which may overlap. When the characteristics defined 
		   by the state type are present the item is said to be in that state.  
	   </p>
	   <p>
		   In this part of ISO 10303 such a state type is recorded as  an instance of the <b>state_type</b> entity.
	   </p>
	<p>
        State types may be specified that are composed of multiple sub-state types. 
        A state type may be related to another state type by a cause and effect relationship, 
        where one state type causes or results from another. State types may also be related 
        as a sequence, through which one state type may transition into another state type.   
        The nature of the relationship between two state types is defined by the role and description 
        attributes of the <b>state_type_relationship</b> entity.
	</p>
	   <p>
		   Data recording the predicted or observed existance of an individual in a state are 
		   the subject of the <b>state_observed_schema</b>.
	   </p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="state_type_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="state_observed_schema">
	<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name\name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   		The <b>state_observed_schema</b> represents the existence of state(s) an individual item is observed to possess at 
   		any point in time.  
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	<p>
		A <b>state_observed</b> entity represents the existence of an individual item, for a period of 
		time, when it is observed, or predicted to possess recognisable characteristics that 
		may not be present at a different time. The characteristics that describe an observed 
		state may be recorded in the description attribute of the <b>state_observed</b> entity, 
		or by reference to relevant state types using the <b>ascribable_state</b> entity.
	</p>
	<p>
		Over time, a given observed state may be associated with multiple state types. 
		This reflects the diagnosis process where something may be observed or predicted 
		to be in an abnormal state before the precise cause, and hence state type, is known.  
		A general state type may be assessed initially using the <b>ascribable_state</b> entity. 
		As investigations proceed other, more precise, state_types can be associated as 
		asserted states again using the <b>ascribable_state</b> entity.  Other state types can be 
		asserted as not applying.
	</p>
	<p>
		An observed state may have occured, may be current, or may be expected to take 
		place in the future.  
	</p>
	<p>
		An item or a set of items may exist in a state.  This fact is captured using the 
		<b>applied_state_assignment</b> entity.
	</p>
</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="state_observed_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <shortnames>
    <shortname name="ASTA" entity="applied_state_type_assignment"/>  
    <shortname name="STTTYP" entity="state_type"/>
    <shortname name="STTYRL" entity="state_type_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="APSTAS" entity="applied_state_assignment"/>
    <shortname name="ASCSTT" entity="ascribable_state"/>
    <shortname name="ASSTRL" entity="ascribable_state_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="STTOBS" entity="state_observed"/>
    <shortname name="STOBRL" entity="state_observed_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="STTRL" entity="state_role"/>
    <shortname name="STT0" entity="state_type_role"/>
 </shortnames>

 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

<!--  <bibliography/> -->

</resource>

