<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.27 2003/08/19 20:24:46 magnevs Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="state"
   part="56"
   version="1"
   wg.number="1820"
   wg.number.express="1821"
   checklist.internal_review="1822"
   checklist.project_leader="1823"
   checklist.convener="1824"
   status="CD"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/08/19 20:24:46 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.27 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
	 resource, state observed, state type, state
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="albert.leyson"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
	   The <b>state_type_schema</b> identifies a type of state by specifying the criteria that shall be satisified 
	   for something to be in a state of that type. 
  </p>
  <example>
       A state is defined by the presence 
	   of an identified fault in a product.
  </example>
  <p>
	   The <b>state_observed_schema</b> identifies an observed state and the link to the thing or things that are 
	   in the state. 
	  
	   Observed states may correspond to a period in the life of product data 
	   when the criteria defining the state type either have been satisfied, are being satisfied, or will be satisfied. 
	   States are not limited to products but may apply to activities, people, and organizations.
	   
	   An observed state records that one or more items were in a defined state_type for a period of their life.  
	   The item to which an observed state applies is determined by using state_observed_assignment. 
	   An observed state may apply to products, activities, people, organizations or to other items of interest, 
	   as defined by Application Protocols or Modules that use this resource part. 
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="Relationship between schemas in ISO 10303-56"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>definition of state;</li>
   <li>definition of what is needed for a state to exist;</li>
   <li>relationship between two or more states;</li>
   <li>assignment of a state to items;</li>
   <li>history of state.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the classification of states;</li>
   <li>those items to which state may be assigned, such as products, activities, people or organizations.</li>
 </outscope>
 
<definition>
    <term>state</term>
    <def>a mode of being.
	<note>All possible states of an item are types of state, which are  
 	identified as a specific <b>state_type</b> in <b>state_type_schema</b>.  
 	As an item is realized or observed to enter any one of the <b>state_type</b>s, 
 	the item acquires an individual state or <b>state_observed</b> in 
 	<b>state_observed_schema</b>. 
	</note>  
	</def>
	</definition>
	
	
 <normrefs>
      <normref.inc normref="ref10303-41.2000"/>
 </normrefs>
<!--
 <normrefs/>



 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="state_type_schema">
	<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name\name_of_schema.xml -->
	<introduction>
		The <b>state_type_schema</b> represents the existence of possible states or types of state that an individual item 
		may acquire.
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	   <p>
		   
	   </p>
	   <p>
   		   A <b>state_type</b> identifies a set of recognisable characteristics that can be used to distinguish
		   an observed state.  These characteristics specify a mode of being.
           When these characteristics are present for an item, the item is said to be in that state, as 
           represented using <b>state_observed</b>.  
           
           <note>An item may exhibit characteristics that match 
           several <b>state_type</b>s for a period of time.   
           </note>
	   </p>
	   <p>
		   In this part of ISO 10303 such a state type is recorded as an instance of the <b>state_type</b> entity.
	   </p>
	<p>
        State types may be specified that are composed of multiple sub-state types.
        A state_type may be related to another state_type by a cause and effect relationship, 
        where one state_type causes or results from another. State types may also be related 
        as a sequence, through which one state_type may transition into another state_type.   
        The nature of the relationship between two state_types is defined by the role and description 
        attributes of the <b>state_type_relationship</b> entity.
	</p>
	   <p>
		   Data recording the predicted or observed existence of an item in a state are 
		   the subject of the <b>state_observed_schema</b>.
	   </p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="state_type_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="state_observed_schema">
	<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name\name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   		The <b>state_observed_schema</b> represents the existence of state(s) an individual item is observed to possess at 
   		any point in time.  
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	<p>
		A <b>state_observed</b> entity represents the existence of recognisable characteristics for a period of 
		time.  The period of time may historical, current, or predicted.  The characteristics that describe an observed 
		state may be recorded in the description attribute of the <b>state_observed</b> entity, 
		or by reference to relevant <b>state_type</b>s using the <b>ascribable_state</b> entity.
	</p>
	<p>
		Over time, a given observed state may be associated with multiple state types. 
		This reflects the diagnosis process where something may be observed or predicted 
		to be in an abnormal state before the precise cause, and hence <b>state_type</b>, is known.  
		A <b>state_type</b> may be assessed initially using the <b>ascribable_state</b> entity. 
		As investigations proceed other, more precise, <b>state_type</b>s can be associated as 
		asserted states again using the <b>ascribable_state</b> entity.  Other <b>state_type</b>s can be 
		asserted as not applying.
	</p>
	<p>
		An observed state may have occured, may be current, or may be expected to take 
		place in the future.  
	</p>
	<p>		An item or a set of items may exist in a state.  This fact is captured by using the 
		<b>state_observed_assignment</b> entity.
		<note>
		The assignment of state to an item or set of items may be meaningful for some process.
		</note>
	</p>
</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="state_observed_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <shortnames>
    <shortname name="STTTYP" entity="state_type"/>
    <shortname name="STTYAS" entity="state_type_assignment"/>  
    <shortname name="STTYRL" entity="state_type_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="STT0" entity="state_type_role"/>
    <shortname name="ASCSTT" entity="ascribable_state"/>
    <shortname name="ASSTRL" entity="ascribable_state_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="STTOBS" entity="state_observed"/>
    <shortname name="STOBAS" entity="state_observed_assignment"/>
    <shortname name="STOBRL" entity="state_observed_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="STO0" entity="state_observed_role"/>
 </shortnames>

 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

<!--  <bibliography/> -->

</resource>

