<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.10 2003/01/05 00:54:23 nigelshaw Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="state"
   part="56"
   version="1"
   wg.number="1820"
   checklist.internal_review="1822"
   checklist.project_leader="1823"
   checklist.convener="1824"
   status="CD"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2003/01/05 00:54:23 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.10 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
	 resource state observed definition
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="albert.leyson"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
	 <p>
		 This part of ISO 10303 is a member of the integrated resource series. 
		 Major subdivisions of this part of ISO 10303 are:
	<ol>
		<li>
			state_type_schema;
		</li>
		<li>
			state_observed_schema.
		</li>
	</ol>
   </p>
   <p>
	   The <b>state_type_schema</b> identifies a type of state by specifying the criterium that shall be satisified 
	   for something to be in a state of that type. For example, a state might be defined by the presence 
	   of an identified fault in a product.
   </p>
   <p>
	   The <b>state_observed_schema</b> identifies an observed state 
	   and the link to the thing or things that are in the state. 
	  
	   Observed states may correspond to a period in the life of something 
	   when the criterium defining the state type either are or will be satisfied. 
	   States are not limited to products but may apply to activities, people, and organizations.
	   
	   An observed state records that one or more items were in a defined state_type for a part of their life.  
	   The item to which an observed state applies is determined by using applied_state_assignment. 
	   An observed state may apply to products, activities, people, organizations or to other items of interest, as defined by Application Protocols or Modules that use this resource part. 


   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>definition of state</li>
   <li>definition of what is needed for a state to exist</li>
   <li>relationship between two or more states</li>
   <li>relationship between a state and the product, activity, people or organization that it affects</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>behaviour or history of product data capable of having state</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="state_type_schema">
	<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name\name_of_schema.xml -->
	<introduction>
		
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	   <p>
		   
	   </p>
	   <p>
		   A state type captures some unique aspect or aspects that characterise a potential observed state. 
		   Over time an item may be in a given observed state for one period and not in the observed 
		   state for another period. 
		   Different items may be in the given state for different time periods, some of which may overlap. 
		   In all these cases the state is the same, 
		   that is, it conforms with the aspects that characterise the state. 
	   </p>
	   <p>
		   In this part of ISO 10303 such a state type is recording using the state_type entity.
	   </p>
	<p>
		State types may be specified that are composed of multiple sub-state types. 
		A state type may be related to another state type by cause and effect 
		when one state type causes another. 
		State types may be ordered as sequences and may transition into another state type.
	</p>
	   <p>
		   The existance of an observed state, together with the items to which it applies, are the subject of 
		   the state_observed_schema.
	   </p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="state_type_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="state_observed_schema">
	<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name\name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	<p>
		An observed state represents the existence of something 
		over a period of time when it exhibits some characteristic that can 
		be identified and is distinct from other periods when that same characteristic does not apply. 
		The characteristics define a type of state and are defined using data types specified in the 
		state_type_schema. 
	</p>
	<p>
		Over time, a given observed state may be associated with multiple state types. 
		This reflects the diagnosis process where something is known to be in an abnormal state 
		but the precise reason is not known (and therefore state type) is not known. 
		A general state type may be asserted at first. 
		Once investigation has revealed the more precise state type, this state type can be associated as
		an assessed state. Similarly other state types can be asserted as not applying.
	</p>
	<p>
		An observed state may have occured, may be current, or may be expected to take place in the future. 
	</p>
	<p>
		An item or a set of items may exist in a state. This fact is captured using the 
		applied_state_assignment entity.
	</p>
</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="state_observed_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <shortnames>
    <shortname name="ASTA" entity="applied_state_type_assignment"/>  
    <shortname name="STTTYP" entity="state_type"/>
    <shortname name="STTYCN" entity="state_type_condition"/>
    <shortname name="STTYRL" entity="state_type_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="APSTAS" entity="applied_state_assignment"/>
    <shortname name="DFSTRL" entity="defined_state_relationship"/>
    <shortname name="STTASS" entity="state_assertion"/>
    <shortname name="STT0" entity="state_assessment"/>
    <shortname name="STTOBS" entity="state_observed"/>
    <shortname name="STOBRL" entity="state_observed_relationship"/>
 </shortnames>

 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

 <bibliography/>
</resource>

