<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../make-menu.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><html>
   <head>
      <this-is section="sql-extension" page="intro" subpage=""/>
      <!--
           Generated at 2010-10-29T18:20:48.427+01:00--><title>Saxonica: XSLT and XQuery Processing: The Saxon SQL Extension</title>
      <meta name="coverage" content="Worldwide"/>
      <meta name="copyright" content="Copyright Saxonica Ltd"/>
      <meta name="title"
            content="Saxonica: XSLT and XQuery Processing: The Saxon SQL Extension"/>
      <meta name="robots" content="noindex,nofollow"/>
      <link rel="stylesheet" href="../saxondocs.css" type="text/css"/>
   </head>
   <body class="main">
      <h1>The Saxon SQL Extension</h1>
      <p>The Saxon distribution includes a set of extension elements providing access to
SQL databases. These are not intended as being necessarily a production-quality piece
of software (there are many limitations in the design), but more as an illustration of
how extension elements can be used to enhance the capability of the processor.</p>
      <p>To use the SQL extension elements in a stylesheet, you need to define a namespace prefix
(for example "sql") in the extension-element-prefixes attribute of the xsl:stylesheet element,
and to map this prefix to a namespace URI, conventionally <code>http://saxon.sf.net/sql</code>.
This namespace must be bound in the Configuration to the class <code>net.sf.saxon.option.sql.SQLElementFactory</code>.
This binding can be done either by calling <a class="bodylink"
            href="../javadoc/net/sf/saxon/Configuration.html#setExtensionElementNamespace"><code>Configuration.setExtensionElementNamespace()</code></a>,
or by means of an entry in the <a class="bodylink" href="../configuration/configuration-file.xml">configuration file</a>.</p>
      <p><i>This changed in Saxon 9.2. In Saxon 9.1 and earlier releases it was necessary to use a namespace 
  ending in "/net.sf.saxon.sql.SQLElementFactory". It is still possible to use the same namespace, but it must
now be bound explicitly.</i></p>
      <p>This extension defines seven new stylesheet elements: <code>sql:connect</code>, <code>sql:query</code>, 
<code>sql:insert</code>, <code>sql:column</code>, <code>sql:update</code>, <code>sql:delete</code>,
and <code>sql:close</code>, described in the following sections.</p>
      <p><i>Note: this extension is not available on the .NET platform.</i></p>
      <table width="100%">
         <tr>
            <td>
               <p align="right"><a class="nav" href="connect.xml">Next</a></p>
            </td>
         </tr>
      </table>
   </body>
</html>