<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.28 2014/04/28 19:50:05 darla Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="material_and_other_engineering_properties"
  name.french="Mat&#233;riaux et autres propri&#233;t&#233;s d'ing&#233;nierie" 
   part="45"
   version="3"
   wg.number="8317"
   wg.number.express="6751"
   checklist.internal_review="5101"
   checklist.project_leader="5102"
   checklist.convener="5103"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2014"
   publication.date="2014-05-01"
   published="y"
   previous.revision.year="2008" 
   previous.revision.cancelled="Yes"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2014/04/28 19:50:05 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.28 $">

 <keywords>
    product property values, data environment, composition, precision, uncertainty
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>
    	ISO 10303-45 specifies the integrated generic resources to describe the values of the material 
    	and other engineering properties of products and the conditions in which these property values are valid. 
    	This part also includes the resource constructs for describing the composition of products.  
    	Property and composition values can be identified either as a numerical value or as a mathematical function. 
    	Numeric values and values as mathematical functions can be further characterized as to their type, precision and uncertainty.
    </p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="p45ed2.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="p45ed2.editor"/>
 </contacts>
<changes>
	<change_edition version="2">
		<description>
			<p>
				The main changes in this edition of this part of ISO 10303 are to enable composition values and property values be specified by mathematical functions 
				and for these functions to be qualified as to their precision and reliability.
			</p>
			<p>
				The example of material designation in Clause 3.3.3 has been moved to become EXAMPLE 1 of Clause 4.4.1.
			</p> 
			
		</description>
		<schema.changes schema_name="material_property_definition">
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object name="characterized_product_composition_value" type="TYPE"></modified.object>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object name="material_designation" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="product_material_composition_relationship" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
		<schema.changes schema_name="qualified_measure">
			
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object name="maths_value_with_unit" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="maths_value_representation_item" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="maths_value_qualification" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="value_format_type" type="TYPE"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="value_format_type_qualifier" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object name="measure_qualification" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
	
	<change_edition version="3">
		<schema.changes schema_name="material_property_definition">
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object name="material_designation" type="ENTITY">
				</modified.object>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
		<!--<schema.changes schema_name="material_property_representation">
			no changes in version 3 so this schema remains at version 1
		</schema.changes>-->
		<schema.changes schema_name="qualified_measure">
			
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object name="value_format_type" type="TYPE"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="value_format_type_qualifier" type="ENTITY"></modified.object>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object name="support_resource_schema" type="REFERENCE_FROM" interfaced.items="identifier"></modified.object>
				<modified.object name="value_qualifier" type="TYPE"></modified.object>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
</changes>
	<!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     Background knowledge to understand the content of these schemas is included with each schema.  
     A review of the first edition of this part of ISO 10303 is available in [8].  
     A technical discussion of the possible applications of the constructs in these schemas is provided in Annex E. 
   </p>
   
   <p>
   	Material and other engineering properties are important to many aspects of the life cycle of a product, such as:
   </p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>product design;</li>
   			<li>product manufacture;</li>
   			<li>product disposal;</li>
   			<li>product recycling;</li>
   			<li>materials selection;</li>
   			<li>product testing;</li>
   			<li>product performance analysis;</li>
   			<li>process planning;</li>
   			<li>process control;</li>
   			<li>product maintenance;</li>
   			<li>failure analysis;</li>
   			<li>component replacement.</li>
   		</ul>
   <p>
   	This part of ISO 10303 is applicable to integrated generic resources, 
   	application modules and application protocols that need to describe the properties of products.  
   	The nature of these products can be solids, liquids, gases or other physical forms.
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="The relationship of the schemas of this part to the ISO 10303 integration architecture (1 of 1)"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>


 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>association of a property with a product;</li>
   <li>specification of the composition of a product in terms of the amount and type of its constituents;</li>
   <li>specification of the set of qualitative and quantitative conditions under which a property is valid;</li>
   <li>specification of the representation of a property, including properties that are either measured or assigned;</li>
   <li>specification of the representation of a composition value by a mathematical expression;</li>
   <li>specification of a property value by a mathematical expression;</li>
   <li>characterization of a composition value as to its uncertainty and reliability;</li>
   <li>characterization of a property value as to its uncertainty and reliability;</li>
   <li>the properties of the surface of a product, including coatings.
   <note number="1">
   	This part of ISO 10303 can be used to describe the properties of a first stage product, such a cast ingot; an intermediate product, such as a tube or a sheet; 
   	or a final stage product requiring no further processing, such as a part pressed from a sheet.
   </note>
   </li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the processes used to measure or assign properties;</li>
   <li>the combination and transformation of property values;
   	<example number="1">
   		A design is determined by statistical analysis of a large number of test results 
   		whose values have been combined together.  
   		This part of ISO 10303	provides for the representation of the test results and 
   		for the representation of their resultant combination but does not address the processes 
   		of combination or transformation.
   	</example>
   </li>
   <li>the use of properties in the analysis of product behaviour;
   	<example number="2">
   		Individual property values can be combined into matrices of coefficients for use in analysis models.
   	</example>
   </li>
   <li>the names and definitions of properties and testing methods.
   	<note number="2">
   	The names and definitions of testing methods and the names and definitions of the properties 
   	that they define are assumed to be specified in dictionaries conforming to ISO 13584 Parts library [6].
   	</note>
   </li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_protocol"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_resource_construct"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.2004"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-50"/>
    <normref.inc normref="uncertainty_1">
    	<term.ref linkend="uncertainty_1"/>
    	<term.ref linkend="standard_uncertainty"/>
    	<term.ref linkend="combined_standard_uncertainty"/>
    	<term.ref linkend="expanded_uncertainty"/>
    	<term.ref linkend="coverage_factor"/>
    </normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc/>
 	<normref.inc  normref="ref13584-42.2010"/>
 </normrefs>

 <definition>
 	<term id="material">material</term>
 	<def>
 	substance or substances of which a product is composed or made
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="material_property">material property</term>
 	<def>
 	characteristic of a product which depends on the material or materials comprising the product and on the process of measurement of the characteristic
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="material_designation">material designation</term>
 	<def>
 	identifier of a material which can be assigned by agreement
 	
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="qualifier">qualifier</term>
 	<def>
 	item of additional information associated with a value
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="reliability">reliability</term>
 	<def>
 	characteristic associated with either a quantitative or qualitative value that describes the confidence or assurance on which the value can depend
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
<!--

 <abbreviations/>
-->

<!-- 4. material_property_definition_schema -->
<schema name="material_property_definition_schema" version="3">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<p>
   		The subjects of the <b>material_property_representation_schema</b> are the associations of a product with: 
   		a property, descriptions of product composition and of material identification.
   	</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		The following are the fundamental concepts and assumptions relating to the material_property_representation_schema:
   	</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   				material properties are representative of all engineering properties that are defined by a specified testing method;
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				an engineering property characterizes some aspect of the behaviour of a product;
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				the composition of a product is described by the specification of the type, amounts and arrangement of its constituents.
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   	<p>
   		The engineering properties may be determined from measurements on the product as a whole, 
   		on a sample taken from the product in some way such as cutting, 
   		or an entirely separate test piece prepared by processing in the same way as the product.  
   		The application of the results derived from a test piece to the whole product is dependent on the relationship to the sample 
   		to the product because, as a result of the manufacturing process, the product may not be either homogeneous or isotropic.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The values of most properties of a product are influenced by the effect that the manufacturing process has had on the product.  
   		The manufacturing process may affect the type and amounts of the units that make up the product and their form and arrangement.  
   		These units may be atoms, molecules or other aggregates of these into discrete forms such as crystals, fibres or volumes of 
   		semi-crystalline or glassy solids.  
   		The arrangement of the units is the material structure of the product.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The material structure of a solid product may be either homogeneous or heterogeneous, 
   		or a mixture of solids such as in composite structure.  
   		A complete specification of the structure includes the relationship of any preferentially aligned elements 
   		of the structure to each other and to the product. 
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		Values for an engineering property may also be assigned to a product by reference to a specification, by calculation, or by assumption.
   	</p>
   	<example number="1">
   		A manufacturer may make a product to a specification and, instead of reporting actual measurements from a specific batch of the product, 
   		he may report the nominal value indicated in the specification.
   	</example>
   	<example number="2">
   		A chemist may perform calculations using assumed values of bond strengths to predict the strength of 
   		a polymer that has never been synthesised.
   	</example>
   	<example number="3">
   		An engineer performing a finite element analysis on part might assign property values to predict potential product performance 
   		as a function of the property.
   	</example>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G  -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="material_property_definition_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="material_property_definition_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

<!-- 5. material_property_representation_schema -->
<schema name="material_property_representation_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<p>
   		The subjects of the <b>material_property_representation_schema</b> are the representations of engineering properties and of the conditions under which these property representations are valid.
   	</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		The following are the fundamental concepts and assumptions related to the representation of engineering properties:
   	</p>
   	<ul>
   		<li>
   			multiple representations of a property are possible including the use of numeric values, 
   			parametric or fundamental equations, graphical representations and non-numeric values;
   			<note>
   				The distinction between a concept and the representation of a concept is described in ISO 10303-43
   			</note>
   		</li>
   		<li>
   			the value of a property may be assigned or measured;
   		</li>
   		<li>
   			if the value is measured, the resulting value will depend on the method of measurement and on the conditions used 
   			in applying the method;
   		</li>
   		<li>
   			if the value is assigned, the conditions under which that assignment is valid may be specified;
   		</li>
   		<li>
   			in the case of either assignment or measurement, 
   			the conditions under which the value is valid are expressed as a set of quantitative and qualitative data which form the data environment.
   		</li>
   	</ul>
   	<example>
   		The ambient conditions for a measurement may be expressed as 'room air' (a qualitative condition) 
   		or air at the quantitative conditions specified as 20 degrees Celsius and 1 atmosphere pressure.
   	</example>
   	<p>
   		The conditions of the measurement method may be maintained as constant throughout the measurement.  
   		Alternatively, some conditions may be varied independently of other conditions to provide a set of related properties.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		Not all values of properties need to be expressed quantitatively, i.e. by numerical values.  
   		Values may also be expressed qualitatively, i.e. by a description.
   	</p>
   	<example>
   		Colour, through expressible quantitatively, is mostly described qualitatively by words such as 'red', 'Aegean blue', 'metallic grey', etc.
   	</example>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="material_property_representation_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="material_property_representation_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g> 
</schema>

<!-- 6. qualified_measure_schema -->
<schema name="qualified_measure_schema" version="3">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<p>
   		The <b>qualified_measure_schema</b> specializes the resource constructs from the 
   		measure_schema and the maths_function_schema to allow quantities to be qualified, i.e. further characterized as to their type, 
   		precision, uncertainty and reliability. The <b>qualified_measure_schema</b> provides a particular syntax to specify the allowed formats for the
   		numeric values that may be associated with a property.
   	</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		A physical quantity may have several aspects other than its value and units.  
   		The value may be uncertain because of the variability in the measurement procedure, leading to a lack of reproducibility.  
   		The value of a datum may be labelled as being approved for design, for example, or otherwise characterized as to its type and status.  
   		This schema supports the addition of these concepts.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The concept of uncertainty on a measured value used in this part of ISO 10303 is taken from 
   		Clause 2.2 of ISO/IEC Guide 98:1995.  
   		In general, the result of a measurement, y, is only an approximation or estimate of the value of the specific quantity 
   		that is the subject of the measurement (the measurand), Y.  
   		The uncertainty of the result of a measurement reflects the lack of exact knowledge of the measurand and thus the result 
   		is complete only when accompanied by a quantitative statement of its uncertainty.  
   		The uncertainty generally consists of several components which may be grouped into two categories according 
   		to the method used to estimate the numerical values of the components:
   	</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   				those which are evaluated by statistical methods;
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				those which are evaluated by other means.
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   	<p>
   		Each component of uncertainty that contributes to the uncertainty of a measurement result is represented by an estimated standard deviation, 
   		termed standard <i>uncertainty</i>, <i>u<sub>i</sub></i>, and equal to the positive square root of the estimated variance.  
   		The procedures for evaluating the standard uncertainty for both of the above categories are described in Clause 4 of ISO/IEC Guide 98:1995.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The standard uncertainty of the results of a measurement, 
   		when that result is obtained from the values of a number of other quantities, is termed the combined standard uncertainty, <i>u<sub>c</sub></i>.  
   		It is the estimated standard deviation associated with the result and is equal to the positive square root of the combined variance, 
   		obtained by summing all variance and covariance components, however evaluated.  
   		The procedure for combining the variance and covariance components is described in Clause 5 of ISO/IEC Guide 98:1995.  
   		This schema provides the means for representing either the standard uncertainty or the combined standard uncertainty.
   	</p>
   	<note>
   		The number of measurements that have been used to derive the uncertainty of a measured value can be specified by use of the 
   		data_environment  associated with the value (See Clause 5).
   	</note>
   	<p>
   		Although the combined standard uncertainty is used to express the uncertainty of many measurement results, 
   		what is often required is a measure of uncertainty that defines an interval about the measurement result 
   		within which the value of the measurand can be confidently asserted to lie.  
   		The measure of uncertainty intended to meet this requirement is termed the expanded <i>uncertainty</i>, <i>U</i>, 
   		and is obtained by multiplying <i>u<sub>c</sub>(y)</i> by a coverage factor, <i>k</i>.  
   		Thus <i>U = ku<sub>c</sub>(y)</i> and and it can be confidently asserted that: 
   		<i>y – U &lt;=Y &lt;= y + U</i>, which is usually written as <i>Y = y ± U</i>.  
   		In general, the value of <i>k</i> is chosen on the basis of the desired level of confidence to be associated with the interval defined by <i>U = ku<sub>c</sub></i>. 
   		Typically, <i>k</i> is in the range of 2 to 3.  
   		When the normal distribution applies to the results and <i>u<sub>c</sub></i> has a negligible uncertainty, then <i>k</i> = 2 defines an interval having 
   		a level of confidence of approximately 95 percent and <i>k</i> = 3 defines an interval having a level of confidence greater that 99 percent.
   	</p>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G  -->
   <express-g>
     
     
     <imgfile file="qualified_measure_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="qualified_measure_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="DSRPIT" entity="descriptive_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="DTENRL" entity="data_environment_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="DTENV" entity="data_environment"/>
 	<shortname name="EXPUNC" entity="expanded_uncertainty"/>
 	<shortname name="MTVLQL" entity="maths_value_qualification"/>
 	<shortname name="MVRI" entity="maths_value_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="MVWU" entity="maths_value_with_unit"/>
 	<shortname name="MSRPIT" entity="measure_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="MSRQLF" entity="measure_qualification"/>
 	<shortname name="MTRDSG" entity="material_designation"/>
 	<shortname name="MTDSCH" entity="material_designation_characterization"/>
 	<shortname name="MTRPRP" entity="material_property"/>
 	<shortname name="MTPRRP" entity="material_property_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="PMCR" entity="product_material_composition_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="PRCQLF" entity="precision_qualifier"/>
 	<shortname name="PRDFR" entity="property_definition_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="QLRPIT" entity="qualified_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="QLTUNC" entity="qualitative_uncertainty"/>
 	<shortname name="STNUNC" entity="standard_uncertainty"/>
 	<shortname name="TYPQLF" entity="type_qualifier"/>
	<shortname name="UNCQLF" entity="uncertainty_qualifier"/>
 	<shortname name="VFTQ" entity="value_format_type_qualifier"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes -->
 <tech_discussion>
 	<b>E.1 Introduction</b>
 	
 	<p>
 		All manufactured products are made of substances whose properties contribute to the behaviour of the product during its production 
 		and in service. 
 		This part of ISO 10303 enables those properties which are closely associated with the substance of the product to be described. 
 		It follows that what are commonly called: “materials”, “engineering materials”, “raw materials” or “starting materials” are all products, 
 		resulting from a production process. Properties of such products can be described by using the resources in this part of ISO 10303.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		Since the focus is on the properties of a product, the constructs in this part of ISO 10303 can be used for the products of the materials industry, 
 		as well as the products of other manufacturing sectors. 
 		In this annex the manner in which this description is achieved is explained and examples of the use of the constructs are given.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The properties of a product which are the subject of this part of ISO 10303 are those which are either determined by a measurement procedure 
 		or are assigned by agreement, such as standardized properties or values approved for design. 
 		The value of a property of a product has to be associated with the conditions under which it is valid. 
 		Some properties of materials may be related to the fundamental nature of the substance. 
 		These may be referred to as intrinsic properties. 
 		This part of ISO 10303 does not attempt to provide separate resources for this category of properties.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The names of specific properties are not included in this part of ISO 10303. 
 		The naming of properties is the responsibility of those application protocols which use the generic resources provided in this part of ISO 10303. 
 		For these application protocols it is assumed that the names and definition of testing methods and of the properties that they define will 
 		be specified in a data dictionary conforming to ISO 13584 Parts Libraries [6].   
 		There are also several other concepts commonly used in the description of engineering materials which are provided for in other parts of ISO 10303. 
 		An example is the, so-called, “class” of a material (e.g., ceramic, polymer: metallic alloy, etc.).
 	</p>
 	
 	<b>E.2 Example of a product</b>
 	
 	<p>
 		In this section, a hypothetical product called the “part 45 example product” is described by both diagrams and words. 
 		This product provides the basis for explaining how different properties are associated with the product. 
 		See Figure E.1 for a diagram of this product.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The product is a regular, rectangular block. 
 		An orthogonal coordinate system corresponds to the principal dimensions of the block. 
 		This shape has been chosen to highlight the concept that a simple exterior shape can have a complex internal arrangement. 
 		The internal arrangement is called the material structure of the product. 
 		There are four possible alternative situations. 
 		The interior of the product could be:
 	</p>
 		<ul>
 			<li>homogeneous in composition and isotropic in properties;</li>
 			<li>inhomogeneous in composition and isotropic in properties;</li>
 			<li>homogeneous in composition and anisotropic in properties;</li>
 			<li>inhomogeneous in composition and anisotropic in properties.</li>
 		</ul>
	 	<figure number="E.1">
			   <title>Part 45 example product</title>
			   <img src="part_45_example_product.gif"/>
		</figure>
 
 	<p>
 		An example of the first situation would be a sintered compact of either a uniform metallic or ceramic powder. 
 		An example of the second category would be a compression moulding of a thermosetting polymer with an inorganic particulate filler. 
 		An example of the third would be a sheet rolled from a metal alloy. 
 		An example of the fourth would be a plate manufactured as a fibre-reinforced, polymer resin composite.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		There are, therefore, several different materials and processes which could be used to manufacture this product. 
 		Each of them would result in a characteristic set of material properties for the product. 
 		The descriptions of the process of manufacture and the conditions during the manufacture of a product 
 		are achieved by using the resources in ISO 10303-49 [5].
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		A real example of the part 45 example product could be aluminium alloy sheet, 
 		manufactured by rolling to the specification of British Standard BS1470:1987 and intended for use as a cladding for buildings. 
 		Some of the details of the product would be described by using the entities in ISO 10303-41. 
 		The entities: <b>product_context</b>, <b>product_definition_context</b> and <b>product_related_product_category</b> from ISO 10303-41 
 		can contain information about the intended use of the product. 
 		The entities: <b>product</b>, <b>product_definition_formation</b> and <b>product_definition</b> from ISO 10303-41 can contain information about the product, 
 		such as the trade name, the sheet thickness, the batch number, the condition (e.g., annealed). 
 		The linking of a product to a specification document (e.g., BS1470:1987) would be achieved by defining an entity in an application protocol 
 		with an attribute which has a reference to the document entity in ISO 10303-41.
 	</p>
 	
 	<b>E.3	Material designation</b>
 	
 	<p>
 		Products of the materials industries are usually identified and classified by means of alphanumeric strings, 
 		defined by national, regional, or international standards, which are called the material designation. 
 		A material designation is usually associated with a particular element composition of the product. 
 		An example of a material designation for a sheet of aluminium alloy would be: “3105”. 
 		The product standards also allow for a designation to be extended by adding further letters and numbers to indicate other distinguishing characteristics, 
 		such as the metallurgical condition. 
 		Therefore a sheet of an aluminium alloy which had been hardened by rolling could have the material designation 3105-H12, 
 		where “Hl2” indicates the hardened condition. 
 		Sheets of the same alloy in the same condition but with different thicknesses, which are therefore different products, could have the same material designation. 
 		Therefore, the material designation is a label with important engineering implications and these have been provided for in this part of ISO 10303.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The <b>material_designation</b> entity in this part of ISO 10303 associates a material designation with a product by reference 
 		to the <b>product_definition</b> entity in ISO 10303-41. 
 		The association of a material designation with either a <b>material_property</b> or a <b>product_material_composition_relationship</b>
 		is achieved by using the <b>material_designation_characterization</b> select type and 
 		this can be used to indicate which engineering concepts give rise to the designation.
 	</p>
 	
 	<b>E.4	Composition of a product</b>
 	
 	<p>
 		ISO 10303 provides constructs to enable the composition of a product to be described and to associate the composition with 
 		a material designation. 
 		The constructs can be used for elements combined as alloys or compounds or for components forming a composite mixture, 
 		such as fibre-reinforced plastics or steel-reinforced concrete products.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		Each constituent of the composition is described as a product by combining the use of entities from ISO 10303-41 and this part of ISO 10303. 
 		The <b>product</b> entity (ISO 10303-41) can contain the name of the constituent, for example silicon as one constituent of the aluminium 
 		alloy designation 3105. 
 		The <b>product_context</b> entity from ISO 10303-41 can describe the context of the constituent as chemical composition, for example. 
 		The <b>product_definition</b> entity from ISO 10303-41 can define a constituent as a chemical element, or as a fibre-reinforcement in a composite.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		Each instance of <b>product_material_composition_relationship</b> describes the relationship of a component of the composition to the whole. 
 		The <b>constituent_amount</b> attribute is a set that can contain one or more values of the amount of a constituent, 
 		such as the maximum and minimum values.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		Values of composition in standard specifications are not usually described by single value numbers.  
 		For example, a composition value can be specified as 'less-than' a given value.  
 		Several elements can be combined to specify that the sum of their values is less than a limiting value.  
 		Usually the composition of the principal element in an alloy is not given but is specified as 'balance', 
 		i.e. the difference between 100 percent and the sum of all the other actual values.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		This new edition now enables a composition value to be specified as a mathematical function using the resources of ISO 10303-50.  
 		The select type <b>characterized_product_composition_value</b> enables the attribute <b>constituent_amount</b> to be either 
 		a <b>measure_with_unit</b> or a <b>maths_value_with_unit</b>.   
 		The unit for the composition value could be a context_dependent_unit such as “weight fraction in percent”, for example.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		Each value of the composition can be qualified. That is, it can be identified as a maximum or minimum value, for example, 
 		and it can also be associated with the uncertainty on the value (see clause E.8).  
 		This capability is available for both the value as a number and for the value as a mathematical function.
 	</p>
 	
 	<b>E.5	Properties and measurement conditions</b>
 	
 	<p>
 		In this part of ISO 10303, values of material properties are always associated with the conditions in which they are valid. 
 		These conditions are called the data environment. 
 		The components of the data environment for a measured value are the operational parameters at the time of the measurement 
 		which have an influence on the numerical value of the result such as: temperature, loading rate, gauge length, etc. 
 		Dependencies between measurement conditions can also be described and linked together in a chain of dependencies. 
 		For example, the correction factor for misalignment in a uniaxial tensile test is derived from the values of three extensions 
 		measured at symmetrical locations on the surface of the test piece. 
 		The model allows for the description of the three extensions and the corrected value which depends on them.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The representation of the numerical value of the property is achieved by using the resources provided in ISO 10303-43. 
 		The decision to use representation was made in preference to the apparently simpler method used for composition because 
 		it enables a property to be associated with a system of coordinates and provides resources for transformations between coordinate systems. 
 		This decision therefore enables the properties to be related to a direction in the product.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The components of the data environment are described in the same manner as the property values, 
 		using the same resources from ISO 10303-43, and therefore they can also have their directions described with respect 
 		to a frame of reference related to the principal directions of the product.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		Examples of directional properties as a result of directional conditions would be the Hall effect in semiconductors or the acoustic 
 		emission of a single crystal transducer. 
 		In these circumstances the direction of the application of the stimulus and the direction of the response must be known with respect 
 		to the geometry of the product and also with respect to its crystal structure in these particular examples. 
 		A blade in the first hot stage of a gas turbine engine can be manufactured as a single crystal with its crystallographic orientation 
 		related to the geometry of the blade. 
 		This preferred orientation provides for a favourable anisotropy of the behaviour under the load conditions during operation.
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The relationship of any test piece sample to the anisotropy of a product should also be described. 
 	</p>
 	<p>
 		The product can have any number of properties and each representation of one property could have several data environment conditions. 
 		Figure E.2 shows, in a simplified manner, an illustration of the relationships between a material property, the product definition, 
 		the representation of a property and its associated data environments. The first sequence associates a property with the product. 
 		This property is associated with one or many environment conditions. The value of each condition is described in a similar manner to a property. 
 		The last sequence in the diagram illustrates the proper termination of a chain of dependencies in the data environment.
 	</p>
 		<figure number="E.2">
			   <title>The relationship between a product property and the conditions in the data environment</title>
			   <img src="relationship_between_product_property_and_conditions.gif"/>
		</figure>
		
	<b>E.6	Properties of regions of a product</b>
	
	<p>
		The manufacturing process can alter the substance in different regions of the product to produce differences in properties between these regions. 
		An example would be a sheet of aluminium alloy formed into a product by pressing between two matched dies. 
		Some regions of the sheet will be stretched by greater amounts than others and the properties of those regions will be different 
		as a consequence of the greater, local plastic deformations. 
		Alternatively, some regions of the product may have had additional processing by, for example, selectively hardening one region of the surface. 
		In ISO 10303 an identifiable, geometrically defined portion of the shape of a product is referred to as a shape aspect.
	</p>
	<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 therefore provides the resources to associate material properties with a shape aspect. 
		This is achieved by the <b>material_property</b> entity which specializes the <b>property_definition</b> entity (in ISO 10303-41) 
		to allow it to be associated either with a whole product or with a shape of a product. 
		The geometry of the shape aspect of the product is described by using the resources in ISO 10303-42 [3].
	</p>
	
	<b>E.7	Product structure</b>
	
	<p>
		In many engineering applications it is necessary to describe the internal structure of the product - the material structure. 
		The influence of the material structure of the product on the properties is particularly important when the product is made as a mixture 
		of solids, such as polymer resins reinforced with arrangements of glass fibres, for example.  
	</p>
	<p>
		As an example of a complex structure, a composite product can be regarded as being built up from a collection of shapes. 
		In composite technology, these shapes have different terms to describe the role that they play in the intermediate stages and 
		in building up the final composite product. 
		The names and definitions of these terms would be specified in an application protocol.
	</p>
	
	<p>
		The constituent of the material structure of the product and their proportions can be described by following the same method 
		used for specifying the composition. 
		In both cases the components are treated as individual products and related to the whole product. 
		The additional concept which enables the constituents of the structure to be described is that they can have the property of shape. 
		The structural constituents may also be oriented with respect to the product frame of reference as shown in figure E.3 which indicates 
		the arrangements of fibres in the bottom layer and an intermediate layer of a multi-layer composite product built up from a series of 
		plies in a layer stacking sequence.
	</p>
	<p>
		This version of the part 45 example product is therefore manufactured from a series of intermediate products. 
		The structure of each layer will have its own coordinate basis and these bases will be related to the product basis 
		by an appropriate transformation. 
		Each intermediate product will have its own composition and properties described by the resources in this part of ISO 10303.
	</p>
	<p>
		ISO 10303-42 and ISO 10303-43 provide the resources used to describe the shapes of the components of the structure, 
		their alignments with respect to each other, and to the product as a whole. 
		The concept of the internal structure is different from the concept of a mechanical assembly, described in ISO 10303-44 [6] 
		in that the organisation of a material structure will include interactions and intersections between the different 
		shape representations making up the structure. 
		Therefore it would be expected that the concepts from ISO 10303-42 and ISO 10303-43 would be used differently to represent 
		material structure in an implementation than they would be for a mechanical assembly.
	</p>
	
	<b>E.8	Qualification of property values</b>
	
	<p>
		Numerical values for properties represent the best estimate of the value which could be obtained in the conditions which applied. 
		Successive measurements of the same property do not, in general, produce identical results and therefore 
		all measured values are subject to an uncertainty. 
		In addition, values of numerical properties, whether or not they are measured values, are often qualified to indicate that 
		they represent either a minimum or a maximum value, for example.
	</p>
	<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 provides the resources to associate qualifiers and statistically defined measures 
		of uncertainty with both quantitative or qualitative values of properties and their associated measurement conditions.
	</p>
		<figure number="E.3">
			   <title>Part 45 example product made as a composite</title>
			   <img src="part_45_example_product_made_as_composite.gif"/>
		</figure>
	<p>
		Measures of uncertainty and qualifiers of values can be associated with both composition values and property values.
	</p>
	<p>
		Examples of the uses of these resources include:
	</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				the value of a hardness number may be specified as 96 ± 4, 
				where 4 represents the statistically determined uncertainty derived from a series of measurements;
			</li>
			<li>
				the value of the weight fraction of a chemical element may be identified 
				as a maximum value and further qualified to indicate that it is a standardized value.
			</li>
		</ul>
	
	<b>E.9	Other requirements</b>
	
	<p>
		Specifications of products commonly use several other items of information and data related to the material substance 
		in addition to those which are included within the scope of this part of ISO 10303. 
		These additional items are modelled by resources located elsewhere in ISO 10303. 
		These resources are available to implementations of this part of ISO 10303 because of the integration of this part 
		with the other parts of ISO 10303.
	</p>
	<p>Examples include:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				details of manufacturing processes (e.g., the temperature of a heat treatment) are provided by resources in ISO 10303-49[5];
			</li>
			<li>
				the shape and geometry of a product, including the specification of a test piece, can be described by using the resources in ISO 10303-42 [3];
			</li>
			<li>
				the description of the configuration of a product and its assembly uses the resources in ISO 10303-44 [4];
			</li>
			<li>
				units, names, codes, product classification categories, approval details, associated documents, etc., are all described using resources in ISO 10303-41.
			</li>
		</ul>
 
 </tech_discussion>
 	

<!-- 
 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->
 <bibliography>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_10303-21"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_10303-22"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-42"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-44"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-49"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO13584-all-parts"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="product_data_technology_for_materials"/>
 </bibliography>

</resource>

