<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: aam.xml,v 1.1 2003/12/04 14:30:22 mikeward Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE idef0 SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/aam.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkapdoc_main.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!-- 
     IDEF0 activity model for ap233_system_engineering_and_design
      -->
<idef0 application_protocol="system_engineering_and_design">
	<!-- view point of the IDEF0 model -->
	<viewpoint>systems engineering and design</viewpoint>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 0-->
	<page number="0" node="A-0" title="Satisfy_capability_demand_using_engineered_system">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A-0" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Satisfy capability demand using engineered system
      </name>
			<description>
        Bring together organizations to form an extended enterprise to create, operate and dispose of a system that provides a specified capability.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 1-->
	<page number="1" node="A0" title="Satisfy_capability_demand_using_engineered_system">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A0" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Satisfy capability demand using engineered system
      </name>
			<description>
        Bring together organizations to form an extended enterprise to create, operate and dispose of a system that provides a specified capability.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A1" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Establish enterprise agreement 
      </name>
			<description>
        Achieve an agreement between two organizations, one in the role of acquirer and the other as supplier so as to effect the provision of a product or service.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A2" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Manage enterprise 
      </name>
			<description>
        Establish, operate and maintain the enterprise as the framework by which to initiate, support and monitor projects.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A3" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Manage project 
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform proper planning and control of a project and project-wide factors .
Note:	The project-wide factors are risk, configuration and management
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Execute project
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the technical processes that mark the successive stages of the system life cycle.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 2-->
	<page number="2" node="A3" title="Manage_project">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A3.1" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Plan, assess and control project 
      </name>
			<description>
        Establish and evolve project plans, assess actual achievement and progress against the plans and control execution of the project through to fulfilment.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A3.2" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Make decision 
      </name>
			<description>
        Select the most beneficial course of project action where alternatives exist.
Note:	Project feedback provides the information by which to recognize the existence of problems and opportunities that lead to a requirement for project decisions.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A3.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Manage risk, configuration and information 
      </name>
			<description>
        Minimize the effects of uncertain events, establish and maintain the integrity of all products of a project and provide relevant, timely, complete valid, confidential information to both the enterprise and external parties.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 3-->
	<page number="3" node="A4" title="Execute_project">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Define system
      </name>
			<description>
        Create specifications at successive tiers of the system right down to individual components.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Produce system
      </name>
			<description>
        Realize and test successive tiers of the system in accordance with the applicable specification.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Validate produced system
      </name>
			<description>
        Provide objective evidence that the capabilities provided by the system when in use comply with the requirements of the relevant stakeholders.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.4" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Exploit system 
      </name>
			<description>
        Operate, maintain and dispose of the system so as to fulfil the demands on the system capability for the agreed service life of the system.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 4-->
	<page number="4" node="A4.1" title="Define_system">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Control engineering change
      </name>
			<description>
        Analyze technical impact of discovered issues and generate feedback to initiate project control processes to assess cost, risk and schedule impacts.
Note:	<i>change proposal *</i> is the basis for activation of <i>Manage project</i> to look at non-technical project issues such as cost, risk and schedule.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create systems engineering model
      </name>
			<description>
        Develop a model at each tier of the system as the basis for a structured set of specifications.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.3" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Design system component 
      </name>
			<description>
        Create a design specification that provides sufficient detail to enable production and testing of a component.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 5-->
	<page number="5" node="A4.1.2" title="Create_systems_engineering_model">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create model for domain tier
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic systems engineering modelling process to generate a specification that can serve across multiple customer organizations in the domain.
Example:	This modelling creates a problem description that will possibly result in more than one separately purchased, interacting system, such as in examining the domain of air transport, where aircraft interact with air traffic control systems and airports.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create model for concept tier
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic systems engineering modelling process to generate a specification to address requirements in a customer organization.
Note:	This modelling creates what is often known as the user or stakeholder requirement (context view) and the system requirement (subject view).  These requirements can be in the form of a user requirement document (URD) and a system requirement document (SRD).
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create model for system tier
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic systems engineering modelling process to provide a specification to address the concept tier model set as a source of requirements.
Note:	This modelling creates what is often known as the architectural design.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.4" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create model for sub-system tier
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic systems engineering modelling process to provide a specification to address requirements from a partition of the system or higher level sub-system tier.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.5" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create model for component tier
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic systems engineering modelling process to provide a specification to address requirements from an atomic partition of a system or sub-system tier model.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 6-->
	<page number="6" node="A4.1.2.3" title="Create_model_for_system_tier">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Analyze context
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic process to create a model set and, thus, address the context for the subject within the applicable tier of the system.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Analyze subject
      </name>
			<description>
        Perform the generic process to create a model set and, thus, address the subject within the applicable tier of the system.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 7-->
	<page number="7" node="A4.1.2.3.1" title="Analyze_context">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Assess available information
      </name>
			<description>
        Prepare foundational information that is necessary for systems engineering modelling.
Note:	This information can include:  text requirements;  heritage information;  user information;  operations concepts as text;  and initial models.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Build solution model
      </name>
			<description>
        Identify effectiveness measures as the basis for trade-off and create both behaviour and structure models
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Perform trade-off analysis
      </name>
			<description>
        Choose among alternative solutions within the models.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.4" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create plan for build and test
      </name>
			<description>
        Address both management of technical issues to establish a schedule that is feasible for production of a solution to the specification models.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 8-->
	<page number="8" node="A4.1.2.3.1.2" title="Build_solution_model">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.2.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Define effectiveness measure
      </name>
			<description>
        Establish the criteria by which alternative model specifications will be judged.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.2.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create behaviour model
      </name>
			<description>
        Define either the excitations or responses for the subject at the system tier of interest.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.2.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Create structure model
      </name>
			<description>
        Identify the logical and physical composition for the specification.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 9-->
	<page number="9" node="A4.1.2.3.1.3" title="Perform_trade-off_analysis">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.3.1" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Accept model information
      </name>
			<description>
        Confirm the availability and status of all information necessary for conducting trade-off analysis.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.3.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Determine attribute value
      </name>
			<description>
        Obtain value to an applicable level of accuracy for a system attribute that is significant for the trade-off analysis.
Note:	This process includes:
- estimation;
- simulation (also known as modelling and simulation);
- measurement from prototypes (requiring the production of suitable prototypes, whether software or hardware).
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.3.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Calculate system performance
      </name>
			<description>
        Use obtained attribute values to determine the overall system performance in terms of the applicable set of requirements.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.1.2.3.1.3.4" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Compare effectiveness of feasible solutions
      </name>
			<description>
        Rank all feasible solutions on the basis of applicable effectiveness measures and determine the optimum solution.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>

	<!-- IDEF0 page 10-->
	<page number="10" node="A4.2" title="Produce_system">
		<!-- activity in the IDEF0 model -->
		<activity identifier="A4.2.1" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Produce system component 
      </name>
			<description>
        Realize and test a component of the system in accordance with the applicable design.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.2.2" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Integrate component into system
      </name>
			<description>
       Take component and install in the applicable location within the system.
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.2.3" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        Verify system
      </name>
			<description>
        Demonstrate that the characteristics and behaviour of a system or system element comply with the applicable architectural design specification
      </description>
		</activity>
		<activity identifier="A4.2.4" inscope="no">
			<name>
        Install system
      </name>
			<description>
        Take verified system and install in operational environment.
      </description>
		</activity>
	</page>


	<!-- IDEF0 Arrow definitions (inputs controls outputs mechanism) -->
	<icoms>
		<!-- IDEF0 Arrow definition (inputs controls outputs mechanism) -->
		<icom identifier="agreement" inscope="no">
			<name>
        agreement
      </name>
			<description>
        Mutual acknowledgement of terms and conditions under which to conduct a working relationship.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="agreement_feedback " inscope="no">
			<name>
        agreement feedback 
      </name>
			<description>
        Feedback that conveys results of activities across an enterprise back to applicable agreement processes.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="attribute_value" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        attribute value
      </name>
			<description>
        Value that indicates a specific characteristic of the system corresponding to a proposed system model.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="authorized_engineering_change" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        authorized engineering change
      </name>
			<description>
        Change that has received approval for application to one or more technical elements in the creation or operation of a system.
Note:	Technical elements can include systems engineering models, design specifications, system or system elements.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="authorized_project_action" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        authorized project action
      </name>
			<description>
        Action that is allowable on the basis of an approval in accordance with defined authorities for a project.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="behaviour_model" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        behaviour model
      </name>
			<description>
        Model that represents all functions of the context or subject at a tier of a system and the ordering, inputs and outputs of those functions.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="by-product " inscope="no">
			<name>
        by-product 
      </name>
			<description>
        Item that arises during production, operation or maintenance of a system and no longer has a useful role to play in the life cycle of the system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="change_proposal " inscope="no">
			<name>
        change proposal 
      </name>
			<description>
        Proposal that identifies the characteristics of a change to some technical element in the creation, operation, maintenance or disposal of a system.
Note:	A project team will consider the non-technical implications of a change proposal before authorizing the change to become a reality.  The extent and formality of this consideration will depend on the expected impact of the change (in general, impact increases with time during the system life cycle).  Organization, enterprise or project policy will specify the criteria on which to assess a change proposal.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="chosen_solution" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        chosen solution
      </name>
			<description>
        Model information that is an optimal specification for a system.
Note:	The effectivess measures are the basis for choosing this one solution over other feasible alternatives.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="component_for_integration " inscope="no">
			<name>
        component for integration 
      </name>
			<description>
        Component that is ready for integration into an emerging system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="component_tier_model" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        component tier model
      </name>
			<description>
        Set that consists of both the context and subject models specifying a component within a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="concept_tier_model" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        concept tier model
      </name>
			<description>
        Developed model set that consists of both the context and subject models specifying the concept tier view of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="context_model_set" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        context model set
      </name>
			<description>
        Set that consists of a behaviour model, structure model and implementation plan for the context of a subject within a tier of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="demand_on_system_capability " inscope="no">
			<name>
        demand on system capability 
      </name>
			<description>
        Change that occurs to the operational environment of a system and initiates a response from the system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="design_for_system_component " inscope="no">
			<name>
        design for system component 
      </name>
			<description>
        Specification that provides sufficient descriptive detail to enable the production and testing of a component so as to meet user requirements during operation, maintenance and disposal processes.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="developed_model_set" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        developed model set
      </name>
			<description>
        Set that consists of both a context model and subject model at a tier of a system.
Example:	A developed model set can describe:
- user requirements;
- system requirements;
- architectural design.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="effectiveness_measure" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        effectiveness measure
      </name>
			<description>
        Requirement that is so important as to have a critical impact on the success or failure of a system.
Example:	When engineering a laptop computer, two major effectiveness measures (optimization criteria) are typically mass and battery life.  The engineer will attempt to minimize mass and maximize battery life.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="enabling_system " inscope="no">
			<name>
        enabling system 
      </name>
			<description>
        System that complements the system-of-interest for the purposes of one or more life-cycle processes.
Note:	For example, a production enabling system is necessary in order to manufacture and integrate the system.
Each enabling system has a distinct life cycle.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="enterprise" inscope="no">
			<name>
        enterprise
      </name>
			<description>
       Virtual organization that is the result of one or more agreements between two or more organizations and is responsible for the life cycle of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="enterprise_feedback " inscope="no">
			<name>
        enterprise feedback 
      </name>
			<description>
        Feedback that conveys the results of project activities to the wider enterprise.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="enterprise_policy_or_procedure " inscope="no">
			<name>
        enterprise policy or procedure 
      </name>
			<description>
        Control that is the basis on which to conduct technical or managerial activity for projects within an enterprise.
Note:	An enterprise policy or procedure is complementary to all relevant organization policies or procedures or social, legal or political directives.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="existing_system_or_element " inscope="yes">
			<name>
        existing system or element 
      </name>
			<description>
       Item that is available from another enterprise for re-use in another system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="feasible_solution" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        feasible solution
      </name>
			<description>
        Model information that specifies a solution meeting the applicable requirements.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="implementation_plan" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        implementation plan
      </name>
			<description>
        Plan that specifies the order for the build and test of a tier of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="information_from_external_source" inscope="no">
			<name>
        information from external source 
      </name>
			<description>
        Information that arises from any source outside the system enterprise.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="initial_model_set" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        initial model set
      </name>
			<description>
        Model information that is available when beginning the systems engineering modelling process.
Note:	In general, the systems engineering modelling process is flexible.  Such modelling can be top-down, bottom-up, out-in or middle-out in terms of the sequence of tiers.  For simple systems, the difference between the tiers requires a minimum amount of formal project control and an individual engineer can work at more than one tier in parallel.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="ISO_15288 " inscope="no">
			<name>
        ISO 15288 
      </name>
			<description>
        Systems engineering -- System life cycle processes.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="ISO_9001 " inscope="no">
			<name>
        ISO 9001 
      </name>
			<description>
        Quality management systems -- Requirements.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="map_of_functions" inscope="yes">
			<name>
	map of _functions      </name>
			<description>
        Set of relationships that each identify the correspondence between a structural element and a behaviour.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="model_set" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        model set
      </name>
			<description>
        Information that consists of all proposed systems engineering models for a particular tier of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="modelling_database" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        modelling database
      </name>
			<description>
        Information that consists of all in-work systems engineering models to date for a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="multi-project_management_aid " inscope="no">
			<name>
        multi-project management aid 
      </name>
			<description>
        Aid that is available to more than one project within an enterprise and able to support common approaches to management across the enterprise.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="organization" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        organization
      </name>
			<description>
        Business entity that consists of an interacting collection of personnel, infrastructure and facilities.
Note:	For example, an organization can be:
- a company;
- a government department.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="organization_policy_or_procedure " inscope="no">
			<name>
        organization policy or procedure 
      </name>
			<description>
        Control that a member organization of a system enterprise applies to business activities and requires the enterprise to take account of.
Note:	An organization policy or procedure is complementary to all relevant social, legal or political directives.X
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="other_standard " inscope="no">
			<name>
        other standard 
      </name>
			<description>
        Standard that is neither ISO 9001 nor ISO 15288 and is available from a statutory standards organization.
Example:	The following other standards are relevant to systems engineering:
- EIA 632 "Processes for engineering a system";
- IEEE 1220 "Standard for application and management of the systems engineering process".
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="project_decision " inscope="no">
			<name>
        project decision 
      </name>
			<description>
        Choice that establishes the optimum project action against a given set of criteria.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="project_definition" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        project definition
      </name>
			<description>
        Definition that embodies the enterprise-level view of a project and is the basis on which members of the enterprise can initiate, execute and continue the project.
Note:	A project definition includes:
- project accountabilities and authorities;
- expected outcomes of the project;
- allocated project resources;
- project reporting requirements;
- project review milestones.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="project_feedback" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        project feedback
      </name>
			<description>
        Feedback that conveys the results of technical activities in a project to the managers of the project.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="project_policy_or_procedure" inscope="no">
			<name>
        project policy or procedure 
      </name>
			<description>
        Control that is the basis on which to conduct technical processes within a project.
Note:	A project policy or procedure is complementary to all relevant enterprise or organization policies or procedures or social, legal or political directives.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="raw_material_or_consumable " inscope="no">
			<name>
        raw material or consumable 
      </name>
			<description>
        Item that manufacturing processes will transform to become an integral part of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="realized_system_or_sub-system" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        realized system or sub-system
      </name>
			<description>
        System or sub-system that is complete and is ready for verification testing.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="recycled_raw_material " inscope="no">
			<name>
        recycled raw material 
      </name>
			<description>
        Item that was once either a part of a system or necessary to operate, maintain or dispose of a system and is ready to be raw material in some further process.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="register_of_risk " inscope="no">
			<name>
        register of risk 
      </name>
			<description>
        Information that identifies and defines risks that are applicable to a project.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="rejected_system_or_element" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        rejected system or element
      </name>
			<description>
        Item that has not met applicable test criteria and requires either corrective action or disposal.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="requirements_database" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        requirements database
      </name>
			<description>
        Collection of information that describes the basis on which to create a system.
Example:	Requirements can include:
- textual descriptions;
- concepts of operations;
- heritage information;
- information about users.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="satisfied_demand_on_system_capability" inscope="no">
			<name>
        satisfied demand on system capability
      </name>
			<description>
        Change that occurs to the operational environment of a system as the result of operation of the system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="set_of_component_requirements" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        set of component requirements
      </name>
			<description>
        Set that consists of both the behaviour and the structure model for a component within a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="social_legal_or_political_directive" inscope="no">
			<name>
        social legal or political directive 
      </name>
			<description>
        Directive that is beyond the direct control of a system enterprise or constituent organizations.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="society_or_organization_feedback" inscope="no">
			<name>
        society or organization feedback 
      </name>
			<description>
        Feedback that connects an enterprise to the broader industrial and social context.
Note:	This feedback can include:
- responses to requirements to provide information either to a member organization of an enterprise or to some other external party;
- requests for information from parties external to an enterprise.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="specification_for_existing_system_or_element" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        specification for existing system or element
      </name>
			<description>
        Specification that defines the characteristics of an item that is available from another enterprise.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="structure_model" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        structure model
      </name>
			<description>
        Model that represents the static structure of the context or subject at a tier of a system.
Note:	A structure model is not the same as a structural analysis model that indicates the stress-strain response to a load for a mechanical system or physical component.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="sub-system_for_integration " inscope="no">
			<name>
        sub-system for integration 
      </name>
			<description>
        Sub-system that is ready for integration into an emerging system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="system_assurance_evidence" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        system assurance evidence
      </name>
			<description>
        Evidence that supports and validates the predictions of system performance and safety and is the basis on which the acquirer can accept the system as meeting the terms of the applicable enterprise agreement.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="system_for_installation" inscope="no">
			<name>
        system for installation 
      </name>
			<description>
        System that is verified as complete and is ready for installation in the operational environment.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="system_for_validation " inscope="no">
			<name>
        system for validation 
      </name>
			<description>
        System that is installed in the operational environment and is ready for validation testing.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="system_or_element_for_re-use " inscope="no">
			<name>
       system or element for re-use 
      </name>
			<description>
        Item that is the result of systems engineering and ready for re-use in a system of another enterprise.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="system_ready_for_exploitation " inscope="no">
			<name>
        system ready for exploitation 
      </name>
			<description>
        System that is validated and is ready for operation.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="technical_issue" inscope="no">
			<name>
        technical issue 
      </name>
			<description>
        Issue that relates to some technical element in the creation, operation, maintenance or disposal of a system.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="trade-off_result" inscope="yes">
			<name>
        trade-off result
      </name>
			<description>
        Result that indicates the basis on which individual potential system or system element solutions meet or fail to satisfy the identified effectiveness measures.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="transfer_of_system_responsibility " inscope="no">
			<name>
        transfer of system responsibility 
      </name>
			<description>
        Notification that indicates a successful installation of a system in the operational environment and passes responsibility for the system to the intended operator.
      </description>
		</icom>

		<icom identifier="waste_material" inscope="no">
			<name>
        waste material 
      </name>
			<description>
        Item that is in a condition beyond serviceable use.
      </description>
		</icom>
	</icoms>
</idef0>
