<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.2 2002/08/22 15:34:48 ckreiler Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="reference_data_library"
   part="xxxx"
   version="1"
   wg.number="00000"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2002/08/22 15:34:48 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.2 $">

 <keywords>
    module
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="plcs.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="robbodington"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of reference data.</p>
  <p>Terms, definitions, and abbreviations</p>
  <p></p>
  <p>The following terms, definitions and abbreviations will aid in the understanding of reference data.  These were primarily taken or adapted from ISO 10303-1:1994 or from other parts of ISO 15926.</p>
  <note>Definitions copied verbatim from other ISO standards are followed by "[ISO xxxxx-y]". An explanatory note follows definitions that have been adapted from other standards.
  </note>
  <ul>
<li>class - A subdivision, sort or category with rules that defines inclusion and or exclusion.  [ISO 15926-2]</li>

<li>commodity class - a class of manufactured item that conforms to agreed open standards</li>

<li>core class - a class that is a commonly used subdivision corresponding to terms used in common language</li>

<li>data - a representation of information in a formal manner suitable for communication, interpretation, or processing by human beings or computers.  [ISO 10303-1]</li>

<li>defacto class - a class corresponding to common natures that are widely recognized but not formally defined or agreed.</li>

<li>information - facts, concepts, or instructions. [ISO 10303-1]</li>

<li>instance - data that represents, in computer processable form, some real world thing.</li>  
<note>This is a different definition of this term from that found in ISO 10303-11.</note>
<li>manufactured item class - a class whose members are manufactured items.</li>

<li>proprietary class - a manufactured item class where the copyright to specifications of conditions for membership is controlled in a proprietary or closed way.</li>

<li>reference data - data, in the form of application object instances, that represents reference information.</li>

<li>reference data library - a managed collection of reference data.</li> 
<li>reference information - information about a 'thing' or type of 'thing' which is of common interest to many process industries facilities and users.</li>
<li>standards class - a class where the conditions for membership are owned/controlled by a standardization body.</li>
</ul>
  <p>
  </p>
  <p>What is Ref Data?</p>
  <p>
  </p>
  <p>Reference data is computer interpretable data to be shared between participants.  It is used primarily to extend and to tailor the data model to suit different groups of users.</p>
  <p></p>
  <p>Within the EXPRESS data modeling language, reference data occurs whenever a type or class is declared.  The reference data includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>The name, identifier and definition of the class or type.</li>
<li>The recognized set of class members, that is, the allowed values for a type.</li>

</ul> 
 <p>Within software applications Reference Data typically appears as selection options on a "pop-up" menu.  Applications using different reference data will not interoperate unless the two sets of reference data have been harmonized or mapped.</p>
  <p>Many current standards could be viewed as sources of reference data.</p>
  <p>Reference data may include data representing: </p>
<ul>
<li>classes; </li>
<li>relations and classes of relations between classes and or individuals.</li>
</ul>
  <p></p>
  <p>Class data are commonly used abstractions that can describe:</p>
 <ul> 
<li>the physical nature of manufactured equipment and materials;</li>
<example number="1">The class known as '1/2inch UNC threaded screw' can be included in the reference data as a class of part.
</example>

<li>the nature of the environment;</li>
<example number="2">The class known as 'hazardous' can be included in the reference data as a status class of state.
</example>

<li>functional natures of equipment and materials; </li>
<example number="3">The class known as 'thrust bearing' can be included in the reference data as a class of part.
</example>
<example number="4">The class known as 'orifice plate' can be included in the reference data as a class of part.
</example>

<li>features of equipment and material;</li>
<example number="5">The concept known as 'R24 groove' can be included in the reference data as a class of feature.
</example>

<li>spatial dimensions of equipment and material;</li>
<example number="6">The concept known as 'diameter' can be included in the reference data as a dimension of shape class.
</example>


<li>physical properties of equipment, materials;</li>
<example number="7">The concept of 'viscosity' can be included in the reference data as a class of property.
</example>
<example number="8">A particular magnitude of viscosity can be included in the reference data as a property.
</example>

<li>measurement units for physical properties;</li>
<example number="9">The unit of measure known as the 'SI metre' can be included in the reference data as a class of class of property quantification.
</example>

<li>process materials;</li> 
<example number="10">The material known as 'natural gasoline' can be included in the reference data as a class of compound.
</example>

<li>materials of construction of facilities and facility equipment;</li>
<example number="11">The material known as 'glass reinforced plastic' can be included in the reference data as a class of composite material.
</example>

<li>activities and events associated with the use of equipment and materials;</li>
<example number="12">The events known as 'start' and 'failure' can be included in the reference data as class of event.
</example>
<example number="13">The process known as 'maintenance replacement of the gear box' can be included in the reference data as a class of activity.
</example>

<li>states and statuses associated with the use of equipment and materials;</li>
<example number="14">The material phase known as 'liquid' can be included in the reference data as a phase class.
</example>
<example number="15">The state of being known as 'painted' can be included as a status class.
</example>
<example number="16">The state of being known as 'in maintenance' can be included as a status class.
</example>

<li>information;</li>
<example number="17">A representation of information known as 'UK Health and Safety Regulations' can be included in the reference data as a class of information representation.
</example>

<li>document annotations and symbols;</li>
<example number="18">The annotation type known as 'English writing' can be included in the reference data as a class of class of information representation.
</example>

<li>people, companies and organizations.</li>
<example number="19">The type of organization known as 'standards body' can be included in the reference data as a class of organization.
</example>
</ul>

<p>Reference data also includes representation of valid relationships between objects represented by the reference data wherever appropriate.</p>
<example number="20">If the reference data includes data for the classes 'thrust bearing' and 'bearing', a specialization relation shall be defined between bearing and thrust bearing, stating all members of the thrust bearing class are also members of the bearing class.
</example>
<example number="21">If the reference data contains a class 'R24 Orifice plate' and the class 'R24 Groove' a composition class of relation will be defined between the orifice plate class and groove class stating that the orifice plate members have parts that are members of the R24 Groove class.
</example>

<p>Reference data may be standardized at any level, for example, for one application, a project, a company, inter-company, trade group, national, and international.</p>

  <p>Reference data can be published:</p>
  <ul>  
<li>As a data set shared between two or more groups of users,</li>
<li>Within an Application Protocol, with either informative (optional) or normative (must be used to achieve compliance) </li>
<li>In a Reference Data Library</li>
</ul>
<p></p>
<p>Reference Data Modules</p>
  <p></p>
  <p>Six modules provide a reference data capability.  These are: class, classification, attribute_classification, external_class, PLIB_class_reference, and set_theory.</p>
  <p>These modules will enable any entity, to be declared as a target for reference data, that is, as subject to classification.</p>
  <p>When implementing an application that uses such an entity it will be necessary to define the classes, the reference data, to be used in that application.</p>
  <p>Applications that wish to exchange data and to interoperate must use the same reference data, or two sets of reference data related by mapping corresponding.</p>
  <p>The agreement to use common reference data may involve any number of parties, for example:</p>
<ul>
  <li>the users of two applications</li>
  <li>all participants in a project or an organization with many applications</li>
  <li>a defined industrial community, such as those involved in a particular supply chain (e.g. ATA, POSC Caesar, Exostar users)</li>
  <li>by an international standards body</li>
</ul>

<p></p>
  <p>Why use Ref Data?</p>
  <p></p>
  <p>Reference data provides a capability to tailor and extend a standardized data model in a controlled manner, as required by evident industrial need.</p>
  <p>STEP has its origins in product geometry.  This domain was sufficiently stable and well bounded to offer a reasonable prospect of achieving international acceptance of a single data model for the domain in a single pass.</p>
  <p>As STEP has broadened its scope to include less prescriptive domains - configuration management, product data management, life-cycle management, product support - the requirement has arisen for a degree of flexibility to provide:</p>
  <ul>
  <li>A capability to address an extensible, open sets of class members, allowing progressive extension of the standard by adding or specializing classes, for example, types of equipment, types of document, type of activity, and fault codes.</li>
  <li>Tailoring of a standardized data model to suit local business needs and terminology, for example, not every business recognizes the same types of document.</li>
  <li>Computer sensible access to data already standardized by others for example, definitions of properties.</li>
</ul>

  <p></p>
  <p>The use of a Reference Data Library offers great flexibility in extending the standard to suit individual project, business, or organization needs.</p>
  <p></p>



</purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   
   <li>the existence of a class or set; </li>
   <li>the distinction between a class or set that is defined by abstract criteria, and a class or set that is defined by enumerating its members; </li>
   <li>a classification relationship between a class and a member of that class; </li>
   <li>the association of a value, represented by a class, to an attribute on an entity;</li>
   <note>the entities are defined by other modules that extend this module.   </note>
   
   <li>the identification of a class that is external to a data exchange file; </li>
   <li>the identification of an external class library that is not in an exchange file and holds the definition for classes used in the exchange file; </li>
   <li>a reference to a class in an external class library; </li>
   <li>the identification of a class in a library compliant to ISO 13584 (Parts Library); </li>
   <li>set theory relationships; </li>
<ul>
   <li>complement; </li>
   <li>intersection;</li>
   <li>power set;</li>
   <li>proper set;</li>
   <li>equivalence or same membership (i.e. equality)</li>
   <li>subset</li>
   <li>union.</li></ul>



</inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>

   <li>classification and the specification of complete set membership; </li>
   <li>mappings between sets or classes; </li>
   <li>a complete enumeration of the members for a class or set; </li>
   <li>the definition of a class; </li>
   <li>the definition of an external class library; </li>
   <li>the definition of a set or class; </li>
   <note>Definition of a set or class is within the scope of the Class application module. </note>
   <li>classification and the specification of complete set membership.</li>

</outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
   <!-- Units of functionality -->
   <uof name="-">
     <description>
     </description>
     <uof.ae entity="-"/>
   </uof>

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
