<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE application_protocol SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/application_protocol.dtd">
<!--
     $Id: application_protocol.xml,v 1.5 2003/02/08 21:35:57 goset1 Exp $
-->
<application_protocol 
name="configuration_control_3d_design_ed2" 
title="Configuration controlled 3D designs of mechanical parts and assemblies"
part="203" 
wg.number="1195" 
wg.number.supersedes="914" 
wg.number.arm="" 
wg.number.mim="" 
version="1" 
status="CD-TS" 
language="E" 
publication.year="2003" 
published="n" 
  previous.revision.number="ISO 10303-203:1994 Amendment 1"
	previous.revision.year="2000"
  previous.revision.cancelled="NO"
  revision.complete="YES"
checklist.internal_review="1199" 
checklist.project_leader="1200" 
checklist.convener="1201" 
rcs.date="$Date: 2003/02/08 21:35:57 $" 
rcs.revision="$Revision:1.5$">
<purpose>
   <p>
The Configuration controlled design 3D design of mechanical parts and assemblies application protocol (AP) supports the requirement to represent occurrences or instances of parts in assemblies and in assemblies of assemblies.  
<note>It is an AP created entirely from modules and is referred to as a modular AP. 
</note>
This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol for the use of product data within a defined context which satisfies an industrial need to exchange configuration-controlled 3D product design data of mechanical parts and assemblies.  
In order to specify the composition of products, organizations use many computer-based application systems.  
Integral to the definition of a product are the specification of its shape, the specification of its configurations and the applicability of its possibly multiple definitions to a particular configuration.  
This data may reside on one or more application systems within an organization.  
The integration of the data that defines the shape of a product with the data concerning its configuration is essential to an organization's ability to define its products without relying on redundant data in disparate application systems.  
In order for the definition of the design of products to be communicated, an organization must be able to share its product data with partners, vendors, and customers.
   </p>
	 <p>The activities addressed in this application protocol are described in annex E.
	 They include:
	 </p>
   <ul>
	<li>identification of a product to an organization's customers and of the components which comprise the product; </li>
  <li>description of the shape of the components of a product;</li>
  <li>documentation of formal change and release of designs for the product;</li>
  <li>tracking of the history of the product as it goes through the formal initiation, change and release process;</li>
  <li>identification of qualified suppliers for the product or the design of the product.</li>
 </ul>
 </purpose>

  <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap203ed2.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="ap203ed2.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <normrefs>
   <normref.inc normref="ref10303-1227"/>
 </normrefs>
<definition>
 <term>design phase</term>
 <def>the period during which the engineering representation of a product is dynamic.</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 <term>mechanical part</term>
 <def>a physical object which can be foremd from material into a static shape.</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 <term>solid model</term>
 <def>a complete 3D representation of the nominal shape of a product so that any point in space can be determined to be inside, on the boundary, or outside the solid model.</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 <term>sub assembly</term>
 <def>a constituent that is an assembly.</def>
  
 </definition>
 
	<fundamentals/>
<aam>
		<idef0>
			<imgfile file="aamidef01.xml"/>
				<imgfile file="aamidef02.xml"/>
		</idef0>	
	</aam>
	<imp_meths>
	<imp_meth general="y" part="21">
			<description>

			</description>
	</imp_meth>
		<imp_meth part="28">
			<description>

			</description>
		</imp_meth>
	</imp_meths>
	
</application_protocol>
