<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE application_protocol SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/application_protocol.dtd">
<!--
     $Id: application_protocol.xml,v 1.9 2003/05/28 16:01:37 darla Exp $
-->
<application_protocol 
name="configuration_control_3d_design_ed2"
module_name="configuration_control_3d_design_ed2" 
title="Configuration controlled 3D design of mechanical parts and assemblies"
part="203" 
wg.number="1195" 
wg.number.supersedes="914" 

version="1" 
status="CD-TS" 
language="E" 
publication.year="2003" 
published="n"
previous.revision.number="ISO 10303-203:1994 Amendment 1"
	previous.revision.year="2000"
  previous.revision.cancelled="NO"
  revision.complete="YES"
checklist.internal_review="1199" 
checklist.project_leader="1200" 
checklist.convener="1201"
purpose="the exchange of configuration-controlled 3D designs of mechanical parts and assemblies."
rcs.date="$Date: 2003/05/28 16:01:37 $" 
rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.9 $"> 
<keywords>
    Application protocol,3D design, assemblies, configuration control 
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the application protocol. -->
 <abstract>
    <li>additional text for abstract</li>
 </abstract>

<!-- A new edition of an AP so document the changes -->
 <changes>
  <!-- The summary of the changes -->
  <change_summary>
   <p> This part was updated to use  EXPRESS Edition 2, harmonized with 214, and extended to provide additional PDM capabilities.  A brief summary of the modifications follows:
</p>

  </change_summary>
  <!-- The details of the changes -->
  <change_detail>
 <ul>
<li>Incorporated geometric dimensioning and tolerances</li>
<li>Added geometric presentation structures that includes colours, layers and groups</li>
<li>Enhanced document management structures</li>
<li>Additional work management capabilities</li>
<li>Added geometric validation properties</li>
<li>Included constructive solid geometry structures</li>
<li>Incorporated 3D associative text</li>
<li>Normatively reference all of the current second edition and technical corrigendum parts of ISO 10303</li>
</ul>
<p>
Details of the modifications are given in Annex L.   
 </p>
   </change_detail>
 </changes>

 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap203ed2.projlead"/>
		<editor ref="ap203ed2.editor"/>
	</contacts>	
<purpose>

   <p>
The Configuration controlled design 3D design of mechanical parts and assemblies application protocol (AP) supports the requirement to represent occurrences or instances of parts in assemblies and in assemblies of assemblies.
</p>  
<note>It is an AP created entirely from modules and is referred to as a modular AP. 
</note>
<p>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol for the use of product data within a defined context which satisfies an industrial need to exchange configuration-controlled 3D product design data of mechanical parts and assemblies.  
In order to specify the composition of products, organizations use many computer-based application systems.  
Integral to the definition of a product are the specification of its shape, the specification of its configurations and the applicability of its possibly multiple definitions to a particular configuration.  
This data may reside on one or more application systems within an organization.  
The integration of the data that defines the shape of a product with the data concerning its configuration is essential to an organization's ability to define its products without relying on redundant data in disparate application systems.  
In order for the definition of the design of products to be communicated, an organization must be able to share its product data with partners, vendors, and customers.
   </p>
	 <p>The activities addressed in this application protocol are described in annex E.
	 They include:
	 </p>
   <ul>
	<li>identification of a product to an organization's customers and of the components which comprise the product; </li>
  <li>description of the shape of the components of a product;</li>
  <li>documentation of formal change and release of designs for the product;</li>
  <li>tracking of the history of the product as it goes through the formal initiation, change and release process;</li>
  <li>identification of qualified suppliers for the product or the design of the product.</li>
 </ul>
 </purpose>
<inscope context="configuration controlled 3D design" from_module="YES"></inscope>
  <outscope from_module="YES"></outscope>
 <normrefs>
   <normref.inc normref="ref10303-1227"/>
 </normrefs>
<definition>
 <term>design phase</term>
 <def>the period during which the engineering representation of a product is dynamic.</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 <term>mechanical part</term>
 <def>a physical object which can be formed from material into a static shape.</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 <term>solid model</term>
 <def>a complete 3D representation of the nominal shape of a product so that any point in space can be determined to be inside, on the boundary, or outside the solid model.</def>
 </definition>
 <definition>
 <term>sub assembly</term>
 <def>a constituent that is an assembly.</def>
  
 </definition>
 <inforeqt>
	<fundamentals><description><p>This clause specifies the information requirements for the exchange of configuration-controlled 3D designs of mechanical parts and assemblies.   The management of the configuration of products is  addressed in this application protocol, and is concerned with authorizations and the associated approvals given by persons in organizations.  The structured list of materials or components needed to make a product can be exchanged, along with initial part design requirements as well as requirements for revised part versions.  It provides the directive for work to proceed on these initial or modified part versions.  
</p><p>
This part provides information about the planned usage of components in a product model, and also includes data about the different products that are sold by an organization to its customers enabling an organization to control the configuration of these products.  It contains the structure through which a part, unique versions of a part, and different design discipline views of a part can be defined. Information about an organization that is qualified to product a particular part in included.  Various documents and references associated with a product can be exchanged using this part. 
</p><p>
The different shape representations for products that are provided include solid modeling:  advanced boundary representation, faceted boundary representation, and constructive solid geometry.  Also, surface and wire frame representations with and without topological structures are included.   The validation of solid or surface exchanges can be facilitated using properties such as center of gravity and wetted area.  Associative three-dimensional text along with dimensional and geometric tolerances provide additional capabilities for product exchanges. 
</p>
</description>
</fundamentals>
<reqtover module="date_time"><description>The information requirements are specified as the Application Reference Model (ARM) of this application module. 
</description></reqtover>
<reqtover module="date_time_assignment"><description>The information requirements are specified as the Application Reference Model (ARM) of this application module. 
</description></reqtover>


</inforeqt>	
<aam>
		<idef0>
			<imgfile file="aamidef01.xml"/>
				<imgfile file="aamidef02.xml"/>
		</idef0>	
	</aam>
	
	<imp_meths>
		<imp_meth general="y" part="21">
			<description>
				<p>For various reasons, some entities may not be completely exported into an exchange structure. 
	There may be mandatory information in the AIM that has no correspondence in the ARM. 
	Sometimes an application may not maintain all the information that is anticipated for the data exchange. 
	Other times, the information may be maintained by a sending system but not included in the data exchange. 
	Nevertheless, the preprocessor must provide values for all mandatory attributes in an exchange file. 
</p>
<p>	When no data is provided by a sending system for a string value, the preprocessor shall use '/NULL' or the empty string ''. 
</p>	
To further indicate the reason why no data is provided, the following convention shall be used:
<ul>
<li>Empty string '' indicates user data managed by the sending system but not provided for data exchange; 
</li>
<li>String '/NULL' indicates user data in a mandatory attribute that is not managed by the sending system or currently not known or a mandatory AIM information that has no correspondence in the ARM; 
</li>
<li>$ is used in the physical file, if an optional attribute is not instantiated. 
</li>
</ul>
			</description>
		</imp_meth>
		
		<imp_meth part="21">
			<description>
				<p>An exchange structure shall be encoded in a file conforming to the
syntax and EXPRESS language mapping defined in ISO 10303-21 and to the AIM schema 
defined in annex A of this part of ISO 10303.
</p>
<p>
The FILE_SCHEMA element of the header shall specify the name of the Express schema used and include its object information identifier (see annex D).
</p>
<example>
The instance below identifies the configuration_control_3d_design AIM extended schema:
</example>
				<screen>
FILE_SCHEMA (('CONFIG_CONTROL_DESIGN { 1 0 10303 203 2 1 1} '))
</screen>
				<p>
	The exchange structure shall not make use of the SCOPE construct (see clause 10.3 of ISO 10303-21).
</p>
			</description>
		</imp_meth>
		
		<imp_meth part="28">
			<description>
				<p>An exchange structure shall be encoded in a file conforming to the
syntax and an EXPRESS language mapping defined in ISO 10303-28 and to the AIM schema 
defined in annex A of this part of ISO 10303.
</p>
<p>The Object Serialization Early Binding (OSEB), defined in ISO 10303-28, shall be used for the Express language mapping.</p>
			</description>
		</imp_meth>
	</imp_meths>
	
</application_protocol>
