<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.14 2009/11/01 21:39:06 lothartklein Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="mathematical_representation"
   name.french="Descriptions mathématiques"
   part="51"
   version="1"
   wg.number="3250" 
   wg.number.supersedes="1000"
   wg.number.express="3251"
   wg.number.express.supersedes="1001"
   checklist.internal_review="3253"
   checklist.project_leader="3254"
   checklist.convener="3255"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2005"
   publication.date="2005-xx-xx"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2009/11/01 21:39:06 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.14 $ ">

 <keywords>
     mathematics, value, space, function, identification, description, module, resource
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope  -->
<abstract><p>ISO 10303-51 constrains the use of the concepts of mathematical value that are defined by ISO 10303-50. The uses are specified as follows:</p>
  <ul>
<li>that a real or integer number identifies a physical quantity instance, or a product, activity or state;</li>
<li>that a mathematical space is the range of an an identification function for a physical quantity space, or a set of products, activities or states;</li>
<li>that   mathematical function describes a property variation over a continuous or discrete domain.</li></ul>
</abstract>
<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope 
 <abstract>
 <li>a specification that a real or integer number is an
 identifier for a physical quantity instance, or for a product, 
 activity or state;</li>
 <li>a specification that a mathematical space is the range of 
 a scale for a physical quantity space, or is the range of an 
 identification function for a set of products, activities or 
 states;</li>
 <li>a specification that a mathematical function is a 
 description of a property variation over a continuous or 
 discrete domain.</li>
 </abstract>
-->
 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>

   <projlead ref="ap221.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="ap221.projeditor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application resource for the
     representation of of mathematical values, spaces and functions to describe or identify products, states and activities. 
sche   </p>
<p>A mathematical value can identify a product, product feature, state or activity.
</p><example number="1">
The temperature sensor at position P in my_test_rig is identified by the integer value 27. </example>

A mathematical value can describe a physical quantity value.
<example number="2">
The temperature, which is possessed by my_test_rig at position P in state S, is described by the real value 45.3 with respect to the Celsius scale.
</example>
A mathematical space can provide an identification scheme, or parameterisation, for a set or space of products, product features, states or activities.
<example number="3">
The members of the set of temperature sensors in my_test_rig are identified by integers in the interval [1, 200].
</example>
A mathematical space can provide an identification scheme, or parameterisation, for a physical quantity space.
<example number="4">
The values within the temperature physical quantity space are described or identified by reals in the set greater than -273.17.
</example>
A mathematical function can describe a variation of property with respect to position within a set of products, product features, states or activities.
<example number="5">
The variation of temperature with respect to the sensors within my_test_rig in state S is described by a discrete function from the integer interval [1, 200] to the set of reals greater than -273.17. This function is understood with respect to a particular parameterisation of the temperature sensors and with respect to the Celsius scale.
</example>
The relationships of the schemas in this part of ISO 10303 to other schemas that define the integrated resources of this International Standard are illustrated in Figure 1 and Figure 2 using the EXPRESS-G notation. EXPRESS-G is defined in annex D of ISO 10303-11. Figure 1 shows references to schemas containing entities that are described. Figure 2 shows references to schemas containing entities that define the nature of the description.
<!--
<figure number="1"><title>Schema relationships for entities that are described</title><img src="schemas_1.gif"/></figure>
 
<figure number="2">
	<title>Schema relationships for entities making the description
  </title>
<img src="schemas_2.gif"/>
</figure>
-->
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="The relationship of the schemas of this part to the ISO 10303 integration architecture (1 of 1)"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
  <li><p>the use of a mathematical values to identify or describe a product, feature, state, activity or property;</p></li>
  <li><p>the use of a mathematical space as an identification scheme for a set or space of products, features, states, activities, or properties;</p></li>
  <li><p>the use of a mathematical function to describe a property variation within a set or space of products, features, states or activities;</p></li>
  <li>the identification scheme or parameterisation for a set of points within the body of a product;
<example number="1"><p>
The set of points within a widget of type XYZ is parameterised by the unit cube within real triple space that has corners (0, 0, 0), (1, 0, 0), (0, 1, 0), (1, 1, 0), (0, 0, 1), (1, 0, 1), (0, 1, 1), (1, 1, 1).</p>
<p>A widget of type XYZ has a simple shape which makes this mapping possible. A more complex widget could be divided into parts, such that each part can map on to a unit cube or some other simple mathematical space.</p>
</example>
</li>
<li><p>
  the identification scheme or parameterisation for a set of features within the body of a product;</p>
  <example number="2"><p>The volume of geometric space within 'my duct' is a product which is has air flowing through it. There is a set of planes within this volume, such that each is approximately normal to the direction of flow. Each of these planes can be regarded as a feature of the volume.</p> 
<p>There are properties for each of the planes in the volume, such as average pressure, average velocity and average temperature. Hence there is a variation of average pressure (say) with respect to the set of planes.
</p></example>
</li>
<li><p>the identification scheme or parameterisation for states within a state space or within an activity;</p>

<example number="3">The set of states within the start up sequence for a 'my duct' is parameterised by the unit real interval [0.0, 1.0].
</example>
</li> 
<li><p>the identification scheme or parameterisation for a set of features within the body of a product, or for a set of states within a state space or activity;</p>
<example number="4"><p>
  A parameterisation of a one dimensional set of planes within a duct is defined by example 2. A parameterisation of a one dimensional set of states during a start up sequence is defined by example 3.</p> 
<p>There is a two dimensional set of states for planes within the duct during the start up sequence. This two dimensional space is parameterised by the unit square with corners (0.0, 0.0), (1.0, 0.0), (1.0, 1.0), (0.0, 1.0).
</p>
</example></li>
<li><p>the identification or description of values within a physical quantity space, with respect to a unit or measure, coordinate system and encoding method;</p>
<example number="5"><p>The Kelvin scale is an identification or description of each temperature value by a real value.</p>
<p>The temperature value that is the triple point of water is identified or described by the real value 273.16, with respect to the Kelvin scale.
</p></example>

</li>
<li><p>the description of a property distribution by a mathematical function;</p>
<note number="1"><p>The description of a property distribution relies upon:</p>
<ul><li>a parameterisation of the product, activity or both, that identifies each position within the product and each state within the activity by a value within a mathematical space; and</li>
<li>a scale for the physical quantity space, that describes each physical quantity value by a value within a mathematical space, with respect to a unit of measure, coordinate system and encoding method.
</li></ul></note>
<p></p>
</li>
<li><p>the description of the relationship between two parameterisations by a mathematical function;</p>

<example number="6"> The top surface of part XYZ_123 is parameterised by the unit square with corners (0,0), (1,0), (0,1) and 1,1). This parameterisation is used for a B-spline description of the surface shape.

The top surface of part XYZ_123 is also parameterised by 'my finite element mesh'. This parameterisation is used to describe the variation of pressure over the surface.

There is a mathematical function over the finite element mesh that gives the point in the unit square corresponding to each point in the mesh.</example>
</li>
<li><p>the description of the relationship between two scales by a mathematical function.</p>
  <example number="7"><p>Celsius and Fahrenheit are two different temperature scales. The two scales are related by the mathematical function that is:</p>
<p align="center">f(x): 100/180(x-32)</p></example>
</li>
</inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
<li><p>the definition of the domain and range of a property distribution;</p>
<note number="2">The definition of the domain and range for a property distribution specify what it is.
This part of ISO 10303 is solely concerned with its numeric representation.</note>
</li>

<li><p>the definition of a mathematical function.</p></li>
 </outscope>

 <normrefs>
      <normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
      <normref.inc normref="ref10303-42"/>
      <normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
      <normref.inc normref="ref10303-50.2000"/>
      <normref.inc normref="ref13584-20.1998"/>
 </normrefs>
 <definition>
   <term>physical quantity value</term>
<synonym>property value</synonym>
<synonym>independent property definition</synonym>
<def>
  magnitude of an aspect of a physical thing that can be observed or measured, or deduced from observations or measurements
<note>
A physical quantity value is a class that a physical thing is can be a member of. Whether or not a physical thing is a member of the class is determined by the observation or measurement.
</note>
</def> </definition>
<definition>
  <term>physical quantity space</term>
<synonym>property space</synonym>
<synonym>property type</synonym>
<def>
  set of values or magnitudes for a physical phenomenon

<note> A physical quantity space is a class that a physical quantity value can be a member of. Whether or not a physical quantity value is a member of the class is determined by the nature of the physical phenomenon that is observed or measured.
</note>
</def>
</definition>
<definition>
  <term>property</term>
<synonym>characteristic</synonym>
<def>
  function from a set of physical objects to a physical quantity space

<note> A property distribution is a mapping from a particular set of physical objects, which can be distributed with respect to space, time or both.
</note>

</def>
</definition>


 <abbreviations>
<abbreviation>
<acronym>D</acronym>
<term>Dimension (as in 1D, 2D, 3D)</term>
</abbreviation>
<abbreviation>
  <acronym>FEA</acronym>
<term>Finite Element Analysis</term>
</abbreviation>
 </abbreviations>
<schema name="mathematical_context_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
<p>The <b>mathematical_context_schema</b> specifies a mapping between a physical set or space and a mathematical space.
</p>
<p>
The physical set can be:</p>
<ul>
<li>a family of products;</li>

<li>positions within a product;</li>

<li>states within an activity or state space;</li>

<li>physical quantity values within a physical quantity space.</li>
</ul>

The mapping defines an identification scheme for members of the physical set. A member of the physical set is identified by a mathematical value within the mathematical space.

<example number="1">The set cross sections along beam 'XB_1234' are identified by the set real values in the range [-1.0, +1.0].
</example>
<example number="2">The set of states during the activity that is 'normal start up of engine type XYZ_123' are identified by the set of real values in the range [0.0, 1.0].
</example>
<example number="3">The set of temperatures are identified by the set of real values greater that -273.15
</example>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
     A mapping between a physical set and a mathematical space is called a parameterisation if the physical set is:
<ul>
<li>a family of products;</li>

<li>positions within a product; or</li>

<li>states within an activity or state space.</li>
</ul>
<p>
A parameterisation can be given a name. There are two ways of providing more information about a parameterisation, as follows:
</p>
<p>
the mathematical value can be specified for each member of the physical set (provided the physical set is finite); or
</p>
<p>
a property distribution can be described with respect to the parameterisation, as described in the mathematical description of distribution schema.
</p>
<example number="1">A parameterisation is defined for the set of cross sections within beam 'XB_1234'. A description of the positions of the cross-sections within the beam for its initial undeformed state provides information about the nature of the parameterisation.
</example>

<example number="2">A parameterisation is defined for the set of states within the activity that is 'normal start up of engine type XYZ_123'. A description of the times of the states within the start up activity provides information about the nature of the parameterisation.
</example>
<p>A mapping between a physical quantity space and a mathematical space is called a scale. A scale can be:</p>
<ul>
<li>a standard scale defined by ISO or some other standardisation body, i.e by a unit of measure; or</li>

<li>defined with respect to another scale by a transformation, such as a 3D coordinate transformation.</li>
</ul>
<note>This part of ISO 10303 references ISO 10303-43 'Integrated generic resources: Representation structures' for entities that define a scale.
</note>
<example number="3"><p>The International Practical Temperature Scale 1968 (IPTS-68) is a mapping between the space of temperatures and the set of real numbers greater than -273.15.</p>
<p>
The fixed points within the scale are degrees of hotness that are identified by particular physical phenomena, such as the freezing point of gold. For each fixed point, a real value is assigned.
</p>
</example>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mathematical_context_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="mathematical_context_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="mathematical_description_of_distribution_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction><p>The <b>mathematical_description_of_distribution_schema</b> specifies a mapping between a property distribution and a mathematical function. The mapping gives semantics to the mathematical function, so that the mathematical function describes or identifies the property distribution.
</p>
<p>A property distribution can be with respect to:
</p>
<ul>
<li>product within a family of products;</li>

<li>position within a product;</li>

<li>state within an activity or state space;</li>

<li>another property; or</li>

<li>a combination (Cartesian product) of these.</li>
</ul>
<example number="1"><p>The variation of power output with respect to:</p>
<ul>
<li>outlet port diameter for an engine in family 'XYZ_1'; and</li>

<li>engine speed in Hertz;</li>
</ul><p>is a property distribution.</p>
</example>
<example number="2"><p>The variation of temperature with respect to:</p>
<ul>
<li>position within the product that is the compressor disc of engine type 'XYZ_123'; and</li>

<li>state within the activity that is 'normal start up of engine type XYZ_123',</li>
</ul>
<p>is a property distribution.</p>
</example>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
     A property distribution is a physical function. The domain of a property distribution function can be:
<ul>
<li>a set of products;</li>

<li>a set of positions within a product;</li>

<li>a set of states within an activity or state space.</li>
</ul>
The range of a property distribution function is a physical quantity space.
<p>
A property distribution D:X->P, where:</p>
<ul>
<li>X is the domain set; and</li>

<li>P is the range physical quantity space,</li>
</ul>
can be described or identified by a mathematical function F:A->B, where

A and B are mathematical spaces;

<p>The description or identification depends upon:
</p>
<ul>
<li>a one to one mapping U:X->A; and</li>

<li>a one to one mapping V:P->B.</li>
</ul>

The property distribution D is described or identified by the mathematical function F, if and only if:

V(D(x)) = F(U(x)), for all x in X.


   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mathematical_description_of_distribution_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="mathematical_description_of_distribution_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="mathematical_description_of_distribution_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
<!--
     <imgfile file="test.xml"/>
-->
   </express-g>
</schema>


 <shortnames>
   <shortname entity="compound_maths_space_context" name="CMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="defined_maths_space_context" name="DMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="explicitly_enumerated_maths_space_context" name="EEMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="maths_space_context" name="MTSPCN"/>
   <shortname entity="maths_value_context" name="MTVLCN"/>
   <shortname entity="membership_of_maths_space_context" name="MOMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="normalized_maths_space_context" name="NMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="representation_context_defined_maths_space_context" name="RCDMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="unit_defined_maths_space_context" name="UDMSC"/>
   <shortname entity="maths_space_context_relationship" name="MSCR"/>
   <shortname entity="maths_space_context_relationship_description" name="MSCRD"/>
   <shortname entity="normalized_property_distribution_description" name="NPDD"/>
   <shortname entity="property_distribution_description" name="PRDSDS"/>
  
  </shortnames>
<!--  
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

<bibliography/> -->
</resource>

