<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.32 2014/02/18 16:20:56 darla Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="numerical_analysis"
   part="53"
   version="1"
   wg.number="6803"
   wg.number.supersedes="2170"
   wg.number.express="6003"
   checklist.internal_review="6004"
   checklist.project_leader="6005"
   checklist.convener="6006"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2011"
   publication.date="2011-10-15" 
   published="y"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2014/02/18 16:20:56 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.32 $">

 <keywords>
    resource, numerical analysis, idealisation
 </keywords>



 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="wg12convener"/>
   <editor ref="ap203ed2.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
  
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an integated resource for the
     representation of analysis problems and the solutions of such problems.
   
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
   <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="The relationship of the schemas of this part to the ISO 10303 integration architecture (1 of 1)"/>
   
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>application-independent analysis;</li>
    <li>idealisations of product definitions evinced by analyses.</li>
   
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>analysis applications.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 <term.ref linkend="term_integrated_resource"/>
    <normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.2004">
<term.ref linkend="term_application_protocol"/> <!-- application protocol -->
<term.ref linkend="term_generic_resource"/> <!-- generic resource -->
 <!-- integrated resource -->
       </normref.inc>
  <normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
   <normref.inc normref="ref10303-52"/>
      
 </normrefs>
 
<definition>
    <term>idealisation</term>
    <def>representation of one thing by another thing that in a particular context is both 
    simpler than, and an approximation to, the first thing. 
	<example number="1">In the context of a numerical calculation, the numbers 3, 22/7, 355/113, and 
	3.14159265 are all idealisations of the mathematical constant pi, in increasing order of
	 reality.  
	</example> 
	<example number="2">In the context of a finite element analysis, a mesh of elements is an idealisation 
	of the shape of the thing being analysed. </example> 
	</def>
	</definition>
<abbreviations><abbreviation.inc linkend="FEA"/></abbreviations>

<schema name="analysis_product_relationships_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   This schema specifies relationships between the definitions of objects and analyses.
  </introduction>
  
  <fund_cons>The analysis_product_relationships_schema associates the concepts in the product_analysis_schema and analysis_schema with the product structure core specified in ISO 10303-41 providing a specification of the idealisation and analysis of the product.

</fund_cons>
  <!-- <fund_cons/> -->

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <!-- imgfile file="analysis_product_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/-->
          <imgfile file="analysis_product_relationships_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="product_analysis_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   This schema defines and describes the structures for describing a view of the objects (products, activities and states) that may be the subject of an analysis.
   </introduction>
<fund_cons>
The product_analysis_schema has two key concepts:
<ol>
<li>temporal spatial domain:  This is a definition of the real world object that is analysed.  The properties of this object are a specification of the analysis.</li>

<li>analysis model:  This is a model of the real world object that is analytically tractable.</li>
</ol>
A single temporal spatial domain may have many analysis models defined for it.
<p><b>Temporal spatial domain</b></p>
The subject of an engineering analysis is a temporal spatial domain that is defined by a set of properties.  An analysis model of a temporal spatial domain is derived from these properties.

<note number="1">The set of properties that define a temporal spatial domain may include shape.</note>

Hence a temporal spatial domain is a class.  A particular physical individual is a member of the class if it possesses the defining properties.  An analysis model of a temporal spatial domain is assumed to be valid for each member of the class.

<note number="2">The properties that define a temporal spatial domain may be obtained by measurements made on a particular physical individual, and may include features such as cracks.  Nonetheless, if another physical individual were found with identical properties, the same analysis model would be equally applicable to it.</note>

Because a temporal spatial domain is a class, some properties may have statistical measures, such as mean, variance, and range.
<p><b>Physical domain</b></p>
A physical domain is a representation of a temporal spatial domain with assumptions about the nature of the temporal spatial domain that allow analysis.




</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <!-- imgfile file="product_analysis_schemaexpg1.xml"/-->
         <imgfile file="product_analysis_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="analysis_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   This schema defines and describes the structures for describing analyses.
   </introduction>
<fund_cons> 
An analysis model may assume that the temporal spatial domain is a continuum, and may also assume an analytically convenient dimension for that continuum.

<note>If an analysis model is a continuum, then there is a 'membership' concept which is interpreted as a place within the continuum.  A field is a function from the continuum to a property space.  For example a temperature field is a function from the continuum to the property space 'temperature'.	</note>
There is also a membership concept for a temporal spatial domain.  In this case, the members are the physical individuals that have the properties assigned to the temporal spatial domain.

<example number="1"><p>
The temporal spatial domain may be a beam during a loading process.  Different analysis models may be created as follows:</p>
	<ul>
 	<li>an analysis model that assumes the beam at each instant to be a 3D continuum of points occupied by matter;</li>
 	<li>an analysis model that assumes the unloaded beam to be a 1D continuum of plane surfaces occupied by matter, and the loaded beam to be a 1D continuum of surfaces occupied by matter which are not necessarily plane;</li>
 	<li>an analysis model that assumes the beam at each instant to be a 1D continuum of plane surfaces occupied by matter.</li>
</ul>

	</example>
Properties of the temporal spatial domain may also be properties of the analysis model.  However, simplified analytically tractable properties may be assumed for an analysis model.

<example number="2">The stress-strain behaviour of a temporal spatial domain may be very complicated.  An approximate elastic behaviour may be assumed for analysis.
	</example>

</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <!-- imgfile file="analysis_schemaexpg1.xml"/-->
          <imgfile file="analysis_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
          <imgfile file="analysis_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>


 	<shortname name="BDONM" entity="behavioural_decomposition_of_numerical_model"/>
<shortname name="BDOTSD" entity="behavioural_decomposition_of_temporal_spatial_domain"/>
<shortname name="DMNPRP" entity="domain_property"/>
<shortname name="IDLRLT" entity="idealisation_relationship"/>
<shortname name="MDACDM" entity="model_action_domain"/>
<shortname name="MDPRDM" entity="model_product_domain"/>
<shortname name="MPDWM" entity="model_product_domain_with_mesh"/>
<shortname name="MDPRDS" entity="model_property_distribution"/>
<shortname name="MDSTDM" entity="model_state_domain"/>
<shortname name="NMRMDL" entity="numerical_model"/>
<shortname name="PHACDM" entity="physical_action_domain"/>
<shortname name="PHPRDM" entity="physical_product_domain"/>
<shortname name="PHSTDM" entity="physical_state_domain"/>
<shortname name="SMLRN" entity="simulation_run"/>
<shortname name="SDONM" entity="spatial_decomposition_of_numerical_model"/>
<shortname name="SDOTSD" entity="spatial_decomposition_of_temporal_spatial_domain"/>
<shortname name="TDOAD" entity="temporal_decomposition_of_action_domain"/>
<shortname name="TDOMA" entity="temporal_decomposition_of_model_action"/>
<shortname name="TMSPDM" entity="temporal_spatial_domain"/>
<shortname name="VWRLT" entity="view_relationship"/>
 
 


 </shortnames>
 
 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

-->
 <bibliography>
				
		
		<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
	
				
	</bibliography>

 
</resource>

