<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.4 2006/01/27 19:45:58 darla Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="numerical_analysis"
   part="53"
   version="1"
   wg.number="2170"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2003"
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2006/01/27 19:45:58 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.4 $">

 <keywords>
    resource, numerical analysis, idealisation
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This document provides general independent means of representing analysis problems and their solutions.</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="wg12convener"/>
   <editor ref="ap203ed2.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an integated resource for the
     representation of analysis problems and the solutions of such problems.
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
   <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>application-indpendent analysis;</li>
    <li>idealisations of product definitions evinced by analyses.</li>
   
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>analysis applications.</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="analysis_product_relationships_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   This schema specifies relationships between the definitions of objects and analyses.
  </introduction>
  
  <fund_cons>to be completed later</fund_cons>
  <!-- <fund_cons/> -->

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="analysis_product_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="product_analysis_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   This schema defines and describes the structures for describing a view of the objects (products, activities and states) that may be the subject of an analysis.
   </introduction>
<fund_cons>to be completed later</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="product_analysis_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
         <imgfile file="product_analysis_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="analysis_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   This schema defines and describes the structures for describing analyses.
   </introduction>
<fund_cons>An analysis model is a representation of a temporal spatial domain with assumptions about the nature of the temporal spatial domain that allow analysis.
An analysis model may assume that the temporal spatial domain is a continuum, and may also assume an analytically convenient dimension for that continuum.

<note>If an analysis model is a continuum, then there is a 'membership' concept which is interpreted as a place within the continuum.  A field is a function from the continuum to a property space.</note>	

<example number="1">a temperature field is a function from the continuum to the property space 'temperature'.</example>

There is also a membership concept for a temporal spatial domain.  In this case, the members are the physical individuals that have the properties assigned to the temporal spatial domain.

<example number="2"><p>The temporal spatial domain may be a beam during a loading process.  Different analysis models may be created as follows:
 	</p><ul>
 	<li>an analysis model that assumes the beam at each instant to be a 3D continuum of points occupied by matter;</li>
 	<li>an analysis model that assumes the unloaded beam to be a 1D continuum of plane surfaces occupied by matter, and the loaded beam to be a 1D continuum of surfaces occupied by matter which are not necessarily plane;</li>
 	<li>an analysis model that assumes the beam at each instant to be a 1D continuum of plane surfaces occupied by matter.</li>
</ul>
</example>
Properties of the temporal spatial domain may also be properties of the analysis model.  However, simplified analytically tractable properties may be assumed for an analysis model.

<example number="3">The stress-strain behaviour of a temporal spatial domain may be very complicated.  An approximate elastic behaviour may be assumed for analysis.</example>	

</fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="analysis_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 <shortname name="SHRTNM" entity="full_name"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

 <bibliography/>
-->
</resource>

