<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: application_protocol.xml,v 1.96 2014/09/05 00:33:15 thomasrthurman Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE application_protocol SYSTEM "../../../dtd/ap_doc/application_protocol.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkapdoc_main.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<!--
     To view the application document in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<!-- The XML for the AP documents
     name :
       is the name/directory of the Application protocol, all lower case with no whitespace

     module_name :
       is the name of the top level implementation module, the AP module

     title :
       is the title of the AP document

     part :
       ISO 10303 part number of the AP document

     purpose :
       Used to complete the first sentence in the introduction
         "This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application protocol (AP) for ....."
       and clause 4
         "This clause specifies the information required for ...."

     wg.number :
       SC4 N-number of the AP document

     wg.number.supersedes :
       the SC4 N-number of the document that this AP document supercedes

     version :
       version of AP document

     status :
       AP document status

     language :
       E for English langauge

     publication.year :
       year of publication of AP document

     published :
       y if published
-->
<application_protocol name="electronic_assembly_interconnect_and_packaging_design"
	name.french="Conception de l'emballage, de l'interconnexion et de l'assemblage électronique"
	module_name="ap210_electronic_assembly_interconnect_and_packaging_design"
	title="Electronic assembly, interconnect and packaging design"
	part="210"
	purpose="the use of the integrated resources necessary for the scope and information requirements for the design of electronic assemblies, interconnect and packaging."
	wg.number="8528"
	wg.number.supersedes="2602"
	version="3"
	status="IS"
	language="E"
	publication.year="2014"
	publication.date="2014-09-01"
	published="y"
	checklist.internal_review=""
	checklist.project_leader=""
	checklist.convener=""
	previous.revision.number="2"
	previous.revision.year="2011"
	previous.revision.cancelled="YES"
	revision.complete="YES"
	revision.scope=""
	rcs.date="$Date: 2014/09/05 00:33:15 $"
	rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.96 $"
	development.folder="dvlp"
	SMRL.version="6"
    SMRL.pub.year.month="2014-06">

 <keywords>
    Component Data, Electrical Design, Function, Die, PWB, PWA, PCB, PCA, MCM, Flex, Rigid, Flex-Rigid,
    Circuit Analysis, Thermal Design, Magnetic Design, Optical Design,
    Netlist, Assembly, Interconnect, Package, Part, Programmable Device,
    Embedded Circuit, Configuration Management, Fabrication Stackup Model, Fabrication Technology,
    Manufacturing Features, Mechanical Features, Mechanical Design,
    Simulation, Electronic Assembly, Tolerance, Requirements, Interconnect Substrate, Layout, Design Rule,
    Design Constraints, Template, Requirements, Electro-mechanical Design.
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the application protocol. -->
 <abstract>
    <p>ISO 1303-210:2014 specifies the use of ISO 10303 integrated resources that satisfy the information sharing requirements
for design engineers, device design engineers, value added engineering data suppliers, design analysts, system engineers,
fabrication planning engineers, interconnect fabrication design engineers,
and manufacturing process planning engineers. The information is shared to transform the detailed design
of and requirements for either an assembly or an interconnect substrate into either a manufacturable
description or an analysable description. Device data is shared to assure adequate product design and for source
control purposes.</p>
 </abstract>

<!-- A new edition of an AP so document the changes -->
 <changes>
  <!-- The summary of the changes -->
  <change_summary>
  	Industrial experience with the second edition of this part of ISO 10303 resulted in significant changes to the information requirements embodied in this edition.
  	This third edition of this part of ISO 10303 has been harmonized with other ISO 10303 design related parts.
  	Specifically noted in the areas of product structure, Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing, Product Data Management and Control are the first edition of ISO 10303-242,
  	and the second edition of ISO 10303-209.
The handling of ISO 13584 catalogue data has been harmonized with the above parts of ISO 10303 where necessary.
The harmonization effort was advanced by using modules developed for the first edition of ISO 10303-242 as well as the second edition of ISO 10303-209.
Due to the nature of  modularization and harmonization, it is infeasible to explicitly identify all changes.
The harmonization with the first edition of ISO 10303-242 provides the capability for supporting composite structures for substrates.
The harmonization with the first edition of ISO 10303-242 provides the capability for supporting kinematic structures. 
Every effort has been made to ensure that this third edition of this part of ISO 10303 is upwardly compatible with the the second edition of this part of ISO 10303.
  </change_summary>
  <change_detail>
  	<p>
  		A detailed computer based comparison between the schemas in the second edition of this part of ISO 10303 and this third edition of this part of ISO 10303 is available
  		at <a href="http://standards.iso.org/iso/10303/tech/implementation_information/-410/"></a>.
  	</p>
  </change_detail>
 </changes>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <purpose>
<p>This part of ISO 10303 defines the context, scope, and information requirements for information
shared between device, fabricated interconnect, system, design, analysts, and manufacturing process planning engineers for
transforming detailed requirements data, detailed device data, detailed manufacturing capabilities
data, and detailed functional design data into analysable and manufacturable descriptions
and specifies the integrated resources necessary to satisfy these requirements.
This part of ISO 10303 includes information needed to support configuration management of the product data.
</p>
 	<p>
 		The use of the terms "electronic" and "device" should not be interpreted by the reader as limiting the scope of this part of ISO 10303
 		to a particular hardware technology in the electrical domain. It is the degree to which the information requirements match the intended
 		application that will determine the usefulness of this part of ISO 10303 for that application.
 	</p>
 	<example>
 		A computer server rack consisting of multiple levels of assembly and interconnect hierarchy may be described using this part of ISO 10303.
 	</example>
<p>The detailed product data identify the functional and physical performance requirements for the
product in its intended environment. The functional and physical interface requirements define
the usage environment of the product. Configuration management information is part of the
product data.
</p>
<p>The detailed functional requirements data may be either functional parametric properties data
or explicit detailed functional design data. The functional parametric properties data, used in
conjunction with an externally defined analysis model, describe the behavior of the product.
The detailed functional design data may be used to identify the usage of functional abstractions
as components and the connections between those components.
</p>
<p>The detailed device data identify the products used in the design and their critical functional
and physical characteristics. The detailed device data are from the external or usage view of the
device. The functional device characteristics may be represented as detailed functional design
data, allowing the association of the detailed functional requirements data to available products.
</p>
 	<p>"External" or "usage view" is equivalent to an interface view and may include behavioural information.
 	</p>
<p>The analysable description includes information, at an appropriate level of abstraction, for physically realizing
the product design. The analysable description may include the functional interconnect of
descriptions and analysis models. The analysable description may be detailed functional design
data that identify connections between components or material features in a design. Sufficient
information is included to support multi-level mixed functional or physical analysis of a system
composed of the assembly or interconnect products.
</p>
<p>The detailed manufacturing capabilities data identify the material properties supported by manufacturing and the associated manufacturing process capabilities used as a basis in
the design.
</p>
<p>The manufacturable description includes information for physically realizing either the
assembly or interconnect product design. A design may be used as a component
in a different design, with geometry providing shape information in a geometric context. Functional interface information is supported.
</p>
<p>The assembly description is technology independent and identifies the products used
as components and provides their placement, physical interconnect, and geometric shape data. These data support a
detailed analysis of the performance of a product in its intended environment.
</p>
<p>The interconnect product design describes the materials composing the interconnect, their arrangement
in the interconnect physical structure, and their shape. The interconnect describes
the arrangement and shape of material features of the interconnect product design. The interconnect
description is technology independent and may range from a collection of discrete wires to complex substrates.
</p>

<p>Figure 1 contains the data planning model that provides a high-level description of the requirements
for this part of ISO 10303. This planning model was created from the in-scope
activities data of the application activity model (AAM). This planning model was used as a
guide in developing the application reference model (ARM).</p>
<figure id="dataplanningmodel">
	<title>Data planning model</title>
	<img src="data_planning_model.gif"/>
</figure>

</purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope
      If from_module is YES then XSL will copy the in scope statement from the module.
      The XSL will automatically insert:
          "This part of ISO 10303 specifies the use of the integrated
           resources necessary for the scope and information requirements for "
      The context is the text that completes the sentence.
     -->

	<inscope from_module="NO" context="electronic assembly interconnect and packaging design">

		<li>configuration control data pertaining to the design phase of a product's development;</li>
		<li>characterization data that includes:
			<ul>
				<li>the identification of assumed, required, planned or actual parameters for functional objects, assemblies, interconnect, components, and analytical models;</li>
				<li>the description of catalogue data including explicit capability for binding externally defined data element type identifiers to product data types;</li>
				<li>chemical substance composition, composite material product structure, conductivity performance measures, shape and material properties;</li>
				<li>characterization of surface conditions including surface finish;</li>
				<li>electrical and mechanical part data, including data for bare semiconductor devices, cables and electrical connectors;</li>
				<li>the description of conductive pattern templates associated with the part;</li>
				<li>representation of interface and seating planes in the physical description of the device;</li>
				<li>representation of the shape of a device under different application contexts and material conditions;</li>
				<li>the functional and physical interface definition of devices or physical objects, or of features realized as part of the interconnect;</li>
				<li>the mapping between the functional and physical interface definitions;</li>
			</ul>
		</li>

		<li>the explicit interface to externally defined models that define the behaviour of a functional object, a device, a physical object, an electronic assembly, or an interconnect;</li>




		<li>requirement data;</li>
		<li>functional and physical network data;</li>

		<li>electrical or mechanical assembly data that includes:
			<ul>
				<li>the physical layout of the assembly, including a description of the placement of the physical objects in the assembly and the description of the constraints on the design of the assembly;</li>
				<li>the allocation of domain specific elements of the assembly design description to the interface description of a part;</li>
				<li>the allocation of each specific connection among the devices used in the assembly to the component or group of components that realizes that connection;</li>
				<li>the description of assembly panels used for manufacturing assemblies in lot quantities;</li>
				<li>representation of the joint between a feature of a component in the role of interconnect and a feature of a component that is in the role of function implementation;</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>interconnect data that includes:
		    <ul>
		    	<li>discrete wiring based interconnect data;</li>
		    	<li>cable based interconnect data;</li>
		       <li>the description of components in the assembly that help realize the interconnect;</li>
		    	<li>layered substrate based connectivity data;</li>
		    	<li>the description of the material stackup, including stackups for sequential laminates and complex configurations of multiple sub-stacks;</li>
		    	<li>the description of conductive and non-conductive materials and patterns, with the option to exclude design intent;</li>
		    	<li>the description of composite structures for non-conductive materials;</li>
		    	<li>representation of hierarchical footprint patterns, including breakout patterns;</li>
		    	<li>the description of fabrication panels used for manufacturing substrates in lot quantities;</li>
		    </ul>
		</li>

<!--
	<ul>
	<li>the description of the material stackup, including stackups for sequential laminates and complex configurations of multiple sub-stacks;</li>
	<li>the description of conductive and non-conductive materials and patterns;</li>
	<li>the description of composite structures for non-conductive materials;</li>
	<li>representation of hierarchical footprint patterns, including breakout patterns;</li>
	<li>geometric patterns that include product data to explicitly represent detailed design intent;</li>
	<li>geometric patterns that do not include detailed design intent knowledge;</li>
	<li>representation of manufacturing requirements using geometric properties or electrical impedance properties;</li>
	<li>geometric patterns that are manufacturable descriptions of the design, including needed manufacturing geometric elements;</li>
	<li>the allocation of domain specific elements of the interconnect design description to the interface description of a part;</li>
	<li>the description of interconnect design where transmission line effects are ignored;</li>
	<li>the description of interconnect design where terminals are point on surface, point on edge, or an area in cross section of the interconnect;</li>
	<li>the description of interconnect design where transmission line effects are modeled using transmission line templates;</li>
	<li>the description of interconnect design where each element in the design is separately modeled using microwave design template library;</li>
	<li>the functional and physical description of features realized as part of the interconnect, including material characteristics and composition;</li>
	<li>representation of an instance of a part in an interconnect through its usage as an embedded component;</li>
	<li>representation of assembly manufacturing specific features;</li>
	<li>representation of test manufacturing specific features;</li>
	<li>representation of fabrication manufacturing specific features;</li>
	</ul>
-->
		<li>multi-domain model data that includes:
			<ul>
				<li>the description of electrical, thermal, mechanical sub-models including two and three dimensional shape representations;</li>
				<li>the description of the explicit relationships required to maintain consistency between the sub-models;</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>two and three dimensional shape representations,including geometric validation properties, of a part, assembly, or interconnect</li>
		<li>geometric and dimensional tolerances applied to geometric shape representations;</li>
		<li>two and three dimensional presentation, including technical drawings, of product data;</li>
	</inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope
      If from_module is YES then XSL will copy the out scope statement from the module
     -->
<outscope from_module="NO">
	<li>the classification and categorization of data element types;</li>
	<li>the definition and interpretation of external file formats for simulation models;</li>
	<li>the plans for or the management of the process used to design or manufacture a product;</li>
	<li>product definition data and configuration control data pertaining to any life cycle phase other than design.</li>
</outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4  -->
 <inforeqt>
   <fundamentals>
   	<data_plan>
   		<imgfile file="data_plan_intro1.xml"/>
   	</data_plan>
     <description>
     	<p>This clause specifies the information requirements for the exchange of
     		configuration-controlled design of parts, assemblies, interconnects, interfaces, networks, and templates.
     		This clause specifies the information requirements for the exchange of
     		configuration-controlled definition of requirements for those items.
     		These items, including requirements, are considered to be products in this part of ISO 10303.
     	</p>

         <p>The management of the configuration of those products is addressed in this part of ISO 10303,
     		and is concerned with authorizations and the associated approvals given by persons in organizations.
     		The structured list of materials, components, templates, or other data items needed to make a product can be exchanged,
     		along with initial product design requirements as well as requirements for revised part versions.
     		Directive for work to proceed on these initial or modified product versions is addressed in this part of ISO 10303.
     	</p>
     	<p>
     		This part of ISO 10303 addresses exchange and sharing of information about the planned usage of products in a product model,
     		and also includes data about the different products that are sold by an organization to its customers
     		enabling an organization to control the configuration of these products.
     		This part of ISO 10303 provides the structure through which a product, unique versions of a product,
     		and different design discipline views of a product can be defined.
     		Several predefined views of a product that are specific to the electronics/electrotechnical industry are provided.
     		The details of these views and other relevant information is organized in <b>conformance options</b>.
     		An overview of the available conformance options is given here.
     	</p>
     	<p><b>4.1.1 Generic conformance options</b></p>

The document related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Basic document">Basic document;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Document structure and properties">Document structure and properties;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Partial document and structured text representation">Partial document and structured text representation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>
     	The generic geometry model related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:External model">External model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Geometrically bounded surface">Geometrically bounded surface;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Shape feature">Shape feature;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:GD&amp;T representation">GD&amp;T representation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Shape validation property">Shape validation property;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>conformance options for wireframe models:
     			<ul>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Geometrically bounded wireframe">Geometrically bounded wireframe;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Edge based wireframe">Edge based wireframe;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Shell based wireframe">Shell based wireframe.</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
                    	<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Construction geometry">Construction geometry;</clause_ref>
                    </li>

     			</ul>
     		</li>

     		<li>conformance options for topologically bounded solids and models:
     			<ul>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Faceted boundary representation">Faceted boundary representation;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Elementary boundary representation">Elementary boundary representation;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Advanced boundary representation">Advanced boundary representation;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     			</ul>
     			<ul>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Manifold surface">Manifold surface;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Manifold subsurface">Manifold subsurface;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Non manifold surface">Non manifold surface;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Compound shape representation">Compound shape representation;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     			</ul>
     			<ul>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Constructive solid geometry 3d">Constructive solid geometry 3d;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Curve swept solid">Curve swept solid;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Modified swept solid">Modified swept solid;</clause_ref>
     				</li>

     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Swept solid">Swept solid;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Thickened face solid">Thickened face solid;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Solid with local modification">Solid with local modification;</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     				<li>
     					<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Solid with construction history">Solid with construction history.</clause_ref>
     				</li>
     			</ul>
     		</li>
     	</ul>


     	The technical drawing and presentation data (as opposed to geometric model data) related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Colours and layers">Colours and layers;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Basic text and curve presentation">Basic text and curve presentation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Text with specified font">Text with specified font;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Basic callout without associativity">Basic callout without associativity;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Associative draughting">Associative draughting;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:GD&amp;T presentation">GD&amp;T presentation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:GD&amp;T presentation with association">GD&amp;T presentation with association;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Mechanical design geometric presentation">Mechanical design geometric presentation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Mechanical design shaded presentation">Mechanical design shaded presentation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Mechanical design presentation representation with draughting">Mechanical design presentation representation with draughting;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Saved view">Saved view;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Technical drawing">Technical drawing;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Technical drawing with pictures">Technical drawing with pictures.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>

     	The management related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Activity">Activity;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Alias identification">Alias identification;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Approval">Approval;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Certification">Certification;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Contract and project">Contract and project;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Date and time">Date and time;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Event and time interval">Event and time interval;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Information rights">Information rights;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Multi linguism">Multi linguism;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Person and organization">Person and organization;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Security classification">Security classification.</clause_ref>
     		</li>

     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Work organization">Work organization.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>


     	The generic product characterization and classification related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Basic product property">Basic product property;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Complex product property">Complex product property;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Basic classification">Basic classification;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Extended classification">Extended classification;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Materials">Materials;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Composite materials">Composite materials;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:External library">External library.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>
     	The product concept, specification, configuration and effectivity related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product concept">Product concept;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product class and specification">Product class and specification;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Effectivity">Effectivity;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product configuration">Product configuration;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Specification control">Specification control.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>

     	The generic product structure related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Basic assembly">Basic assembly;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Assembly with transformation">Assembly with transformation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Assembly with usage dependent shape of components">Assembly with usage dependent shape of components;</clause_ref>
     		</li>

     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Enhanced assembly">Enhanced assembly;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Part make from relationship">Part make from relationship;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product version relationship">Product version relationship;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Alternate product and assembly component substitution">Alternate product and assembly component substitution;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Physical and functional breakdown">Physical and functional breakdown;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Geometric placement within physical breakdown elements">Geometric placement within physical breakdown elements;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Solutions for physical and functional breakdown">Solutions for physical and functional breakdown.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>
     	<p><b>4.1.2 Electronics domain specific capabilities</b></p>
     	<p>
     		Extensions to the generic capabilities for the electronics domain are provided. Due to the general nature of electronics, these options are considered applicable at higher levels
     		of product structure as determined by application implementation.
     	</p>
     	<example>
     		An interconnect may be embedded in a molded or composite product, as in an automobile dashboard that is an electrotechnical assembly containing several daughterboards connected
     		by flexible interconnect.
     	</example>
     	<p><b>4.1.2.1 Network based design and analysis</b></p>
     	<p>
     		Specific product structure options are provided to support network based design and analysis. Typical applications include block diagram or circuit design and analysis, with
     		functionality provided to directly support commonly understood industrial usage with externally defined  templates
     		using languages such as Spice(TM), C(TM), VHDL-AMS(TM), SystemC(TM), Verilog(TM), or Modelica(TM). The networks may be used to represent either lumped or
     		distributed systems depending on the approximations in the templates and the structural representation actually
     		selected during design or analysis. The externally defined simulation template is explicitly attached to the interface of elements in the network.
     		The networks obviously are not limited to electrical domain.
     	</p>
     	<p>
     		Once the functional network is accepted, physical components are selected,
     		a process known as packaging traverses the functional hierarchy with the result that each element of the network is related to the component that implements that element.
     		The mapping of the functional element to the physical component may be exchanged using this part
     		of ISO 10303, as supported by the Functional decomposition to design arm.  The ability of the mapping to be supported allows
     		formal traceability to be supported between functional and physical domains supporting dynamic back annotation.
     		The mapping results are explicitly represented by a flattened network representation of the connections between the physical components that are to be implemented by interconnect.
     	</p>
     	The network based design and analysis conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrical network model">Electrical network model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>

     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Functional network interface model">Functional network interface model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Functional network model">Functional network model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Physical network topology model">Physical network topology model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Requirement allocation to functional network element">Requirement allocation to functional network element;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Simulation model template definition and application">Simulation model template definition and application;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:System wiring definition">System wiring definition;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Thermal network model">Thermal network model.</clause_ref>
     		</li>

     	</ul>


     	<p><b>4.1.2.2 Requirements</b></p>

     	<p>Specific product structure options are provided to support requirements exchange, with extensive predefined classification provided.
     		A complete capability is provided to assign quantities to a requirement.
     		Requirements may be assigned to products, versions of products, product views and domain specific structures in those views.
     		The results of evaluating a design against requirements, including Design Rules, may be captured.
     		The results may include data tables, externally defined graphical representations or externally defined audio or visual representations.
     		Traceability is provided by supporting formal assignment between a node in the requirement decomposition tree and the element in the functional or physical design that is there to satisfy that requirement.
     		Traceability is also supported by supporting formal assignment between a node in the requirement decomposition tree and a class to which the element in the functional or physical design may be assigned, thus asserting that any element that is a member of that class is there to satisfy that requirement.
     		The generic requirement related conformance options are:
     	</p>
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Requirement">Requirement;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Planned and evaluated characteristics">Planned and evaluated characteristics.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>
<p>
	Specific application of requirements are identified in other sections of this clause.
</p>
     	<p><b>4.1.2.3 Rules</b></p>
     	Design Rules may be managed with a complete life cycle and exchanged with an explicit representation language. The generic rules related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Rules">Rules;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Software">Software.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.4 Software</b></p>
     	The software related conformance options are:
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Software">Software.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     	</ul>



     	<p><b>4.1.2.5 Packaging</b></p>

  <p>
  	Support is provided for both the assignment of mapping between the functional netlist and the assembly structure and the assignment of mapping between
  	the functional netlist and the interconnect structure.  Full support is provided for formally modeling the
  	multi-product physical assembly needed to actually implement the detailed functional netlist.  There is no
  	limitation imposed due to assuming there is only one CAD layout application being used to implement the physical
  	design.  The physical design may be split amongst three dimensional system for complex shapes, including the usage of
  	cables, and their connectors, and the two dimensional CAD system traditionally used for PWB board layout.
  	There is full traceability possible through the various model instances that represent the electro-mechanical design.  Principal
  	features of this apprach include strong support for storing designs and design representations of
  	electrical or thermal components in a library along with complete functional and simulation models for those
  	components. In this way, a complex component will need to have its functional to physical mapping defined and stored only once.
  	Obviously, an assembly that is physically complex can be considered a component and relevant information stored in a library.
  	The physical interconnect "wiring" may be assigned to electrical, thermal, magnetic, or optical domains with capabilities to apply material classification properties
  	to the "wiring" and to supporting material structures for verification purposes.
  	The packaging conformance options are:
  </p>
     <ul>
     	<li>
     		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Assignment of a delay between two packaged nodes to the component implementing the path in an assembly">Assignment of a delay between two packaged nodes to the component implementing the path in an assembly;</clause_ref>
     	</li>
     	<li>
     		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Assignment of a packaged node to the component implementing the node in an assembly">Assignment of a packaged node to the component implementing the node in an assembly;</clause_ref>
     	</li>
     	<li>
     		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly network model">Electrotechnical assembly network model;</clause_ref>
     	</li>
     	<li>
     		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Functional network mapping to interconnect design elements">Functional network mapping to interconnect design elements.</clause_ref>
     	</li>
     </ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.6 Communication Protocol physical layers</b></p>
     	Support is provided to specify low level protocol layers typically associated with physical design. This provides the ability to explicitly specify a source for a requirement
     rather than using an external document approach.

     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Physical layer protocol model">Physical layer protocol model.</clause_ref>
     		</li>
       	</ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.7 Physical design</b></p>
     	<p>
     		In the context of this part of ISO 10303 assembly design and interconnect design inherit common characteristics from a more generic physical design level.
     		The physical design level conformance options are:
     	</p>
     	<ul>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Physical and keepout model shape classification">Physical and keepout model shape classification;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Physical design model manifold surface shape">Physical design model manifold surface shape;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Physical interface model">Physical interface model.</clause_ref>
     		</li>

     	</ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.7 Assembly design</b></p>
     	<p>
The assembly design provides a similar capability to the functional design, that is hiearchical physical
design is supported.  The model provides the ability for a design organization to substitute various possible alternatives for analysis while maintaining the same physical interface
definition.  It is possible to
model at the semiconductor device, package, substrate, module, black box (multiple modules in one box), drawer, rack, and system level.  Parts of a design may be stored in
a library as a 'macro' and re-used.  Complete designs, including interfaces, may be stored in a library and re-used. Various options
for physical shape are provided to support analysis.  Discrete wire and detailed cable routing is supported. Critical assembly feature to feature relationships  are provided to support verification
that the "as-designed" assembly including interconnect satisfies the physical connectivity definition defined during packaging.
       </p>
	   <ul>

	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly component placement requirements">Electrotechnical assembly component placement requirements;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model in a 2D context">Electrotechnical assembly design model in a 2D context;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model in a 3D context">Electrotechnical assembly design model in a 3D context;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model manufacturing features">Electrotechnical assembly design model manufacturing features;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model physical elements requirement allocation">Electrotechnical assembly design model physical elements requirement allocation;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with cable included in a 2D context">Electrotechnical assembly design model with cable included in a 2D context;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with cable included in a 3D context">Electrotechnical assembly design model with cable included in a 3D context;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with component die bond wire mapping included">Electrotechnical assembly design model with component die bond wire mapping included;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with component die bond wire mapping included in a 2D context">Electrotechnical assembly design model with component die bond wire mapping included in a 2D context;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with component die bond wire mapping included in a 3D context">Electrotechnical assembly design model with component die bond wire mapping included in a 3D context;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with component grouping">Electrotechnical assembly design model with component grouping;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with discrete connector included">Electrotechnical assembly design model with discrete connector included;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>

	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with edge based component mounting">Electrotechnical assembly design model with edge based component mounting;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with explicit electrical subassembly">Electrotechnical assembly design model with explicit electrical subassembly;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with discrete wiring">Electrotechnical assembly design model with discrete wiring;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with layered interconnect included">Electrotechnical assembly design model with layered interconnect included;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with interface component">Electrotechnical assembly design model with interface component;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with macros">Electrotechnical assembly design model with macros;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with shield">Electrotechnical assembly design model with shield;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly design model with stacked component mounting">Electrotechnical assembly design model with stacked component mounting;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly extracted network model">Electrotechnical assembly extracted network model;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly functional interface requirement">Electrotechnical assembly functional interface requirement;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly interface model using discrete connections">Electrotechnical assembly interface model using discrete connections;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly interface model using a printed connector">Electrotechnical assembly interface model using a printed connector;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>

	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly panel model">Electrotechnical assembly panel model;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly physical interface model requirement allocation">Electrotechnical assembly physical interface model requirement allocation;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Electrotechnical assembly technology">Electrotechnical assembly technology;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product marking">Product marking;</clause_ref>
	   	</li>
	   	<li>
	   		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Test requirement allocation">Test requirement allocation.</clause_ref>
	   	</li>

	   </ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.8 Interconnect design</b></p>
     	<p>

As in the assembly design there is an interface definition, known as a usage view, which provides the support
required to isolate the CAD model for the interconnect from that for the assembly while maintaining full traceability through the hierarchy.  The connections supported by the interconnect are included in the usage view to support trade studies and test.
Further, the usage view includes various options for physical shape  models to support analysis.  Embedded passive and active components are supported, as is various non traditional materials such as optical fiber for interconnect.
Microwave models (where features of the design are considered to be components) are supported, as is the abstraction that a terminal of a component in the interconnect is on the edge of the component model rather than the surface.
Full traceability of the physical netlist to the as layed out geometry is provided for planar, three dimensional and manifold surface layouts.
Full support is provided for treatment of the mechanical aspects of the interconnect, including materials, stackup, and Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing.
     	</p>
     	<note>
     		Manifold surface models may be used for molded and composite structures.
     	</note>
     	<ul>

     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Interconnect interface model">Interconnect interface model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect complex template">Layered interconnect complex template;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model component placement requirements">Layered interconnect design model component placement requirements;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design layer manifold surface shape">Layered interconnect design layer manifold surface shape;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model">Layered interconnect design model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model electrical features">Layered interconnect design model electrical features;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model elements requirement allocation">Layered interconnect design model elements requirement allocation;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model geometric dimensioning and tolerancing">Layered interconnect design model geometric dimensioning and tolerancing;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model manifold surface shape">Layered interconnect design model manifold surface shape;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model manufacturing assembly features">Layered interconnect design model manufacturing assembly features;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model manufacturing test features">Layered interconnect design model manufacturing test features;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model mechanical features">Layered interconnect design model mechanical features;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with embedded discrete components">Layered interconnect design model with embedded discrete components;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with layer position and located thickness in a 2d context">Layered interconnect design model with layer position and located thickness in a 2d context;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with layer position and located thickness in a 3d context">Layered interconnect design model with layer position and located thickness in a 3d context;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with macros">Layered interconnect design model with macros;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with microwave components in a 2D context">Layered interconnect design model with microwave components in a 2D context;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with microwave components in a 3D context">Layered interconnect design model with microwave components in a 3D context;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with printed components in a 2D context">Layered interconnect design model with printed components in a 2D context;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with printed components in a 3D context">Layered interconnect design model with printed components in a 3D context;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design model with shield">Layered interconnect design model with shield;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect design network model">Layered interconnect design network model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect extracted network model">Layered interconnect extracted network model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect fabrication requirement">Layered interconnect fabrication requirement;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect interface model">Layered interconnect interface model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect interface model connection zones">Layered interconnect interface model connection zones;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect material stackup fabricator model">Layered interconnect material stackup fabricator model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect material stackup library model">Layered interconnect material stackup library model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect macro definition">Layered interconnect macro definition;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Layered interconnect panel model">Layered interconnect panel model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product marking">Product marking;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Sequential laminate assembly model">Sequential laminate assembly model;</clause_ref>
     		</li>
     		<li>
     			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Test requirement allocation">Test requirement allocation.</clause_ref>
     		</li>

     </ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.9 Component data</b></p>
     	<p>
This part of ISO 10303 provides complete support for all data commonly found in a component data sheet, including functional and physical properties.
The physical properties, component feature classification and terminal and connection area identification are directly supported including various shape models for analysis and Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing.
Orientation identification is unambiguously supported with direct support for both three dimensional master models as well as derived two dimensional models.
Direct support for unpackaged (bare) die usage is provided, as well as packaged components.  Support is provided for thermal analysis of complex multi-chip substrates such as MCM.
Component features may be specified in accordance with their function, location and may be grouped. Behavioural models may be assigned to components as well as to terminals, which may be modeled as whole elements or modeled with connection areas.
Connectors are an important component and there are several models provided that may be used depending on the context, ranging from a minimal connector defined to support the physical layer definition
in an electrical protocol to a complete connector definition intended to support three dimensional mockup interconnect traceability.
When this capability is combined with the capability to define CAD footprints for a particular package and fabrication technology, a rather complete library data set is supported.
Cables are often part of an assembly or interconnect and support is provided for the external definition of the functional and physical properties of a cable, including connector positioning if available.
The component data conformance options include the conformance options specified in Clause 4.1.1 as well as the following:

     	</p>

	   	<ul>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Cable interface model">Cable interface model;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component black box model">Component black box model;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component footprint definition">Component footprint definition;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component functional modifications">Component functional modifications;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component package model">Component package model;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component package model in a 2D context">Component package model in a 2D context;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component package model in a 3D context">Component package model in a 3D context;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component package model with corresponding 2D and 3D contexts">Component package model with corresponding 2D and 3D contexts;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component physical modifications">Component physical modifications;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component white box model for analysis">Component white box model for analysis;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Connector model">Connector model;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Functional specification">Functional specification;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Part feature grouping">Part feature grouping;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Predefined part feature functional classification">Predefined part feature functional classification;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Product marking">Product marking;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Test requirement allocation">Test requirement allocation;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Unpackaged semiconductor device interface model">Unpackaged semiconductor device interface model.</clause_ref>
	   		</li>

	   	</ul>

     	<p><b>4.1.2.10 Footprint data</b></p>

     	<p>
     		Footprints may be defined for a particular interconnect technology and related to the package they are intended to support. The footrpint related conformance options are:
     	</p>
	   	<ul>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Component footprint definition">Component footprint definition;</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   		<li>
	   			<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:External library">External library.</clause_ref>
	   		</li>
	   	</ul>
     	<p><b>4.1.2.11 Template data</b></p>
     	<p>
     		Templates play an important role in electronic design. The Template related conformance options are:
     	</p>
      <ul>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:External library">External library;</clause_ref>
      	</li>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Printed element template model">Printed element template model;</clause_ref>
      	</li>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Simulation model template definition and application">Simulation model template definition and application;</clause_ref>
      	</li>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Template 3D model shape">Template 3D model shape;</clause_ref>
      	</li>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Template and keepout model shape classification">Template and keepout model shape classification;</clause_ref>
      	</li>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Template model">Template model;</clause_ref>
      	</li>
      	<li>
      		<clause_ref linkend="conformance:co:Template model manifold surface shape">Template model manifold surface shape.</clause_ref>
      	</li>



      </ul>



     </description>
   </fundamentals>

   <reqtover module="ap210_electronic_assembly_interconnect_and_packaging_design">
    <description>
      <p>
        <module_ref linkend="ap210_electronic_assembly_interconnect_and_packaging_design:introduction">
          ISO 10303-410</module_ref>
        defines the full information model for
        this part of ISO 10303 by providing a single root for all of the modules used.
      </p>
    </description>
   </reqtover>



 </inforeqt>

<!--  Terminology map
  <terminology_map>
-->
    <!-- mapping of a business to term to an AP term -->
<!--
    <term_map>
      <description>
        @@@@ description of the mapping @@@
      </description>
      <business_term term_id="@@@@"/>
      <ap_term term_id="@@@@" application_protocol="@@@@"/>
      <module_term term_id="@@@@" module="@@@@"/>
    </term_map>
  </terminology_map>
-->
 <!-- Activity Model -->
 <aam>
   <idef0>
     <imgfile file="aamidef01.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef02.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef03.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef04.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef05.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef06.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef07.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef08.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef09.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef10.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef11.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef12.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef13.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef14.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef15.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef16.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef17.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef18.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef19.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef20.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aamidef21.xml"/>
   </idef0>
 </aam>

 <!--  -->
<imp_meths>
<imp_meth general="n" part="21">
  <description>
      <p>
        If the implementation method is ISO 10303-21, the file format shall be
        encoded according to the syntax and EXPRESS language mapping defined in
        ISO 10303-21 and to the MIM schema referenced in
        <clause_ref linkend="express_mim_lf"/> of this part of
        ISO 10303.
      </p>
      <p>
        The FILE_SCHEMA element of the header shall specify the name of the
        EXPRESS schema used and include its object information identifier (see
        <clause_ref linkend="object_registration"/>).
      </p>
      <example>
        The instance below identifies the Ap210_electronic_assembly_interconnect_and_packaging_design schema:
      </example>
      <screen>
        FILE_SCHEMA (('AP210_ELECTRONIC_ASSEMBLY_INTERCONNECT_AND_PACKAGING_DESIGN_MIM_LF {1 0 10303 410 2 1 4}'))
      </screen>
    </description>
</imp_meth>
</imp_meths>

<!-- <usage_guide>
   @@@
 </usage_guide>

 <tech_disc>
  @@@@
 </tech_disc>-->

	<bibliography>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-209e2"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-242"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO13584-all-parts"/>
    <bibitem.inc ref="ISO-16792-undated"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="IEEE-IDEF0-1998"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="bajaj02"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="bajaj04"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="bajaj03"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="bajaj01"/>
    <bibitem.inc ref="APConGde"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="wg3n1594"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="BLANCHARD1998"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="NISTIR-7677"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="NISTIR-7634"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="stori01"/>
  	<bibitem.inc ref="NISTIR-7648"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="denno02"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="denno01"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="rassaian01"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="mccaleb01"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="NASA2007"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="PDMUGV1.2R4.3_2002"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="peak03"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="peak05"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="peak01"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="peak02"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="peak04"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="step_handbook_v3"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="seth01"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="seth02"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="tamburini02"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="tamburini01"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="jwg9n026"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="thurman02"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="wg3n2608"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="thurman01"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="jwg9n031"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="wg3n2606"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="Wu01"/>
	<bibitem.inc ref="Zwemer01"/>
</bibliography>

</application_protocol>
