<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.3 2015/08/31 07:28:41 lothartklein Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource 
    name="constructive_solid_geometry"
   part="515"
   version="1"
   wg.number="416"
      wg.number.express="417"
   status="IS"
   publication.year="2000"
   published="y"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2015/08/31 07:28:41 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.3 $">

 <keywords>
    solid primitive, extruded solid, swept solid, manifold brep, boolean operation
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>This document specifies the use of ISO 10303 integrated resources satisfying the
	requirements for the representation as a consistent set of geometric entities for the
	definition of constructive solid geometry models build up from solid primitives, 
	and the boolean operations of union, intersection, and difference on these solids and other extruded, swept and manifold solids.</p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap242ed2.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="ap242.editor"/>
 </contacts>


 <foreword>
 This second edition cancels and replaces the first edition (ISO 10303-515:2000), 
 which has been technically revised. 
 </foreword>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
	<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application interpreted construct for
		a consistent set of geometric and structural entities for
		the definition of Constructive Solid Geometry (CSG).
		The geometric information is conveyed by solid models,
		and the structural information is communicated through acyclic graphs.
	</p>
</purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>solid primitives;
   <example number="1">sphere, right circular cone, right circular cylinder, and torus are types of solid primitives.
   </example></li>
   <li>regularised boolean operations of union, intersection, and difference on solid primitives, manifold
brep and other solids;
<example  number="2">manifold solid breps, extruded face solids, revolved face solids, solid replicas, and halfspace
solids are other types of solids.</example>
</li>
   <li>extruded_face_solids and swept_face_solids to define new primitive shapes;</li>
   <li>boolean results generated by applying operators to solids.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>2D geometric entities;</li>
   <li>self-intersecting geometry;</li>
   <li>evaluation of constructive solid geometry models to generate B-rep models.</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

<schema name="aic_csg" version="2">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<note>There may be subtypes and items of select lists that appear in the integrated resources that are not
imported into the AIC. Constructs are eliminated from the subtype tree or select list through the use of the
implicit interface rules of ISO 10303-11. References to eliminated constructs are outside the scope of the AIC.
In some cases, all items of the select list are eliminated. Because AICs are intended to be implemented in the
context of an application protocol, the items of the select list will be defined by the scope of the application
protocol.</note>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons/>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>      
     <imgfile file="aic_csgexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aic_csgexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 <shortname name="CSSHRP" entity="CSG_SHAPE_REPRESENTATION"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

 <bibliography/>
-->
</resource>

