<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: issues.xml,v 1.4 2004/01/14 15:28:34 darla Exp $ -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../xsl/projmg/apdoc_issues_file.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "../../../../dtd/projmg/apdoc_issues.dtd">
<issues ap_doc="configuration_control_3d_design_ed2">

<!--
Description of how the issues files is given in: stepmod\help\issues.htm
 id - an identifer of the isssue unique to this file
 type - the primary XML element in apDoc.xml that the issue is against.
        Either: 
            general | keywords | contacts | purpose |
            inscope | outscope | normrefs | definition |
            abbreviations | arm | armexpg | arm_lf |
            armexpg_lf | mapping_table | mim  | mimexpg |
            mim_lf | mimexpg_lf | usage_guide | bibliography
 linkend - the target of the comment 
 category - editorial | minor_technical | major_technical | repository 
 by - person raising the issue
 date - date issue raised yy-mm-dd
 status - status of issue. Either "open" or "closed"
 seds - if "yes" then the issue has been raised as a SEDS.
        The id should be the id of the SEDS in the SC4 database

Comment - is a comment raised by someone about the issue

<issue
  id=""
  type=""
  linkend=""
  category=""
  by=""
  date=""
  status="open"
  seds="no">
  <description>

  </description>

<comment
   by="" 
   date="">
<description>
</description>
</comment>
 </issue>
-->

<!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
<!-- +++++++++++++++++++   ISSUES                  ++++++++++++++ -->
<!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->

<!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->

<issue
  id="DE-4"
  type="general"
  category="major_technical"
  by="DE"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="DE"
  seds="no">
  <description>
The AP does not contain any Conformance Class. All the information is defined by one Application Module 403.
This lead to problems in the industrial application of this AP. Especially, it is indispensable to have a conformance for PDM data exchange. To ensure the compatibility with current implementations and to keep the interoperability with other STEP AP, a Conformance Class corresponding to the scope of the PDM Schema is an absolute requirement.	Define a suitable set of Conformance Classes for 10303-203ed2. At least one for the PDM Schema scope is required.
Develop the corresponding Application Module(s) / Implementation Module(s).
</description>

<comment
   by="DE" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="US-2"
  type="general"
  category="major_technical"
  by="TH"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="US"
  seds="no">
  <description>
With only one upper level module, and only one conformance class, and no UoFs, it is difficult to understand the overall concepts because the reader needs to navigate through a lot of lower-lever modules and extrapolate.	Add additional higher level modules. Do an analysis to see if any of the lower modules can be rolled up into higher level modules.
</description>

<comment
   by="TH" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="US-4"
  type="general"
  category="major_technical"
  by="TH"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="US"
  seds="no">
  <description>
It is difficult to understand what is in the AP because the planning model is too high-level.	Provide clear requirements for a detailed planning model for all modular APs and incorporate one into this document.  At a minimum have a high level planning model whose functional boxes are filled with the names of the constituent modules.  
</description>

<comment
   by="TH" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept - change to resemble 239 and Contents guidelines.
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-1"
  type="general"
  category="major_technical"
  by="SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Successive editions of one  AP are required to have the same scope in general with the first edition. From this viewpoint, we reviewed the scope of the ed2. 
However, it is difficult to understand the similarity and the difference of the scope of AP 203ed2 against that of AP 203ed1.	We recommend to reconstruct the contents of the Scope, in order to clarify the differences of the AP 203 ed2 against the scope of AP 203 ed1.
In particular, it is recommended to clarify newly added items within the scope, and  removed items to outside of the scope.

</description>

<comment
   by="SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept in principle - follow practise of 224 214 210
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-2"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Geometric validation properties
The scope of the AP 203 ed2 has a sentence "geometric validation properties to allow the translation of geometric shape representations (advanced boundary representation and faceted boundary representation solids) to be checked for quality" 
However, the constituent module AM 1039 deals only with such items as centroid, volume, and surface area, as described in Section 4.3.1 of AM 1039.
We think that the term "geometric validation properties" includes wider range of properties of the geometric model, such as consistency between points on different surfaces.	We recommend to modify  "geometric validation properties" to more suitable term, such as "properties derived from shape representations"

</description>

<comment
   by="SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Discuss w CAX-IF.  Add a note to say  intent is limited
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-3"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="MS SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Clause 4.2.x
Contents
WG12 N1412 includes the document entitled "Modular AP Outline", which includes the result of the discussion in the last San Diego meeting about the contents of Modular AP document. This document requests that 4.2.x shall include the description to show the relation between the conformance class module (This should be "implementation module" now) and the scope statement in the AP.
4.2.x of the current 10303-203 ed2 only lists each module used, but does not include such a description.
For example, the AP document of AP 239, under development has the following sentences.
4.2.3 ISO 10303-1287: AP239 activity recording
This application module shall be used to address the following areas of scope. ISO 10303-1287 specifies an application module for the representation of activity recording. It uses the application module ISO 10303-1259 (Activity as realized) module to assert that the work described by an activity methods, defined by the application module, ISO 10303-1049 (Activity method), has actually taken place. It also enables the recording of an observation, defined by the application module ISO 10303-1258 (Observation) to hold information not allowed for by the definition of the work.	4.2.x shall be modified to include the requested description like those in 4.2.x of the AP document of AP239 (10303-239), which is now under development.

</description>

<comment
   by="MS SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-4"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="MS"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
4.2.x	
Contents	
Sub-clause 4.2 of 10303-203 ed2 lists all modules used in this AP.
On the other side 4.2 of 10303-239, which will be issued in the ballot soon, looks to be listing only implementation modules.
We think that consensus is necessary about what kinds of modules shall be listed in 4.2.	Please reconfirm the contents of Sub-clause 4.2 for the modular AP document, based on WG12 N1412 or later version of "Modular AP Outline".

</description>

<comment
   by="MS" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept - see 239
</description>
</comment>
</issue>

<issue
  id="JP-5"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Clause 5	
title
The title of Clause 5 of AP 203ed2 is "Module interpreted model", however, the document of "Modular AP Outline" in WG12 N1412 specifies the title of Clause 5 as "Application interpreted model".	Please reconfirm the title of Clause 5 for the modular AP document, based on WG12 N1412 or later version of "Modular AP Outline".
</description>

<comment
   by="SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Guidelines issue so  refer to QC 
First check SC4 minutes Rob emails  etc.

</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-6"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Clause 5	
Mapping specification
The Clause 5 of AP203ed2 seems to be described according to WG 12 N1412 "Modular AP Outline"
However, we think it is better that Clause 5 of AP document includes the mapping specification of the ARM, as specified by the Supplementary Directives for the conventional AP documents, for easy understanding of the implementers and the users.	Please discuss this issue at the module harmonisation meeting.

</description>

<comment
   by="SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Discuss .  I happen to agree. Contents guidelines are affected and also XSLT
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-7"
  type="general"
  category="minor_technical"
  by="SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Clause 6	
Conformance class	
Many implementers have developed translators based on the conformance classes of AP203ed1 and they are deployed in production for variety of industrial activities. Therefore, industrial users of AP203 will strongly require upward compatibility of AP 203ed2 against AP 203ed1.
Only one conformance class named CC1 is defined in Section 6. On the other hand, six conformance classes were given in AP 203 ed1. This may cause some troubles in the translation of the existing CAD data of the industrial users.	We recommend to clarify the conformance class of the AP 203ed2 is different from the ones of AP203ed1. For example, CC of AP 203ed2 is named as "CC7".

</description>

<comment
   by="SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Discuss how to map names for upward compatability
Simon: CC4 and CC6 are most used.  Actual implementations include CLG, valprops

</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-8"
  type="general"
  category="minor_technical"
  by="MS SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Clause 6.1	
NOTE	
The following description in Sub-clause 6.1 shall be common to all conformance classes.
"NOTE  Conformance to configuration control of 3D design of mechanical parts and assemblies requires that all ARM and MIM elements defined in the AP module, (ISO 10303-403), be supported."
By this reason, we think that the description of conformance requirement only to ARM elements is not appropriate, because STEP data models shall have to be implemented based on AIM or MIM.	We recommend to move this description into the preface of clause 6, and to merge it with the 1st sentence of the last paragraph of clause 6 without the reference to ARM, as shown in the following.
"Conformance to a particular class requires that all MIM elements defined as part of that class be supported."

</description>

<comment
   by="MS SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Refer to QC

</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-9"
  type="general"
  category="minor_technical"
  by="MS SY"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Annex H		
AIM of AP203 ed1 includes AP specific entities like cc_ design_ approval. We understand that these entities are renamed in the constituting Application Modules of AP203 ed2. For example, the cc_ design_ approval was changed to applied_ approval_ assignment. But Annex H does not mention these renamed entities.	We recommend to add the description of these renamed entities in Annex H.
</description>

<comment
   by="MS SY" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Accept in principle.  Create a table that maps old names to new.  NOTE BAN has newer version - will give to DNS to enter in repository

</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-10"
  type="general"
  category="minor_technical"
  by="CS"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
Surface_ property		
Since surface property is not included in the outside of the scope, we checked its existence but we could not find it. As the use of this model in NC machining application is strongly expected, it should be included in the model not in the form of annotation but in the form of data entity. 	AP203 edition-2 shall have the same structure for Property including Surface_ property as that of AP224 shown in the attached file.
</description>

<comment
   by="CS" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
Agree in principle.   Need to decide if goes in this TC, or in DIS, or e3. NC programs have a tough time without this piece of information. Compare with  AP214 for harmonization.
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-11"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="NS"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
AM 1050,
AM 1051		
In the Poitiers Meeting, WG3/T24 manufacturing team determined to establish an Ad-Hoc committee for the harmonization of Geometric and Dimensional Tolerance defined in AP 214, AP 224 and AM 1050. This harmonisation should be strongly  promoted with all the related standard developers efforts for eliminating near future confusion.	This document should be revised based on coming agreement of harmonisation meeting before going to the next document stage.

</description>

<comment
   by="NS" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-12"
  type="general"
  category="minor_technical"
  by="NS"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
AM 1050
4.3.9	
Location_ dimension	
ARM entity Location _dimension is mapped to the resource entity dimensional _location (Part 47), which represents the relative location between a pair of shape aspects. 

However, the following two attributes, origin and target, may be a geometric_ representation_ item, such as Axis _placement.

origin: the element that is the origin for the Location_dimension. 
target: the element that is the target for the Location_dimension. 	Please confirm the consistency with the dimensional _location in Part 47.

</description>

<comment
   by="NS" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
</description>
</comment>
</issue>
<issue
  id="JP-13"
  type="general"
  category="editorial"
  by="NS"
  date="04-01-14"
  status="open"
  ballot_comment="yes"
  member_body="JP"
  seds="no">
  <description>
AM 1131
4.3.1	
Constructive _geometry	
A Constructive _geometry is defined as a type of Representation that contains a collection of geometric elements used to support the definition of a Geometric_ model.
The term "Constructive_ geometry" may be misunderstood as the "constructive _solid geometry" composed of primitive solids.	We recommend to change the entity name if possible.

</description>

<comment
   by="NS" 
   date="04-01-14">
<description>
</description>
</comment>
</issue>

</issues>