<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.23 2013/10/23 13:43:37 darla Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="mechanical_design_geometric_presentation"
   name.french="Pr&#233;sentation g&#233;om&#233;trique de conception m&#233;canique"
   part="517"
   version="3"
   object.reg.version="3"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="6176"
   wg.number.express="6177"
   wg.number.supersedes="5251"
   wg.number.express.supersedes="5252"
   checklist.internal_review="6178"
   checklist.project_leader="6179"
   checklist.convener="6180"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2011"
   publication.date="2011-10-15" 
   published="n"
   previous.revision.year="2000" 
   previous.revision.cancelled="Yes"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2013/10/23 13:43:37 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.23 $">

 <keywords>
    application interpreted construct, camera model, curve style, surface style.
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>
		This document specifies the application interpreted construct for the description of structures for a limited
		visual presentation of wireframe, surface, and solid models as used in mechanical design. 
		The projection of the 3D-models onto the plane of the display and specification of point, curve, and surface styles are included. 
		Light sources, shading, and reflectance, the concept of layers, and the representation of text are out of scope.
	</p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="simon.frechette"/>
   <editor ref="lothar.klein"/>
 </contacts>

 <foreword>
   This third edition cancels and replaces the second edition (ISO 10303-517:2011), 
   which has been technically revised.  
   It also incorporates the Technical Corrigendum ISO 10303-517:2000/Cor.1:2002.
 </foreword>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
    This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application interpreted construct for the
    description of the visual presentation
	of the shape of mechanical design models. 
	Shape is projected into a plane display area. 
	The projections themselves are not represented, however the shape and corresponding projection algorithms are given.
	Presentation attributes are included, such as line font and colour, that may be applied to parts or all
	of wireframe, surface, and solid models. 
	Association of attributes with topological items is included to provide for the styling of high level shape constructs. 
	Advanced visualization capabilities, such as light sources and surface reflectance are not included. 
	The representation of annotation, such as text and 	symbols, are not specified.
   </p>
	<p>
		Technical modifications to the first edition of this part of ISO 10303 are categorised as follows: changes to the EXPRESS
		declarations, new EXPRESS declarations, and changes to definitions of EXPRESS entity data types.
	</p>
	
	<!-- aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentation -->
	<p>The following aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentation EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been modified:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>USE FROM geometry_schema;</li>
		<li>USE FROM presentation_appearance_schema;</li>
		<li>USE FROM presentation_organization_schema;</li>
		<li>USE FROM presentation_resource_schema;</li>
		<li>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area;</li>
		<li>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_representation.</li>
	</ul>
	
	<p>The following aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentation EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been removed:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>USE FROM measure_schema;</li>
		<li>camera_image_3d_with_scale;</li>
		<li>draughting_pre_defined_colour;</li>
		<li>draughting_pre_defined_curve_font;</li>
		<li>aspect_ratio.</li>
	</ul>
	
	<p>The following aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentation EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been added:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>REFERENCE FROM presentation_organization_schema;</li>
		<li>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area_items.</li>
	</ul>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>  -->

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <scope>
		Only basic presentation attributes, such as colour or linefont, can be associated with points, curves, surfaces, 
		and topological constructs. 
		Advanced visualization functionality such as light sources and surface reflectance are not included. 
		The description of annotation is not included.
		<p/>
 </scope>
 
 <inscope>
	   <li>the visual presentation of mechanical design shape representations;</li>
	   <li>the assignment of visual presentation attributes to geometric and topological items;</li>
	   <li>algorithms for the projection of 3D shapes into planes;</li>
	   <li>the location of shape projections within a window;</li>
	   <li>multiple views within one window;</li>
	   <li>the background colour of a window;</li>
	   <li>point and curve colour;</li>
	   <li>point font;</li>
	   <li>curve font;</li>
	   <li>curve styles dependent on the role of the curves in the definition of a surface;
	   		<example>
	   			Boundary curves and grid curves play different roles in the definition of a surface.
	   		</example>
	   </li>
	   <li>pre-defined colours;</li>
	   <li>pre-defined curve styles.</li>
 </inscope> 

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the presentation of annotation, i.e., text and symbols;</li>
   <li>the assignment of geometric items to layers;</li>
   <li>surface characteristics such as transparency and reflectance;</li>
   <li>multiple windows;</li>
   <li>representation of products;</li>
   <li>hidden line and hidden surface removal;</li>
   <li>surface colour;</li>
   <li>light sources.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_abstract_test_suite"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_context"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_interpreted_construct"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_protocol"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_externally_defined"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_implementation_method"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_interpretation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_model"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_predefined"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_presentation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_structure"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-42">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_curve"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_surface"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-46">
 		<term.ref linkend="annotation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="layer"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="picture"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="presentation_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="rgb"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="symbol_46"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="synthetic_camera_model"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="visualization"/>
 	</normref.inc> 	
 </normrefs>
<!--
 <definition/>
-->
 <abbreviations>
 	<abbreviation id="AIC">
 		<acronym>AIC</acronym>
 		<term>Application Interpreted Construct</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	
 	<abbreviation id="AP">
 		<acronym>AP</acronym>
 		<term>Application Protocol</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	
 	<abbreviation id="ATS">
 		<acronym>ATS</acronym>
 		<term>Abstract Test Suite</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	
 	<abbreviation id="RGB">
 		<acronym>RGB</acronym>
 		<term>Red, Green, Blue colour space</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 </abbreviations>


<schema name="aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentation">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   	<p>
   		This application interpreted construct provides a consistent set of entities for the representation of pictures.
   	</p>
   		<example number="1">
   			Pictures of mechanical products that are in the design stage are examples of pictures supported by this AIC.
   		</example>
   	<p>
   		All pictures shall be presented in the same window on a display. 
   		A picture may include one or several views of a product shape. 
   		Only the association between product shape and its projection algorithms is represented, not the projections themselves.
   	</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   	<p>
   		The structure for the management of pictures is implemented using entities <b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area</b>, 
   		<b>presentation_view</b>, and <b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_representation</b>.
   		The relationships between these entities are represented using the <b>mapped_item</b> and <b>representation_map</b> entities.
   		A <b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area</b> is a subtype of <b>presentation_area</b>.
   		This subtype has been created for the purpose of this part of ISO 10303.
   		All the contents of a window shall be included into one <b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area</b>.
   		A view is represented by a <b>presentation_view</b>.
   		The view contains entity <b>camera_image_3d_with_scale</b> which has been created for the purpose of this part of ISO 10303.
   		This entity references <b>camera_image</b> which has the information that is necessary to compute the projection of a shape; 
   		this information is included in the camera model.
   		Only entity <b>camera_model_d3</b> shall be used as camera model; none of its subtypes is valid.
   		Light sources and hidden line removal are not part of the camera model.
   		<b>Camera_image_3d_with_scale references</b> not only the camera model, 
   		but links it with <b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_representation</b> which contains product shape descriptions.
   		These shapes may or may not be styled.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The appearance of product shape may be specified using styles for <b>points</b>, <b>curves</b>, and <b>surfaces</b>.
   		Styles may also be assigned to topological elements of product shape.
   		A style assignment is made by instantiating a <b>styled_item</b> which refers to a <b>representation_item</b> 
   		together with its <b>presentation_style_assignment</b>.
   		For the purpose of this part of ISO 10303 a subtype of <b>representation</b> has been created,
		<b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_representation</b>, to collect all <b>styled_item</b>s for a
		<b>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area</b>.
   	</p>
   	<p>
   		The <b>presentation_style_assignment</b> of a <b>styled_item</b> affects the appearance of the referenced
		<b>representation_item</b> as well as the appearance of all <b>representation_item</b>s referenced directly or indirectly by that item.
		Only those <b>representation_item</b>s are affected that are not already styled.
		This means styling a styled <b>representation_item</b> has no effect.
		Styling a partially styled <b>representation_item</b> affects only the appearance of the unstyled parts.
		Styling an unstyled <b>representation_item</b> affects the appearance of the whole item.
		Only styled <b>representation_item</b>s may be presented.
		Whether they are actually presented depends also on other facts, like <b>invisibility</b>.
		This part of ISO 10303 does not make any statement about the effect if style conflicts occur.
   	</p>
   		<example number="2">
   			A style conflict occurs, for example, when a <b>representation_item</b> is used by several <b>styled_items</b>.
   		</example>
	<p>
		A <b>presentation_style_assignment</b> is used to assign styles to a <b>representation_item</b> independently
		from any presentation context. 
		A subtype of <b>presentation_style_assignment</b>, the <b>presentation_style_by_context</b>, 
		allows the assignment of style for a specific presentation context. 
		A presentation context can be any <b>representation</b> or <b>representation_item</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		<b>Point_styles</b> allow the specification of the marker symbol, marker size, and colour to be used for presenting points.
	</p>
	<p>
		<b>Curve_styles</b> allow the specification of curve fonts, curve width, and colour. 
		The appearance of curve ends and corners, and of patterns for filling visible curve segments is not distinguished. 
		A curve font specifies whether a curve shall be drawn using solid, dashed, or dotted lines. 
		The specification of arbitrary patterns for curve fonts and the usage of externally defined curve fonts are not incuded. 
		Curve fonts may be pre–defined. 
		The entities used for the definition of curve fonts are <b>draughting_pre_defined_curve_font</b> and <b>curve_style_font</b>. 
		The curve width shall be specified as a measure value.
	</p>
	<p>
		Surface styles provide the resources to specify the visual appearance of surfaces. 
		Separate surface styles may be applied to each side of a surface using entities <b>surface_style_usage</b> and <b>surface_side_style</b>. 
		A surface side style may be any combination of fill area style, boundary style, silhouette style, segmentation
		curve style, control grid style, or parameter line style. 
		The rendering of <b>curve</b>s and <b>surface</b>s is not included.
	</p>
	<p>
		A fill area style specifies a style for presenting visible surfaces by mapping a coloured fill area upon them.
	</p>
	<p>
		A boundary style specifies a curve style for presenting the boundary curves of a surface. 
		If no boundary style is specified, the boundary curves shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A silhouette style specifies a curve style for presenting the silhouette curves of a surface. 
		If no silhouette style is specified, silhouette curves shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A segmentation curve style specifies a curve style for presenting the segmentation curves of a surface.
		This style affects only surfaces which are divided into segments such as B–spline surfaces. 
		If no segmentation curve style is specified, segmentation curves shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A control grid style specifies a curve style for presenting the mesh of control points which are used for the
		definition of a surface. 
		This style affects only surfaces which are defined over a mesh of control points,
		such as B–spline surfaces. 
		If no control grid style is specified, the control grid shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A parameter line style specifies a curve style for presenting iso–parameter lines of a surface. 
		The number of parameter lines in each parameter direction has to be specified for this style. 
		If no parameter line style is specified, the parameter lines shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		The entities defining these surface styles are <b>surface_style_fill_area</b>, <b>surface_style_boundary</b>, 
		<b>surface_style_silhouette</b>, <b>surface_style_segmentation_curve</b>, <b>surface_style_control_grid</b>, and <b>surface_style_parameter_line</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		Colours may be specified based on the RGB colour model using entity <b>colour_rgb</b> or by <b>draughting_pre_defined_colour</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 does not include constructs for the representation of annotation.
	</p>
	<p>
		The following entities are intended to be independently instantiated in the application protocol schemas that use this AIC:
	</p>
		<ul>
			<li>camera_image_3d_with_scale;</li>
			<li>draughting_pre_defined_colour:</li>
			<li>draughting_pre_defined_curve_font;</li>
			<li>invisibility;</li>
			<li>mapped_item;</li>
			<li>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area;</li>
			<li>mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_representation;</li>
			<li>over_riding_styled_item;</li>
			<li>presentation_style_by_context.</li>
		</ul>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentationexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aic_mechanical_design_geometric_presentationexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="MDGPA" entity="mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_area"/>
 	<shortname name="MDGPR" entity="mechanical_design_geometric_presentation_representation"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->

 <bibliography>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
 </bibliography>

</resource>

