<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <?xml-stylesheet 
  type="text/xsl" 
  href="../../../xsl/descriptions.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE 
  express SYSTEM "../../../dtd/description.dtd">
<ext_descriptions module_directory="manifold_surface" schema_file="arm.xml" rcs.date="$Date: 2002/05/10 16:12:13 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.2 $"
  describe.selects="YES"
>


  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm"/>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation">
A manifold_surface_shape_representation is a shape_representation that consists of one or many shell_based_surface models. Each shell_based_surface_model is built up of open_shells which are sets of faces. Connected_face_set, which is the supertype of open_shell and closed_shell, shall not be instantiated. Faces use edges and vertexs; all of these shall reference geometric entities such as points, curves, and surfaces. The link between topology and geometric entities such as points, curves, and surfaces. The link between topology and geometry may be established by either using face_surface or advanced_face as defined in ISO 10303-511. The two options differ both in the selection of valid point, curve, and surface subtypes and in constraints on references to underlying geometry. 

        <note> The representation of face surfaces as advanced faces is recommended for manifold surface models that are intended to be used together with boundary representation solid models; the integration of such a manifold surface model into, for example, an advanced boundary representation model, which is defined in ISO 10303-514, will be easier.
      </note>
      
      <p>
All geometric entities shall be of dimensionality three except for two-dimensional geometry that is used for the purpose of defining pcurves. The use of one-dimensional cartesian points is excluded.
      </p>
      
      <p>
All unbounded geometry shall be trimmed by using topological constructs.
      </p>
      
      <p>
The items of a manifold surface shape representation may also be of type mapped-item, or axis2 placement 3d. These are used to assemble one or several manifold surface shape representations into one other manifold surface - shape representation.
      </p>
      
   </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP1 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP1">
The items in a manifold surface shape representation shall be shell based-surface models, mapped items, or axis2 placement 3ds.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP2 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP2">
At least one of the items in a manifold surface shape representation shall be either a shell based surface model or a mapped item.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP3 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP3">
If there is a mapped item in a manifold surface shape representation, the mapped representation of its mapping source shall also be a manifold surface shape-representation.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP4 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP4">
The boundary of a shell based surface model, that is its attribute sbsm boundary, shall be defined by using only open shells, closed shells, or oriented closed shells; oriented open shells are not valid.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP5 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP5">
A face shall be instantiated as either a face surface, its subtype advanced face, or an oriented face.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP6 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP6">
The face geometry of a face surface shall be either a b-spline surface, an elementary surface, an offset surface, a surface replica, a swept surface, or a surface within the reference tree of an advanced face.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP7 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP7">
All basis geometry that is referenced by surfaces shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be valid curves and surfaces. The basis surface of an offset surface shall be either an elementary surface, b spline - surface, offset surface, swept surface, or surface replica. The parent surface of a surface replica shall be either an elementary surface, b spline - surface, offset surface, swept surface, or surface replica. The swept curve of a swept surface shall be either a line, conic, pcurve, surface curve, offset curve 3d, b spline curve, polyline, pcurve replica. The attribute self intersect shall be set to FALSE or UNKNOWN for b spline surfaces and offset surfaces.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP8 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP8">
The bound of a face bound, which is referenced from a face, shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be an edge loop or a vertex loop.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP9 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP9">
The geometry of a bounding edge, that is the edge element of an oriented edge, shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be an edge curve.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP10 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP10">
The curve used to define the geometry of an edge, that is the edge geometry of an edge curve of an edge, shall be either a b spline curve, a conic, a curve replica, a line, an offset curve 3d, apcurve, apolyline, asurface curve, or acurve in the reference tree of an advanced face.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP11 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP11">
All basis geometry that is referenced by curves shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be valid curves and surfaces. The parent curve of a curve replica shall be either a line, conic, pcurve, surface curve, offset curve 3d, b spline curve, polyline, orcurve replica. The basis curve of an offset curve 3d shall be either a line, conic, pcurve, surface curve, offset curve 3d, b spline curve, polyline, or curve replica. The curve 3d of a surface curve shall be either a line, conic, offset curve 3d, b spline - curve, polyline, or curve replica. The basis surface of a surface curve shall be either a b spline surface, elementary - surface, offset surface, surface replica, or swept surface. Polylines shall contain at least three cartesian points. The attribute self intersect shall be set to FALSE or UNKNOWN for b spline curves and set curve 3ds.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP12 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP12">
The edge start and edge end of an edge shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be vertex points.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP13 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP13">
The vertex geometry of a vertex that is part of an edge loop shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be a cartesian point, point on curve, point on surface, or degenerate pcurve.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP14 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP14">
The loop vertex of a vertex loop shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be a vertex point.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP15 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP15">
The vertex geometry of a vertex that is part of a vertex loop shall be either within the reference tree of an advanced face or shall be a cartesian point, point on curve, point on surface, or degenerate pcurve.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP16 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP16">
The portion of a b spline curve that is within the topological domain of a manifold - surface shape representation shall not self-intersect.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP17 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP17">
The portion of a b spline surface that is within the topological domain of a manifold - surface shape representation shall not self-intersect.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP18 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP18">
The portion of an offset curve 3d that is within the topological domain of a manifold - surface shape representation shall not self-intersect.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP19 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP19">
The portion of an offset surface that is within the topological domain of a manifold - surface shape representation shall not self-intersect.
        </ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Manifold_surface_arm  Entity: Manifold_surface_shape_representation  Where: IP20 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Manifold_surface_arm.Manifold_surface_shape_representation.wr:IP20">
If a face has only one connected outer bound, the corresponding loop shall be represented as face outer bound. If the outer bound is not connected, face outer bound shall not be used.
        </ext_description>
</ext_descriptions>