<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
	name="ap210_interconnect_functional_requirements" 
	name.french="Exigence fonctionnelles d'interconnexion pour l'AP 210"
	part="1619" version="1" sc4.working_group="12" wg.number="2024" wg.number.arm="2025" wg.number.arm_lf="2026" wg.number.mim="2027" wg.number.mim_lf="2028" wg.number.supersedes="1655" wg.number.arm.supersedes="1656" wg.number.mim.supersedes="1657" wg.number.arm_lf.supersedes="1718" wg.number.mim_lf.supersedes="1719" checklist.internal_review="2075" checklist.project_leader="2076" checklist.convener="2077" status="TS" language="E" publication.year="2006" publication.date="2006-12-13" published="y" rcs.date="$Date: 2007/01/30 07:49:26 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.29 $" development.folder="dvlp">
    <keywords>
    module,electrical, network analysis, function, requirement,functional allocation, optical, magnetic, embedded component, printed component, routing
 </keywords>
<abstract>
	<p>
		the
     representation of interconnect functional requirements.
This Data includes functional device data 
specific to an interconnect product. The functional
view of Devices which are fabricated as part of the interconnect product fabrication process are included in the functional definition.
Discrete physical devices that are embedded are not included. Configuration management information and
design change management information is provided.
	</p>
      <li>nodal network representation of the behaviour of the interconnect;</li>
      <li>allocation of functions in the nodal network representation to embedded physical components that implement the functionality;</li>
      <li>allocation of functions in the nodal network representation to printed components that implement the functionality;</li>
      <li>mapping the set of nodes in the hierarchical network representation to the physical network that is implemeting the functional node.</li>

</abstract>    
    <contacts>
        <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
        <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
    </contacts>
    <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of interconnect functional requirements.
This Data includes the functional device data 
specific to an interconnect product. The functional
view of Devices that are fabricated as part of the interconnect product fabrication process are included in the functional definition.
Discrete physical devices that are embedded are considered to be external to the interconnect product
since their internal geometric design patterns are not used as part of the direct realization of the interconnect product. 
	   Configuration management information and
design change management information is provided.
   </p>
		<example number="1">
		Printed inductors, printed connectors, embedded passives such as printed capacitors are all considered in this part of ISO 10303 to be
			fabricated as part of the interconnect substrate since they are based on geometric patters defined in the authoring CAD system.	
		</example>
		<example number="2">
			MOS transistor die are prefabricated and the geometric patterns used in that prefabrication step are not included in the patterns
			generated in the CAD system defining the layout.  During the realization process for the interconnect operations that expose
			the terminals of the MOS transistors by removing silicon dioxide are considered by this part of ISO 10303 to be equivalent to
			lead preparation processes in discrete manufacturing at the assembly level and are ignored.
		</example>
 </purpose>
    <inscope>
      <li>nodal network representation of the behaviour of the interconnect;</li>
      <li>allocation of functions in the nodal network representation to embedded physical components that implement the functionality;</li>
      <li>allocation of functions in the nodal network representation to printed components that implement the functionality;</li>
      <li>mapping the set of nodes in the hierarchical network representation to the physical network that is implemeting the functional node;</li>
      <li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="ap210_functional_decomposition:1_scope">Ap210 functional decomposition;</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1614;</li>
      <li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="functional_decomposition_to_interconnect_design:1_scope">Functional decomposition to interconnect design</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1677;</li>
      <li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="functional_decomposition_with_nodal_representation_to_packaged_mapping:1_scope">Functional decomposition with nodal representation to packaged mapping</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1678;</li>
      <li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="planned_characteristic:1_scope">Planned characteristic</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1733;</li>
      <li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="test_requirement_allocation:1_scope">Test requirement allocation</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1751.</li>
   </inscope>
    <outscope>
        <li>algorithmic representation of the behaviour of the interconnect;</li>
        <li>shape representation of the interconnect.</li>
    </outscope>
    <arm>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </arm>
    <arm_lf/>
    <mapping_table>
        
    </mapping_table>
    <mim>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </mim>
    <mim_lf/>    
</module>
