<collection_page page_type="main">
      <h2><a name="introduction">0 Introduction</a></h2>
      <h3><a name="introduction">0.1 General</a></h3>
      <p>
         ISO 10303 is an International Standard for the computer-interpretable 
         representation of product information and for the exchange of product data.
         The objective is to provide a neutral mechanism capable of describing
         products throughout their life cycle. This mechanism is suitable not only
         for neutral file exchange, but also as a basis for implementing and
         sharing product databases, and as a basis for archiving.
         
      </p>
      <p>
         This part of ISO 10303 contains the collection of application modules.
      </p>

<h3>0.2 Application protocol background</h3>
<p>ISO 10303 has been designed to support an extensive domain of product data communication requirements, i.e. all product data necessary to completely define any product for all applications over the product's entire life cycle. With the broad scope and complexity of ISO 10303, the implementation of ISO 10303 in its entirety by any one organization is unlikely.</p>
<p>For the use of ISO 10303 within a particular application context, an application protocol (AP) provides the information required for practical implementation. This includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>the definition of the application context, scope and functional requirements;</li>
<li>the definition of the application information requirements;</li>
<li>the required use of the ISO 10303 integrated resource constructs to support the application information requirements;</li>
<li>the specification of levels of conformance for evaluating implementations of the AP.</li>
</ul>
<h3>0.3 Application modules background</h3>
<p>Application modules are the key component of the
ISO 10303 modular architecture. The basis of the approach is understanding and harmonizing the requirements,
both new and those documented in existing APs, grouping the requirements
into reuseable modules, and using the modules
in the development of an AP.</p>
<p>An application module contains much of the technical content that, in the initial ISO
10303 architecture, was documented in an AP. The role of an AP document
in the modular architecture is to provide a business context for the industrial
use and implementation of the application modules that are the data specification
of the AP.</p>
<p>There are three types of application modules: foundation modules (level
1), implementation modules (level 2), and AP modules (level 3). Foundation
modules provide lower level reusable structures that are not likely to
be implemented alone, but are highly shareable and reusable. Implementation
modules define a capability that can be implemented and against which conformance
classes can be defined. Each AP references a single root module that
is an AP module. An AP module is an implementation module, and the
contents of an AP module are the same as other implementation modules,
the only documentation difference being in their name and title. The
AP module from one AP can be used by another AP. A detailed description
of the content of an application module is provided in Reference [<a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_AMConGde06">10</a>]. A detailed description of the content of an
application protocol that uses application modules is provided in
Reference [<a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_APConGde">11</a>].</p>
<p>The ISO 10303 modular architecture is intended to:</p>
<ul>
<li>
ensure the ability to implement a combination of subsets of multiple
APs, or to extend existing APs to meet a business need;</li>

<li>
ensure the ability to reuse application software developed to support
one AP in the development of an implementation of another AP with the same,
or similar, requirements;</li>

<li>
avoid the duplication and repeated documentation of the same requirements
in different application protocols, leading to potentially different solutions
for the same requirements;</li>

<li>
 ensure the ability to reuse data generated by an implementation of one
or more APs by an implementation of one or more different APs.</li>
</ul>
<h3>0.4 Document structure</h3>
<p>The application modules were previously published in the form of Technical Specifications as separate parts of ISO 10303, with part numbers between 1001 and 1999. This part of ISO 10303 cancels and replaces those separately-published parts. However, the application modules are still designated by their original part numbers, and are still formatted as ISO Technical Specifications.</p>
<p><small>EXAMPLE ISO/TS 10303-1025 designates application module 1025, "alias identification", which is contained in this part of ISO 10303. The alias identification module has the same elements that any ISO Technical Specification would have, notably Foreword, Introduction, Scope, Normative references, etc. Within the alias identification module, the phrase "this part of ISO 10303" refers to the alias identification module, not to ISO/TS 10303-1000 as a whole.</small></p>
<h3>0.5 References</h3>
<p>The Normative references clause, Bibliography, and Index in this part of ISO 10303 apply to this part of ISO 10303 as a whole, excluding the modules. Each application module has its own Normative reference clause, its own Bibliography, and its own Index.</p>
<p>This part of ISO 10303 also provides
         <A href="frame_index.htm" target="index">navigation indices</A>
         for the modules that are included in this collection.
      </p>
<h3>0.6 Use of this part of ISO 10303</h3>
<p>The following application protocols make use of the modules in this part of ISO 10303:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-203">ISO 10303-203</a>;</li>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-209">ISO 10303-209</a>;</li>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-210">ISO 10303-210</a>;</li>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-233">ISO 10303-233</a>;</li>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-236">ISO 10303-236</a>;</li>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-239">ISO 10303-239</a>;</li>
<li><a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_ISO_10303-241">ISO 10303-241</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3>0.7 Intended audience</h3>
<p>The intended audience for this part of ISO 10303 includes standards committees that are developing ISO 10303 modular application protocols, software developers that are implementing ISO 10303 modular application protocols, and those who
are considering adopting ISO 10303, or systems built on it, for product data representation and exchange.</p>
<h3>0.7 Preparation</h3>
<p>This part of ISO 10303 was prepared in accordance with Reference [<a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_Part1000_proc">9</a>].</p>
</collection_page>
