<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: issues.xml,v 1.2 2005/05/05 22:48:15 thomasrthurman Exp $ -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../xsl/projmg/issues_file.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE issues SYSTEM "../../../../dtd/projmg/issues.dtd">
<issues module="pre_defined_datum_3d_symbol">

<!--
Description of how the issues files is given in: stepmod\help\issues.htm
 id - an identifer of the isssue unique to this file
 type - the primary XML element in module.xml that the issue is against.
        Either: 
            general | keywords | contacts | purpose |
            inscope | outscope | normrefs | definition |
            abbreviations | arm | armexpg | arm_lf |
            armexpg_lf | mapping_table | mim  | mimexpg |
            mim_lf | mimexpg_lf | usage_guide | bibliography
 linkend - the target of the comment 
 category - editorial | minor_technical | major_technical | repository 
 by - person raising the issue
 date - date issue raised yy-mm-dd
 status - status of issue. Either "open" or "closed"
 seds - if "yes" then the issue has been raised as a SEDS.
        The id should be the id of the SEDS in the SC4 database

Comment - is a comment raised by someone about the issue

<issue
  id=""
  type=""
  linkend=""
  category=""
  by=""
  date=""
  status="open"
  seds="no">
  <description>

  </description>

<comment
   by="" 
   date="">
<description>
</description>
</comment>
 </issue>
-->

<!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
<!-- +++++++++++++++++++   ISSUES                  ++++++++++++++ -->
<!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
<issue
  id="1"
  type="arm"
  linkend=""
  category="major_technical"
  by="T.Thurman"
  date="2005-05-05"
  status="closed"
  seds="no">
  <description>
comments from WG12 Convener review document:

A more careful evaluation needs to be done on the subject of GDT presentation, in particular whether or not it is harmonized with ISO standards on this subject (16?) and the upcoming harmonization work AP203E2 will be doing on GDT presentation.

LK: Datum symbols are clearly part of the ISO standards. I have my Iso Technical Handbook on technical drawing right now in Lithuania. Will ask to send it back to me to be able to give exact references. However it is clear that AP210 does so far not deal with the extended requirements of the new upcoming ISO  16792. 

March 30, 2005: agree to have formal statement that datum symbol shall conform to ISO 16792 for 3d case. 
TT: Defer to ballot comments.  The problem is that the purpose of the pre defined symbols is not communication between a computer and a human but between two processors, so there are some very specific features that need to be present and the present model doesn’t specify that very well.  The features are used to have unambiguous map between the 2d and 3d contexts. i.e, an intersection of two lines in one symbol is the same point as an intersection of a line and a plane in the other symbol.

  </description>
<comment
   by="T. Thurman" 
   date="2005-05-05">
<description>
The representation of the symbols is not merely for presentation to a user, but more 
importantly to allow explicit mapping from 2d to 3d.
The structure of the predefined symbols needs to be provided so that explicit relationships between
a specific node in the structure of the 2d symbol and the equivalent node in the
structure of the 3d symbol.

</description>
</comment>

 </issue>

</issues>
