<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.21 2007/07/05 00:15:51 abf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="schedule"
   part="1437"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="4612"
   wg.number.arm="4613"
   wg.number.mim="4614"
   wg.number.supersedes="3742"
   wg.number.arm.supersedes="3743"
   checklist.convener="4636"
   checklist.internal_review="4637"
   checklist.project_leader="4638"
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2007/07/05 00:15:51 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.21 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, project management, schedule
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead2"/>
   <editor ref="ap233.editor2"/>  
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of a data model that identifies activities, dependencies, 
     durations and milestones associated with products described in 
     a work breakdown structure.  This includes the information necessary
     to produce Workflow Diagrams, Network Schedules, Gantt Charts and 
     Resource Leveling.
   </p>
   
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>facility to assign activity information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign activity method information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign condition evaluation information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign event information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign justification information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign process property information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign resource information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign scheme information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign state information to schedule management data;</li>
   <li>facility to assign task information to schedule management data.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope 
 <outscope>
   <li>the response of a system to excitation; </li>
   <li>the representation of function or state based behavior;</li>
   <li>association of schedule with activity or product data;</li>   
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated work;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated person and organization;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated project breakdown;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated project management information resources;</li>
   <li>the relationships between organization structure, project breakdown, project management information 
   resources and work structure. </li>  
</outscope>
-->

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
      <!-- <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg3.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg4.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg5.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg6.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg7.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg8.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg9.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg10.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg11.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg12.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg13.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg14.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg15.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg16.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg17.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg18.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg19.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg20.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg21.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg22.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg23.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg24.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg25.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg26.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg27.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg28.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg29.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg30.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg31.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg32.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg33.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg34.xml"/>  -->
   </express-g>
 </arm>

 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table> -->

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
    <shortnames>   
    <shortname name="SCAAA" entity="ss_characterizable_applied_action_assignment"/>
    <shortname name="SCAAMA" entity="ss_characterizable_applied_action_method_assignment"/>
    </shortnames>   
 </mim>

     <usage_guide>
     
        <p>
     Within organizations and between organizations it is beneficial 
     to be able to exchange plans and schedules. These may be at a high 
     level where they deal with the tasks of work breakdown structure 
     or at low and detailed level where they coordinate individual 
     workers. This module captures information concerning schedules, 
     resource allocation and leveling. This information is needed to 
     manage the life cycle process of developing and using a system such 
     that persons and organizations can coordinate their activities.</p>
   
   <p>
     This module is constructed from several ISO/TS Application 
     modules.  The USE FROM connectivity associated with these modules are 
     shown below in Figure 1 the Schedule concept map.</p>
	
   	<figure><title> Schedule Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Schedule_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   <p>The modules shown within this figure that are primary contributors to 
   AP233's schedule information modelling capability are:</p>
   
   <ul>
   <li>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="activity_method_implementation:introduction"/> 
   provides the capability to associate 
   additional information with an activity method.</li>

   <li>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="attribute_classificaton:introduction"/> 
   provides the association of a value, 
   represented by a class, to an attribute of an entity.</li>

   <li>
   The module <module_ref linkend="condition_evaluation:introduction"/> 
   identifies the evaluation of conditions that impact an activity or its 
   execution. The module records the parameter values evaluated and the 
   logicalresult of the evaluation.</li>

   <li>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="process_property_assignment:introduction"/> 
   captures the specification of a property 
   of an activity, the representation of a property of an activity, 
   or the use of an 
   independent property in the definition of an activity. </li>
   
   <li>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="property_assignment:introduction"/> 
   provides for the assignment of a property to product data, use of an 
   independent property in the definition of an item and the association 
   of a representation with a property.</li>

   <li>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="resource_as_realized:introduction"/> 
   captures the recording of resources used or 
   consumed by activities. It captures the usage or consumption of 
   actual resources 
   and types of resource items. It captures the relationship between 
   the resource 
   actually applied and realized with the corresponding resource 
   requirement statements. 
   It captures the relationship between the resource as realized and 
   the corresponding resource events.</li>

   <li>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="resource_property_assignment:introduction"/> 
   captures the definition of a property 
   that may be associated with a resource or related element. It captures the 
   representation of a property that may be associated with a resource 
   or related 
   element; the use of an independent property in the definition of 
   a resource, and the means to assign a property to a resource or 
   related element. The entity property includes time intervals.</li>
   
   <li>The module <module_ref linkend="scheme:introduction"/> 
   captures the identification of schemes that support the 
   ordering of activities. It captures the identification of entries 
   in a scheme, and the association of dates and times with schemes 
   and entries in schemes. It captures the definition of relationships 
   between entries within a scheme, including dependencies and 
   sequencing. It captures the definition of relationships between 
   schemes, and the definition of relationships between scheme entries and 
   schemes that expand on entries.</li>
   
   <li>The module <module_ref linkend="task_specification:introduction"/> 
   captures the specification of a task as a sequence of instructions 
   encoded as text. It captures the specification of a 
   task as a structured set of instructions. It captures the association of 
   pre-conditions to a task or a stage within a task, the association 
   of post-conditions 
   to a task or a stage within a task, and the assignment of a task.</li>

   <li>The module <module_ref linkend="time_interval_assignment:introduction"/> 
   captures the association of a time interval with product or 
   activity data.</li>
   
   <li>The module <module_ref linkend="work_output:introduction"/> 
   captures the definition and quantification of planned and recorded
   output, the relationship between work outputs, and the relationships
   between the work output and detailed descriptions of the output.</li>
   </ul>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules identified in Figure 1 are shown below in 
	Figure 2 the Activity Concept Map.</p>
	
   	<figure><title> Activity Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Activity_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "Where" concept of classififcation
	are shown below in Figure 3 the Where Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> Where Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Where_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "How" concept of condition 
	and condition evaluation are shown below in Figure 4 the How Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> How Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="How_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "Representation" concepts of 
	schedule and process property representation are shown below in Figure 5 the Representation Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> Representation Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Representation concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "Resource" concepts of 
	resource item, required, as realized and management are shown below in Figure 6 the Resource Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> Resource Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Resource_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "What" concept of 
	observation are shown below in Figure 7 the What Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> What Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="What_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "When" concept of 
	time, event and effectivity are shown below in Figure 8 the When Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> When Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="When_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "Why" concept of 
	documentation and file identification are shown below in Figure 9 the Why Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> Why Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Why_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

   	<p>The USE FROM connectivity between the modules associated with the "Authorization" concept of 
	justification is shown below in Figure 10 the Authorization Concept Map.</p>

	<figure><title> Authorization Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Authorization_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>


 	<p><b>Extensible type select lists (generic)</b></p>
	
	<p>The problem of creating extensible type lists has proven to be an extreme challenge.
	A publish and subscribe analogy is used to explain the approach used.</p>  

	<p>Schemas enable information modelling capability within a domain. The capabilities are 
	enabled by entities.  Entities use other entities directly as specified attributes or less 
	directly via extensible select types.  The associated extensible select type list can be viewed as a 
	subscription list. The list itself contains all entity names associated with entity concepts 
	that subscribe to the capability offered by the schema containing the entity that uses 
	the extensible type list as an attribute.</p>  

	<p>The complexity of the extensible select type list specification problem stems from the fact that 
	lists are relative to a sub-domain of the domain associated with the schema that defines the 
	extensible type list.</p>

	<p>This creates a list creation problem that is 3 dimensional.  The coordinate axes are:</p>
	<ul>
	<li>domain specified by all USE FROM schemas,</li> 
	<li>extensible select types defined within this domain,</li>
	<li>entities defined within a sub-domain of this domain.</li>   </ul>
	
	<p>To size this, AP233 has about 10 major domains, 1000 entities and 
	100 extensible types.  If one does not apply some organizational logic to the problem this 
	implies a yes/no cognitive decisions space containing 1,000,000 points.</p>
	
	<p>In order to penetrate this problem some logical approach that is both scalable and 
	checkable is required.  In AP233 WD1 all schemas where grouped into high level concept
	groups: program management resource information (pmri), organization structure (os),
	project breakdown (pb). schedule (ss) and work structure (ws).  As AP233 WD2 
	evolved major module restructuring occurred and the ability to group at a more 
	detail level of abstraction was enabled.  </p>

	<p><b>Extensible type select lists - schedule</b></p> 
	 
	<p>All extensible select types and entities used in the associated type extend lists 
	defined within this module are defined within the following modules:
	</p>
	
	<ul>
        <li><module_ref linkend="Activity:introduction">
          Activity</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1047);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Activity_method:introduction">
          Activity_method_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1049);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Activity_method_assignment:introduction">
          Activity_method_assignment_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1249);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Activity_method_implementation:introduction">
          Activity_method_implementation_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1261);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Condition_evaluation:introduction">
          Condition_evaluation_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1254);</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Event:introduction">
          Event_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1064);
	</li>

	<li><module_ref linkend="Event_assignment:introduction">
          Event_assignment_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1364);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Foundation_state_definition:introduction">
          Foundation_state_definition_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1469);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Justification:introduction">
          Justification_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1263);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Process_property_assignment:introduction">
          Process_property_assignment_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1040);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Property_assignment:introduction">
          Property_assignment_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1030);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Required_resource:introduction">
          Required_resource_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1267);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Resource_as_realized:introduction">
          Resource_as_realized_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1269);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Resource_item:introduction">
          Resource_item_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1268);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Resource_management:introduction">
          Resource_management_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1266);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Resource_property_assignment:introduction">
          Resource_property_assignment_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1273);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Scheme:introduction">
          Scheme_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1260);
	</li>

	<li><module_ref linkend="State_observed:introduction">
          State_observed_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1256);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Task_element:introduction">
          Task_element_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1480);
	</li>
	
	<li><module_ref linkend="Task_specification:introduction">
          Task_specification_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1262);
	</li>
	
	</ul>

	 <p>From the perspective of information cross coupling; the type extend lists 
	 identify within this module specify how all schedule information modeling 
	 concepts defined within the schemas of the schedule domain are coupled together 
	 via type extends within the schedule domain.</p>
	 
	 
   <p><b> Re. Scheme - Validation Test Concerns by Lothar Klein</b></p>
   <ul>
   <li>As part of our AP233 evaluation work we are looking on how best to
	implement the Scheme module. We identified a couple of problems
	and think it is best to make several changes for our trial
	implementation:</li>
   <li>This e-mail focuses on changes for Scheme only, but please have in mind
	the neighboring modules for Task_specification and Activity, Project
	etc. as well. At the end all this has to work in a consistent way.
	I did not list Activity_as_realize here because I think we don't
	need the entities defined there - this is a separate debate.</li>
   <li>Note that the changes listed below shall help to improve data exchange
	and data_integration of different tools. The pre- and post-processor
	may not know from each other - so they may not be aligned up-front.</li>
   <li>The current state of debate on this email tread is being collected and can be downloaded at 
   <a href="http://stepmod.cvs.sourceforge.net/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/system_management/Scheme%20schedule%20debate.doc?revision=1.1"/></li>
   </ul>
   
   <p><b>Re. Schedule testing</b></p>
   <p>LkSoft and InterCAX have identified a number of schedule representation problems.
   These were not ready for detail discussion in Rochester.  Reference Mike Dickerson 
   for detail of schedule testing effort.</p>
   
	
</usage_guide>

</module>
