<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.14 2006/06/17 17:05:12 abf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="schedule"
   part="1437"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="4442"
   wg.number.arm="4443"
   wg.number.mim=""
   wg.number.supersedes="3742"
   wg.number.arm.supersedes="3743"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2006/06/17 17:05:12 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.14 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, project management, schedule, scheme
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="ap233.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of a data model that identifies activities, dependencies, 
     durations and milestones associated with products described in 
     a work breakdown structure.  This includes the information necessary
     to produce Workflow Diagrams, Network Schedules, Gantt Charts and 
     Resource Leveling.
   </p>
   
   <p>
     Within organizations and between organizations it is beneficial 
     to be able to exchange plans and schedules. These may be at a high 
     level where they deal with the tasks of work breakdown structure 
     or at low and detailed level where they coordinate individual 
     workers. This module captures information concerning schedules, 
     resource allocation and leveling. This information is needed to 
     manage the life cycle process of developing and using a system such 
     that persons and organizations can coordinate their activities.</p>
   
   <p>
     This module is constructed from several ISO/TS Application 
     modules.</p>

   <p>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="activity_method_implementation:introduction"/> 
   provides the capability to associate 
   additional information with an activity method.</p>

   <p>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="attribute_classificaton:introduction"/> 
   provides the association of a value, 
   represented by a class, to an attribute of an entity.</p>

   <p>
   The module <module_ref linkend="condition_evaluation:introduction"/> 
   identifies the evaluation of conditions that impact an activity or its 
   execution. The module records the parameter values evaluated and the 
   logicalresult of the evaluation.</p>

   <p>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="process_property_assignment:introduction"/> 
   captures the specification of a property 
   of an activity, the representation of a property of an activity, 
   or the use of an 
   independent property in the definition of an activity. </p>
   
   <p>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="property_assignment:introduction"/> 
   provides for the:</p>
   <ul>
	<li>assignment of a property to product data;</li>
	<li>use of an independent property in the definition of an item;</li>
	<li>association of a representation with a property.</li>
	</ul>

   <p>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="resource_as_realized:introduction"/> 
   captures the recording of resources used or 
   consumed by activities. It captures the usage or consumption of 
   actual resources 
   and types of resource items. It captures the relationship between 
   the resource 
   actually applied and realized with the corresponding resource 
   requirement statements. 
   It captures the relationship between the resource as realized and 
   the corresponding resource events.</p>

   <p>
   The module 
   <module_ref linkend="resource_property_assignment:introduction"/> 
   captures the definition of a property 
   that may be associated with a resource or related element. It captures the 
   representation of a property that may be associated with a resource 
   or related 
   element; the use of an independent property in the definition of 
   a resource, and the means to assign a property to a resource or 
   related element. The entity property includes time intervals.</p>
   
   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="scheme:introduction"/> 
   captures the identification of schemes that support the 
   ordering of activities. It captures the identification of entries 
   in a scheme, and the association of dates and times with schemes 
   and entries in schemes. It captures the definition of relationships 
   between entries within a scheme, including dependencies and 
   sequencing. It captures the definition of relationships between 
   schemes, and the definition of relationships between scheme entries and 
   schemes that expand on entries.</p>
   
   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="task_specification:introduction"/> 
   captures the specification of a task as a sequence of instructions 
   encoded as text. It captures the specification of a 
   task as a structured set of instructions. It captures the association of 
   pre-conditions to a task or a stage within a task, the association 
   of post-conditions 
   to a task or a stage within a task, and the assignment of a task.</p>

   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="time_interval_assignment:introduction"/> 
   captures the association of a time interval with product or 
   activity data.</p>
   
   <p>The module <module_ref linkend="work_output:introduction"/> 
   captures the definition and quantification of planned and recorded
   output, the relationship between work outputs, and the relationships
   between the work output and detailed descriptions of the output.</p>

<!--
   <p><b> Re. Scheme - Validation Test Concerns by Lothar Klein</b></p>
   <ul>
   <li>As part of our AP233 evaluation work we are looking on how best to
	implement the Scheme module. We identified a couple of problems
	and think it is best to make several changes for our trial
	implementation:</li>
   <li>This e-mail focuses on changes for Scheme only, but please have in mind
	the neighbouring modules for Task_specification and Activity, Project
	etc. as well. At the end all this has to work in a consistent way.
	I did not list Activity_as_realize here because I think we don't
	need the entities defined there - this is a separate debate.</li>
   <li>Note that the changes listed below shall help to improve data exchange
	and data_integration of different tools. The pre- and post-processor
	may not know from each other - so they may not be aligned up-front.</li>
   <li>The current state of debate on this email tread is being collected and can be downloaded at 
   <a href="http://cvs.sourceforge.net/viewcvs.py/*checkout*/stepmod/stepmod/etc/ap233/references/system_management/Scheme%20schedule%20debate.doc?rev=1.1"/></li>
   </ul>
   
   <p><b>Re. Schedule testing</b></p>
   LkSoft and InterCAX have identified a number of schedule representation problems.
   These were not ready for detail discussion in Rochester.  Reference Mike Dickerson 
   for detail of schedule testing effort.
   
   <p><b>Change Log from base line AP233 WD#1:</b></p><ol>
   <li>WD#2 - Removed all references to module "information packet". Reason: Not needed, the module document
   and its related modules can be used to service this need.</li></ol>
-->   
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>definition of an activity and relationships;</li>
   <li>relationship between an activity and the product or activity data that it affects or uses;</li>
   <li>historical occurrence of an activity and the relationship to planned or defined activities;</li>
   <li>identification, description and relationships between activity methods;</li>
   <li>assignment of activity methods to product data;</li>
   <li>identification and recording of condition parameter values evaluated;</li>
   <li>characterization of an event and relationships;</li>
   <li>association of an event with product or activity data;</li>
   <li>specification and representation of a property of an activity;</li>
   <li>association of a project, responsible organization and execution dates to activity and product data;</li>
   <li>the specification, classifications and required quantity of a resource;</li>
   <li>definition and grouping of resource requirements and resources;</li>
   <li>recording of resources used or consumed by activities, organizations and relationships;</li>
   <li>resource availability, planning, recording, allocation, issuing and relationships;</li>
   <li>definition, representation and assignment of property to a resource or related element;</li>
   <li>the identification and relationships of schemes and entries in scheme;</li>
   <li>association of scheme, dates, times and time intervals;</li>
   <li>definition of state and relationships between a state, type of state, product, activity, people or organization that it affects;</li>
   <li>identification and relationship between state and the product, activity, people or organization that it affects;</li>
   <li>assignment of a task and its specification as a sequence of instructions;</li>
   <li>association of pre/post conditions to a task or a stage within a task.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the response of a system to excitation; </li>
   <li>the representation of function or state based behavior;</li>
   <li>association of schedule with activity or product data;</li>   
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated work;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated person and organization;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated project breakdown;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of schedule associated project management information resources;</li>
   <li>the relationships between organization structure, project breakdown, project management information 
   resources and and work structure. </li>
</outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg3.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg4.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg5.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg6.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg7.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg8.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg9.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg10.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg11.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg12.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg13.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg14.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg15.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg16.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg17.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg18.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg19.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg20.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg21.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg22.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg23.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg24.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg25.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg26.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg27.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg28.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg29.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg30.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg31.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg32.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg33.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg34.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>


</module>
