<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.1 2004/10/25 18:23:20 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="schedule"
   part="1437"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="00000"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2004/10/25 18:23:20 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.1 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems engineering, schedule, scheme, project management
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of a data model that identifies activities, dependencies, 
     durations and milestones associated with products described in the WBS.  
     Includes the information necessary to produce Workflow Diagrams, Network 
     Schedules, Gantt Charts and Resource Leveling. </li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of a data model that identifies activities, dependencies, 
     durations and milestones associated with products described in the WBS.  
     Includes the information necessary to produce Workflow Diagrams, Network 
     Schedules, Gantt Charts and Resource Leveling. 
   </p>
   
   <p>From Systems Engineering encompasses the design and specification of systems, and 
   the planning and management of the engineering processes that design, manufacture, 
   field, and support that system. Within organizations and between organizations it 
   is beneficial to be able to exchange plans and schedules. These may be at a high 
   level where they deal with the tasks of work breakdown structure or at low and 
   detailed level where they coordinate individual workers. This module captures 
   information concerning schedules, resource allocation and leveling. That information 
   is needed to manage the life cycle process of developing and using a system such 
   that persons and organizations can coordinate their activities.</p>
   
   <p>From This AP233 business case module is constructed from several ISO/TS Application 
   modules.</p>

   <p>The Activity Module captures the definition of an activity. An activity is a 
   work element, function or task. It captures the relationship between two activities 
   that might be on sequential, concurrent, or alternative paths. It captures the 
   relationship between an activity and inputs and outputs from the activity, 
   i.e. the product or activity data that it generates or uses.</p>
   <p>The Activity as Realized Module captures planned or defined activities that 
   will occur in the future. It captures the historical occurrence of an activity and 
   the relationship of the planned activity to the actual historical occurrence of 
   the activity.</p>
   <p>The Activity Method Module captures identification and description of activity 
   detail, such how the transformation occurs. </p>
   <p>The Activity Method Assignment Module captures relationships between activity 
   methods. It captures the assignment of activity methods to product data.</p>
   <p>The Activity method implementation module provides the capability to associate 
   additional information with an activity method.</p>
   <p>The Attribute classification module provides the association of a value, 
   represented by a class, to an attribute on  an entity.</p>
   <p>The Classification assignment module provides assignment of classification 
   information to product or activity data.</p>
   <p>The Condition Module captures the conditions that impact an activity or its 
   execution. Condition is specified by a textual description with a logical result 
   or by external entities as input to a condition expression. It captures the 
   assignment of conditions to activities and relationships among conditions.</p>
   <p>The Event Model captures the characterization of an event. It captures 
   characterization of a relationship between two events and the characterization 
   of an event with respect to another event.</p>
   <p>The Management resource information module provides the:</p>
	<ul>faciulty to assign management data to product data;</ul>
	<ul>faciulty to assign management data to activity data;</ul>
	<ul>faciulty to assign management data to management data;</ul>
	<ul>assignment of management data to management data.</ul>
   <p>The Process property assignment Module capture the specification of a property 
   of an activity, the representation of a property of an activity, or the use of an 
   independent property in the definition of an activity. </p>
   <p>The Project Module captures the definition of a project and its responsible 
   organization. It captures its planned and actual execution dates. It captures the 
   association of a project to activity and product data and relationship between 
   two projects.</p>
   <p>The property assignment module provides for the:</p>
	<ul>Assignment of a property to product data;</ul>
	<ul>Use of an independent property in the definition of an item;</ul>
	<ul>Association of a representation with a property.</ul>
   <p>The Resource as Realized Module captures the recording of resources used or 
   consumed by activities. It captures the usage or consumption of actual resources 
   and types of resource items. It captures the relationship between the resource 
   actually applied and realized with the corresponding resource requirement statements. 
   It captures the relationship between the resource as realized and the corresponding 
   resource events.</p>
   <p>The Resource Item Module captures the definition of a resource and the 
   definition of a grouping of resources as a resource in its own right.</p>
   <p>The Resource Management Module captures the availability of a resource. It 
   captures the planning and recording of resource provision, the allocation and 
   issuing of a resource, and the relationships between allocated resources and 
   the corresponding resource requirements.</p>
   <p>The Resource Property Assignment Module captures the definition of a property 
   that may be associated with a resource or related element. It captures the 
   representation of a property that may be associated with a resource or related 
   element; the use of an independent property in the definition of a resource, 
   and the means to assign a property to a resource or related element. The entity 
   property includes time intervals.</p>
   <p>The Scheme Module captures the identification of schemes that support the 
   ordering of activities. It captures the identification of entries in a scheme, 
   and the association of dates and times with schemes and entries in schemes. It 
   captures the definition of relationships between entries within a scheme, 
   including dependencies and sequencing. It captures the definition of relationships 
   between schemes, and the definition of relationships between scheme entries and 
   schemes that expand on entries.</p>
   <p>The Task Specification Module captures the specification of a task as a 
   sequence of instructions encoded as text. It captures the specification of a 
   task as a structured set of instructions. It captures the association of 
   pre-conditions to a task or a stage within a task, the association of post-conditions 
   to a task or a stage within a task, and the assignment of a task.</p>
   <p>The time interval module …</p>
   <p>The time interval assignment module provides for the association of a time 
   interval with product or activity data.</p>

 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>######## Editorial note: Following list must be condensed down</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Activity   </li>
   <li>definition of an activity;</li>
   <li>relationship between two activities;</li>
   <li>relationship between an activity and the product or activity data that it affects or uses.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Activity as realized   </li>
   <li>the historical occurrence of an activity;</li>
   <li>the relationship of the historical occurrence of an activity to planned or defined activities.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Activity method   </li>
   <li>identification and description of an activity method.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Activity method assignment   </li>
   <li>relationships between activity methods;</li>
   <li>the assignment of activity methods to product data.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Activity method implementation.   </li>
   <li>the capability to associate additional information with an activity method.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Condition evaluation    </li>
   <li>identification of the evaluation of a condition specified by a textual  description that resulted in a logical;</li>
   <li>recording of parameter values evaluated and the logical result of  the evaluation.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Date time assignment   </li>
   <li>assignment of a date with a role to activity or product data;</li>
   <li>assignment of a date and time with a role to activity or product data.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Event   </li>
   <li>characterization of an event;</li>
   <li>characterization of a relationship between two events;</li>
   <li>characterization of an event with respect to another event.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Event assignment   </li>
   <li>association of an event with product or activity data</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Process property assignment    </li>
   <li>specification of a property of an activity;</li>
   <li>representation of a property of an activity;</li>
   <li>use of an independent property in the definition of an activity.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Project   </li>
   <li>definition of a project, of its responsible organization and of its planned and actual execution dates;</li>
   <li>association of a project to activity and product data;</li>
   <li>relationship between two projects.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Property_assignment   </li>
   <li>Assignment of a property to product data;</li>
   <li>Use of an independent property in the definition of an item;</li>
   <li>Association of a representation with a property.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Required resource   </li>
   <li>the specification of an actual items or type of item as required resources;</li>
   <li>the specification of classifications of required resources;</li>
   <li>the specification of the required quantity of a resource;</li>
   <li>the grouping of resource requirements.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Resource as realized   </li>
   <li>the recording of resources used or consumed by activities, organizations;</li>
   <li>the recording of usage or consumption of actual as well as types of resource items;</li>
   <li>the recording of the relationship between the resource as realized and the corresponding resource requirement statements;</li>
   <li>the recording of the relationship between the resource as realized and the corresponding resource events.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Resource item   </li>
   <li>the definition of a resources;</li>
   <li>the definition of a grouping of resources as a resource in its own right.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Resource management   </li>
   <li>the availability of a resource;</li>
   <li>the planning and recording of resource provision;</li>
   <li>the allocation and issuing of a resource;</li>
   <li>the relationships between allocated resources and the corresponding resource requirements.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Resource property assignment    </li>
   <li>the definition of a property that may be associated with a resource or related element;</li>
   <li>the representation of a property that may be associated with a resource or related element;</li>   
   <li>the use of an independent property in the definition of a resource;</li>
   <li>the means to assign a property to a resource or related element.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Scheme   </li>
   <li>the identification of schemes;</li>
   <li>the identification of entries in a scheme;</li>
   <li>the association of dates and times with schemes and entries in schemes;</li>
   <li>the definition of relationships between entries within a scheme, including dependencies and sequencing;</li>
   <li>the definition of relationships between schemes;</li>
   <li>the definition of relationships between scheme entries and schemes that expand on entries.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From State definition   </li>
   <li>definition of state;</li>
   <li>definition of what is needed for a state definition to exist;</li>
   <li>relationship between two or more state definitions;</li>
   <li>relationship between a state definition or type of state and the product, activity, people or organization that it affects.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From State observed   </li>
   <li>identification of individual or realized states;</li>
   <li>relationship between two or more states;</li>
   <li>relationship between an individual or realized state and the product, activity, people or organization that it affects.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Task specification   </li>
   <li>the specification of a task as a sequence of instructions encoded as text;</li>
   <li>the specification of a task as a structured set of instructions;</li>
   <li>the association of pre-conditions to a task or a stage within a task;</li>
   <li>the association of post-conditions to a task or a stage within a task;</li>
   <li>the assignment of a task.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Time interval   </li>
   <li>identification of a time interval;</li>
   <li>characterization of a bounded time interval;</li>
   <li>representation of a relationship between two time intervals.</li>
   <li>######## Editorial note: From Time interval assignment   </li>
   <li>association of a time interval with product or activity data.</li>

 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
    <li>xxxxx</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
