<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.23 2010/01/08 21:49:43 lothartklein Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="finite_element_analysis_definition_relationships"
   name.french="Rapports entre les d&#233;finitions d'analyses des &#233;l&#233;ments finis"
   part="107"
   version="1"
   wg.number="4311"
   wg.number.express="4312"
   checklist.internal_review="2242"
   checklist.project_leader="2243"
   checklist.convener="2244"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2006"
   publication.date="2006-04-01"
   published="y"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2010/01/08 21:49:43 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.23 $">

 <keywords>
    resource, finite element analysis, design, PDM, idealisation, module
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>ISO 10303-107:2006 specifies the association between idealised concepts within a finite element analysis and the design definitions of those concepts. 
    The concepts that are idealised within a finite element analysis include the action that is simulated, the states of the product, and the section properties.
 ISO 10303-107:2006 also specifies the association between a representation of a field that is calculated by a finite element analysis and a property of a defined state of a product.
 </p></abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="keithhunten"/>
   <editor ref="davidleal"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application resource for the
     representation of product information and for the exchange of product data. 
     The objective is to provide a neutral mechanism capable of describing products 
     throughout their life cycle. This mechanism is suitable not only for neutral file exchange, 
     but also as a basis for implementing and sharing product databases, and as a basis for archiving. 
     This part of ISO 10303 is a member of the integrated application resources series. 
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies the fea_definition_relationships_schema.
</p><p>
This part of ISO 10303 provides a means of associating finite element analysis information with 
information about the design and structure of a product. This part of ISO 10303 provides links 
between:</p>

<ul><li>finite element information specified by ISO 10303-104; and</li>

<li>both:<ul>
<li>the product and property definition information specified by ISO 10303-41; and</li>
<li>the product topology information specified by ISO 10303-42.</li>
</ul></li></ul>
 





<p>
These links enable the following actions to take place:</p>
<ul>
<li>a finite element analysis step can be linked to the design specification of the action that the finite element analysis step simulates;
</li></ul>
<note number="1"> This provides additional information about the analysis step, and a navigation route to the analysis step using a Product Data Management (PDM) system.</note>
<ul><li>
a finite element analysis state can be linked to the design specification of the product state that it calculates;
</li></ul>
<note number="2"> This provides additional information about the analysis state, and a navigation route to the analysis state using a PDM system. </note>
<ul><li>
a surface or curve section property can be linked to the design specification of the section;
</li></ul>
<note number="3"> This provides additional information about the section and its properties. The design specification of a variation of surface section properties with respect to position can be specified using ISO 10303-51 and ISO 10303-50.</note>
<ul><li>
an FEA node, FEA element or aspect of an FEA element can be linked to the topology of a product.
</li></ul>
<note number="4">This provides a direct link between the features of a product as identified by its CAD topology and FEA. This will enable the results from an analysis to be related to a design feature.</note>
<p>
The relationships of the schemas in this part of ISO 10303 to other schemas that define the integrated resources of this International Standard are illustrated in Figure 1 using the EXPRESS-G notation. EXPRESS-G is defined in annex D of ISO 10303-11. 

Figure 1 - Schema relationships for Product and model relationship


   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="Relationship between schemas in ISO 10303-107"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>an association between a set of a finite element analysis steps and the design or specification for an action;</li>
   <li>an association between a finite element analysis state and a design or specification for a product state;</li>
    <li>an association between a finite element analysis result and a property which is possessed by a product state;</li>
   <li>an association between a surface or curve section property in a finite element model and a property which is possessed by a product; </li>
   <li>an association between a node or element in a finite element model and an aspect of the topology of the product. 
</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the identification or description of an action;</li>
   <li>the identification or description of a product, or state of a product; </li>
   <li>the identification or description of a property;</li>
   <li>the topology of a product;</li>
   <li>a finite element model of a product.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 
 <normref.inc normref="ref8824-1"/> 
<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1">
<term.ref linkend="term_product"/> <!-- product -->
       </normref.inc>
      <normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.2004"/>
       <normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
         <normref.inc normref="ref10303-42"/>
  <normref.inc normref="ref10303-51">
   <term.ref linkend="independent_property_definition"/> <!-- "independent property definition"-->
 <term.ref linkend="property"/> <!-- "property"-->
 <term.ref linkend="property_space"/> <!-- "property space"-->
 </normref.inc>
     <normref.inc normref="ref10303-53"/>
    <normref.inc normref="ref10303-56"/>
     <normref.inc normref="ref10303-104">
      <term.ref linkend="analysis_step"/> <!-- analysis step -->
       </normref.inc>


 </normrefs>
<!--
 <definition/>
-->
 
 

<abbreviations>
		<abbreviation id="D">
			<acronym>D</acronym>
			<term>Dimension (as in 1D, 2D, 3D)</term>
			</abbreviation>	
		<abbreviation id="FEA">
			<acronym>FEA</acronym>
			<term>Finite Element Analysis</term>
		</abbreviation>		
		<abbreviation id="PDM">
			<acronym>PDM</acronym>
			<term>Product Data Management</term>
			</abbreviation>	
		<abbreviation id="URL">
			<acronym>URL</acronym>
			<term>Universal Resource Locator</term>	
		</abbreviation>		
</abbreviations>
<schema name="product_and_model_relationships_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   The product_and_model_relationships_schema specifies the relationship between:
   <ul><li>an idealisation of a product as a domain of an analysis; and</li>
   <li>a discretised model of a product for analysis.</li></ul>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>Within ISO 10303, the following are separate concepts:
   <ul><li>the design defintion of a product;</li></ul>
   <note number="1">The design definition of a product is recorded using ISO 10303-41.</note>
   <ul><li>the idealisation of a product for analysis;</li></ul>
<note number="2">A single design definition can have many idealisations for analysis.</note>
<note number="3">The idealisations of a product for analysis can be recorded using ISO 10303-41 or using ISO 10303-53.</note>
   <ul><li>the discretised model of a product for analysis.</li></ul>
   <note number="4">An idealisation for analysis can have many discretised models created for it.</note>
   <note number="5">The discretised model of a product for analysis can be recorded using either ISO 10303-104, or ISO 10303-53.</note><p>
   The ISO 10303 series of parts allows a single idealisation for analysis to be recorded in different ways, and allows a disctretised model to be recorded in different ways.  This part of ISO 10303 associates a discretised model of a product with the corresponding idealisation of the product, irrespective of the way in which they are recorded. </p>
<p>This part of ISO 10303 can also specify that: </p>
<ul><li>different records of an idealisation of a product for analysis have the same meaning; and</li>
<li>different records of a discretised model of a product have the same meaning.</li></ul>
</fund_cons>
<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="product_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
       <imgfile file="product_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="action_and_model_relationships_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>The action_and_model_relationships_schema specifies the relationship between:
   <ul><li>an idealisation of a product as a domain of an analysis; and</li>
   <li>a discretised model of a product for analysis.</li></ul>
   </introduction>
     <fund_cons>Within ISO the following are separate concepts:
     <ul><li>the design definition of a product;</li></ul>
     <note number="1">The design definition of a product is recorded using ISO 10303-41.</note>
     <ul><li>the idealisation of a product for analysis;</li></ul>
     <note number="2">A single design definition can have many idealisations for analysis.</note>
     <note number="3">The idealisation of a product for analysis can be recorded using ISO 10303-41. </note>
     <ul><li>the discretised model of a product for analysis;</li></ul>
     <note number="4">An idealisation for analysis can have many discretised models created for it. </note>
     <note number="5">The discretised model of a product for analysis can be recorded using either ISO 10303-104, or ISO 10303-53. </note>
     <p>The ISO 10303 series of parts allows a single idealisation for analysis to be recorded in different ways, and allows a discretised model to be recorded in different ways. This part of ISO 10303 associates a discretised model of a product with the corresponding idealisation of the product, irrespective of the way in which they are recorded.</p>
     <p>This part of ISO 10303 can also specify that:</p>
     <ul><li>different records of an idealisation of a product for analysis have the same meaning; and</li>
     <li>different records of a discretised model of a product have the same meaning.</li>
     </ul>
     
     </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
      <imgfile file="action_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="action_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="state_and_model_relationships_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>The state_and_model_relationships schema specifies the relationship between:
   <ul><li>an idealisation of a state as a domain of an analysis; and</li>
   <li>a discretised model of a state for analysis.</li></ul>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   Within ISO 10303, the following are separate concepts:
   
   <ul><li>the design definition of a state; </li></ul>
     <note number="1"> The design definition of a state is recorded using ISO 10303-56.</note>
     <ul><li>the idealisation of a state for analysis;</li></ul>
     <note number="2">A single design definition can have many idealisations for analysis.</note>
     <note number="3">The idealisation for a state for analysis can be recorded using ISO 10303-56, or using ISO 10303-53.</note>
     <ul><li>The discretised model of a state for analysis</li></ul>
       <note number="4">An idealisation for analysis can have many discretised models created for it.</note> 
     <note number="5">The discretised model of a state for analysis can be recorded using either ISO 10303-104, or ISO 10303-53.</note>
   <p>The ISO 10303 series of parts allows a single idealisation for analysis te be recorded in different ways, and allows a discretised model to be recorded in different ways. This part of ISO 10303 associates a discretised model of a state with the corresponding idealisation of the state, irrespective of the way in which they are recorded.
   </p>
   <p>This part of ISO 10303 can also specify that: </p>
   <ul><li>different records of an idealisation of a state for analysis have the same meaning; and</li>
   <li>different records of a discretised model of a state have the same meaning.</li></ul>
  
    </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
        <imgfile file="state_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="state_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="property_distribution_and_model_relationships_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   The property_distribution_and_model_relationships_schema specifies the relationship between:
    <ul><li>a property distribution; and</li>
    <li>a discretised model of a property distribution for numerical analysis.</li></ul>
    </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   Within ISO 10303, the following are separate concepts:
   <ul><li>the distribution of a property over an idealised product, action or state;</li></ul>
     <note number="1">A property distribution over an idealised product, action or state can be recorded using ISO 10303-41, or using ISO 13030-53. </note>
  <ul><li>the discretised model of a property distribution for numerical analysis</li></ul>
     <note number="2">A property distribution can have many discretised models created for it.</note>
     <note number="3">The discretised model of a property distribution obtained by analysis can be recorded using either ISO 10303-104, or ISO 10303-53.</note>
  The ISO 10303 series of parts allows a single property distribution to be recorded in different ways, and allows a discretised model of a property distribution to be recorded in different ways. This part of ISO 10303 associates a discretised model of a property distribution with the corresponding distribution, irrespective of the way in which they are recorded.
  
    </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
        <imgfile file="property_distribution_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="property_distribution_and_model_relationships_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<schema name="fea_definition_relationships_schema" version="1">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   The fea_definition_relationships_schema specifies relationships between the definitions of a beam or shell section property and the idealisations of these definitions for finite element analysis.
<p>The fea_definition_relationships_schema also specifies the relationships between:</p>
    <ul><li>a topological region; and</li>
    <li>a topological vertex;</li></ul>
       <p>and a corresponding finite element model, single finite element, or node.</p>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
  A finite element analysis is based upon an idealisation of an activity, state, property distribution, or shell or beam section. A single activity, state, property distribution, or shell or beam section can have many different idealisations that are used in, or created by, many different finite element analyses.
     <note>This schema provides links between the definitions of concepts contained in ISO 10303-41, and the FEA idealisations of them contained in ISO 10303-104.</note>
  
    </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
        <imgfile file="fea_definition_relationships_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="fea_definition_relationships_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="fea_definition_relationships_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>
<shortnames>
<shortname name="ACVWRL" entity="action_view_relationship"/>
<shortname name="SDAM" entity="same_discretised_action_model"/>
<shortname name="SMIDAC" entity="same_idealised_action"/>
<shortname name="ELTPRL" entity="element_topological_relationship"/>
<shortname name="FBSIR" entity="fea_beam_section_idealisation_relationship"/>
<shortname name="FMTO" entity="fea_model_topological_relationship"/>
<shortname name="SSDIR" entity="fea_shell_section_distribution_idealisation_relationship"/>
<shortname name="FSSIR" entity="fea_shell_section_idealisation_relationship"/>
<shortname name="NDTPRL" entity="node_topological_relationship"/>
<shortname name="PRVWRL" entity="product_view_relationship"/>
<shortname name="DSVWRL" entity="distribution_view_relationship"/>
<shortname name="SDDM" entity="same_discretised_distribution_model"/>
<shortname name="SMIDDS" entity="same_idealised_distribution"/>
<shortname name="STVWRL" entity="state_view_relationship"/>
<shortname name="SDSM" entity="same_discretised_state_model"/>
<shortname name="SMIDST" entity="same_idealised_state"/>
 </shortnames>
 

          


 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

 <!--  <bibliography -->
</resource>

