<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id: arm.xml,v 1.3 2002/01/16 14:23:55 robbod Exp $ -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../xsl/express.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE express SYSTEM "../../../dtd/express.dtd">
<express
  language_version="2"
  rcs.date="$Date: 2002/01/16 14:23:55 $"
  rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.3 $">

  <application
    name="express2xml.js"
    owner="Eurostep Limited"
    url="http://www.eurostep.com"
    version="1.6"
    source="../data/modules/document_structure/arm.exp"/>

  <schema name="Document_structure_arm">
    <interface
      kind="use"
      schema="Document_definition_arm">
    </interface>

    <interface
      kind="use"
      schema="Document_and_version_identification_arm">
    </interface>

    <interface
      kind="use"
      schema="File_identification_arm">
    </interface>

    <entity
      name="Document_version_relationship">
      <description>A <b>Document_version_relationship</b> is a relationship between <b>Document_versions</b>.</description>
      <explicit
        name="relation_type">
      <description>The relation_type specifies the meaning of the relationship.
<p>Where applicable the following values shall be used:</p>
<p>'derivation': The application object defines a deriving relationship where the related Document_versions is based on the relating Document_version which is an earlier version of the same or of a different Document;</p>
<p>'hierarchy': The application object defines a hierarchical relationship where the related Document_version is a sub version of the relating Document_version;</p>
<example>'Revision 1.1' and 'revision 1.2' are examples of sub-versions of 'version 1'.</example>
<p>'sequence': The application object defines a version sequence where the relating Document_version is the preceding version and the related Document_version is the following version. Each document shall be referred to by at most one Document_version_relationship as related and a 'relation_type' of 'sequence';</p>
<p>'supplied document': The application object defines a relationship between two Document_version objects representing the same object in different organizational contexts.</p></description>
        <builtintype
          type="STRING"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="description"
        optional="YES">
      <description>The description specifies additional information about the Document_version_relationship.</description>
        <builtintype
          type="STRING"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="relating_document_version">
      <description>The related specifies the second of the two Document_versions related by the Document_version_relationship.</description>
        <typename
          name="Document_version"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="related_document_version">
      <description>The related specifies the second of the two Document_versions related by the Document_version_relationship.</description>
        <typename
          name="Document_version"/>
      </explicit>
    </entity>

    <entity
      name="Document_definition_relationship">
      <description>A <b>Document_definition_relationship</b> is a relationship between <b>Document_definition</b>s.</description>
      <explicit
        name="relation_type">
      <description>The relation_type specifies the meaning of the relationship. 
<p>Where applicable the following values shall be used:</p>
<p>'addition': The application object specifies that the related document provides supplementary or collateral information with regard to the information provided by the relating document;</p>
<p>'copy': The application object defines a relationship where the related Document_definition is a copy of the relating Document_definition;</p>
<p>'decomposition': The application object defines a relationship where the related Document_definition is one of potentially more sub documents of the relating Document_definition;</p>
<example number="1">The decomposition of a document into clauses is an example for the use of this value.</example>
<p>'derivation': The application object defines a relationship where the related Document_definition is derived from the relating Document_definition;</p>
<example number="2">A raster image may be derived from a 3D CAD model.</example>

<example number="3">A html version may be derived from a text document as an alternative.</example>
<p>'peer': The application object specifies that the related document provides required information with regard to that provided by the relating document. The peer document is essential for a complete understanding;</p>
<p>'reference': The application object defines a relationship where the related document is referenced from the relating;</p>
<example number="4">A hyperlink is an example for a 'reference'.</example>
<p>'sequence': The application object defines a logical sequence where the related Document_definition comes after the relating Document_definition;</p>
<example number="5">A sequence of clauses.</example>
<p>'substitution': The application object defines a relationship where the related Document_definition replaces the relating Document_definition;</p>
<p>'translation': The Document_definition_relationship specifies that the related document is generated through a translation process from the relating document.</p> </description>
        <builtintype
          type="STRING"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="description"
        optional="YES">
      <description>The description specifies additional information about the Document_definition_relationship.</description>
        <builtintype
          type="STRING"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="relating_document_definition">
      <description>The related specifies the first of the two Document_definition related by the Document_definition_relationship.</description>
        <typename
          name="Document_definition"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="related_document_definition">
      <description>The related specifies the second of the two Document_definition related by the Document_definition_relationship.</description>
        <typename
          name="Document_definition"/>
      </explicit>
    </entity>

    <entity
      name="File_relationship">
      <description>A <b>File_relationship</b> is a relationship between two <b>File</b> objects. It specifies that the related File is referenced from the relating File. 
<example number="1"> A service manual may contain graphics for explanatory reasons. In this case the File objects that contain the graphics are referenced as related from the File object that contains the body of the service manual with relation_type 'reference'.</example></description>
      <explicit
        name="relation_type">
      <description>
The relation_type specifies the meaning of the relationship. The values 'addition', 'decomposition', and 'peer' are only allowed if neither the relating nor the related File are included in a Document_definition. 
<p>Where applicable the following values shall be used:</p>

<p>'addition': The application object specifies that the related document provides supplementary or collateral information with regard to the information provided by the relating document;</p>
<example number="2">The recommended practices for this part of ISO 10303 may be an addition.</example>
<p>'copy': The application object defines a relationship where the related File is a copy of the relating File;</p>
'decomposition': The application object defines a relationship where the related File is one of potentially more sub documents of the relating File; 
<example number="3">The decomposition of a document into clauses or into several CAD models is an example for 'decomposition'.</example>
<p>'derivation': The application object defines a relationship where the related File is derived from the relating File;</p>
<example number="4">The derivation of a hypertext document from an text document is an example for 'derivation'.</example>
<p>'peer': The application object specifies that the related document provides required information with regard to that provided by the relating document. The peer document is essential for a complete understanding;</p>
'reference': The application object defines a relationship where the related document is referenced from the relating one; 
<example number="5">The link in a hypertext document may be a reference.</example>
<p>'sequence': The application object defines a logical sequence where the related File comes after the relating File;</p>
<example number="6">A sequence of clauses is an example for 'sequence'.</example>
<p>'substitution': The application object defines a relationship where the related File replaces the relating File;</p>
<p>'translation': The application object specifies that the related document is generated through a translation process from the relating document.</p>
<p>The values 'addition', 'decomposition', and 'peer' are used for the purpose of creating logical structures of documents. These values shall only be used for the relation_type of File_relationship, if the referenced File objects do not participate in a Document_definition. In the latter case, Document_definition_relationship shall be used instead.</p>

</description>
        <builtintype
          type="STRING"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="description"
        optional="YES">
      <description>The description specifies additional information about the File_relationship.</description>
        <builtintype
          type="STRING"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="relating_document_file">
      <description>The related specifies the first of the two Files related by the File_relationship.</description>
        <typename
          name="File"/>
      </explicit>
      <explicit
        name="related_document_file">
      <description>The related specifies the second of the two Files related by the File_relationship.</description>
        <typename
          name="File"/>
      </explicit>
    </entity>

  </schema>

</express>
