<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.24 2014/01/27 18:20:13 darla Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="mechanical_design_shaded_presentation"
   name.french="Conception m&#233;canique en pr&#233;sentation ombr&#233;e"
   part="518"
   version="3"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="8438"
   wg.number.express="8487"
   wg.number.supersedes="6182"
   wg.number.express.supersedes="6183"
   checklist.internal_review="6184"
   checklist.project_leader="6185"
   checklist.convener="6186"
   status="IS"
   language="E"
   publication.year="2013"
   publication.date="2013-03-01" 
   published="y"
   previous.revision.year="2011" 
   previous.revision.cancelled="Yes"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2014/01/27 18:20:13 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.24 $">

 <keywords>
    AIC, visual presentation, projection, camera model, colour shaded.
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>
		This document specifies the use of ISO 10303 application interpreted construct satisfying the requirements for mechanical
		design shaded presentations. 
		This part of ISO 10303 is mainly based on ISO 10303-46. 
		Point, curve, and surface styles may be specified for the constituents of any shape representation. 
		Shading and surface characteristics, such as reflectance and transparency are included. 
		The concept of layers is out of scope, as is the representation of text.
	</p>
 </abstract>

	<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="simon.frechette"/>
   <editor ref="lothar.klein"/>
 </contacts>
	<changes>
		<change_edition version="2">
			<schema.changes schema_name="aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentation">
				<description>Unidentified changes.</description>
			</schema.changes>
		</change_edition>
		<change_edition version="3">
			<schema.changes schema_name="aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentation">
				<schema.modifications>
					<modified.object name="presentation_organization_schema" type="USE_FROM"></modified.object>
				</schema.modifications>
			</schema.changes>
		</change_edition>
	</changes>
 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
      This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application resource for the
     description of advanced visual presentations
	of the shape of mechanical design models. 
	Shape is projected into a plane display area. 
	The projections themselves are not represented, however the shape and corresponding projection algorithms are given. 
	Basic presentation attributes are included, such as line font and colour, and more advanced
	functionality, such as light sources and surface reflectance. 
	The latter are used to provide a more realistic presentation of properties. 
	All presentation attributes may be applied to parts or all of wireframe, surface, and solid models. 
	Association of attributes with topological items is included to provide for the styling of
	high level shape constructs. 
	The representation of annotation, such as text and symbols, is not specified. 
   </p>
	<p>
		Technical modifications to the first edition of this part of ISO 10303 are categorised as follows: changes to the EXPRESS
		declarations, new EXPRESS declarations, and changes to definitions of EXPRESS entity data types.
	</p>
	
	<!-- aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentation -->
	<p>The following aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentation EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been modified:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation.</li>
	</ul>
	
	<p>The following aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentation EXPRESS declarations and interface specifications have been added:</p>
	<ul>
		<li>USE FROM product_property_representation_schema.</li>
	</ul>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>  -->

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <scope>
	    Basic presentation attributes, such as
		colour, can be associated with points, curves, surfaces, and topological constructs. Advanced visualization
		properties, such as surface reflectance and transparency, can be applied to curves and surfaces. The
		projection algorithm includes light sources and hidden line and hidden surface removal. The description
		of annotation is not included.
 	<p/>
 </scope>
 <inscope>
 	   <li>the visual presentation of mechanical design shape representations;</li>
	   <li>the assignment of visual presentation attributes to geometric and topological items;</li>
	   <li>algorithms for the projection of 3D shapes onto planes;</li>
	   <li>the location of shape projections within a window;</li>
	   <li>multiple views within one window;</li>
	   <li>the background colour of a window;</li>
	   <li>hidden line and hidden surface removal;</li>
	   <li>light sources;</li>
	   <li>point, curve, and surface colour;</li>
	   <li>point font;</li>
	   <li>curve font;</li>
	   <li>
	   	curve styles dependent on the role of the curves in the definition of a surface;
	   	<example>
	   		Boundary curves and grid curves play different roles in the definition of a surface.
	   	</example>
	   </li>
	   <li>shaded and unshaded surface colour;</li>
	   <li>surface characteristics such as transparency and reflectance;</li>
	   <li>pre-defined colours;</li>
	   <li>pre-defined curve styles.</li>	
 	</inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the presentation of annotation, i.e. text and symbols;</li>
   <li>the assignment of geometric items to layers;</li>
   <li>multiple windows;</li>
   <li>representation of products.
   		<note>
   			The scope of this part of ISO 10303 is closely related to ISO 10303-517. 
   			This part extends the scope of ISO 10303-517 to also include hidden line and hidden surface representations, light sources, and
			curve and surface rendering.
   		</note>
   </li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_abstract_test_suite"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_context"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_interpreted_construct"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_protocol"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_data_exchange"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_externally_defined"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_generic_resource"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_implementation_method"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_interpretation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_model"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_predefined"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_presentation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_structure"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-42">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_curve"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_surface"/>
 	</normref.inc>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-43"/>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-46">
 		<term.ref linkend="annotation"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="layer"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="picture"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="presentation_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="rgb"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="realistic_presentation_of_properties"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="symbol_46"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="synthetic_camera_model"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="visualization"/>
 	</normref.inc> 	
 </normrefs>

<!-- 
 <definition/>
-->
 <abbreviations>
 	<abbreviation id="AIC">
 		<acronym>AIC</acronym>
 		<term>Application Interpreted Construct</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	
 	<abbreviation id="AP">
 		<acronym>AP</acronym>
 		<term>Application Protocol</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	
 	<abbreviation id="ATS">
 		<acronym>ATS</acronym>
 		<term>Abstract Test Suite</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 	
 	<abbreviation id="RGB">
 		<acronym>RGB</acronym>
 		<term>Red, Green, Blue colour space</term>
 	</abbreviation>
 </abbreviations>


<schema name="aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentation" version="2">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
	   	This application interpreted construct provides a consistent set of entities for the representation of pictures
		of mechanical products that are in the design stage. 
		All pictures shall be presented in the same window on a display. 
		A picture may include one or several views of a product shape. 
		Using this part of ISO 10303 only the association between a product shape and its projection algorithms is represented, not
		the projections themselves.
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
	<p>
		The structure for the management of pictures is implemented using entities <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_area</b>, 
		<b>presentation_view</b>, and <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation</b>. 
		The relationships between these entities are represented using the <b>mapped_item</b> and <b>representation_map</b> entities. 
		A <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation</b> is a subtype of <b>presentation_area</b>. 
		This subtype has been created for the purpose of this part of ISO 10303. 
		All the contents of a window, that is the views on one or several product shapes, shall be included in one
		<b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_area</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		A view is represented by a <b>presentation_view</b>. 
		The view shall contain entity <b>camera_image_3d_with_scale</b>, which for the purpose of this part of ISO 10303 
		has been created as a subtype of <b>camera_image</b> and, thus, of <b>mapped_item</b>. 
		Via <b>camera_usage</b> this entity references <b>camera_model_d3</b> as its <b>mapping_origin</b>, 
		which has the information that is necessary to compute the projection of a shape. 
		To allow more realistic presentations of a product shape, hidden line and hidden surface removal, as well
		as light sources, can be specified using the subtypes of <b>camera_model_d3</b>, <b>camera_model_d3_with_hlhsr</b>, 
		and <b>camera_model_with_light_sources</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		The product shape itself is linked into the presentation hierarchy by <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation</b>, 
		which has also been created for the purpose of this part of ISO 10303.
		This entity shall be referenced as the <b>mapped_representation</b> of a <b>camera_image_3d_with_scale</b>. 
		All <b>items</b> of a <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation</b> shall be either <b>styled_item</b>s that
		describe shape, <b>camera_model_d3</b>s, or <b>mapped_item</b>s. <b>Mapped_item</b>s shall be mappings of either
		<b>shape_representation</b>s or of other <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation</b>s. 
		The <b>item</b> of a <b>styled_item</b> may either reference directly a <b>geometric_representation_item</b> or a <b>topological_representation_item</b>, 
		or indirectly via a <b>mapped_item</b> that is the mapping of a <b>shape_representation</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		The appearance of product shape may be specified using styles for <b>point</b>s, <b>curve</b>s, and <b>surface</b>s. 
		Styles may also be assigned to topological elements of product shape. 
		A style assignment is made by instantiating a <b>styled_item</b>, which refers to a <b>representation_item</b> together with 
		its <b>presentation_style_assignment</b>. 
		The <b>representation_item</b> may be a <b>mapped_item</b> that references a <b>shape_representation</b> as its <b>mapped_representation</b>. 
		The <b>styled_item</b>s are collected into a <b>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation</b>, as mentioned above.
	</p>
	<p>
		The <b>presentation_style_assignment</b> of a <b>styled_item</b> affects the appearance of the referenced <b>representation_item</b> 
		as well as the appearance of all <b>representation_item</b>s referenced directly or indirectly by that item. 
		Only those <b>representation_item</b>s are affected that are not already styled. 
		This means styling a styled <b>representation_item</b> has no effect. 
		Styling a partially styled <b>representation_item</b> affects only the appearance of the unstyled parts. 
		Styling an unstyled <b>representation_item</b> affects the appearance of the whole item. 
		Only styled <b>representation_item</b>s may be presented. 
		Whether they are actually presented depends also on other facts, like <b>invisibility</b>. 
		This part of ISO 10303 does not make any statement about the effect if style conflicts occur.
	</p>
			<example>
				A style conflict occurs, for example, when a <b>representation_item</b> is used by several <b>styled_item</b>s.
			</example>
	<p>
		A <b>presentation_style_assignment</b> is used to assign styles to a <b>representation_item</b> independently from
		any presentation context. 
		A subtype of <b>presentation_style_assignment</b>, the <b>presentation_style_by_context</b>, allows the assignment 
		of style for a specific presentation context. 
		A presentation context can be any <b>representation</b> or <b>representation_item</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		<b>Point_style</b>s allow the specification of the marker symbol, marker size, and colour to be used for presenting points.
	</p>
	<p>
		<b>Curve_style</b>s allow the specification of curve fonts, curve width, and colour. 
		The appearance of curve ends and corners, and of patterns for filling visible curve segments is not distinguished. 
		A curve font specifies whether a curve shall be drawn using solid, dashed, or dotted lines. 
		The specification of arbitrary patterns for curve fonts and the usage of externally defined curve fonts are not included. 
		Curve fonts may be pre–defined. 
		The entities used for the definition of curve fonts are <b>draughting_pre_defined_curve_font</b> and <b>curve_style_font</b>. 
		The curve width shall be specified as a measure value. 
		The <b>curve_style_rendering</b> controls the rendering of curves on a surface and is described together with surface styles below.
	</p>
	<p>
		Surface styles provide the resources to specify the visual appearance of surfaces. 
		Separate surface styles may be applied to each side of a surface using entities <b>surface_style_usage</b> and <b>surface_side_style</b>. 
		A surface side style may be any combination of fill area style, boundary style, silhouette style, segmentation
		curve style, control grid style, parameter line style, or rendering style.
	</p>
	<p>
		A fill area style specifies a style for presenting visible surfaces by mapping a coloured fill area upon them.
	</p>
	<p>
		A boundary style specifies a curve style for presenting the boundary curves of a surface. 
		If no boundary style is specified, the boundary curves shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A silhouette style specifies a curve style for presenting the silhouette curves of a surface. 
		If no silhouette style is specified, silhouette curves shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A segmentation curve style specifies a curve style for presenting the segmentation curves of a surface.
		This style affects only surfaces which are divided into segments, such as B–spline surfaces. 
		If no segmentation curve style is specified, segmentation curves shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A control grid style specifies a curve style for presenting the mesh of control points which are used for the
		definition of a surface. 
		This style affects only surfaces which are defined over a mesh of control points,
		such as B–spline surfaces. 
		If no control grid style is specified, the control grid shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		A parameter line style specifies a curve style for presenting iso–parameter lines of a surface. 
		The number of parameter lines in each parameter direction has to be specified for this style. 
		If no parameter line style is specified, the parameter lines shall not be presented.
	</p>
	<p>
		The entities defining these surface styles are <b>surface_fill_area</b>, <b>surface_style_boundary</b>, <b>surface_style_silhouette</b>, 
		<b>surface_style_segmentation_curve</b>, <b>surface_style_control_grid</b>, and <b>surface_style_parameter_line</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		The entities <b>curve_style_rendering</b> and <b>surface_rendering_propertie</b>s specify the rendering method
		and properties for curves on a surface. 
		A rendering style specifies the method which shall be used for rendering the surface. 
		If this style is specified, surface rendering using reflectance calculations is performed
		for presenting the surface. 
		For this style, a colour shall be specified for the surface. 
		Additional rendering properties including transparency and ambient, diffuse, and specular reflectance coefficients can
		optionally be specified. 
		The entities for rendering styles are <b>surface_style_rendering</b>, <b>surface_style_rendering_with_properties</b>, 
		<b>surface_style_transparent</b>, <b>surface_style_reflectance_ambient</b>, <b>surface_style_reflectance_ambient_diffuse</b>, 
		and <b>surface_style_reflectance_ambient_diffuse_specular</b>. 
		Pre–defined surface styles are not included.
	</p>
	<p>
		Colours may be specified based on the RGB colour model using entity <b>colour_rgb</b> or by <b>draughting_pre_defined_colour</b>.
	</p>
	<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 does not include constructs for the representation of annotation.
	</p>
	<p>
		The following entities are intended to be independently instantiated in the application protocol schemas that use this AIC:
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>camera_image_3d_with_scale;</li>
		<li>draughting_pre_defined_colour;</li>
		<li>draughting_pre_defined_curve_font;</li>
		<li>invisibility;</li>
		<li>mapped_item;</li>
		<li>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_area;</li>
		<li>mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation;</li>
		<li>over_riding_styled_item;</li>
		<li>presentation_style_by_context.</li>
	</ul>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentationexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="aic_mechanical_design_shaded_presentationexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>  
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="MDSPA" entity="mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_area"/>
 	<shortname name="MDSPR" entity="mechanical_design_shaded_presentation_representation"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->

 <bibliography>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-517"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
 </bibliography>

</resource>

