<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.48 2017/06/17 19:18:04 brandonus Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="representation_structures" 
   name.french="Structures de repr&#233;sentation"
   part="43" 
   version="5"
   object.reg.version="5"
   wg.number="9560" 
   wg.number.supersedes="9205"
   checklist.internal_review="9532" 
   checklist.project_leader="9533" 
   checklist.convener="9534"
   status="IS" 
   language="E" 
   publication.year="2017-12"
   publication.date="2017-12-15" 
   published="n" 
   previous.revision.year="2016-02" 
   previous.revision.cancelled="NO"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2017/06/17 19:18:04 $" 
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.48 $" 
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    resource, integrated generic resources, representation, coordinate space, transformation
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <p>
    ISO 10303-43 specifies the resource constructs that group elements of product data into collections 
    in order to describe aspects of products.
	</p>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="simon.frechette"/>
   <editor ref="lothar.klein"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Change History -->
<changes>
	<change_edition version="2">
		<schema.changes schema_name="representation_schema">
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="representation"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="uncertainty_measure_with_unit"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="acyclic_mapped_representation"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="item_in_context"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="using_representations"/>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="compound_item_definition"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="founded_item_select"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="list_representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="set_representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="compound_representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="founded_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="representation_item_relationship"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="uncertainty_assigned_representation"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="value_representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="using_items"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="valid_measure_value"/>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
	<change_edition version="3">
		<schema.changes schema_name="representation_schema">
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="binary_representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="bytes_representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="definitional_representation_relationship"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="definitional_representation_relationship_with_same_context"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="acyclic_representation_relationship"/>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="founded_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="mapped_item"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="representation_item"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="acyclic_mapped_representation"/>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
	<change_edition version="4">
		<schema.changes schema_name="representation_schema">
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object name="list_item_defined_transformation" type="TYPE"/>
				<modified.object name="set_item_defined_transformation" type="TYPE"/>
				<modified.object name="get_representation_for_items" type="TYPE"/>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object name="transformation" type="TYPE"/>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
	<change_edition version="5">
		<schema.changes schema_name="representation_schema">
			<schema.additions>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="representation_context_reference"/>
				<modified.object type="ENTITY" name="representation_reference"/>
				<modified.object type="TYPE" name="representation_or_representation_reference"/>
				<modified.object type="FUNCTION" name="get_representations_for_items"/>
			</schema.additions>
			<schema.modifications>
				<modified.object name="representation_map" type="ENTITY"/>
				<modified.object name="representation_relationship" type="ENTITY"/>
			</schema.modifications>
		</schema.changes>
	</change_edition>
</changes>	

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
 <p>
 	The representation_schema specifies the overall structure for representation. Collections of elements can be
	formed to act as the representation of some aspect of product data, such as a property of a product. Each
	element in such a collection is a representation item. An example of a property that can be represented
	is the shape of a product. The aspect or property that is being represented is not specified in this part of
	ISO 10303. Instead the subject of the representation is defined where the capabilities for representation
	are used in other parts of ISO 10303.
 </p>
 <p>
 	When representation items are collected to participate in a representation, they share a common context
	which is associated with the representation. This context is referred to as a representation context.
 </p>
 <p>
 	Not all elements of product data participate in representations. Those items which can participate in
	representations are defined to be representation items. Representation items are those elements that have
	complete meaning only when associated with a context. As an example, a point is a representation item
	which is only meaningful within a context (a coordinate space). In contrast, the name of a person is not
	a representation item because it has meaning separate from any context.
 </p>
 <p>
 	In addition to being an element of representation, a representation item can also support the definition
	of other representation items. This part of ISO 10303 allows for this distinction.	
 </p>
 <p>
 	A collection of product data can contain numerous representation items, each participating in one or more
	representations. These representations can be related to form a structure which also relates the
	representation contexts. This structure can then be used to determine which representation items can be
	related to each other in a meaningful way. As an example, distance between points is only meaningful if
	the coordinate systems in which the points are defined can be related.
 </p>
 <p>
 	Representations that are unrelated in one context can be related in another. Consider the representation
	of the shape of a part and its components. The shape of each component can be represented as an
	independent concept, unrelated to the shape of the other components. In the context of the assembled part,
	however, the shapes of the components are related.
 </p>
 <p>
 	An aspect of product data can have zero, one, or multiple representations, none of which are the concept
	itself. For example, the shape of a part can be represented by a collection both of two-dimensional
	geometry and of constructive solid geometry. Either representation is an idealization of the shape.
 </p>
 <p>
 	Each representation is not necessarily a complete model of some aspect of product data, but it can
	represent a model of the aspect that is suitable for specific applications. Neither shape representation in
	the previous paragraph is necessarily a complete representation of the shape concept. Another shape
	representation might include tolerance information. Rather, each representation is suitable to some specific
	application’s view or approach.
 </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 
 <schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml" title="Relationship of the representation_schema to the ISO 10303 integration architecture"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag>

 <scope>
   These are collections of elements of product data that are grouped together in order to describe properties and aspects of products.
 </scope>
 
 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>the specification of contexts for representation;</li>
   <li>the specification of elements of representation;</li>
   <li>the association of elements of representation with one or more contexts in which they are combined to represent a concept;</li>
   <li>the association of elements of representation such that one defines another;</li>
   <li>a structure for relating two representations such that one participates in the definition of the other;</li>
   <li>a structure for relating two representations in which one does not participate in the definition of the other;</li>
   <li>constraints to prevent the recursive definition of instances of an element of representation;</li>
   <li>the specification of the transformation of one element of representation to another by specifying the input and output of the transformation;</li>
   <li>the specification of the transformation of one element of representation to another by specifying the transforming function.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>the complete specification of types of representation, types of elements of representation, and types of representation context;</li>
   <li>the specification of the uses of representation;</li>
   <li>the association of representation with any of its possible uses;</li>
   <li>
   		constraints requiring a directed relationship between representations;
   		<note>
   			A directed relationship exists between items A and B if the meaning of the relationship of A to B is
			different from the meaning of B to A.
			A and B are peers in a non-directed relationship.
			A directed relationship can be specified in an annotated EXPRESS schema that uses or specializes this schema.
   		</note>
   </li>
   <li>constraints forbidding cyclic structures of related representations;</li>
   <li>constraints requiring a directed relationship between the contexts in which related representations exist;</li>
   <li>constraints forbidding cyclic structures of relationships between representation contexts.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
 	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-1">
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_application_protocol"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_assembly"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_information"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_product_data"/>
 		<term.ref linkend="term_structure"/>
 	</normref.inc>
	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-11.1994"/>
	<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41">
		<term.ref linkend="term39"/>
		<term.ref linkend="term40"/>
	</normref.inc>
	
 </normrefs>
 
 <!-- 3.2 Other terms and definitions -->
 <definition>
 	<term id="context_of_representation">context of representation</term>
 	<def>
 		basis through which elements of a representation are related to each other
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="element_of_representation">element of representation</term>
 	<def>
 		data element that participates in the description of a representation, 
 		either directly or by describing other elements of representation
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="founded">founded</term>
 	<def>
 		property of an element of representation that results from its association, direct or indirect, 
 		with a context of representation
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
 <definition>
 	<term id="representation">representation</term>
 	<def>
 		organized collection of associated data elements, collected together for one or more specific uses
 	</def>
 </definition>
 
<!--


 <abbreviations/>
-->
<!-- +++++++++++ 4. Representation schema +++++++++++ -->
<schema name="representation_schema" number="9687" number.supersedes="9205" version="5">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   		<p>
   		The subjects of the <b>representation_schema</b> are the structures that relate a collection of elements of product data to a context.
   		These structures are representations.
   		Representations are used to describe aspects of products.
   		The associations between representations and the aspects of products they describe are specified 
   		in annotated EXPRESS schemas that use or specialize this schema.
   		Representations can be used to:
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
			describe a property or a relationship between two properties, in which the properties are associated 
			with a complete product or with a part of a product;
			<note number="1">
				The use of representations to collect elements of product data in order to describe the properties of a
				product is specified in ISO 10303-41, and can be specified in annotated EXPRESS schemas that use or
				specialize the constructs specified in this part of ISO 10303 and in ISO 10303-41.
			</note>
			</li>
			<li>
			describe a picture.
			<note number="2">
				The use of representations to collect elements of product data in order to describe a picture of a
				product is specified in ISO 10303-46 [6], and can be specified in annotated EXPRESS schemas that use or
				specialize the constructs specified in this part of ISO 10303 and in ISO 10303-46 [6].
			</note>
			</li>
		</ul>
		<p>One representation can be part of another representation.</p>
		<example number="1">
			A collection of lines and points describes the shape of a wall. 
			This representation can be used as part of the description of the shape of the building, of which the wall is a part.
		</example>
		<p>Each representation has a context and a collection of elements specified in that context.</p>
		<example number="2">
			For the representation of geometric elements, the context is a coordinate space.
		</example>
		<p>A context can be related to other contexts.</p>
		<example number="3">
			Local coordinate spaces can be defined for each building in a factory complex. 
			These coordinate spaces can be related to each other, and to the coordinate space of the factory complex itself.
		</example>
		<p>Transformations between representations can be specified.</p>
   </introduction>
   
   <fund_cons>
   		<b><i>Representation</i></b>
   		<p>The following concepts and assumptions apply to the portions of this schema that deal with representation:</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   			A representation consists of a collection of elements of representation and a context.
   			A representation corresponds to an instance of the 
   			<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation"/> 
   			entity data type.
   			By structuring the elements in this way, relationships between elements can be established.
   			Elements of representation are related if:
   				<ol>
   					<li>they are elements in the same representation, or</li>
   					<li>they are elements in different representations that have the same context, or</li>
   					<li>they are elements in different representations that have different contexts, if the contexts are related</li>
   				</ol>
   			<example number="1">
   				Consider two points with coordinate values of (0,0,0) and (1,0,0).
   				It is not possible to calculate the distance between these points until it is established that they are in the same coordinate space.
   				The specification of a point by itself does not contain enough data to state which coordinate space it is in and what
				other elements also share that coordinate space.
				In this part of ISO 10303, a point is an example of an element of representation, and a coordinate space is an example of a context.
   			</example>
   			</li>
   			<li>
   			A representation can be used more than once. A representation is separate from its use.
   			<example number="2">
   				Consider a collection of points and lines in a coordinate space.
   				This collection can be used to describe the shape of a product.
   				The collection can also be used, possibly with some transformation, to describe
				a drawing or picture of the product. 
				Neither of these uses is part of the definition of the collection itself.
   			</example>
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   		<note>
   			Representations can be specialized further in annotated EXPRESS schemas that use or specialize this schema.
   		</note>
   		
   		<b><i>Context of representation</i></b>
   		<p>The following assumptions apply to the portions of this schema that deal with the context of representation:</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   				A representation has a context. 
   				It is the context in which the elements of the representation are related.
   				The context of a representation corresponds to an instance of the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation_context"/>
				entity data type.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				The context of a representation exists only as a basis for the representations that use it. 
   				Therefore, representation contexts are related only if representations using the contexts are related.
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   		<note>
   			Representation contexts can be specialized further in annotated EXPRESS schemas that use or specialize this schema.
   		</note>
   		<example>
   			Possible specializations include contexts for geometry, topology, finite element modelling and kinematic modelling.
   		</example>
   		
   		<b><i>Elements of representation</i></b>
   		<p>The following concepts and assumptions apply to the portions of this schema that deal with elements of representation:</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   				Elements of representation participate directly in a representation, or support the definition of 
   				another element of representation, or both.
   				<example number="1">
   					A point could be the only element in the representation of the location of a product, or it could
					serve as the end point of a line that is the only element in the representation of the edge of a product. 
					In the first case the point itself is an element in a representation directly.
					In the second case, the point serves only to provide definition for the line entity.
   				</example>
   				<example number="2">
   					An element of representation that specifies the presentation of a text string could be part of the description of a drawing. 
   					In this case it participates directly in a representation. 
   					The same element of representation could, alternatively, be part of a dimension callout. 
   					In this second case the text is part of the callout, and participates indirectly in the description of the drawing.
   				</example>
   				<note>
   					Elements of representation that describe the presentation of text strings are specified in ISO 10303-46 [6]. 
   					Elements of representation that describe dimension callouts are described in ISO 10303-101 [8].
   				</note>
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				Elements of representation can refer to each other, thereby forming graphs of such elements in
				which each graph has an identifiable root.
				The association of a root element with a context associates all elements in the graph with the context.
				<example number="3">
					A curve is defined by a number of points. 
					These points are all in the same coordinate space as the curve by virtue of their reference from the curve.
				</example>
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				Elements of representation are collected into representations and associated with contexts as a
				basis for establishing relationships between elements.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				An element of representation corresponds to an instance of the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation_item"/> 
   				entity data type.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				An association of one or more elements of representation with a context corresponds to an
				instance of the 
				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation"/> 
				entity data type.
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   		
   		<b><i>Association of representations</i></b>
   		<p>The following concepts and assumptions apply to the portions of this schema that deal with the association of representations:</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>A representation can be related to another representation.</li>
   			<li>
   				One representation can be related to another representation such that they both participate in the
				association, but one does not define the other.
				This type of association corresponds to the 
				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation_relationship"/> 
				entity data type.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				One representation can be related to another representation such that the first is part of the definition of the second.
   				This type of association corresponds to the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.mapped_item"/> 
   				and 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation_map"/> 
   				entity data types.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				Two collections of representation elements can be unrelated in two separate contexts, and yet be
				related in a third context, or be related only as they both participate in a relating structure.
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   		<example>
   			Two collections of points and lines each represent the shape of a part. 
   			Each of those shapes exists in a separate context independent and completely unrelated to the other.
   			A third context can exist for the shape of an assembly of which these parts are components.
   			In this third context, all of the elements are related, either
			through a direct association of those elements with that context, or through an association of the representations
			of the parts with the representation of the assembly.
   		</example>
   		
   		<b><i>Transformation</i></b>
   		<p>The following concepts and assumptions apply to the portions of this schema that deal with transformations:</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   				Elements in different representations can be compared if
   				<ol>
   					<li>the representations have the same context, or</li>
   					<li>a transformation is defined that relates the representations to each other.</li>
   				</ol>
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				A transformation can be defined as a function f between a domain A and a range B.
   				The function f:A->B takes each element a in A and maps it to an element b in B, i.e., f(a)=b.
   				The complete specification of a transformation requires the following:
   				<ol>
   					<li>the set of elements a to be transformed;</li>
   					<li>the set of elements b resulting from the transformations;</li>
   					<li>the definition of the context A that is common to the set of elements a;</li>
   					<li>the definition of the context B that is common to the set of elements b;</li>
   					<li>the function f.</li>
   				</ol>
   				The domain A and the range B are instances of the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation_context"/> 
   				entity data type.
   				The elements a and b are instances of the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation_item"/> 
   				entity data type.
   				The relationships between a and A, and between b and B, are instances of the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.representation"/> 
   				entity data type: a is an element in a representation whose context is A, b is an element in a representation whose
				context is B.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				Two different approaches are used in this part of ISO 10303 to specify transformations.
   				<ol>
   					<li>
   						The function f can be specified. 
   						This type of transformation corresponds to the 
   						<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.functionally_defined_transformation"/> 
   						entity data type.
   						<example number="1">
   							Two representations are related such that one is rotated and skewed with respect to the other.
							This transformation can be specified by a matrix.
   						</example>
   						<note number="1">
   							The data structures for particular kinds of transformation functions, such as matrices, are not
							specified in this part of ISO 10303.
   						</note>
   						<example number="2">
   							Points on a map are related to points on the surface of the earth by a function that transforms the
							three dimensional surface to a two dimensional picture, and applies a scaling factor.
   						</example>
   					</li>
   					<li>
   						An element a in context A and an element b in context B that are sufficient to derive the
						function can be specified.
						This type of transformation corresponds to the
						<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.item_defined_transformation"/>
						entity data type, or to the mapping defined by the
						<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.mapped_item"/> 
						entity data type.
						<example number="3">
							A translation between coordinate spaces can be uniquely determined by two instances of
							<b>axis2_placement_3d</b> 
							a1 and b1 (one in each coordinate space), such that f takes a1 and transforms it to b1.
						</example>
						<note number="2">
							The 
							<b>axis2_placement_3d</b> 
							entity data type is defined in ISO 10303-42 [4].
						</note>
   					</li>
   				</ol>
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   		
   		<b><i>Uncertainty</i></b>
   		<p>
   			Numeric values that are measured or calculated can be imprecise.
   			Uncertainty is a measure of the interval of confidence associated with this imprecision.
   			In this International Standard, uncertainty can be specified for:
   		</p>
   		
   		<ol>
   			<li>multiple representations that share a common context;</li>
   			<li>individual representations;</li>
   			<li>individual elements of representation.</li>
   		</ol>
   		
   		<p>This part of ISO 10303 supports (1) and (2).</p>
   		<note number="1">(3) is supported by ISO 10303-45 [5].</note>
   		<note number="2">
	   		Uncertainty is unrelated to the subject of tolerances or permitted variations. 
	   		These are supported by ISO 10303-47 [7].
   		</note>
   		<p>The following concepts and assumptions apply to the portions of this schema that deal with uncertainty:</p>
   		<ul>
   			<li>
   				The uncertainty for numeric values can be specified for all the representations that share a context.
   				This is specified using the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.global_uncertainty_assigned_context"/> 
   				entity data type.
   			</li>
   			<li>
   				The uncertainty for numeric values can be specified for a representation in a given context.
   				This is specified using the 
   				<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.uncertainty_assigned_representation"/>  
   				entity data type.
   			</li>
   		</ul>
   		<p>
   			If uncertainties are specified more than once, the following precedence rules shall apply.
   			The uncertainty specified for an individual element of representation shall have precedence over the uncertainty specified by any
   			<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.uncertainty_assigned_representation"/> 
   			in which the item participates.
   			The uncertainty specified by an
   			<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.uncertainty_assigned_representation"/> 
   			shall have precedence over the uncertainty specified by any
   			<express_ref linkend="representation_schema:ir_express:representation_schema.global_uncertainty_assigned_context"/>
   			in which the representation participates.
   		</p>
   		<note number="3">
   			Uncertainty for an individual element of representation is specified by the
   			<b>qualified_representation_item</b> 
   			entity data type, defined in ISO 10303-45 [5].
   		</note>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
        <imgfile file="representation_schemaexpg1.xml"/> 
        <imgfile file="representation_schemaexpg2.xml"/>
        <imgfile file="representation_schemaexpg3.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 	<shortname name="CMRPIT" entity="compound_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="DFNRPR" entity="definitional_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="FNDITM" entity="founded_item"/>
 	<shortname name="FNDFTR" entity="functionally_defined_transformation"/>
 	<shortname name="GC" entity="global_uncertainty_assigned_context"/>
 	<shortname name="ITDFTR" entity="item_defined_transformation"/>
 	<shortname name="MPPITM" entity="mapped_item"/>
 	<shortname name="PRRPCN" entity="parametric_representation_context"/>
 	<shortname name="RPRSNT" entity="representation"/>
 	<shortname name="RPRCNT" entity="representation_context"/>
 	<shortname name="RPRITM" entity="representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="RPITRL" entity="representation_item_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="RPRMP" entity="representation_map"/>
 	<shortname name="RPRRLT" entity="representation_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="RRWT" entity="representation_relationship_with_transformation"/>
 	<shortname name="UNASRP" entity="uncertainty_assigned_representation"/>
 	<shortname name="UMWU" entity="uncertainty_measure_with_unit"/>
 	<shortname name="VLRPIT" entity="value_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="BNRPIT" entity="binary_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="BYRPIT" entity="bytes_representation_item"/>
 	<shortname name="DFRPRL" entity="definitional_representation_relationship"/>
 	<shortname name="DRRWSC" entity="definitional_representation_relationship_with_same_context"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>
-->
 <bibliography>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ref8824-1"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_10303-21"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO_10303-22"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-42"/>
 	
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-45"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-46"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-47"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO-10303-101"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-1667"/>
 	<bibitem.inc ref="GELLERT"/>
 </bibliography>

</resource>

