<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module name="ap210_assembly_functional_requirements" part="1605" version="1" sc4.working_group="3" wg.number="1613" wg.number.arm="1614" wg.number.mim="1615" wg.number.arm_lf="1690" wg.number.mim_lf="1691" checklist.internal_review="1740" checklist.project_leader="1741" checklist.convener="1742" status="CD-TS" language="E" publication.year="" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2005/02/10 02:43:59 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.17 $" development.folder="dvlp" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <keywords>
    module, electrical, network analysis, function, requirement,functional allocation
 </keywords>
    
    <contacts>
        <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
        <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
    </contacts>
    <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of assembly functional requirements.
This Data includes all information required to specify the behaviour of the assembly, including
interface definition. Explicit structural definition is provided for the functional network,
including representations of usage view and design view, representations of folded and elaborated
network hierarchy. This includes gate allocation information. Explicit allocation of each
functional network node to the implementing component is included. Extensive use of formal
encapsulation is provided for signal definition, mathematical models, etc. This data includes information
required to support embedded components in an interconnect product. Configuration
management information and design management information is provided.
   </p>
 </purpose>
    <inscope>
        <li>nodal network representation of the behaviour of the assembly;</li>
        <li>allocation of functions in the nodal network representation to physical components that implement the functionality;</li>
        <li>mapping the set of nodes in the hierarchical network representation to the single elaborated physical node that is equivalent;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="assembly_module_usage_view:1_scope">Assembly module usage view</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1642;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="functional_decomposition_to_assembly_design:1_scope">Functional decomposition to assembly design</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1675;</li>
 		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="functional_decomposition_to_design:1_scope">Functional decomposition to design</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1676;</li>
 		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="functional_decomposition_with_nodal_representation_to_packaged_mapping:1_scope">Functional decomposition with nodal representation to packaged mapping</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1678;</li>
 		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="physical_node_requirement_to_implementing_component_allocation:1_scope">Physical node requirement to implementing component allocation</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1723;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="planned_characteristic:1_scope">Planned characteristic</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1733;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="requirement_assignment:1_scope">Requirement assignment</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1233;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="requirement_decomposition:1_scope">Requirement decomposition</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1740;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="requirement_identification_and_version:1_scope">Requirement identification and version</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1140;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="requirement_view_definition:1_scope">Requirement view definition</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1141;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="requirement_view_definition_relationship:1_scope">Requirement view definition relationship</module_ref>, ISO/TS 10303-1142;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module <module_ref linkend="test_requirement_allocation:1_scope">Test requirement allocation</module_ref>, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1751.</li>
    </inscope>
    <outscope>
        <li>algorithmic representation of the behaviour of the assembly</li>
        <li>shape representation of the assembly</li>
    </outscope>
    <arm>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </arm>
    <arm_lf/>
    <mapping_table>
        
    </mapping_table>
    <mim>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </mim>
    <mim_lf/>
</module>
