<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.14 2007/01/10 22:23:06 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="work_structure"
   part="1438"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="4434"
   wg.number.arm="4435"
   wg.number.mim=""
   wg.number.supersedes="3772"
   wg.number.arm.supersedes="3773"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   publication.date=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2007/01/10 22:23:06 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.14 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems engineering, project management, work
 </keywords>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead2"/>
   <editor ref="ap233.editor2"/>  
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the pieces of work necessary to complete a project.</p> 

   <p>This module is constructed from several ISO/TS Application 
   modules.  The Work_structure_arm contains the information necessary to 
   defined the work to be performed. </p>
      
   <p>The Work_structure_arm provides for the identification and 
     characterization of a <module_ref linkend="work_request:introduction"/> 
     and a <module_ref linkend="work_order:introduction"/>. It provides 
     for an association to be made between the work request and the 
     <module_ref linkend="observation:introduction"/> which initiated 
     the work request. It contains an identification of the activities 
     governed by a work order. It defines the hierarchy of tasks to be 
     performed along with required inputs, and deliverable products 
     and information.  It contains the definition and quantification 
     of planned as well as completed 
     <module_ref linkend="work_output:introduction"/>.</p> 
   </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>identification and characterization a work request and work order;</li>
   <li>association of a work request with an activity method;</li>
   <li>identification of the product or activity data affected by the work request;</li>
   <li>identification of the activities that are governed by a work order;</li>
   <li>the definition and quantification of planned as well as recorded work outputs;</li>
   <li>the relationships between the work output and detailed descriptions of the output.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope
 <outscope>
   <li>association of work structure with activity or product data;</li>   
   <li>identification and characterization of work associated schedule;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of work associated person and organization;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of work associated project breakdown;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of work associated project management information resources;</li>
   <li>the relationships between organization structure, project breakdown, project management 
   information resources and schedule.</li>
 </outscope>
 -->
 
<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <!-- <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg3.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg4.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg5.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg6.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg7.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg8.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg9.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg10.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg11.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg12.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg13.xml"/> -->
   </express-g>
 </arm>

 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>
 

    <usage_guide>

	<p><b>Extensible type select lists (generic)</b></p>
	
	<p>The problem of creating extensible type lists has proven to be an extreme challenge.
	A publish and subscribe analogy is used to explain the approach used.</p>  

	<p>Schemas enable information modelling capability within a domain. The capabilities are 
	enabled by entities.  Entities use other entities directly as specified attributes or less 
	directly via extensible select types.  The associated extensible select type list can be viewed as a 
	subscription list. The list itself contains all entity names associated with entity concepts 
	that subscribe to the capability offered by the schema containing the entity that uses 
	the extensible type list as an attribute.</p>  

	<p>The complexity of the extensible select type list specification problem stems from the fact that 
	lists are relative to a sub-domain of the domain associated with the schema that defines the 
	extensible type list.</p>

	<p>This creates a list creation problem that is 3 dimensional.  The coordinate axes are:</p>
	<ul>
	<li>domain specified by all USE FROM schemas,</li> 
	<li>extensible select types defined within this domain,</li>
	<li>entities defined within a sub-domain of this domain.</li>   </ul>
	
	<p>To size this, AP233 has about 10 major domains, 1000 entities and 
	100 extensible types.  If one does not apply some organizational logic to the problem this 
	implies a yes/no cognitive decisions space containing 1,000,000 points.</p>
	
	<p>In order to penetrate this problem some logical approach that is both scalable and 
	checkable is required.  In AP233 WD1 all schemas where grouped into high level concept
	groups: program management resource information (pmri), organization structure (os),
	project breakdown (pb). schedule (ss) and work structure (ws).  As AP233 WD2 
	evolved major module restructuring occurred and the ability to group at a more 
	detail level of abstraction was enabled.  </p>

	 <p><b>Extensible type select lists - work structure </b></p>

	 <p>The Work_structure_arm module contains the type extend lists relative to  
	 extensible select types defined within the following modules and those that they inherit:</p>

	 <ul><li>
        <module_ref linkend="project_management_resource_information:introduction">
          Project_management_resource_information_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1434);
	</li>
	<li>
        <module_ref linkend="work_order:introduction">
          Work_order_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1043);
	</li></ul>
	
	<p>The USE FROM connectivity associated with these module are shown below in 
	Figure 1 the Project concept map.</p>
	
	   
   	<figure><title> Project Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Project_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
	<p>The USE FROM connectivity associated with the work output module is shown below in 
	Figure 2 the Schedule concept map.</p>
	
	
   	<figure><title> Schedule Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="Schedule_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>
	
	<p>The USE FROM connectivity associated with the observation module is shown below in 
	Figure 3 the What concept map.</p>
	
	
   	<figure><title> What Concept Map  </title>
	<img src="What_concepts.gif"/>	
	</figure>

		
	<p>The entities defined within the work structure type extend lists are 
	obtained from the following modules:
	</p>
	
	<ul>
        <li><module_ref linkend="Observation:introduction">
          Observation_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1258);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Work_order:introduction">
          Work_order_type_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1243);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Work_output:introduction">
          Work_output_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1300);</li>
	
        <li><module_ref linkend="Work_request:introduction">
          Work_request_arm</module_ref>
        (ISO 10303-1042);</li>
	
	</ul>
	
	 <p>From the perspective of information cross coupling; the type extend lists 
	 identify within this module specify how all work structure information modeling 
	 concepts defined within the schemas of the work structure domain are coupled together 
	 via type extends within the work structure domain.</p>
	 

</usage_guide>
</module>
