<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.1 2004/10/25 18:30:36 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="work_structure"
   part="1438"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="00000"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2004/10/25 18:30:36 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.1 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems engineering, project management, work
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the pieces of work necessary to complete a project.</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p> This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of the pieces of work necessary to complete a project.</p> 
   <p>The Work_structure_arm contains the high level information basic to the work 
   to be performed under contract. A formal legal contract may be present, or it 
   may be informal and represent transfer of information and responsibility among 
   product development teams. The contract is identified along with information 
   associating activity or product data with the contract. The Work_structure_arm 
   contains approval information, identification and status, associated with the 
   contract, the product, and work activities. It defines the hierarchy of tasks 
   to be performed along with required inputs and deliverable information or products. 
   It contains the definition and quantification of planned as well as completed 
   work outputs.</p> 
   <p>The Work_structure_arm contains the identification and characterization of 
   a work request and a work order. It contains identification of the activities 
   that are governed by a work order.</p> 
   <p>The work_structure_arm contains the definition of a security classification 
   level and the assignment of a security classification level to any activity or 
   product data. This capability supports both governmental security and business 
   proprietary information.</p> 
 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>######## Editorial note: Following list must be condensed down</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Approval_arm;</li> 
   <li>characterization of an approval;</li>
   <li>assignment of an approval to product or activity data;</li>
   <li>relationship between two approvals;</li>
   <li>identification of an approval status.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Contract_arm;</li> 
   <li>creating and identifying the contract;</li>
   <li>associating activity or product data to the contract.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Document_assignment_arm;</li> 
   <li>assignment of documents to product or activity data;</li>
   <li>assignment of parts or sections of documents to product or activity data.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From File_identification_arm;</li> 
   <li>identification of a digital file, such as a file on a computer system;</li>
   <li>identification of a physical file, such as a stack of paper;</li>
   <li>specification of the data identifying and locating a File in a  digital or physical storage system.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Issue_and_change_management_arm; TBD</li> 
    <note>Concept model created at ISO/SC4 Seattle meeting, detail review TDB at INCOSE 
    winter meeting in Tampa.  EXPRESS creationn work will begin after Tampa meeting. 
    The following are high level requirements, subject to discussion.</note>
   <li>creating and identifying the issue;</li>
   <li>identification of a version of an issue.</li>
   <li>characterization of an issue;</li>
   <li>grouping of issues</li>
   <li>identification of an Issue Resolution Board to evaluate issues</li>
   <li>membership of the IRB</li>
   <li>date and time of IRB meetings</li>
   <li>issues considered, issue impact evaluation, and issue resolution assignment to organization entities. </li>
   <li>assignment of an issue to contract, product or activity data;</li>
   <li>assignment of parts or sections of an issue to contract, product or activity data.</li>
   <li>relationship between two issues;</li>
   <li>identification of an issue status.</li>
   <li>the specification and identification of what the issue is  and in what context;</li>
   <li>the association of the issue to the supporting evidential data on which it is based.</li>
   <li>classification of issue resolution to temporary fix, permanent fix, fix delayed to a future product release, fix delayed to contract modification.</li>
   <li>association of the issue resolution to a modified schedule or plan.</li>
   <li>issue resolution justification and approval</li>
   <li>track of issue status, impact, and of open and closed issues.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Justification_arm;</li> 
   <li>the provision of one or more justifications for something;</li>
   <li>the specification and identification of what is being justified and in what context;</li>
   <li>the specification of relationships between justifications;</li>
   <li>the association of the justification to the supporting evidential data on which it is based.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Observation_arm;</li> 
   <li>the observation of historical facts about products, resources, and activities;</li>
   <li>the association of an observation to the thing observed;</li>
   <li>the association of an observation to its context;</li>
   <li>the association of an observation to the actual activity taking place when it was observed;</li>
   <li>the association of the observation with the observer;</li>
   <li>the association of the observation to its consequences;</li>
   <li>the association of observations with each other;</li>
   <li>the aggregation of observations;</li>
   <li>the record of the date and time that the observation was made;</li>
   <li>the classification of the observation;</li>
   <li>the formal verification or confirmation of the observation.</li>
 <li>######## Editorial note: From Security_classification_arm;</li> 
   <li>definition of a security classification level;</li>
   <li>asignment of a security classification level to activity or product data.</li>

 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>xxxx</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
