<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module name="ap210_interconnect_design" part="1617" version="1" sc4.working_group="3" wg.number="1649" wg.number.arm="1650" wg.number.mim="1651" wg.number.arm_lf="1714" wg.number.mim_lf="1715" checklist.internal_review="1740" checklist.project_leader="1741" checklist.convener="1742" status="CD-TS" language="E" publication.year="" published="n" rcs.date="$Date: 2005/02/03 16:13:43 $" rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.13 $" development.folder="dvlp" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <keywords>
    module, elelctrical, interconnect, embedded, microwave, requirement, shape, specification, geometric dimensioning, geometric tolerance, fabrication requirement, design view, usage view, layered electrical product design, signal prioritizatin, routing, wiring
 </keywords>
    
    <contacts>
        <projlead ref="AP210.projlead"/>
        <editor ref="pdmmodules.editor"/>
    </contacts>
    <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of interconnect design.
This data provides functional and physical layout information sufficient to allow manufacture and
test of an interconnect. Design re-use is explicitly supported with traceability. Complete traceability
back to requirements is provided. Product connection requirements, shape requirements,
product specifications, process specifications, material specifications including manufacturing
view of stackup, Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing are provided. This data identifies
those elements that do not meet design requirements. This data includes both design view
and usage view of the interconnect product. Support for specification of signal prioritization is
provided. Support for specifying the explicit network topology to be implemented is provided.
Configuration management information and design management information is provided. This
data includes at least one geometric representation.
   </p>
 </purpose>
    <inscope>
        <li>two dimensional layered interconnect substrate;</li>
        <li>configuration management data;</li>
        <li>design management data;</li>
        <li>three dimensional layered interconnect substrate;</li>
        <li>three dimensional molded interconnect substrate;</li>
        <li>material conductivity classification;</li>
        <li>as-routed connections;</li>
        <li>embedded components;</li>
        <li>test points;</li>
        <li>tolerance based cutout design;</li>
        <li>tolerance based cavity design;</li>
        <li>as-required connections;</li>
        <li>partially routed connections;</li>
        <li>pre-defined printed templates for design re-use;</li>
        <li>geometric properties for trace layout;</li>
        <li>geometric properties for pad taper layout;</li>
        <li>explicit definition of terminals of the interconnect substrate;</li>
        <li>explicit definition of cavities and cutouts of the interconnect substrate required for components;</li>
        <li>mapping between the explicit definition of terminals and internal design features;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Area 2d, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1631;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Characteristic, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1654;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Chemical substance, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1655;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Connectivity allocation to physical network, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1658;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Design specific assignment to interconnect usage view, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1663;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Device marking, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1664;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Fill area, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1672;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Interconnect 2d shape, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1682;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Interconnect 3d shape, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1683;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Interconnect module to assembly module relationship, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1685;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Interconnect non planar shape, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1688;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Land, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1692;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Layered interconnect module 2d design, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1695;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Layered interconnect module 3d design, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1696;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Layered interconnect module 3d shape, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1697;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Layout macro definition, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1701;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Pre defined datum symbol, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1734;</li>
		<li>items within the scope of application module Via component, ISO/CD-TS 10303-1754.</li>
    </inscope>
    <outscope>
        <li>printed terminal shape data defined for microwave applications</li>
    </outscope>
    <arm>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </arm>
    <arm_lf/>
    <mapping_table>
        
    </mapping_table>
    <mim>
        <express-g>
            <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
        </express-g>
    </mim>
</module>
