<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.9 2005/07/28 11:13:44 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="project_breakdown"
   name.french=""
   part="1436"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number=""
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   wg.number.supersedes="3722"
   wg.number.arm.supersedes="3723"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   publication.date=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2005/07/28 11:13:44 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.9 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems engineering, project breakdown, project management, 
    product breakdown
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of relationships between project, product, associated high level 
     breakdowns and properties.</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of relationships between project, product, associated high level 
     breakdowns and properties.</p>

     <p>The Project_breakdown_arm is about the identification of a project and product 
     structure, i.e. how a project is defined and a product is assembled, categorized, 
     and version controlled. It is not about the identification of configuration items .</p>
          
     <p>It contains the information that identifies a product 
     or a product version and the inclusion of a product or product version in a product 
     category. It contains the characterization of a version of a product, suitable for 
     one or more application domains and one or more life-cycle stages. It contains the 
     context-dependent relationship among product definitions such as the fact that one or 
     more versions of products are used in another product.</p>
     
     <p>It contains the identification of a hierarchical breakdown 
     of a product and the identification of the elements that comprise a breakdown. It 
     includes the identification of parent-child relationships between breakdown elements, 
     and the identification of relationships between elements in different breakdowns.</p>
     
     <p>It contains identification of a kind of product from user requirements and the 
     identification of a set of products grouped together for a common purpose, 
     such  as sales/marketing, analysis, production, usage, support activity,  support 
     solution and disposal.  It contains the reference to the stakeholder for the group, who 
     causes the  creation of the group, along with the identification of a group as a subset 
     of another group. It contains the list of common characteristics which is shared by the 
     members of the  group, such as scheduled for maintenance, sales, upgrading.</p>
     
     <p>It contains the identification of project and product information selected for 
     configuration management activities.</p>
     
     Modules used are:
          <module_ref linkend="Configuration_item:introduction"/>, 
          <module_ref linkend="Independent_property:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_as_individual:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_breakdown:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_categorization:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_concept_identification:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_group:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_identification:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_relationship:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_version:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_version_relationship:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_view_definition:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_view_definition_relationship:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Project:introduction"/> and
          <module_ref linkend="Selected_item:introduction"/>.
	     
   <p><b>Change Log from base line AP233 WD#1:</b></p><ol>
   <li>WD#2 - Removed all references to module "information packet". Reason: Not needed, the module document
   and its related modules can be used to service this need.</li></ol>

 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>identification of a kind of product from stakeholder and user requirements;</li>
   <li>identification of and relationship between two projects;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of product, product version and relationships;</li>
   <li>the identification of a breakdown, breakdown elements;</li>
   <li>identification of the configuration of a product for a given product concept;</li>
   <li>context-dependent relationship between two product definitions;</li>
   <li>the identification of parent-child relationships;</li>
   <li>the identification of relationships between elements in different breakdowns;</li>
   <li>identification of product information and definitions for configuration management purposes;</li>
   <li>identification and definition and relationships between product categories;</li>
   <li>representation of the data that identify a product;</li>
   <li>association of a project item to product or property;</li>
   <li>identification of a set of products grouped together for a common purpose;</li>
   <li>identification of a group as a subset of another group.</li>
</inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>association of project breakdown with activity or product data;</li>   
   <li>identification and characterization of project breakdown associated schedule;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of project breakdown associated person and organization;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of project breakdown associated work;</li>
   <li>identification and characterization of project breakdown associated project management information resources;</li>
   <li>the relationships between work, schedule, person and organization, 
   project breakdown and project management information resources.</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>

 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
