<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.3 2004/10/26 13:31:09 abhpf Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the module in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<module
   name="project_breakdown"
   part="1436"
   version="1"
   sc4.working_group="12"
   wg.number="00000"
   wg.number.arm=""
   wg.number.mim=""
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="WD"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2004/10/26 13:31:09 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.3 $"
   development.folder="dvlp">

 <keywords>
    module, systems engineering, project breakdown, project management, 
    product breakdown
 </keywords>

<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for relationships 
    between project, product, associated breakdowns and properties</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap233.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="harry.frisch"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the
     representation of relationships between project, product, associated breakdowns and properties</p>

     <p>The Project_breakdown_arm is about the identification of a project and product 
     structure, i.e. how a project is defined and a product is assembled, categorized, 
     and version controlled. Some projects and products exist and evolve over many years 
     with many product releases and updates. This arm contains information about the 
     identification of the configuration of a project or product for a given product 
     concept as it evolves over time.</p>
     
     <p>It contains the definition of a project of its responsible organization and 
     of its planned and actual execution dates. It contains the association of a 
     project to activity and product data, and the relationships among projects. It 
     contains the information to identify a planned product or an actual product.</p>
     
     <p>The Project_breakdown_arm contains the information that identifies a product 
     or a product version and the inclusion of a product or product version in a product 
     category. It contains the characterization of a version of a product, suitable for 
     one or more application domains and one or more life-cycle stages. It contains the 
     context-dependent relationship among product definitions such as the fact that one or 
     more versions of products are used in another product.</p>
     
     <p>The Project_breakdown_arm contains the identification of a hierarchical breakdown 
     of a product and the identification of the elements that comprise a breakdown. It 
     includes the identification of parent-child relationships between breakdown elements, 
     and the identification of relationships between elements in different breakdowns.</p>
     
     <p>It contains the identification of a kind of product from user requirements. 
     It contains identification of a set of products grouped together for a common purpose, 
     such  as sales/marketing, analysis, production, usage, support activity,  support 
     solution and disposal It contains the reference to the stakeholder for the group, who 
     causes the  creation of the group, along with the identification of a group as a subset 
     of another group. It contains the list of common characteristics which is shared by the 
     members of the  group, such as scheduled for maintenance, sales, upgrading.</p>
     
     <p>It contains the identification of project and product information selected for 
     configuration management activities.</p>
     
     Modules used are:
          <module_ref linkend="configuration_item:introduction"/>, 
          <module_ref linkend="independent_property:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="information_packet:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_as_individual:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_breakdown:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_categorization:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_concept_identification:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_group:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_identification:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_relationship:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_version:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_version_relationship:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_view_definition:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Product_view_definition_relationship:introduction"/>,
          <module_ref linkend="Project:introduction"/> and
          <module_ref linkend="Selected_item:introduction"/>.

 </purpose>

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>----- Editorial note: Following list must be condensed down</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Configuration_item_arm</li>
   <li>The existing scope and introduction of this module does not really address what 
   the module does. The module is about the identification of a product configuration i.e. 
   how  a product is assembled, not about the identification of configuration  items.</li>
   <li>identification of the configuration of a product for a given product concept.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Independent_property_arm</li>
   <li>specification of a property independent of its being a property of some object;</li>
   <li>specification of a relationship between independent properties.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_as_individual_arm</li>
   <li>representation of the information to identify an actual product;</li>
   <li>representation of the information to identify an actual product prior  to its realization - a planned product.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_breakdown_arm</li>
   <li>the identification of a breakdown of a product or product_as_individual;</li>
   <li>the identification of the elements that comprise a breakdown;</li>
   <li>the identification of parent-child relationships between breakdown elements;</li>
   <li>the identification of relationships between elements in different breakdowns.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_categorization_arm</li>
   <li>definition of a category of products;</li>
   <li>relationship between two product categories.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_concept_identification_arm</li>
   <li>identification of a kind of product from user requirements.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_identification_arm</li>
   <li>representation of the data that identify a product;</li>
   <li>inclusion of a product in a product category.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_group_arm</li>
   <li>identification of a set of products grouped together for a common purpose, such  as sales/marketing, analysis, production, usage, support activity,  support solution and disposal;</li>
   <li>identification of a group as a subset of another group;</li>
   <li>reference to the stakeholder for the group, who causes the  creation of the group;</li>
   <li>list of common characteristics which is shared by the members of the  group, such as scheduled for maintenance, sales, upgrading.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_relationship_arm</li>
   <li>specification of a relationship between two products.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_version_arm</li>
   <li>the identification of a version of a product.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_version_relationship_arm</li>
   <li>identification of a relationship between two versions of product;</li>
   <li>identification of an identity relationship between two versions of product made by two organizations.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_view_definition_arm</li>
   <li>characterization of a version of a product, suitable for one or more application domains and one or more life-cycle stages;</li>
   <li>identification of a universe of discourse suitable for the description of products.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Product_view_definition_relationship_arm</li>
   <li>context-dependent relationship between two product definitions;</li>
   <li>representation of the fact that a product version is used in another one.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Project_arm</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Selected_item_arm</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Project breakdown information  type extends 
   enabled by entities of the Project breakdown arm’s USE FROM schemas</li>
   <li>definition of a project, of its responsible organization and of its planned and actual execution dates;</li>
   <li>association of a project to activity and product data;</li>
   <li>relationship between two projects.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Selected_item_arm</li>
   <li>the identification of product information selected for  configuration management activities.</li>
   <li>----- Editorial note: From Project breakdown information  type extends 
   enabled by entities of the Project breakdown arm’s USE FROM schemas</li>
   <li>The association of a project item to product or property</li>
   <li>The specification of the definitions needed to classify project, product and 
breakdown data as being significant for configuration management purposes.</li>
   <li>The specification of the definitions needed for product and product version information to be selected for 
configuration management activities.</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>xxxx</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

 <!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
 <arm>
   <!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->

   <!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </arm>


 <!-- Clause 5.1 Mapping specification -->
 <mapping_table>
   <ae entity="xx"/>
 </mapping_table>

 <!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
 <mim>
   <!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </mim>

</module>
