<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: resource.xml,v 1.1 2005/10/13 07:19:16 liutkuviene Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE resource SYSTEM "../../../dtd/res_doc/resource.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkresource.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
 <!-- 
     To view the resource in IExplorer, open: sys/1_scope.xml
      -->
<resource
   name="visual_presentation"
   part="46"
   version="1"
   wg.number="00000"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2005/10/13 07:19:16 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.1 $">

 <keywords>
    resource
 </keywords>


<!-- the abstract for the resource. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
 <abstract>
    <li>xxxxx</li>
 </abstract>

 <!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="xxx"/>
   <editor ref="xxx"/>
 </contacts>

 <!-- Introduction -->
 <!-- The introduction should start as shown: -->
 <purpose>
   <p>
     This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application resource for the visualization of displayable
     properties of products. 
   </p>
   <p>
   The information given in all four schemas of this part together is suficient to describe in detail
   how product information shall be visualized by a receiving system. The presentation information
   contained in this part can be used only in conjunction with product information suitable for
   display. Presentation information as contained in this part cannot be displayed by itself without
   reference to product information.
   </p>
   <p>
   The presentation organization schema describes the hierarchical and partially recursive structure
   of the presentation sets, areas and views in which images of the product information are displayed. 
   It also explains how the components of the product information image and its annotation
   are organized as displayable objects and how these are placed into the context of presentations.
   This schema also accounts for the definition of the projective process for geometry by means of
   a camera model and for the specification of lighting and shading models.
   </p>
   <p>
   The presentation definition schema serves to define how the individual geometric and 
   non-geometric components of the product information are selected, assembled into presentation
   groups, and associated with presentation styles.
   </p>
   <p>
   The presentation appearance schema defines the appearance attributes that can be chosen to
   describe the desired visual appearance of the displayable elements of the product information
   by enumerating the available graphical presentation styles.
   </p>
   <p>
   The presentation resource schema provides basic graphical capabilities such as text font definition, 
   symbol definition, and colour definition.
   </p>
   <p>
   The visual presentation characteristics described in this part are often associated with 
   information from other generic resource parts, especially with geometric and topological representations
   (ISO 10303-42). The Application Protocols determine which resource parts are used together.
   Applications which make use of the generic resources in this part provide both the product
   information to be visually presented and the semantic meaning of the presentation. Possible
   applications include rendered views of product shape, results of scientific visualization, technical
   drawings, diagrams, charts, and graphics for technical publications.
   </p>
   <p><b><i>Relation to graphics standards</i></b></p>
   <p>
   The integrated resources specified in this part of ISO 10303 support the visual presentation
   of the properties of products. The generation of visual images using data specified by these
   integrated resources requires the use of an appropriate display system. This part of ISO 10303
   specifies the input data to such systems, together with the necessary structures and constraints
   that relate presentation data to other aspects of product data.
   </p>
   <p>
   Many display systems conform to existing ISO standards for computer graphics, 
   such as GKS-3D (ISO/IEC 8805) and PHIGS/PHIGS PLUS (ISO/IEC 9592). This part of ISO 10303 takes
   into account the concepts and terminology of these standards. Input data specified by this part
   of ISO 10303 is therefore intended to be suitable for further processing by displays conforming
   to graphics standards.
   </p>
 </purpose>

 <!-- Schema Interface express-g diagrams  -->
 <!-- refer to p41ed2 as example  -->
 <!--schema_diag>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="schema_diagexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
 </schema_diag-->

 <!-- Items in scope -->
 <inscope>
   <li>xxxxx</li>
 </inscope>

 <!-- Items out of scope -->
 <outscope>
   <li>xxxx</li>
 </outscope>

<!--
 <normrefs/>

 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->

<!-- ++++++++++ presentation_organization_schema ++++++++++ -->
<schema name="presentation_organization_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   <p>
   The presentation_organization_schema provides a structure for he management of a picture
   and the components of a picture. It also specifies the relationship between the properties of a
   product and their representation in a picture. The components of a picture may be related to
   each other, either as an association between two components that are otherwise independent, or, 
   as one component is an element of the definition of another. These relationships allow complex
   structures of pictures and components to be created.
   </p>
   <p>
   The components of a picture may be organized within a hierarchy built of presentation sets, presentation
   areas, areas dependent annotation representations, presentation views, view dependent 
   annotation representations, and product data representation views. The hierarchy consists of
   the following four levels:
   </p>
   <dl>
   <dt><b>Level 1:</b></dt>
   <dd><b>presentation set:</b> A presentation set is a collection of independent pictures that are concerned with the same subject.
   Examples of presentation sets are a collection of drawing sheets or a collection of the images of several display screens.</dd>
   <dt><b>Level 2:</b></dt>
   <dd><b>presentation area:</b> A presentation area is a generalization of a display that represents a single area
   on a display screen or device. A presentation area contains any number of presentation areas, presentation views, 
   and area-dependent annotation representations.</dd>
   <dt><b>Level 3:</b></dt>
   <dd><b>presentation view:</b> A presentation view is a two-dimensional presentation of product shape,
   which includes any annotation that is associated with that view. A presentation 
  
   
   
   view contains any number of product data representation views and view-dependent annotation representations.</dd>
   <figure number="1">
   <title>Presentation hierarchy</title>
   <img src="presentation_hierarchy.gif"/>
   </figure>
   <dd><b>area dependent annotation representation:</b> An area dependent annotation representation 
   is all annotation with a presentation area.</dd>
   <dt><b>Level 4:</b></dt>
   <dd><b>product data representation view:</b> A product data representation view is a two-dimensional
   presentation of product shape, which includes any annotation associated
   with the product shape.</dd>
   <dd><b>view-dependent annotation representation:</b> A view-dependent annotation representation 
   is the annotation associated with a presentation view.</dd>
   </dl>
  <p>
  An actual presentation hierarchy may contain more levels than described above. A single
  presentation area may itself be composed of several presentation areas. A presentation hieararchy
  may also contain less levels than described above, because some of the components making up 
  the hierarchy are not required.
  </p>
  <note>
  Figures 1 and 2 illustate the relationships between the levels of the presentation hierarchy.
  </note>
  <figure number="2">
   <title>Example of a presentation hierarchy</title>
   <img src="Example_of_presentation_hierarchy.gif"/>
   </figure>
   </introduction>
   
   <!-- Fundamental concepts and assumptions -->
   <fund_cons>
   <!-- Presentation hierarchy -->
   <b><i>Presentation hierarchy</i></b>
   <p>
   Within the presentation hierarchy, only a presentation area contains suficient information to
   allow the unambiguous generation of a picture using a suitable output device such as a computer 
   screen, printer, or plotter.
   </p>
   <p>
   Other elements in the hierarchy do not provide the necessary placement information for proper
   positioning on a display device. Presentation views or other lower level components are displayable
   only when related directly or indirectly to a presentation area.
   </p>
   <p>
   The <b>presentation_organization_schema</b> describes the presentation hierarchy through 
   representation of the different elements of the hierarchy and the relationships between them.
   </p>
   <note number="1">
   The concepts of representation and of relationships between representations are described
   in ISO 10303-43.
   </note>
   <p>
   Each element of the presentation hierarchy is described using the presentation representation
   entity, a subtype of representation. Subtypes of the presentation representation entity describe
   different elements within the hierarchy.
   </p>
   <note number="2">
   The representation entity is defined in ISO 10303-43.
   </note>
   <p>
   The context of each element of the presentation hierarchy is described using 
   the <b>geometric_representation_context</b> entity; this is constrained to be two dimensional.
   </p>
   <note number="3">
   The <b>geometric_representation_context</b> entity is defined in ISO 10303-42.
   </note>
   <p>
   The contents of each element of the presentation hierarchy are described by the set 
   of items of each presentation representation. The items are either two-dimensional geometry
   or annotation that are to be presented in the element, or the results of including other elements.
   </p>
   <p>
   Some elements of the hierarchy are constrained with respect to their contents, 
   or to the relationships that they may play with other elements. Specific semantics 
   are associated with these constraints; for example, the <b>product_data_representation_view</b> 
   entity describes an element of the hierarchy that only includes the results 
   of projecting three{dimensional geometry or annotation.
   </p>
   <p>
   The topmost level of the presentation hierarchy is represented by the entities <b>presentation_set</b>, 
   <b>presentation_area</b>, and <b>area_in_set</b>. The <b>area_in_set</b> entity supports many-to-many 
   relationships between presentation sets and presentation areas.
   </p>
   <p>
   Other elements of the presentation hierarchy are related to each other using 
   either the <b>presentation_representation_relationship</b> entity, or the <b>mapped_item</b> 
   and <b>representation_map</b> entities.
   </p>
   <note number="4">
   The <b>mapped_item</b> and <b>representation_map</b> entities are defined in ISO 10303-43.
   </note>
   <p>
   An association between two elements of the hierarchy which are independently 
   defined is described using the <b>presentation_representation_relationship</b> entity. 
   This describes the relationship between two instances of the presentation_representation 
   entity; in this relationship, one <b>presentation_representation</b> is denoted as the parent,
   the other as the child. The description of a transformation is included in the 
   relationship; this transformation is the geometric relationship between the <b>items</b> 
   of the parent <b>presentation_representation</b> and those of the child <b>presentation_representation</b>.
   </p>
   <example number="2">
   To define a hierarchy which consists of a single presentation area, two presentation 
   views and a single area dependent annotation representation, three instances of 
   presentation representation relationship are required as shown in figure 3.
   </example>
   <figure number="3">
   <title>Mapping the presentation hierarchy to instances of entities</title>
   <img src="Mapping_presentation_hierarchy_instances_entities.gif"/>
   </figure>
   <p>
   An association between two elements of the hierarchy, where one participates 
   in the definition of the other, is described using the <b>mapped_item</b> and <b>representation_map</b> entities.
   </p>
   <p>
   Such an association is described by an instance of the <b>mapped_item</b> entity. 
   This instance is included as one of the <b>items</b> of the <b>presentation_representation</b> 
   that contains the other. The second presentation_representation is referenced as 
   the <b>mapped_representation</b> of a <b>representation_map</b>, that is specified as the 
   <b>mapping_source</b> of the <b>mapped_item</b>. The transformation that describes the 
   geometric relationship between the <b>items</b> of the two <b>presentation_representations</b> 
   is described by the <b>mapping_target</b> of the <b>mapped_item</b> and the <b>mapping_origin</b> of the representation_map.
   </p>
   <example number="3">
   To include a <b>presentation_view</b> within a <b>presentation_area</b> requires one instance 
   of <b>mapped_item</b>, one instance of representation map, and two instances of 
   <b>axis2_placement_2d</b> that act as the origin and the target for the mapping, as shown in figure 4.
   </example>
   <note number="5">
   The <b>axis2_placement_2d</b> entity is defined in ISO 10303-42.
   </note>
   <figure number="4">
   <title>Association of presentation view and presentation area using mapped_item</title>
   <img src="Association_presentation_view_presentation_area_umi.gif"/>
   </figure>
   
   <!-- Camera model and projection -->
   <b><i>Camera model and projection</i></b>
   <p>
   Each level of the presentation hierarchy consists only of two-dimensional geometry 
   or annotation. A three-dimensional synthetic camera model must be specified 
   to associate a presentation with a three-dimensional product shape or planar annotation 
   in three-dimensional space. This model specifies how the projection of three-dimensional 
   geometry and annotation to two dimensions shall be executed by the displaying system. 
   The three-dimensional synthetic camera model is defined in analogy to the 
   graphics standards GKS{3D and PHIGS. More details about the synthetic camera 
   model can be found in [6], [7] and in computer graphics literature, e.g., in [11]
   or [12]. For draughting requirements, a two{dimensional camera model is also supported. 
   This two-dimensional model performs scaling and translation in two-dimensional space.
   </p>
   <p>
   The <b>product_data_representation_view</b> is the only component of the presentation hierarchy
   which may consist of two-dimensional projections of associated three-dimensional product shape
   or of annotation in three-dimensional space. Because this part of ISO 10303 does not define the
   projected picture, but all information necessary to compute the projection, only a placeholder
   for that picture is part of the <b>product_data_representation_view</b>. This placeholder is called
   <b>camera_image</b> and refers to the camera model and the two- or three-dimensional product
   shape elements or annotation.
   </p>
   <p>
   To allow more realistic presentations of three-dimensional objects, hidden line and hidden surface
   removal, as well as light sources, can be specified for a three-dimensional camera model.
   </p>
   
   <!-- Layers -->
   <b><i>Layers</i></b>
   <p>
   A layer is a collection of product shape elements, annotation elements, or components of the
   presentation hierarchy grouped for the purpose of controlling visibility and style. 
   The set of all items associated with a layer can be defined as visible or invisible 
   within a component of the presentation hierarchy. A single item can be associated 
   with several layers and a single layer can be used in several components of 
   the presentation hierarchy. For an item which is associated with several layers, 
   a different presentation style can be assigned to each layer. A layer is defined by
   a <b>presentation_layer_assignment</b>. The visibility and style assignment of a given layer within
   a component of the presentation hierarchy is specified by a <b>presentation_layer_usage</b>.
   </p>
   
   <!-- Association of presentation with a product model -->
   
   <b><i>Association of presentation with a product model</i></b>
   <p>
   This part of ISO 10303 allows the association of presentation information with 
   the product information which is presented. This association is achieved through
   the use of a <b>presented_item_representation</b>. This entity relates the item 
   which is presented with the presentation of that item. The <b>presented_item</b> shall 
   be specialized by Application Protocols.
   </p>
   <example number="4">
   Presented items are the body design of a car, the layout of an electronic chip, or the architecture of a building.
   </example>
   
   </fund_cons>
   

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="presentation_organization_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

<!-- ++++++++++ presentation_definition_schema ++++++++++ -->
<schema name="presentation_definition_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="presentation_definition_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

<!-- ++++++++++ presentation_appearance_schema ++++++++++ -->
<schema name="presentation_appearance_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="presentation_appearance_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>

<!-- ++++++++++ presentation_resource_schema ++++++++++ -->
<schema name="presentation_resource_schema">
<!-- Note schema EXPRESS are in ..\resources\resource_name name_of_schema.xml -->
   <introduction>
   </introduction>
   <fund_cons>
   </fund_cons>

<!-- EXPRESS-G -->
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="presentation_resource_schemaexpg1.xml"/>
   </express-g>
</schema>



 <!-- shortnames  -->
 <shortnames>
 <shortname name="SHRTNM" entity="full_name"/>
 </shortnames>

 <!-- optional annexes 
 <tech_discussion/>

 <examples/>

 <add_scope/>

 <bibliography/>
-->
</resource>

