<collection_page page_type="main">
      <h2><a name="introduction">Introduction</a></h2>
      <h3><a name="introduction">General</a></h3>
      <p>
         ISO 10303 is an International Standard for the computer-interpretable 
         representation of product information and for the exchange of product data.
         The objective is to provide a neutral mechanism capable of describing
         products throughout their life cycle. This mechanism is suitable not only
         for neutral file exchange, but also as a basis for implementing and
         sharing product databases, and as a basis for archiving.
         
      </p>
      <p>
         A complete list of parts of ISO 10303 is available from the following URL: 
         
      </p>
      <div align="center">
	<blockquote>
	   <a href="http://standards.iso.org/iso/10303/STEP_Parts_List.htm" target="_blank">
	      http://standards.iso.org/iso/10303/STEP_Parts_List.htm</a>.
            
        </blockquote>
      </div>
      <p>To provide for unambiguous identification of an information object in an open system, an object identifier is assigned to each part of ISO 10303. The meaning of that value is defined in ISO/IEC 8824-1, and is described in ISO 10303-1. 
      </p>
      <p>
         This collection is the standard for the exchange of product model data (STEP) module and resource library (SMRL).
      </p>
      <p>
	 The SMRL was developed in accordance with Reference [<a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_Part1000_proc">11</a>].
      </p>

<h3>Application protocol background</h3>
<p>ISO 10303 has been designed to support an extensive domain of product data communication requirements, i.e. all product data necessary to completely define any product for all applications over the product's entire life cycle. With the broad scope and complexity of ISO 10303, the implementation of ISO 10303 in its entirety by any one organization is unlikely.</p>
<p>For the use of ISO 10303 within a particular application context, an application protocol (AP) provides the information required for practical implementation. This includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>the definition of the application context, scope and functional requirements;</li>
<li>the definition of the application information requirements;</li>
<li>the required use of the ISO 10303 integrated resource constructs to support the application information requirements;</li>
<li>the specification of levels of conformance for evaluating implementations of the AP.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Application modules background</h3>
<p>Application modules are the key component of the
ISO 10303 modular architecture. The basis of the approach is understanding and harmonizing the requirements,
both new and those documented in existing APs, grouping the requirements
into reuseable modules, and using the modules
in the development of an AP.</p>
<p>An application module contains much of the technical content that, in the initial ISO
10303 architecture, was documented in an AP. The role of an AP document
in the modular architecture is to provide a business context for the industrial
use and implementation of the application modules that are the data specification
of the AP.</p>
<p>There are three types of application modules: foundation modules (level
1), implementation modules (level 2), and AP modules (level 3). Foundation
modules provide lower level reusable structures that are not likely to
be implemented alone, but are highly shareable and reusable. Implementation
modules define a capability that can be implemented and against which conformance
classes can be defined. Each AP references a single root module that
is an AP module. An AP module is an implementation module, and the
contents of an AP module are the same as other implementation modules,
the only documentation difference being in their name and title. The
AP module from one AP can be used by another AP. A detailed description
of the content of an application module is provided in Reference [<a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_AMConGde06">9</a>]. A detailed description of the content of an
application protocol that uses application modules is provided in
Reference [<a href="biblio.htm#bibitem_APConGde">10</a>].</p>
<p>The ISO 10303 modular architecture is intended to:</p>
<ul>
<li>
ensure the ability to implement a combination of subsets of multiple
APs, or to extend existing APs to meet a business need;</li>

<li>
ensure the ability to reuse application software developed to support
one AP in the development of an implementation of another AP with the same,
or similar, requirements;</li>

<li>
avoid the duplication and repeated documentation of the same requirements
in different application protocols, leading to potentially different solutions
for the same requirements;</li>

<li>
 ensure the ability to reuse data generated by an implementation of one
or more APs by an implementation of one or more different APs.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Library structure</h3>
<p>The SMRL consists of the following parts:</p>
<ul>
<li>application modules series of parts: ISO 10303 parts 401 to 499 and 1001 to 1999;</li>
<li>application interpreted constructs series of parts: ISO 10303 parts 501 to 599;</li>
<li>integrated resources series of parts: ISO 10303 parts 41 to 112;</li>
<li>logical model of expressions: ISO 13584-20;</li>
   <li>business object models series of parts: ISO 10303 parts 3001 to 3099.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Convention</h3>
<p>Within the SMRL, any reference to a part number that does not include a standard number refers to a part of ISO 10303. There is one exception to this. A reference to Part 20 refers to ISO 13584-20.</p>
<h3>Navigation</h3>
<p>Each part belonging to the SMRL is maintained as a separate ISO document. However, the individual parts belonging to the SMRL will not be sold or distributed separately; they will only be sold and distributed as part of a package consisting of the entire SMRL. The SMRL product contains a top-level structure that provides
<a href="frame_index.htm" target="index">navigation indices</a>
for the parts that are included in the SMRL.</p>
<h3>Use of the SMRL</h3>
<p>The following are the modular application protocols. These parts of ISO 10303 make use of the AMs, which are in the SMRL:</p>
<ul>
<li>ISO 10303-203;</li>
<li>ISO 10303-209;</li>
<li>ISO 10303-210;</li>
<li>ISO 10303-221;</li>   
<li>ISO 10303-233;</li>
<li>ISO 10303-236;</li>
<li>ISO 10303-239;</li>
<li>ISO 10303-242.</li>
</ul>
<p>Other ISO 10303 application protocols make use of the AICs and IRs.</p>
<h3>Intended audience</h3>
<p>The intended audience of the SMRL includes standards committees that are developing modular application protocols, software developers that are implementing modular application protocols, and those who are considering adopting ISO 10303 modular application protocols, application modules, and resource parts, or systems built on them, for product data representation and exchange.</p>
</collection_page>
