<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.22 2006/11/20 10:32:52 rugarcia Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<module name="parameterized_catalog_data_information" 
	name.french="Informations param&#233;triques de donn&#233;es de catalogue" 
	part="1353" 
	version="1" 
	sc4.working_group="12" 
	wg.number="2169" 
	wg.number.arm="2170" 
	wg.number.mim="2172" 
	wg.number.arm_lf="2171" 
	wg.number.mim_lf="2173" 
	checklist.internal_review="1307" 
	checklist.project_leader="1308" 
	checklist.convener="1314" 
	status="TS" 
	language="E" 
	publication.year="2006" 
	publication.date="2006-07-26" 
	published="y" 
	rcs.date="$Date: 2006/11/20 10:32:52 $" 
	rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.22 $" 
	development.folder="dvlp">
	<keywords>
		module, 
		catalog
	</keywords>
	<!-- the abstract for the module. If not provided, the XSL will use the in scope -->
	<!-- Reference to contacts detailed in stepmod/data/basic/contacts.xml -->
	<contacts>
		<projlead ref="ap236.projlead"/>
		<editor ref="ap236.editor"/>
	</contacts>
	<!-- Introduction -->
	<purpose>
		<p>
		This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation of the data that identify 
		and characterize products offered to market and of their components. This application module provides 
		specifications suitable for the representation of any kind of such products. In particular, this application 
		module enables the representation of products proposed to market with a great number of variants and 
		whose composition is characterized due to the selection among a set of different product features. 
		</p>
		<example>
		Examples of such products are the products developed by the furniture industry, the automotive industry 
		and the commercial airplane industry.
		</example>
		<p>
		This application module specifies the data types and their constraints. It specifies the conformance class 
		1 of ISO 10303-236.
		</p>
		<p>
		A catalogue contains a list of references of different commercial products that are proposed to customers 
		or to distributors. A catalogue provides a commercial view of the products of a supplier or manufacturer 
		but it does not represent the design information of the commercial products.
		</p>
		<p>
		It also provides information about the planned usage of components in a product model.
		</p>
		<p>
		The core of the product model is catalogue information. This information is connected to other parts in order 
		to define the geometry of the products and to select a set of product features.
		</p>
		<p> 
		This application module provides the definition for the main information data of a catalogue, such as the 
		definition of a product (and its different versions) and its specifications (the features of a product that the 
		customer can chose in order to select one product from another). The structure of the product (the product 
		itself or the decomposition of the product in its components), the effectivity of the catalogue itself or its 
		products, the effectivity of the prices of the products, documents (hardcopies or digital files) that gives 
		additional information about the product such as detailed information, pictures, technical drawings, and a 
		classification of the products in order they could be found easily in a catalogue depending on different 
		search criteria; the properties of the product (not selectable by the user). It specifies the main concepts 
		for representing a catalogue specification in the <module_ref linkend="product_class:introduction">ISO 
		1303-1103</module_ref> (Product class).
		</p>
		<p>
		In particular, this application module enables the representation of products proposed to market with a 
		great number of variants and whose composition is characterized with expressions of operands selected in 
		a set of product features.
		</p>
		<note>
		This application module is an extension of the Catalog_data_information module,
				<module_ref linkend="catalog_data_information:introduction">ISO/TS 10303-1351</module_ref>.
		</note>
		<p>
		This application module specifies the schema associated with conformance class 2 of application protocol 
		ISO 10303-236.
		</p>
	</purpose>
	<!-- Items in scope -->
	<inscope>
		<li>representation of catalog product data definition;</li>
		<li>supporting of catalog product stucture;</li>
		<li>possibility of variants and options for product representations;</li>
		<li>products classification and products specification associated control;</li>
		<li>product dimensions;</li>
		<li>price lists based on products identification and associated characteristics;</li>
		<li>product configuration based on diferent characteristics;</li>
		<li>multi-language support;</li>
		<li>approval status of the products;</li>
		<li>effectivity for data validation;</li>
		<li>documents definition and assignment;</li>
		<li>product identified by its manufacturing configuration;</li>
		<li>parameterized properties for products based on expressions and using other product property values;</li>
		<li>establishment of relationships between variables and properties.</li>
	</inscope>
	<!-- Items out of scope -->
	<outscope>
		<li>work management data;</li>
		<li>any kind of geometric representation other than geometric models placing externally defined geometric models;</li>
		<li>products constraints based on expressions;</li>
		<li>variants and options based on expressions.</li>
	</outscope>
	<!-- Clause 4 ARM  -->
	<arm>
		<!-- Note ARM short form EXPRESS is in arm.xml -->
		<!-- Short form EXPRESS-G -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</arm>
	<arm_lf/>
	<!-- Clause 5.2 MIM -->
	<mim>
		<!--  Note MIM short form express is in mim.xml -->
		<express-g>
			<imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
		</express-g>
	</mim>
	<mim_lf/>
	<bibliography>	
		<bibitem.inc ref="ISO10303-236"/>		
	</bibliography>
</module>
