<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <?xml-stylesheet 
  type="text/xsl" 
  href="../../../xsl/descriptions.xsl"?>
<?DOCTYPE 
  express SYSTEM "../../../dtd/description.dtd"?>
<ext_descriptions module_directory="assembly_structure" schema_file="arm.xml" 
rcs.date="" rcs.revision="">


  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm"/>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm  Entity: Assembly_component_relationship 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm.Assembly_component_relationship">
	 An <b>Assembly_component_relationship</b> is a type of <b>View_definition_usage</b>. 
It identifies a possibly quantified usage of a product version as a component of another product version.
<p>The relationship is established between two instances of <b>Product_view_definition</b>.</p>
<p>The inherited attribute <b>SELF\View_definition_relationship.view1</b> identifies the <b>Product_view_definition</b> of the assembly.</p>
<p>The inherited attribute <b>SELF\View_definition_relationship.view2</b> identifies the <b>Product_view_definition</b> of the product version that plays the role of component.</p>
<p>The <b>Assembly_component_relationship</b> specifies that, in the <b>initial_context</b> of the <b>Product_view_definition</b> that is referred to as <b>view1</b>, it is considered that the product version that is indirectly identified with the view2 attribute, is a component of the product version that is indirectly identified with the view1 attribute.
</p>
<note number="1">In another context, the structure of the assembly may be described differently, adding, for example, an intermediate level between the products.</note>
<note number="2">This entity data type may be used to establish assembly relationships during design or to represent the composition of an assembly existing in the real world.</note>
<note number="3">An <b>Assembly_component_relationship</b> identifies an item in a parts list. Should the quantity be zero, the component would still be listed in the parts list.</note>

<p>In case the component is a <module_ref linkend="part_and_version_identification:3_definition:NCM">part</module_ref>, the following additional specifications apply:</p>
<ul>
<li>the <b>quantity</b> attribute shall either be not specified or shall characterize a number of occurrences of the component;</li>
<li>if the <b>quantity</b> attribute specifies a number of occurrences, these occurrences shall be considered as a single group within the assembly structure.</li>
<li>if the <b>quantity</b> attribute is not specified, the relationship actually identifies a single occurrence of the component;</li>
</ul>
<p>In case the component is a <module_ref linkend="part_and_version_identification:3_definition:NCM">non-countable material</module_ref>, the following additional specifications apply:</p>
<ul>
<li>the <b>quantity</b> attribute shall either be not specified or shall characterize the amount of the material used as component;</li>
<li>if the <b>quantity</b> attribute is not specified, the amount of material used as component shall be considered as unknown;</li>

</ul>
<example>A assembly may require inclusion of ten grams of grease. 
</example>
<note number="3">This version of the Assembly structure module does not enable to represent the fact that the quantity of a fluid component is, 
for example 'at most 10 grams' or 'between 5 or 20 grams'. However, some ISO 10303 application protocols, for example ISO 10303-214, provide a representation for those requirements.</note>

</ext_description>


  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm  Entity: Assembly_component_relationship  Attribute: quantity 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm.Assembly_component_relationship.quantity">
the <b>Numerical_value</b> that defines the amount of this usage of the component in the assembly. This attribute need not be specified.
</ext_description>
  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm  Entity: Assembly_component_relationship  Attribute: location_indicator 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm.Assembly_component_relationship.location_indicator">
	 a text that identifies this usage of the component in the assembly in a diagram, list, chart, or on a physical piece of
equipment. This attribute need not be specified.
	 </ext_description>

	   ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm  Entity: Assembly_component_relationship  Where: WR1 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm.Assembly_component_relationship.wr:WR1">
If it is specified and if its value is expressed with a number, the quantity value shall be greater than zero.
	 </ext_description>
  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm  Entity: Next_assembly_usage 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm.Next_assembly_usage">
A <b>Next_assembly_usage</b> is a type of <b>Assembly_component_relationship</b>.
It establishes a relationship between a component and its immediate parent assembly in a product structure.

</ext_description>

  <!-- 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++
   Schema: Assembly_structure_arm  Entity: Promissory_usage 
  ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ 
  -->
   <ext_description linkend="Assembly_structure_arm.Promissory_usage">
A <b>Promissory_usage</b> is a type of <b>Assembly_component_relationship</b>. 
It establishes a relationship between an assembly and a component, regardless the number of intermediate levels between them, which may be established with instances of <b>Next_assembly_usage</b>.

<note>A <b>Promissory_usage</b> may be used when the product structure is not completely defined, to capture the intent that the constituent will
be used in that assembly.
</note>
</ext_description>
</ext_descriptions>