<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- $Id: module.xml,v 1.8 2002/12/17 10:45:07 lglauro Exp $ -->
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "../../../dtd/module.dtd">
<!-- Generated by mkmodule.js, Eurostep Limited, http://www.eurostep.com -->
<module
   name="product_class"
   part="1103"
   version="1"
   wg.number="1585"
   wg.number.arm="1586"
   wg.number.mim="1587"
   checklist.internal_review=""
   checklist.project_leader=""
   checklist.convener=""
   status="CD-TS"
   language="E"
   publication.year=""
   published="n"
   rcs.date="$Date: 2002/12/17 10:45:07 $"
   rcs.revision="$Revision: 1.8 $">

 <keywords>
    module, product class, specification, specification category, Boolean specification expression
 </keywords>

 <contacts>
   <projlead ref="ap236.projlead"/>
   <editor ref="ap236.editor"/>
 </contacts>

 <purpose>
This part of ISO 10303 specifies an application module for the representation of the identification and characterization of families of similar product to be offered to the market.
 </purpose>

 <inscope>
 <li>identification, as a product class, of a set of similar products to be offerred to the market;</li>
 <li>relationships between product classes;</li>
 <li>identification of categories of specifications that may be used to characterize the members of a product-class;</li>
 <li>representation of Boolean expressions of specifications;</li>
 <li>representation of dependency rules between specifications;</li>
 <li>association of specification categories, of specifications, of specification expressions and of specification dependency rules with a product-class.</li>
 </inscope>

 <outscope>
 <li>identification of the parts to be used in the members of a product class;</li>
 <li>identification of process-plans to be used to manufacture, assemble or control the members of a product class.</li>
 </outscope>


 <normrefs>
		<normref.inc normref="ref10303-41.2000"/>
		<normref.inc normref="ref10303-44.2000"/>
		 <normref.inc module.name="product_breakdown"/>
  	 <normref.inc module.name="specification_based_configuration"/>
</normrefs>
<!--
 <definition/>

 <abbreviations/>
-->
 
 <arm>
 <uof name="Product_class">
 <description>
 The Product_class UoF specifies the data structure for the representation of families of products with a large number of variants.
<note>
Generally the major part of the products on the market are grouped in sets of products and have a large number of options and variants. 
<example number="1"><li> furniture products may be grouped in collections, series, products and each type of furniture product may be offered with different finishings, different colours, different fabrics and different handles</li></example>
<example number="2"><li> passenger cars may be grouped in models and each models may have several options like radio, phone connection, satellite navigator, leather seats and different variants like colours.</li>
</example>
</note>
Because of the large number of variants there is no unique identification for each of the variants that could be produced. The main concepts that are used to handle this large number of variants are the following: 
<li>product classes are used to identify sets of similar products to be offered to the market;</li><li> 
specifications are used to describe characteristics of the products;</li><li> 
specification categories are used to group similar characteristics of the products;</li><li> 
specification expressions are used to control the usage of a part within a product and to represent conditions for product classes.</li>
</description> 
<uof.ae entity="Class_category_association"/>
<uof.ae entity="Class_condition_association"/>
<uof.ae entity="Class_inclusion_association"/>
<uof.ae entity="Class_specification_association"/>
<uof.ae entity="Product_class"/>
<uof.ae entity="Product_class_relationship"/>
<uof.ae entity="Specification"/>
<uof.ae entity="Specification_category"/>
<uof.ae entity="Specification_category_hierarchy"/>
<uof.ae entity="Specification_expression"/>
<uof.ae entity="Specification_inclusion"/>

</uof>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="armexpg1.xml"/>
		 <imgfile file="armexpg2.xml"/>
     <imgfile file="armexpg3.xml"/>
    </express-g>
 </arm>

 <mapping_table/>

 <mim>
   <express-g>
     <imgfile file="mimexpg1.xml"/>
		 <imgfile file="mimexpg2.xml"/>
		 
    </express-g>
		<shortnames>
      <shortname name="EPCFC" entity="exclusive_product_concept_feature_category"/>
			<shortname name="IPCF" entity="inclusion_product_concept_feature"/>
			<shortname name="PPCF" entity="package_product_concept_feature"/>
			<shortname name="PRDCLS" entity="product_class"/>
			<shortname name="PCF0" entity="product_concept_feature_category"/>
			<shortname name="PCFCU" entity="product_concept_feature_category_usage"/>
   </shortnames>
 </mim>
<bibliography>
	<bibitem>
		<stdnumber>ISO/TS 10303-1248:2003</stdnumber>
     		<stdtitle>
			Industrial automation systems and integration - Product data representation and exchange - Part 1248: Application module: Product breakdown
		</stdtitle>
		</bibitem>
		<bibitem>
		<stdnumber>ISO/TS 10303-1108:2003</stdnumber>
     		<stdtitle>
			Industrial automation systems and integration - Product data representation and exchange - Part 1108: Application module: Specification based configuration
		</stdtitle>
  	</bibitem>
</bibliography>
</module>
